The Book of OmniChapter 1 Omni, Amaron,
Chemish, Abinadom, and Amaleki, each in turn, keep
the records—Mosiah discovers the people of
Zarahemla, who came from Jerusalem in the days of
Zedekiah—Mosiah is made king over them—The
descendants of Mulek at Zarahemla had discovered
Coriantumr, the last of the Jaredites—King
Benjamin succeeds Mosiah—Men should offer their
souls as an offering to Christ. About 323–130 B.C.
1 Behold, it came to pass that I,
Omni, being commanded by my father,
Jarom, that I should write somewhat upon
these plates, to preserve our genealogy—
2 Wherefore, in my days, I would
that ye should know that I fought
much with the sword to preserve my
people, the Nephites, from falling
into the hands of their enemies, the
Lamanites. But behold, I of myself
am a wicked man, and I have not kept
the statutes and the commandments
of the Lord as I ought to have done.
3 And it came to pass that two
hundred and seventy and six years had
passed away, and we had many
seasons of peace; and we had many
seasons of serious war and bloodshed.
Yea, and in fine, two hundred and
eighty and two years had passed
away, and I had kept these plates
according to the commandments of my
fathers; and I conferred them upon
my son Amaron. And I make an end.
4 And now I, Amaron, write the
things whatsoever I write, which
are few, in the book of my father.
5 Behold, it came to pass
that three hundred and
twenty years had passed away,
and the more wicked part of
the Nephites were destroyed.
6 For the Lord would not
suffer, after he had led
them out of the land of
Jerusalem and kept and
preserved them from falling into
the hands of their
enemies, yea, he would not suffer
that the words should not
be verified, which he
spake unto our fathers,
saying that: Inasmuch as ye
will not keep my commandments
ye shall not prosper in the land.
7 Wherefore, the Lord did
visit them in great
judgment; nevertheless, he
did spare the righteous
that they should not perish,
but did deliver them out
of the hands of their enemies.
8 And it came to
pass that I did
deliver the plates unto
my brother Chemish.
9 Now I, Chemish,
write what few
things I write, in
the same book with
my brother; for
behold, I saw the
last which he wrote,
that he wrote it
with his own hand;
and he wrote it in
the day that he
delivered them unto
me. And after
this manner we keep
the records, for it
is according to
the commandments of
our fathers. And I make an end.
10 Behold, I,
Abinadom, am the son
of Chemish.
Behold, it came to
pass that I saw
much war and
contention between my
people, the
Nephites, and the
Lamanites; and I, with
my own sword,
have taken the lives
of many of the
Lamanites in the
defence of my brethren.
11 And behold,
the record of
this people is
engraven upon plates
which is had by
the kings,
according to the
generations; and I
know of no
revelation save that
which has been
written, neither
prophecy;
wherefore, that which
is sufficient is
written. And I make an end.
12 Behold, I am
Amaleki, the
son of Abinadom.
Behold, I will
speak unto you
somewhat
concerning Mosiah,
who was made
king over the land
of Zarahemla;
for behold, he
being warned of
the Lord that
he should flee
out of the land
of Nephi, and
as many as
would hearken unto
the voice of
the Lord should
also depart out
of the land
with him, into the wilderness—
13 And it came
to pass that he
did according
as the Lord had
commanded him.
And they
departed out of the
land into the
wilderness, as
many as would
hearken unto the
voice of the
Lord; and they
were led by many
preachings and
prophesyings.
And they were
admonished
continually by the
word of God; and
they were led
by the power of
his arm,
through the
wilderness until they
came down into
the land which is
called the
land of Zarahemla.
14 And they
discovered a
people, who were
called the
people of
Zarahemla. Now, there
was great
rejoicing among
the people of
Zarahemla; and
also Zarahemla
did rejoice
exceedingly,
because the Lord
had sent the
people of
Mosiah with the
plates of brass
which
contained the record of the Jews.
15 Behold, it
came to pass
that Mosiah
discovered
that the people
of Zarahemla
came out
from Jerusalem
at the time
that Zedekiah,
king of
Judah, was carried
away captive
into Babylon.
16 And they
journeyed in
the
wilderness, and
were brought by
the hand of
the Lord
across the
great waters,
into the land
where
Mosiah discovered
them; and
they had
dwelt there from
that time forth.
17 And at
the time
that Mosiah
discovered
them, they
had become
exceedingly
numerous.
Nevertheless,
they had
had many
wars and
serious
contentions, and
had fallen by
the sword
from time
to time; and
their
language had
become
corrupted; and
they had
brought no
records with
them; and
they denied
the being of
their
Creator; and
Mosiah, nor
the people of Mosiah, could understand them.
18 But it
came to pass
that
Mosiah caused
that they
should be
taught in his
language.
And it came
to pass that
after they
were
taught in the
language of
Mosiah,
Zarahemla gave
a genealogy
of his
fathers,
according to his
memory;
and they are
written,
but not in
these plates.
19 And it
came to
pass that
the people
of
Zarahemla, and of
Mosiah,
did unite
together;
and Mosiah
was
appointed to be their king.
20 And it
came to
pass in
the days
of Mosiah,
there
was a large
stone
brought
unto him
with
engravings on
it; and he
did
interpret the
engravings by the
gift and power of God.
21 And
they gave
an
account of
one
Coriantumr,
and the
slain of
his
people. And
Coriantumr was
discovered by the
people
of
Zarahemla;
and he
dwelt with
them for
the space of nine moons.
22 It
also
spake a
few words
concerning
his
fathers. And
first
parents
came out
from
the
tower, at
the time
the
Lord
confounded
the
language of
people;
and the
severity of
the Lord
fell
upon them
according to
his
judgments,
which
are
just; and
their
bones lay scattered in the land northward.
Behold,
I,
Amaleki,
was
born in
the
days of
Mosiah;
and I
have
lived
to see
his
death;
and
Benjamin, his
son,
reigneth in his stead.
24 And
behold, I
have
seen, in
the
days of
king
Benjamin, a
serious war
and
much
bloodshed
between the
Nephites
and the
Lamanites.
But
behold,
the
Nephites
did
obtain
much
advantage over
them;
yea,
insomuch
that king
Benjamin
did
drive them
out
of the
land
of
Zarahemla.
And it
came
to
pass
that I
began
to
be
old;
and,
having
no
seed,
and
knowing
king
Benjamin
to be
a
just man
before
the
Lord,
wherefore, I
shall
deliver
up
these
plates
unto
him,
exhorting
all
men
to
come
unto
God, the
Holy
One
of
Israel,
and
believe in
prophesying,
and in
revelations,
the
ministering of
angels,
and in
the
gift
of
speaking
with
tongues,
and
in the
gift
of
interpreting
languages,
and in
all
things
which are
good; for
there is
nothing which is good save it comes from the Lord: and that which is evil cometh from the devil.
And
now, my
beloved
brethren, I
would
that
ye
should
come
unto
Christ,
who is
the
Holy
One
of
Israel,
and
partake of
his
salvation,
and
the
power
of his
redemption.
Yea,
come
unto
him,
and
offer
your
whole
souls
as an
offering
unto
him,
and
continue in
fasting
and
praying, and
endure to
the
end;
and
as the
Lord
liveth ye
will
be
saved.
And
now I
would
speak
somewhat
concerning
a
certain
number
who
went
up
into
the
wilderness to
return
to
the
land
of
Nephi;
for
there
was
a
large
number
who
were
desirous to possess the land of their inheritance.
Wherefore,
they
went
up
into
the
wilderness.
And
their
leader
being a
strong
and
mighty
man,
and
a
stiffnecked
man,
wherefore
he
caused
a
contention
among
them;
and
they
were
all
slain,
save
fifty,
in the wilderness, and they returned again to the land of Zarahemla.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
they
also
took
others
to
a
considerable
number,
and
took their journey again into the wilderness.
And
I,
Amaleki,
had
a
brother,
who
also
went
with
them;
and
I
have
not
since
known
concerning
them.
And
I
am
about
to
lie
down
in
my
grave;
and
these
plates
are
full.
And
I
make
an
end
of
my
speaking.