Chapter 14 Alma and Amulek are imprisoned and
smitten—The believers and their holy scriptures are
burned by fire—These martyrs are received by the
Lord in glory—The prison walls are rent and fall—Alma
and Amulek are delivered, and their persecutors
are slain. About 82–81 B.C.
1 And it came to pass after he had made an end of
speaking unto the people many of them did believe
on his words, and began to repent, and to search
the scriptures
2 But the more part of them were desirous that
they might destroy Alma and Amulek; for they were
angry with Alma, because of the plainness of his
words unto Zeezrom; and they also said that Amulek had
lied unto them, and had reviled against their law
and also against their lawyers and judges
3 And they were also angry with Alma and Amulek;
and because they had testified so plainly against
their wickedness, they sought to put them away
privily
4 But it came to pass that they did not; but they
took them and bound them with strong cords, and
took them before the chief judge of the land
5 And the people went forth and witnessed against
them—testifying that they had reviled against the
law, and their lawyers and judges of the land, and
also of all the people that were in the land; and
also testified that there was but one God, and
that he should send his Son among the people, but he
should not save them; and many such things did
the people testify against Alma and Amulek. Now this
was done before the chief judge of the land
6 And it came to pass that Zeezrom was astonished
at the words which had been spoken; and he also
knew concerning the blindness of the minds, which he
had caused among the people by his lying words;
and his soul began to be harrowed up under a
consciousness of his own guilt; yea, he began to be
encircled about by the pains of hell
7 And it came to pass that he began to cry unto
the people, saying: Behold, I am guilty, and these
men are spotless before God. And he began to plead
for them from that time forth; but they reviled
him, saying: Art thou also possessed with the devil?
And they spit upon him, and cast him out from
among them, and also all those who believed in the
words which had been spoken by Alma and Amulek; and
they cast them out, and sent men to cast stones at
them
8 And they brought their wives and children
together, and whosoever believed or had been taught to
believe in the word of God they caused that they
should be cast into the fire; and they also brought
forth their records which contained the holy
scriptures, and cast them into the fire also, that they
might be burned and destroyed by fire
9 And it came to pass that they took Alma and
Amulek, and carried them forth to the place of
martyrdom, that they might witness the destruction of
those who were consumed by fire
10 And when Amulek saw the pains of the women and
children who were consuming in the fire, he also
was pained; and he said unto Alma: How can we
witness this awful scene? Therefore let us stretch
forth our hands, and exercise the power of God which
is in us, and save them from the flames
11 But Alma said unto him: The Spirit constraineth
me that I must not stretch forth mine hand; for
behold the Lord receiveth them up unto himself, in
glory; and he doth suffer that they may do this
thing, or that the people may do this thing unto
them, according to the hardness of their hearts, that
the judgments which he shall exercise upon them
in his wrath may be just; and the blood of the
innocent shall stand as a witness against them, yea,
and cry mightily against them at the last day
12 Now Amulek said unto Alma: Behold, perhaps they
will burn us also
13 And Alma said: Be it according to the will of
the Lord. But, behold, our work is not finished;
therefore they burn us not
14 Now it came to pass that when the bodies of
those who had been cast into the fire were consumed,
and also the records which were cast in with them,
the chief judge of the land came and stood before
Alma and Amulek, as they were bound; and he smote
them with his hand upon their cheeks, and said
unto them: After what ye have seen, will ye preach
again unto this people, that they shall be cast
into a lake of fire and brimstone
15 Behold, ye see that ye had not power to save
those who had been cast into the fire; neither has
God saved them because they were of thy faith. And
the judge smote them again upon their cheeks, and
asked: What say ye for yourselves
16 Now this judge was after the order and faith of
Nehor, who slew Gideon
17 And it came to pass that Alma and Amulek
answered him nothing; and he smote them again, and
delivered them to the officers to be cast into prison
18 And when they had been cast into prison three
days, there came many lawyers, and judges, and
priests, and teachers, who were of the profession of
Nehor; and they came in unto the prison to see
them, and they questioned them about many words; but
they answered them nothing
19 And it came to pass that the judge stood before
them, and said: Why do ye not answer the words of
this people? Know ye not that I have power to
deliver you up unto the flames? And he commanded them
to speak; but they answered nothing
20 And it came to pass that they departed and went
their ways, but came again on the morrow; and the
judge also smote them again on their cheeks. And
many came forth also, and smote them, saying: Will
ye stand again and judge this people, and condemn
our law? If ye have such great power why do ye
not deliver yourselves
21 And many such things did they say unto them,
gnashing their teeth upon them, and spitting upon
them, and saying: How shall we look when we are
damned
22 And many such things, yea, all manner of such
things did they say unto them; and thus they did
mock them for many days. And they did withhold food
from them that they might hunger, and water that
they might thirst; and they also did take from them
their clothes that they were naked; and thus they
were bound with strong cords, and confined in
prison
23 And it came to pass after they had thus
suffered for many days, (and it was on the twelfth day,
in the tenth month, in the tenth year of the reign
of the judges over the people of Nephi) that the
chief judge over the land of Ammonihah and many of
their teachers and their lawyers went in unto the
prison where Alma and Amulek were bound with
cords
24 And the chief judge stood before them, and
smote them again, and said unto them: If ye have the
power of God deliver yourselves from these bands,
and then we will believe that the Lord will destroy
this people according to your words
25 And it came to pass that they all went forth
and smote them, saying the same words, even until
the last; and when the last had spoken unto them the
power of God was upon Alma and Amulek, and they
rose and stood upon their feet
26 And Alma cried, saying: How long shall we
suffer these great afflictions, O Lord? O Lord, give us
strength according to our faith which is in
Christ, even unto deliverance. And they broke the cords
with which they were bound; and when the people
saw this, they began to flee, for the fear of
destruction had come upon them
27 And it came to pass that so great was their
fear that they fell to the earth, and did not obtain
the outer door of the prison; and the earth shook
mightily, and the walls of the prison were rent in
twain, so that they fell to the earth; and the
chief judge, and the lawyers, and priests, and
teachers, who smote upon Alma and Amulek, were slain by
the fall thereof
28 And Alma and Amulek came forth out of the
prison, and they were not hurt; for the Lord had
granted unto them power, according to their faith which
was in Christ. And they straightway came forth out
of the prison; and they were loosed from their
bands; and the prison had fallen to the earth, and
every soul within the walls thereof, save it were
Alma and Amulek, was slain; and they straightway
came forth into the city
29 Now the people having heard a great noise came
running together by multitudes to know the cause
of it; and when they saw Alma and Amulek coming
forth out of the prison, and the walls thereof had
fallen to the earth, they were struck with great
fear, and fled from the presence of Alma and Amulek
even as a goat fleeth with her young from two
lions; and thus they did flee from the presence of Alma
and Amulek.