Chapter 11 The Nephite monetary system is set
forth—Amulek contends with Zeezrom—Christ will not
save people in their sins—Only those who inherit the
kingdom of heaven are saved—All men will rise in
immortality—There is no death after the
Resurrection. About 82 B.C.
1 Now it was in the law of Mosiah that every man
who was a judge of the law, or those who were
appointed to be judges, should receive wages according
to the time which they labored to judge those who
were brought before them to be judged
2 Now if a man owed another, and he would not pay
that which he did owe, he was complained of to the
judge; and the judge executed authority, and sent
forth officers that the man should be brought
before him; and he judged the man according to the
law and the evidences which were brought against
him, and thus the man was compelled to pay that which
he owed, or be stripped, or be cast out from
among the people as a thief and a robber
3 And the judge received for his wages according
to his time—a senine of gold for a day, or a senum
of silver, which is equal to a senine of gold; and
this is according to the law which was given
4 Now these are the names of the different pieces
of their gold, and of their silver, according to
their value. And the names are given by the
Nephites, for they did not reckon after the manner of the
Jews who were at Jerusalem; neither did they
measure after the manner of the Jews; but they altered
their reckoning and their measure, according to
the minds and the circumstances of the people, in
every generation, until the reign of the judges,
they having been established by king Mosiah
5 Now the reckoning is thus—a senine of gold, a
seon of gold, a shum of gold, and a limnah of gold
6 A senum of silver, an amnor of silver, an ezrom
of silver, and an onti of silver
7 A senum of silver was equal to a senine of gold,
and either for a measure of barley, and also for
a measure of every kind of grain
8 Now the amount of a seon of gold was twice the
value of a senine
9 And a shum of gold was twice the value of a
seon
10 And a limnah of gold was the value of them all
11 And an amnor of silver was as great as two
senums
12 And an ezrom of silver was as great as four
13 And an onti was as great as them all
14 Now this is the value of the lesser numbers of
their reckoning
15 A shiblon is half of a senum; therefore, a
shiblon for half a measure of barley
16 And a shiblum is a half of a shiblon
17 And a leah is the half of a shiblum
18 Now this is their number, according to their
reckoning
19 Now an antion of gold is equal to three
shiblons
20 Now, it was for the sole purpose to get gain,
because they received their wages according to
their employ, therefore, they did stir up the people
to riotings, and all manner of disturbances and
wickedness, that they might have more employ, that
they might get money according to the suits which
were brought before them; therefore they did stir up
the people against Alma and Amulek
21 And this Zeezrom began to question Amulek,
saying: Will ye answer me a few questions which I
shall ask you? Now Zeezrom was a man who was expert in
the devices of the devil, that he might destroy
that which was good; therefore, he said unto
Amulek: Will ye answer the questions which I shall put
unto you
22 And Amulek said unto him: Yea, if it be
according to the Spirit of the Lord, which is in me; for
I shall say nothing which is contrary to the
Spirit of the Lord. And Zeezrom said unto him: Behold,
here are six onties of silver, and all these will
I give thee if thou wilt deny the existence of a
Supreme Being
23 Now Amulek said: O thou child of hell, why
tempt ye me? Knowest thou that the righteous yieldeth
to no such temptations
24 Believest thou that there is no God? I say unto
you, Nay, thou knowest that there is a God, but
thou lovest that lucre more than him
25 And now thou hast lied before God unto me. Thou
saidst unto me—Behold these six onties, which are
of great worth, I will give unto thee—when thou
hadst it in thy heart to retain them from me; and
it was only thy desire that I should deny the true
and living God, that thou mightest have cause to
destroy me. And now behold, for this great evil
thou shalt have thy reward
26 And Zeezrom said unto him: Thou sayest there is
a true and living God
27 And Amulek said: Yea, there is a true and
living God
28 Now Zeezrom said: Is there more than one God
29 And he answered, No
30 Now Zeezrom said unto him again: How knowest
thou these things
31 And he said: An angel hath made them known unto
me
32 And Zeezrom said again: Who is he that shall
come? Is it the Son of God
33 And he said unto him, Yea
34 And Zeezrom said again: Shall he save his
people in their sins? And Amulek answered and said unto
him: I say unto you he shall not, for it is
impossible for him to deny his word
35 Now Zeezrom said unto the people: See that ye
remember these things; for he said there is but one
God; yet he saith that the Son of God shall come,
but he shall not save his people—as though he had
authority to command God
36 Now Amulek saith again unto him: Behold thou
hast lied, for thou sayest that I spake as though I
had authority to command God because I said he
shall not save his people in their sins
37 And I say unto you again that he cannot save
them in their sins; for I cannot deny his word, and
he hath said that no unclean thing can inherit the
kingdom of heaven; therefore, how can ye be
saved, except ye inherit the kingdom of heaven?
Therefore, ye cannot be saved in your sins
38 Now Zeezrom saith again unto him: Is the Son of
God the very Eternal Father
39 And Amulek said unto him: Yea, he is the very
Eternal Father of heaven and of earth, and all
things which in them are; he is the beginning and the
end, the first and the last
40 And he shall come into the world to redeem his
people; and he shall take upon him the
transgressions of those who believe on his name; and these
are they that shall have eternal life, and salvation
cometh to none else
41 Therefore the wicked remain as though there had
been no redemption made, except it be the loosing
of the bands of death; for behold, the day cometh
that all shall rise from the dead and stand
before God, and be judged according to their works
42 Now, there is a death which is called a
temporal death; and the death of Christ shall loose the
bands of this temporal death, that all shall be
raised from this temporal death
43 The spirit and the body shall be reunited again
in its perfect form; both limb and joint shall be
restored to its proper frame, even as we now are
at this time; and we shall be brought to stand
before God, knowing even as we know now, and have a
bright recollection of all our guilt
44 Now, this restoration shall come to all, both
old and young, both bond and free, both male and
female, both the wicked and the righteous; and even
there shall not so much as a hair of their heads
be lost; but every thing shall be restored to its
perfect frame, as it is now, or in the body, and
shall be brought and be arraigned before the bar of
Christ the Son, and God the Father, and the Holy
Spirit, which is one Eternal God, to be judged
according to their works, whether they be good or
whether they be evil
45 Now, behold, I have spoken unto you concerning
the death of the mortal body, and also concerning
the resurrection of the mortal body. I say unto
you that this mortal body is raised to an immortal
body, that is from death, even from the first death
unto life, that they can die no more; their
spirits uniting with their bodies, never to be divided;
thus the whole becoming spiritual and immortal,
that they can no more see corruption
46 Now, when Amulek had finished these words the
people began again to be astonished, and also
Zeezrom began to tremble. And thus ended the words of
Amulek, or this is all that I have written.