Chapter 10 Lehi descended from Manasseh—Amulek
recounts the angelic command that he care for
Alma—The prayers of the righteous cause the people to be
spared—Unrighteous lawyers and judges lay the
foundation of the destruction of the people. About
82 B.C.
1 Now these are the words which Amulek preached
unto the people who were in the land of Ammonihah,
saying
2 I am Amulek; I am the son of Giddonah, who was
the son of Ishmael, who was a descendant of
Aminadi; and it was that same Aminadi who interpreted the
writing which was upon the wall of the temple,
which was written by the finger of God
3 And Aminadi was a descendant of Nephi, who was
the son of Lehi, who came out of the land of
Jerusalem, who was a descendant of Manasseh, who was the
son of Joseph who was sold into Egypt by the
hands of his brethren
4 And behold, I am also a man of no small
reputation among all those who know me; yea, and behold, I
have many kindreds and friends, and I have also
acquired much riches by the hand of my industry
5 Nevertheless, after all this, I never have known
much of the ways of the Lord, and his mysteries
and marvelous power. I said I never had known much
of these things; but behold, I mistake, for I have
seen much of his mysteries and his marvelous
power; yea, even in the preservation of the lives of
this people
6 Nevertheless, I did harden my heart, for I was
called many times and I would not hear; therefore I
knew concerning these things, yet I would not
know; therefore I went on rebelling against God, in
the wickedness of my heart, even until the fourth
day of this seventh month, which is in the tenth
year of the reign of the judges
7 As I was journeying to see a very near kindred,
behold an angel of the Lord appeared unto me and
said: Amulek, return to thine own house, for thou
shalt feed a prophet of the Lord; yea, a holy man,
who is a chosen man of God; for he has fasted many
days because of the sins of this people, and he
is an hungered, and thou shalt receive him into thy
house and feed him, and he shall bless thee and
thy house; and the blessing of the Lord shall rest
upon thee and thy house
8 And it came to pass that I obeyed the voice of
the angel, and returned towards my house. And as I
was going thither I found the man whom the angel
said unto me: Thou shalt receive into thy house—and
behold it was this same man who has been speaking
unto you concerning the things of God
9 And the angel said unto me he is a holy man;
wherefore I know he is a holy man because it was said
by an angel of God
10 And again, I know that the things whereof he
hath testified are true; for behold I say unto you,
that as the Lord liveth, even so has he sent his
angel to make these things manifest unto me; and
this he has done while this Alma hath dwelt at my
house
11 For behold, he hath blessed mine house, he hath
blessed me, and my women, and my children, and my
father and my kinsfolk; yea, even all my kindred
hath he blessed, and the blessing of the Lord hath
rested upon us according to the words which he
spake
12 And now, when Amulek had spoken these words the
people began to be astonished, seeing there was
more than one witness who testified of the things
whereof they were accused, and also of the things
which were to come, according to the spirit of
prophecy which was in them
13 Nevertheless, there were some among them who
thought to question them, that by their cunning
devices they might catch them in their words, that
they might find witness against them, that they might
deliver them to their judges that they might be
judged according to the law, and that they might be
slain or cast into prison, according to the crime
which they could make appear or witness against
them
14 Now it was those men who sought to destroy
them, who were lawyers, who were hired or appointed by
the people to administer the law at their times
of trials, or at the trials of the crimes of the
people before the judges
15 Now these lawyers were learned in all the arts
and cunning of the people; and this was to enable
them that they might be skilful in their
profession
16 And it came to pass that they began to question
Amulek, that thereby they might make him cross
his words, or contradict the words which he should
speak
17 Now they knew not that Amulek could know of
their designs. But it came to pass as they began to
question him, he perceived their thoughts, and he
said unto them: O ye wicked and perverse
generation, ye lawyers and hypocrites, for ye are laying the
foundations of the devil; for ye are laying traps
and snares to catch the holy ones of God
18 Ye are laying plans to pervert the ways of the
righteous, and to bring down the wrath of God upon
your heads, even to the utter destruction of this
people
19 Yea, well did Mosiah say, who was our last
king, when he was about to deliver up the kingdom,
having no one to confer it upon, causing that this
people should be governed by their own voices—yea,
well did he say that if the time should come that
the voice of this people should choose iniquity,
that is, if the time should come that this people
should fall into transgression, they would be ripe
for destruction
20 And now I say unto you that well doth the Lord
judge of your iniquities; well doth he cry unto
this people, by the voice of his angels: Repent ye,
repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand
21 Yea, well doth he cry, by the voice of his
angels that: I will come down among my people, with
equity and justice in my hands
22 Yea, and I say unto you that if it were not for
the prayers of the righteous, who are now in the
land, that ye would even now be visited with utter
destruction; yet it would not be by flood, as
were the people in the days of Noah, but it would be
by famine, and by pestilence, and the sword
23 But it is by the prayers of the righteous that
ye are spared; now therefore, if ye will cast out
the righteous from among you then will not the
Lord stay his hand; but in his fierce anger he will
come out against you; then ye shall be smitten by
famine, and by pestilence, and by the sword; and
the time is soon at hand except ye repent
24 And now it came to pass that the people were
more angry with Amulek, and they cried out, saying:
This man doth revile against our laws which are
just, and our wise lawyers whom we have selected
25 But Amulek stretched forth his hand, and cried
the mightier unto them, saying: O ye wicked and
perverse generation, why hath Satan got such great
hold upon your hearts? Why will ye yield yourselves
unto him that he may have power over you, to
blind your eyes, that ye will not understand the words
which are spoken, according to their truth
26 For behold, have I testified against your law?
Ye do not understand; ye say that I have spoken
against your law; but I have not, but I have spoken
in favor of your law, to your condemnation
27 And now behold, I say unto you, that the
foundation of the destruction of this people is
beginning to be laid by the unrighteousness of your
lawyers and your judges
28 And now it came to pass that when Amulek had
spoken these words the people cried out against him,
saying: Now we know that this man is a child of
the devil, for he hath lied unto us; for he hath
spoken against our law. And now he says that he has
not spoken against it
29 And again, he has reviled against our lawyers,
and our judges
30 And it came to pass that the lawyers put it
into their hearts that they should remember these
things against him
31 And there was one among them whose name was
Zeezrom. Now he was the foremost to accuse Amulek and
Alma, he being one of the most expert among them,
having much business to do among the people
32 Now the object of these lawyers was to get
gain; and they got gain according to their employ.