An account of the sons of Mosiah, who rejected
their rights to the kingdom for the word of God, and
went up to the land of Nephi to preach to the
Lamanites; their sufferings and deliverance—according
to the record of Alma. Comprising chapters 17
through 27.Chapter 17 The sons of Mosiah have the
spirit of prophecy and of revelation—They go their
several ways to declare the word to the
Lamanites—Ammon goes to the land of Ishmael and becomes the
servant of King Lamoni—Ammon saves the king’s flocks
and slays his enemies at the water of Sebus.
Verses 1–3, about 77 B.C.;
verse 4, about 91–77 B.C.;
and
verses 5–39, about 91 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that as Alma was
journeying from the land of Gideon southward, away to the
land of Manti, behold, to his astonishment, he
met with the sons of Mosiah journeying towards the
land of Zarahemla
2 Now these sons of Mosiah were with Alma at the
time the angel first appeared unto him; therefore
Alma did rejoice exceedingly to see his brethren;
and what added more to his joy, they were still his
brethren in the Lord; yea, and they had waxed
strong in the knowledge of the truth; for they were
men of a sound understanding and they had searched
the scriptures diligently, that they might know
the word of God
3 But this is not all; they had given themselves
to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the
spirit of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation,
and when they taught, they taught with power and
authority of God
4 And they had been teaching the word of God for
the space of fourteen years among the Lamanites,
having had much success in bringing many to the
knowledge of the truth; yea, by the power of their
words many were brought before the altar of God, to
call on his name and confess their sins before him
5 Now these are the circumstances which attended
them in their journeyings, for they had many
afflictions; they did suffer much, both in body and in
mind, such as hunger, thirst and fatigue, and also
much labor in the spirit
6 Now these were their journeyings: Having taken
leave of their father, Mosiah, in the first year of
the judges; having refused the kingdom which
their father was desirous to confer upon them, and
also this was the minds of the people
7 Nevertheless they departed out of the land of
Zarahemla, and took their swords, and their spears,
and their bows, and their arrows, and their
slings; and this they did that they might provide food
for themselves while in the wilderness
8 And thus they departed into the wilderness with
their numbers which they had selected, to go up to
the land of Nephi, to preach the word of God unto
the Lamanites
9 And it came to pass that they journeyed many
days in the wilderness, and they fasted much and
prayed much that the Lord would grant unto them a
portion of his Spirit to go with them, and abide with
them, that they might be an instrument in the
hands of God to bring, if it were possible, their
brethren, the Lamanites, to the knowledge of the
truth, to the knowledge of the baseness of the
traditions of their fathers, which were not correct
10 And it came to pass that the Lord did visit
them with his Spirit, and said unto them: Be
comforted. And they were comforted
11 And the Lord said unto them also: Go forth
among the Lamanites, thy brethren, and establish my
word; yet ye shall be patient in long-suffering and
afflictions, that ye may show forth good examples
unto them in me, and I will make an instrument of
thee in my hands unto the salvation of many souls
12 And it came to pass that the hearts of the sons
of Mosiah, and also those who were with them,
took courage to go forth unto the Lamanites to
declare unto them the word of God
13 And it came to pass when they had arrived in
the borders of the land of the Lamanites, that they
separated themselves and departed one from
another, trusting in the Lord that they should meet again
at the close of their harvest; for they supposed
that great was the work which they had undertaken
14 And assuredly it was great, for they had
undertaken to preach the word of God to a wild and a
hardened and a ferocious people; a people who
delighted in murdering the Nephites, and robbing and
plundering them; and their hearts were set upon
riches, or upon gold and silver, and precious stones;
yet they sought to obtain these things by murdering
and plundering, that they might not labor for them
with their own hands
15 Thus they were a very indolent people, many of
whom did worship idols, and the curse of God had
fallen upon them because of the traditions of their
fathers; notwithstanding the promises of the Lord
were extended unto them on the conditions of
repentance
16 Therefore, this was the cause for which the
sons of Mosiah had undertaken the work, that perhaps
they might bring them unto repentance; that
perhaps they might bring them to know of the plan of
redemption
17 Therefore they separated themselves one from
another, and went forth among them, every man alone,
according to the word and power of God which was
given unto him
18 Now Ammon being the chief among them, or rather
he did administer unto them, and he departed from
them, after having blessed them according to
their several stations, having imparted the word of
God unto them, or administered unto them before his
departure; and thus they took their several
journeys throughout the land
19 And Ammon went to the land of Ishmael, the land
being called after the sons of Ishmael, who also
became Lamanites
20 And as Ammon entered the land of Ishmael, the
Lamanites took him and bound him, as was their
custom to bind all the Nephites who fell into their
hands, and carry them before the king; and thus it
was left to the pleasure of the king to slay them,
or to retain them in captivity, or to cast them
into prison, or to cast them out of his land,
according to his will and pleasure
21 And thus Ammon was carried before the king who
was over the land of Ishmael; and his name was
Lamoni; and he was a descendant of Ishmael
22 And the king inquired of Ammon if it were his
desire to dwell in the land among the Lamanites, or
among his people
23 And Ammon said unto him: Yea, I desire to dwell
among this people for a time; yea, and perhaps
until the day I die
24 And it came to pass that king Lamoni was much
pleased with Ammon, and caused that his bands
should be loosed; and he would that Ammon should take
one of his daughters to wife
25 But Ammon said unto him: Nay, but I will be thy
servant. Therefore Ammon became a servant to king
Lamoni. And it came to pass that he was set among
other servants to watch the flocks of Lamoni,
according to the custom of the Lamanites
26 And after he had been in the service of the
king three days, as he was with the Lamanitish
servants going forth with their flocks to the place of
water, which was called the water of Sebus, and all
the Lamanites drive their flocks hither, that
they may have water
27 Therefore, as Ammon and the servants of the
king were driving forth their flocks to this place of
water, behold, a certain number of the Lamanites,
who had been with their flocks to water, stood
and scattered the flocks of Ammon and the servants
of the king, and they scattered them insomuch that
they fled many ways
28 Now the servants of the king began to murmur,
saying: Now the king will slay us, as he has our
brethren because their flocks were scattered by the
wickedness of these men. And they began to weep
exceedingly, saying: Behold, our flocks are
scattered already
29 Now they wept because of the fear of being
slain. Now when Ammon saw this his heart was swollen
within him with joy; for, said he, I will show
forth my power unto these my fellow-servants, or the
power which is in me, in restoring these flocks
unto the king, that I may win the hearts of these my
fellow-servants, that I may lead them to believe
in my words
30 And now, these were the thoughts of Ammon, when
he saw the afflictions of those whom he termed to
be his brethren
31 And it came to pass that he flattered them by
his words, saying: My brethren, be of good cheer
and let us go in search of the flocks, and we will
gather them together and bring them back unto the
place of water; and thus we will preserve the
flocks unto the king and he will not slay us
32 And it came to pass that they went in search of
the flocks, and they did follow Ammon, and they
rushed forth with much swiftness and did head the
flocks of the king, and did gather them together
again to the place of water
33 And those men again stood to scatter their
flocks; but Ammon said unto his brethren: Encircle the
flocks round about that they flee not; and I go
and contend with these men who do scatter our
flocks
34 Therefore, they did as Ammon commanded them,
and he went forth and stood to contend with those
who stood by the waters of Sebus; and they were in
number not a few
35 Therefore they did not fear Ammon, for they
supposed that one of their men could slay him
according to their pleasure, for they knew not that the
Lord had promised Mosiah that he would deliver his
sons out of their hands; neither did they know
anything concerning the Lord; therefore they
delighted in the destruction of their brethren; and for
this cause they stood to scatter the flocks of the
king
36 But Ammon stood forth and began to cast stones
at them with his sling; yea, with mighty power he
did sling stones amongst them; and thus he slew a
certain number of them insomuch that they began to
be astonished at his power; nevertheless they
were angry because of the slain of their brethren,
and they were determined that he should fall;
therefore, seeing that they could not hit him with their
stones, they came forth with clubs to slay him
37 But behold, every man that lifted his club to
smite Ammon, he smote off their arms with his
sword; for he did withstand their blows by smiting
their arms with the edge of his sword, insomuch that
they began to be astonished, and began to flee
before him; yea, and they were not few in number; and
he caused them to flee by the strength of his arm
38 Now six of them had fallen by the sling, but he
slew none save it were their leader with his
sword; and he smote off as many of their arms as were
lifted against him, and they were not a few
39 And when he had driven them afar off, he
returned and they watered their flocks and returned them
to the pasture of the king, and then went in unto
the king, bearing the arms which had been smitten
off by the sword of Ammon, of those who sought to
slay him; and they were carried in unto the king
for a testimony of the things which they had done.