Chapter 15 Alma and Amulek go to Sidom and
establish a church—Alma heals Zeezrom, who joins the
Church—Many are baptized, and the Church prospers—Alma
and Amulek go to Zarahemla. About 81 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that Alma and Amulek were
commanded to depart out of that city; and they
departed, and came out even into the land of Sidom; and
behold, there they found all the people who had
departed out of the land of Ammonihah, who had been
cast out and stoned, because they believed in the
words of Alma
2 And they related unto them all that had happened
unto their wives and children, and also
concerning themselves, and of their power of deliverance
3 And also Zeezrom lay sick at Sidom, with a
burning fever, which was caused by the great
tribulations of his mind on account of his wickedness, for
he supposed that Alma and Amulek were no more; and
he supposed that they had been slain because of
his iniquity. And this great sin, and his many other
sins, did harrow up his mind until it did become
exceedingly sore, having no deliverance; therefore
he began to be scorched with a burning heat
4 Now, when he heard that Alma and Amulek were in
the land of Sidom, his heart began to take
courage; and he sent a message immediately unto them,
desiring them to come unto him
5 And it came to pass that they went immediately,
obeying the message which he had sent unto them;
and they went in unto the house unto Zeezrom; and
they found him upon his bed, sick, being very low
with a burning fever; and his mind also was
exceedingly sore because of his iniquities; and when he
saw them he stretched forth his hand, and besought
them that they would heal him
6 And it came to pass that Alma said unto him,
taking him by the hand: Believest thou in the power
of Christ unto salvation
7 And he answered and said: Yea, I believe all the
words that thou hast taught
8 And Alma said: If thou believest in the
redemption of Christ thou canst be healed
9 And he said: Yea, I believe according to thy
words
10 And then Alma cried unto the Lord, saying: O
Lord our God, have mercy on this man, and heal him
according to his faith which is in Christ
11 And when Alma had said these words, Zeezrom
leaped upon his feet, and began to walk; and this was
done to the great astonishment of all the people;
and the knowledge of this went forth throughout
all the land of Sidom
12 And Alma baptized Zeezrom unto the Lord; and he
began from that time forth to preach unto the
people
13 And Alma established a church in the land of
Sidom, and consecrated priests and teachers in the
land, to baptize unto the Lord whosoever were
desirous to be baptized
14 And it came to pass that they were many; for
they did flock in from all the region round about
Sidom, and were baptized
15 But as to the people that were in the land of
Ammonihah, they yet remained a hard-hearted and a
stiffnecked people; and they repented not of their
sins, ascribing all the power of Alma and Amulek
to the devil; for they were of the profession of
Nehor, and did not believe in the repentance of
their sins
16 And it came to pass that Alma and Amulek,
Amulek having forsaken all his gold, and silver, and
his precious things, which were in the land of
Ammonihah, for the word of God, he being rejected by
those who were once his friends and also by his
father and his kindred
17 Therefore, after Alma having established the
church at Sidom, seeing a great check, yea, seeing
that the people were checked as to the pride of
their hearts, and began to humble themselves before
God, and began to assemble themselves together at
their sanctuaries to worship God before the altar,
watching and praying continually, that they might
be delivered from Satan, and from death, and from
destruction
18 Now as I said, Alma having seen all these
things, therefore he took Amulek and came over to the
land of Zarahemla, and took him to his own house,
and did administer unto him in his tribulations,
and strengthened him in the Lord
19 And thus ended the tenth year of the reign of
the judges over the people of Nephi.