The Book of Alma the Son of AlmaThe account of
Alma, who was the son of Alma, the first and
chief judge over the people of Nephi, and also the
high priest over the Church. An account of the
reign of the judges, and the wars and contentions
among the people. And also an account of a war
between the Nephites and the Lamanites, according
to the record of Alma, the first and chief
judge.Chapter 1 Nehor teaches false doctrines,
establishes a church, introduces priestcraft, and
slays Gideon—Nehor is executed for his
crimes—Priestcrafts and persecutions spread among the
people—The priests support themselves, the people care
for the poor, and the Church prospers. About 91–88 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that in the first year
of the reign of the judges over the people of
Nephi, from this time forward, king Mosiah
having gone the way of all the earth, having
warred a good warfare, walking uprightly before
God, leaving none to reign in his stead;
nevertheless he had established laws, and they were
acknowledged by the people; therefore they were
obliged to abide by the laws which he had made.
2 And it came to pass that in the
first year of the reign of Alma in the
judgment-seat, there was a man brought
before him to be judged, a man who was
large, and was noted for his much strength.
3 And he had gone about among the
people, preaching to them that
which he termed to be the word of
God, bearing down against the church;
declaring unto the people that
every priest and teacher ought to
become popular; and they ought not
to labor with their hands, but that
they ought to be supported by the people.
4 And he also testified unto the
people that all mankind should be
saved at the last day, and that
they need not fear nor tremble,
but that they might lift up their
heads and rejoice; for the Lord
had created all men, and had also
redeemed all men; and, in the
end, all men should have eternal life.
5 And it came to pass that he
did teach these things so much
that many did believe on his words,
even so many that they began to
support him and give him money.
6 And he began to be lifted
up in the pride of his
heart, and to wear very costly
apparel, yea, and even
began to establish a church
after the manner of his preaching.
7 And it came to pass as
he was going, to preach to
those who believed on his
word, he met a man who
belonged to the church of
God, yea, even one of their
teachers; and he began to
contend with him sharply,
that he might lead away the
people of the church; but
the man withstood him,
admonishing him with the words of God.
8 Now the name of the
man was Gideon; and it
was he who was an
instrument in the hands of
God in delivering the
people of Limhi out of bondage.
9 Now, because Gideon
withstood him with
the words of God he
was wroth with Gideon,
and drew his sword
and began to smite him.
Now Gideon being
stricken with many
years, therefore he was
not able to withstand
his blows, therefore
he was slain by the sword.
10 And the man who
slew him was taken
by the people of
the church, and was
brought before Alma,
to be judged
according to the crimes
which he had committed.
11 And it came to
pass that he
stood before Alma
and pled for
himself with much boldness.
12 But Alma said
unto him:
Behold, this is the
first time that
priestcraft has
been introduced
among this
people. And behold,
thou art not only
guilty of
priestcraft, but hast
endeavored to
enforce it by the
sword; and were
priestcraft to
be enforced among
this people it
would prove
their entire destruction.
13 And thou
hast shed the
blood of a
righteous man, yea, a
man who has done
much good
among this people;
and were we to
spare thee his
blood would
come upon us for vengeance.
14 Therefore
thou art
condemned to die,
according to the
law which has
been given us
by Mosiah,
our last king;
and it has been
acknowledged
by this
people; therefore
this people must
abide by the law.
15 And it
came to pass
that they took
him; and his
name was
Nehor; and they
carried him
upon the top of
the hill
Manti, and there
he was
caused, or rather
did
acknowledge, between
the heavens and
the earth,
that what he
had taught to
the people
was contrary to
the word of
God; and
there he suffered an ignominious death.
Nevertheless, this
did not put an
end to the
spreading of
priestcraft
through the
land; for
there were
many who loved
the vain
things of the
world, and
they went
forth preaching
false
doctrines; and
this they did
for the sake
of riches and honor.
Nevertheless, they
durst not
lie, if it
were known,
for fear of
the law,
for liars
were
punished; therefore
they
pretended to
preach
according to their
belief;
and now the
law could
have no power
on any man for his belief.
18 And
they durst
not steal,
for fear of
the law,
for such
were
punished;
neither durst
they rob,
nor murder,
for he
that murdered
was
punished unto death.
19 But it
came to
pass that
whosoever
did not
belong to the
church of
God began
to
persecute those
that did
belong to
the church
of God, and
had taken
upon them
the name
of Christ.
20 Yea,
they did
persecute
them, and
afflict
them with
all
manner of
words, and
this
because of
their
humility;
because they
were not
proud in
their own
eyes, and
because
they did
impart
the word of
God, one
with
another,
without money and without price.
21 Now
there was
a
strict law
among the
people
of the
church,
that there
should
not any
man,
belonging
to the
church,
arise and
persecute those
that did
not
belong to
the
church, and
that
there should
be no
persecution among themselves.
Nevertheless,
there were
many
among
them who
began to
be
proud, and
began
to
contend
warmly
with their
adversaries,
even
unto
blows; yea,
they
would
smite one
another with their fists.
23 Now
this
was in
the
second
year
of the
reign
of
Alma, and
it
was a
cause of
much
affliction
to the
church; yea,
it
was the
cause
of
much trial with the church.
For the
hearts of
many
were
hardened,
and
their
names
were
blotted
out,
that
they
were
remembered
no
more
among
the
people
of
God.
And
also
many
withdrew themselves from among them.
Now
this
was
a
great
trial to
those
that
did
stand
fast
in
the
faith;
nevertheless,
they
were
steadfast
and
immovable
in
keeping
the
commandments
of
God,
and
they
bore
with
patience the persecution which was heaped upon them.
And
when
the
priests
left
their
labor
to
impart
the
word
of
God
unto
the
people,
people
also
left
their
labors to
hear
the
word
of
God.
And
when
the
priest
had
imparted
unto
them
the
word
of
God
they
all
returned
again
diligently
unto
their
labors;
and
the
priest,
not
esteeming
himself
above
his
hearers,
for
the
preacher
was no
better
than
the
hearer,
neither
was
the
teacher
any
better
than
the
learner;
and
thus
they
were
all
equal,
and
they
did
all
labor,
every
man
according
to
his
strength.
And
they
did
impart
of
their
substance,
every
man
according
to
that
which
he
had,
to
the
poor,
and
the
needy,
and
the
sick,
and
the
afflicted;
and
they
did
not wear costly apparel, yet they were neat and comely.
And
thus
they
did
establish
the
affairs
of
the
church;
and
thus
they
began
to
have
continual
peace again, notwithstanding all their persecutions.
And
now,
because
of
the
steadiness
of
the
church
they
began
to
be
exceedingly
rich,
having
abundance
of
all
things
whatsoever
they
stood
in
need—an
abundance
of
flocks
and
herds,
fatlings
of
every
kind,
and
also
abundance
of
grain,
and
of
gold,
and
of
silver,
and
of
precious
things,
and
abundance
of
silk
and
fine-twined
linen,
and
all
manner
of
good
homely
cloth.
30 And thus, in their prosperous circumstances, they did not send away any who were naked, or that were hungry, or that were athirst, or that were sick, or that had not been nourished; and they did not set their hearts upon riches; therefore they were liberal to all, both old and young, both bond and free, both male and female, whether out of the church or in the church, having no respect to persons as to those who stood in
And
thus,
in
their
prosperous
circumstances,
they
did
not
send
away
any
who
were
naked,
or
that
were
hungry,
or
that
were
athirst,
or
that
were
sick,
or
that
had
not
been
nourished;
and
they
did
not
set
their
hearts upon riches; therefore they were liberal to all, both old and young, both bond and free, both male and female, whether out of the church or in the church, having no respect to persons as to those who stood in need.
31 And thus they did prosper and become far more wealthy than those who did not belong to their
And
thus
they
did
prosper
and
become
far
more
wealthy
than
those
who
did
not
belong
to
their
church.
32 For those who did not belong to their church did indulge themselves in sorceries, and in idolatry or idleness, and in babblings, and in envyings and strife; wearing costly apparel; being lifted up in the pride of their own eyes; persecuting, lying, thieving, robbing, committing whoredoms, and murdering, and all manner of wickedness; nevertheless, the law was put in force upon all those who did transgress it, inasmuch as it was
For
those
who
did
not
belong
to
their
church
did
indulge
themselves
in
sorceries,
and
in
idolatry
or
idleness,
and
in
babblings,
and
in
envyings
and
strife;
wearing
costly
apparel;
being
lifted
up
in
the
pride
of
their
own
eyes;
persecuting,
lying,
thieving,
robbing,
committing
whoredoms,
and
murdering,
all
manner
of
wickedness;
nevertheless,
force
upon
all
those
who
did
transgress
it,
inasmuch
as
it
was
possible.
33 And it came to pass that by thus exercising the law upon them, every man suffering according to that which he had done, they became more still, and durst not commit any wickedness if it were known; therefore, there was much peace among the people of Nephi until the fifth year of the reign of the judges.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
by
thus
exercising
the
law
upon
them,
every
man
suffering
according
to
that
which
he
had
done,
they
became
more
still,
and
durst
not
commit
any
wickedness
if
it
were
known;
therefore,
there
was
much
peace
among
the
people
of
Nephi
until
the
fifth
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges.