Chapter 13 Men are called as high priests because
of their exceeding faith and good works—They are
to teach the commandments—Through righteousness
they are sanctified and enter into the rest of the
Lord—Melchizedek was one of these—Angels are
declaring glad tidings throughout the land—They will
declare the actual coming of Christ. About 82 B.C.
1 And again, my brethren, I would cite your minds
forward to the time when the Lord God gave these
commandments unto his children; and I would that ye
should remember that the Lord God ordained
priests, after his holy order, which was after the order
of his Son, to teach these things unto the
people
2 And those priests were ordained after the order
of his Son, in a manner that thereby the people
might know in what manner to look forward to his Son
for redemption
3 And this is the manner after which they were
ordained—being called and prepared from the
foundation of the world according to the foreknowledge of
God, on account of their exceeding faith and good
works; in the first place being left to choose good
or evil; therefore they having chosen good, and
exercising exceedingly great faith, are called with
a holy calling, yea, with that holy calling which
was prepared with, and according to, a
preparatory redemption for such
4 And thus they have been called to this holy
calling on account of their faith, while others would
reject the Spirit of God on account of the
hardness of their hearts and blindness of their minds,
while, if it had not been for this they might have
had as great privilege as their brethren
5 Or in fine, in the first place they were on the
same standing with their brethren; thus this holy
calling being prepared from the foundation of the
world for such as would not harden their hearts,
being in and through the atonement of the Only
Begotten Son, who was prepared
6 And thus being called by this holy calling, and
ordained unto the high priesthood of the holy
order of God, to teach his commandments unto the
children of men, that they also might enter into his
rest
7 This high priesthood being after the order of
his Son, which order was from the foundation of the
world; or in other words, being without beginning
of days or end of years, being prepared from
eternity to all eternity, according to his
foreknowledge of all things
8 Now they were ordained after this manner—being
called with a holy calling, and ordained with a
holy ordinance, and taking upon them the high
priesthood of the holy order, which calling, and
ordinance, and high priesthood, is without beginning or
end
9 Thus they become high priests forever, after the
order of the Son, the Only Begotten of the
Father, who is without beginning of days or end of
years, who is full of grace, equity, and truth. And
thus it is. Amen
10 Now, as I said concerning the holy order, or
this high priesthood, there were many who were
ordained and became high priests of God; and it was on
account of their exceeding faith and repentance,
and their righteousness before God, they choosing
to repent and work righteousness rather than to
perish
11 Therefore they were called after this holy
order, and were sanctified, and their garments were
washed white through the blood of the Lamb
12 Now they, after being sanctified by the Holy
Ghost, having their garments made white, being pure
and spotless before God, could not look upon sin
save it were with abhorrence; and there were many,
exceedingly great many, who were made pure and
entered into the rest of the Lord their God
13 And now, my brethren, I would that ye should
humble yourselves before God, and bring forth fruit
meet for repentance, that ye may also enter into
that rest
14 Yea, humble yourselves even as the people in
the days of Melchizedek, who was also a high priest
after this same order which I have spoken, who
also took upon him the high priesthood forever
15 And it was this same Melchizedek to whom
Abraham paid tithes; yea, even our father Abraham paid
tithes of one-tenth part of all he possessed
16 Now these ordinances were given after this
manner, that thereby the people might look forward on
the Son of God, it being a type of his order, or
it being his order, and this that they might look
forward to him for a remission of their sins, that
they might enter into the rest of the Lord
17 Now this Melchizedek was a king over the land
of Salem; and his people had waxed strong in
iniquity and abomination; yea, they had all gone astray;
they were full of all manner of wickedness
18 But Melchizedek having exercised mighty faith,
and received the office of the high priesthood
according to the holy order of God, did preach
repentance unto his people. And behold, they did repent;
and Melchizedek did establish peace in the land
in his days; therefore he was called the prince of
peace, for he was the king of Salem; and he did
reign under his father
19 Now, there were many before him, and also there
were many afterwards, but none were greater;
therefore, of him they have more particularly made
mention
20 Now I need not rehearse the matter; what I have
said may suffice. Behold, the scriptures are
before you; if ye will wrest them it shall be to your
own destruction
21 And now it came to pass that when Alma had said
these words unto them, he stretched forth his
hand unto them and cried with a mighty voice, saying:
Now is the time to repent, for the day of
salvation draweth nigh
22 Yea, and the voice of the Lord, by the mouth of
angels, doth declare it unto all nations; yea,
doth declare it, that they may have glad tidings of
great joy; yea, and he doth sound these glad
tidings among all his people, yea, even to them that
are scattered abroad upon the face of the earth;
wherefore they have come unto us
23 And they are made known unto us in plain terms,
that we may understand, that we cannot err; and
this because of our being wanderers in a strange
land; therefore, we are thus highly favored, for we
have these glad tidings declared unto us in all
parts of our vineyard
24 For behold, angels are declaring it unto many
at this time in our land; and this is for the
purpose of preparing the hearts of the children of men
to receive his word at the time of his coming in
his glory
25 And now we only wait to hear the joyful news
declared unto us by the mouth of angels, of his
coming; for the time cometh, we know not how soon.
Would to God that it might be in my day; but let it
be sooner or later, in it I will rejoice
26 And it shall be made known unto just and holy
men, by the mouth of angels, at the time of his
coming, that the words of our fathers may be
fulfilled, according to that which they have spoken
concerning him, which was according to the spirit of
prophecy which was in them
27 And now, my brethren, I wish from the inmost
part of my heart, yea, with great anxiety even unto
pain, that ye would hearken unto my words, and
cast off your sins, and not procrastinate the day of
your repentance
28 But that ye would humble yourselves before the
Lord, and call on his holy name, and watch and
pray continually, that ye may not be tempted above
that which ye can bear, and thus be led by the Holy
Spirit, becoming humble, meek, submissive,
patient, full of love and all long-suffering
29 Having faith on the Lord; having a hope that ye
shall receive eternal life; having the love of
God always in your hearts, that ye may be lifted up
at the last day and enter into his rest
30 And may the Lord grant unto you repentance,
that ye may not bring down his wrath upon you, that
ye may not be bound down by the chains of hell,
that ye may not suffer the second death
31 And Alma spake many more words unto the people,
which are not written in this book.