Chapter 18 King Lamoni supposes that Ammon is the
Great Spirit—Ammon teaches the king about the
Creation, God’s dealings with men, and the redemption
that comes through Christ—Lamoni believes and
falls to the earth as if dead. About 90 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that king Lamoni caused that
his servants should stand forth and testify to
all the things which they had seen concerning the
matter
2 And when they had all testified to the things
which they had seen, and he had learned of the
faithfulness of Ammon in preserving his flocks, and
also of his great power in contending against those
who sought to slay him, he was astonished
exceedingly, and said: Surely, this is more than a man.
Behold, is not this the Great Spirit who doth send
such great punishments upon this people, because of
their murders
3 And they answered the king, and said: Whether he
be the Great Spirit or a man, we know not; but
this much we do know, that he cannot be slain by the
enemies of the king; neither can they scatter the
king’s flocks when he is with us, because of his
expertness and great strength; therefore, we know
that he is a friend to the king. And now, O king,
we do not believe that a man has such great power,
for we know he cannot be slain
4 And now, when the king heard these words, he
said unto them: Now I know that it is the Great
Spirit; and he has come down at this time to preserve
your lives, that I might not slay you as I did your
brethren. Now this is the Great Spirit of whom
our fathers have spoken
5 Now this was the tradition of Lamoni, which he
had received from his father, that there was a
Great Spirit. Notwithstanding they believed in a Great
Spirit, they supposed that whatsoever they did
was right; nevertheless, Lamoni began to fear
exceedingly, with fear lest he had done wrong in slaying
his servants
6 For he had slain many of them because their
brethren had scattered their flocks at the place of
water; and thus, because they had had their flocks
scattered they were slain
7 Now it was the practice of these Lamanites to
stand by the waters of Sebus to scatter the flocks
of the people, that thereby they might drive away
many that were scattered unto their own land, it
being a practice of plunder among them
8 And it came to pass that king Lamoni inquired of
his servants, saying: Where is this man that has
such great power
9 And they said unto him: Behold, he is feeding
thy horses. Now the king had commanded his servants,
previous to the time of the watering of their
flocks, that they should prepare his horses and
chariots, and conduct him forth to the land of Nephi;
for there had been a great feast appointed at the
land of Nephi, by the father of Lamoni, who was
king over all the land
10 Now when king Lamoni heard that Ammon was
preparing his horses and his chariots he was more
astonished, because of the faithfulness of Ammon,
saying: Surely there has not been any servant among all
my servants that has been so faithful as this
man; for even he doth remember all my commandments to
execute them
11 Now I surely know that this is the Great
Spirit, and I would desire him that he come in unto me,
but I durst not
12 And it came to pass that when Ammon had made
ready the horses and the chariots for the king and
his servants, he went in unto the king, and he saw
that the countenance of the king was changed;
therefore he was about to return out of his presence
13 And one of the king’s servants said unto him,
Rabbanah, which is, being interpreted, powerful or
great king, considering their kings to be
powerful; and thus he said unto him: Rabbanah, the king
desireth thee to stay
14 Therefore Ammon turned himself unto the king,
and said unto him: What wilt thou that I should do
for thee, O king? And the king answered him not
for the space of an hour, according to their time,
for he knew not what he should say unto him
15 And it came to pass that Ammon said unto him
again: What desirest thou of me? But the king
answered him not
16 And it came to pass that Ammon, being filled
with the Spirit of God, therefore he perceived the
thoughts of the king. And he said unto him: Is it
because thou hast heard that I defended thy
servants and thy flocks, and slew seven of their brethren
with the sling and with the sword, and smote off
the arms of others, in order to defend thy flocks
and thy servants; behold, is it this that causeth
thy marvelings
17 I say unto you, what is it, that thy marvelings
are so great? Behold, I am a man, and am thy
servant; therefore, whatsoever thou desirest which is
right, that will I do
18 Now when the king had heard these words, he
marveled again, for he beheld that Ammon could
discern his thoughts; but notwithstanding this, king
Lamoni did open his mouth, and said unto him: Who art
thou? Art thou that Great Spirit, who knows all
things
19 Ammon answered and said unto him: I am not
20 And the king said: How knowest thou the
thoughts of my heart? Thou mayest speak boldly, and tell
me concerning these things; and also tell me by
what power ye slew and smote off the arms of my
brethren that scattered my flocks
21 And now, if thou wilt tell me concerning these
things, whatsoever thou desirest I will give unto
thee; and if it were needed, I would guard thee
with my armies; but I know that thou art more
powerful than all they; nevertheless, whatsoever thou
desirest of me I will grant it unto thee
22 Now Ammon being wise, yet harmless, he said
unto Lamoni: Wilt thou hearken unto my words, if I
tell thee by what power I do these things? And this
is the thing that I desire of thee
23 And the king answered him, and said: Yea, I
will believe all thy words. And thus he was caught
with guile
24 And Ammon began to speak unto him with
boldness, and said unto him: Believest thou that there is
a God
25 And he answered, and said unto him: I do not
know what that meaneth
26 And then Ammon said: Believest thou that there
is a Great Spirit
27 And he said, Yea
28 And Ammon said: This is God. And Ammon said
unto him again: Believest thou that this Great
Spirit, who is God, created all things which are in
heaven and in the earth
29 And he said: Yea, I believe that he created all
things which are in the earth; but I do not know
the heavens
32 And Ammon said: Yea, and he looketh down upon
all the children of men; and he knows all the
thoughts and intents of the heart; for by his hand were
they all created from the beginning
33 And king Lamoni said: I believe all these
things which thou hast spoken. Art thou sent from God
34 Ammon said unto him: I am a man; and man in the
beginning was created after the image of God, and
I am called by his Holy Spirit to teach these
things unto this people, that they may be brought to
a knowledge of that which is just and true
35 And a portion of that Spirit dwelleth in me,
which giveth me knowledge, and also power according
to my faith and desires which are in God
36 Now when Ammon had said these words, he began
at the creation of the world, and also the creation
of Adam, and told him all the things concerning
the fall of man, and rehearsed and laid before him
the records and the holy scriptures of the people,
which had been spoken by the prophets, even down
to the time that their father, Lehi, left
Jerusalem
37 And he also rehearsed unto them (for it was
unto the king and to his servants) all the
journeyings of their fathers in the wilderness, and all
their sufferings with hunger and thirst, and their
travail, and so forth
38 And he also rehearsed unto them concerning the
rebellions of Laman and Lemuel, and the sons of
Ishmael, yea, all their rebellions did he relate
unto them; and he expounded unto them all the records
and scriptures from the time that Lehi left
Jerusalem down to the present time
39 But this is not all; for he expounded unto them
the plan of redemption, which was prepared from
the foundation of the world; and he also made known
unto them concerning the coming of Christ, and
all the works of the Lord did he make known unto
them
40 And it came to pass that after he had said all
these things, and expounded them to the king, that
the king believed all his words
41 And he began to cry unto the Lord, saying: O
Lord, have mercy; according to thy abundant mercy
which thou hast had upon the people of Nephi, have
upon me, and my people
42 And now, when he had said this, he fell unto
the earth, as if he were dead
43 And it came to pass that his servants took him
and carried him in unto his wife, and laid him
upon a bed; and he lay as if he were dead for the
space of two days and two nights; and his wife, and
his sons, and his daughters mourned over him, after
the manner of the Lamanites, greatly lamenting
his loss.