Chapter 16 The Lamanites destroy the people of
Ammonihah—Zoram leads the Nephites to victory over
the Lamanites—Alma and Amulek and many others preach
the word—They teach that after His Resurrection
Christ will appear to the Nephites. About
81–77 B.C.
1 And it came to pass in the eleventh year of the
reign of the judges over the people of Nephi, on
the fifth day of the second month, there having
been much peace in the land of Zarahemla, there
having been no wars nor contentions for a certain
number of years, even until the fifth day of the second
month in the eleventh year, there was a cry of
war heard throughout the land
2 For behold, the armies of the Lamanites had come
in upon the wilderness side, into the borders of
the land, even into the city of Ammonihah, and
began to slay the people and destroy the city
3 And now it came to pass, before the Nephites
could raise a sufficient army to drive them out of
the land, they had destroyed the people who were in
the city of Ammonihah, and also some around the
borders of Noah, and taken others captive into the
wilderness
4 Now it came to pass that the Nephites were
desirous to obtain those who had been carried away
captive into the wilderness
5 Therefore, he that had been appointed chief
captain over the armies of the Nephites, (and his name
was Zoram, and he had two sons, Lehi and Aha)—now
Zoram and his two sons, knowing that Alma was
high priest over the church, and having heard that he
had the spirit of prophecy, therefore they went
unto him and desired of him to know whither the
Lord would that they should go into the wilderness in
search of their brethren, who had been taken
captive by the Lamanites
6 And it came to pass that Alma inquired of the
Lord concerning the matter. And Alma returned and
said unto them: Behold, the Lamanites will cross the
river Sidon in the south wilderness, away up
beyond the borders of the land of Manti. And behold
there shall ye meet them, on the east of the river
Sidon, and there the Lord will deliver unto thee
thy brethren who have been taken captive by the
Lamanites
7 And it came to pass that Zoram and his sons
crossed over the river Sidon, with their armies, and
marched away beyond the borders of Manti into the
south wilderness, which was on the east side of the
river Sidon
8 And they came upon the armies of the Lamanites,
and the Lamanites were scattered and driven into
the wilderness; and they took their brethren who
had been taken captive by the Lamanites, and there
was not one soul of them had been lost that were
taken captive. And they were brought by their
brethren to possess their own lands
9 And thus ended the eleventh year of the judges,
the Lamanites having been driven out of the land,
and the people of Ammonihah were destroyed; yea,
every living soul of the Ammonihahites was
destroyed, and also their great city, which they said God
could not destroy, because of its greatness
10 But behold, in one day it was left desolate;
and the carcasses were mangled by dogs and wild
beasts of the wilderness
11 Nevertheless, after many days their dead bodies
were heaped up upon the face of the earth, and
they were covered with a shallow covering. And now
so great was the scent thereof that the people did
not go in to possess the land of Ammonihah for
many years. And it was called Desolation of Nehors;
for they were of the profession of Nehor, who were
slain; and their lands remained desolate
12 And the Lamanites did not come again to war
against the Nephites until the fourteenth year of the
reign of the judges over the people of Nephi. And
thus for three years did the people of Nephi have
continual peace in all the land
13 And Alma and Amulek went forth preaching
repentance to the people in their temples, and in their
sanctuaries, and also in their synagogues, which
were built after the manner of the Jews
14 And as many as would hear their words, unto
them they did impart the word of God, without any
respect of persons, continually
15 And thus did Alma and Amulek go forth, and also
many more who had been chosen for the work, to
preach the word throughout all the land. And the
establishment of the church became general throughout
the land, in all the region round about, among
all the people of the Nephites
16 And there was no inequality among them; the
Lord did pour out his Spirit on all the face of the
land to prepare the minds of the children of men,
or to prepare their hearts to receive the word
which should be taught among them at the time of his
coming
17 That they might not be hardened against the
word, that they might not be unbelieving, and go on
to destruction, but that they might receive the
word with joy, and as a branch be grafted into the
true vine, that they might enter into the rest of
the Lord their God
18 Now those priests who did go forth among the
people did preach against all lyings, and
deceivings, and envyings, and strifes, and malice, and
revilings, and stealing, robbing, plundering,
murdering, committing adultery, and all manner of
lasciviousness, crying that these things ought not so to
be
19 Holding forth things which must shortly come;
yea, holding forth the coming of the Son of God,
his sufferings and death, and also the resurrection
of the dead
20 And many of the people did inquire concerning
the place where the Son of God should come; and
they were taught that he would appear unto them after
his resurrection; and this the people did hear
with great joy and gladness
21 And now after the church had been established
throughout all the land—having got the victory over
the devil, and the word of God being preached in
its purity in all the land, and the Lord pouring
out his blessings upon the people—thus ended the
fourteenth year of the reign of the judges over the
people of Nephi.