Chapter 19 Lamoni receives the light of
everlasting life and sees the Redeemer—His household falls
into a trance, and many see angels—Ammon is
preserved miraculously—He baptizes many and establishes a
church among them. About 90 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that after two days and two
nights they were about to take his body and lay it
in a sepulchre, which they had made for the
purpose of burying their dead
2 Now the queen having heard of the fame of Ammon,
therefore she sent and desired that he should
come in unto her
3 And it came to pass that Ammon did as he was
commanded, and went in unto the queen, and desired to
know what she would that he should do
4 And she said unto him: The servants of my
husband have made it known unto me that thou art a
prophet of a holy God, and that thou hast power to do
many mighty works in his name
5 Therefore, if this is the case, I would that ye
should go in and see my husband, for he has been
laid upon his bed for the space of two days and two
nights; and some say that he is not dead, but
others say that he is dead and that he stinketh, and
that he ought to be placed in the sepulchre; but
as for myself, to me he doth not stink
6 Now, this was what Ammon desired, for he knew
that king Lamoni was under the power of God; he knew
that the dark veil of unbelief was being cast
away from his mind, and the light which did light up
his mind, which was the light of the glory of God,
which was a marvelous light of his goodness—yea,
this light had infused such joy into his soul, the
cloud of darkness having been dispelled, and that
the light of everlasting life was lit up in his
soul, yea, he knew that this had overcome his
natural frame, and he was carried away in God
7 Therefore, what the queen desired of him was his
only desire. Therefore, he went in to see the
king according as the queen had desired him; and he
saw the king, and he knew that he was not dead
8 And he said unto the queen: He is not dead, but
he sleepeth in God, and on the morrow he shall
rise again; therefore bury him not
9 And Ammon said unto her: Believest thou this?
And she said unto him: I have had no witness save
thy word, and the word of our servants; nevertheless
I believe that it shall be according as thou hast
said
10 And Ammon said unto her: Blessed art thou
because of thy exceeding faith; I say unto thee, woman,
there has not been such great faith among all the
people of the Nephites
11 And it came to pass that she watched over the
bed of her husband, from that time even until that
time on the morrow which Ammon had appointed that
he should rise
12 And it came to pass that he arose, according to
the words of Ammon; and as he arose, he stretched
forth his hand unto the woman, and said: Blessed
be the name of God, and blessed art thou
13 For as sure as thou livest, behold, I have seen
my Redeemer; and he shall come forth, and be born
of a woman, and he shall redeem all mankind who
believe on his name. Now, when he had said these
words, his heart was swollen within him, and he sunk
again with joy; and the queen also sunk down,
being overpowered by the Spirit
14 Now Ammon seeing the Spirit of the Lord poured
out according to his prayers upon the Lamanites,
his brethren, who had been the cause of so much
mourning among the Nephites, or among all the people
of God because of their iniquities and their
traditions, he fell upon his knees, and began to pour
out his soul in prayer and thanksgiving to God for
what he had done for his brethren; and he was also
overpowered with joy; and thus they all three had
sunk to the earth
15 Now, when the servants of the king had seen
that they had fallen, they also began to cry unto
God, for the fear of the Lord had come upon them
also, for it was they who had stood before the king
and testified unto him concerning the great power of
Ammon
16 And it came to pass that they did call on the
name of the Lord, in their might, even until they
had all fallen to the earth, save it were one of
the Lamanitish women, whose name was Abish, she
having been converted unto the Lord for many years, on
account of a remarkable vision of her father
17 Thus, having been converted to the Lord, and
never having made it known, therefore, when she saw
that all the servants of Lamoni had fallen to the
earth, and also her mistress, the queen, and the
king, and Ammon lay prostrate upon the earth, she
knew that it was the power of God; and supposing
that this opportunity, by making known unto the
people what had happened among them, that by beholding
this scene it would cause them to believe in the
power of God, therefore she ran forth from house
to house, making it known unto the people
18 And they began to assemble themselves together
unto the house of the king. And there came a
multitude, and to their astonishment, they beheld the
king, and the queen, and their servants prostrate
upon the earth, and they all lay there as though
they were dead; and they also saw Ammon, and behold,
he was a Nephite
19 And now the people began to murmur among
themselves; some saying that it was a great evil that
had come upon them, or upon the king and his house,
because he had suffered that the Nephite should
remain in the land
20 But others rebuked them, saying: The king hath
brought this evil upon his house, because he slew
his servants who had had their flocks scattered at
the waters of Sebus
21 And they were also rebuked by those men who had
stood at the waters of Sebus and scattered the
flocks which belonged to the king, for they were
angry with Ammon because of the number which he had
slain of their brethren at the waters of Sebus,
while defending the flocks of the king
22 Now, one of them, whose brother had been slain
with the sword of Ammon, being exceedingly angry
with Ammon, drew his sword and went forth that he
might let it fall upon Ammon, to slay him; and as
he lifted the sword to smite him, behold, he fell
dead
23 Now we see that Ammon could not be slain, for
the Lord had said unto Mosiah, his father: I will
spare him, and it shall be unto him according to
thy faith—therefore, Mosiah trusted him unto the
Lord
24 And it came to pass that when the multitude
beheld that the man had fallen dead, who lifted the
sword to slay Ammon, fear came upon them all, and
they durst not put forth their hands to touch him
or any of those who had fallen; and they began to
marvel again among themselves what could be the
cause of this great power, or what all these things
could mean
25 And it came to pass that there were many among
them who said that Ammon was the Great Spirit, and
others said he was sent by the Great Spirit
26 But others rebuked them all, saying that he was
a monster, who had been sent from the Nephites to
torment them
27 And there were some who said that Ammon was
sent by the Great Spirit to afflict them because of
their iniquities; and that it was the Great Spirit
that had always attended the Nephites, who had
ever delivered them out of their hands; and they said
that it was this Great Spirit who had destroyed
so many of their brethren, the Lamanites
28 And thus the contention began to be exceedingly
sharp among them. And while they were thus
contending, the woman servant who had caused the
multitude to be gathered together came, and when she saw
the contention which was among the multitude she
was exceedingly sorrowful, even unto tears
29 And it came to pass that she went and took the
queen by the hand, that perhaps she might raise
her from the ground; and as soon as she touched her
hand she arose and stood upon her feet, and cried
with a loud voice, saying: O blessed Jesus, who
has saved me from an awful hell! O blessed God, have
mercy on this people
30 And when she had said this, she clasped her
hands, being filled with joy, speaking many words
which were not understood; and when she had done
this, she took the king, Lamoni, by the hand, and
behold he arose and stood upon his feet
31 And he, immediately, seeing the contention
among his people, went forth and began to rebuke them,
and to teach them the words which he had heard
from the mouth of Ammon; and as many as heard his
words believed, and were converted unto the Lord
32 But there were many among them who would not
hear his words; therefore they went their way
33 And it came to pass that when Ammon arose he
also administered unto them, and also did all the
servants of Lamoni; and they did all declare unto
the people the selfsame thing—that their hearts had
been changed; that they had no more desire to do
evil
34 And behold, many did declare unto the people
that they had seen angels and had conversed with
them; and thus they had told them things of God, and
of his righteousness
35 And it came to pass that there were many that
did believe in their words; and as many as did
believe were baptized; and they became a righteous
people, and they did establish a church among them
36 And thus the work of the Lord did commence
among the Lamanites; thus the Lord did begin to pour
out his Spirit upon them; and we see that his arm
is extended to all people who will repent and
believe on his name.