Chapter 12 Alma speaks to Zeezrom—The mysteries of
God can be given only to the faithful—Men are
judged by their thoughts, beliefs, words, and
works—The wicked will suffer a spiritual death—This
mortal life is a probationary state—The plan of
redemption brings to pass the Resurrection and, through
faith, a remission of sins—The repentant have a
claim on mercy through the Only Begotten Son. About
82 B.C.
1 Now Alma, seeing that the words of Amulek had
silenced Zeezrom, for he beheld that Amulek had
caught him in his lying and deceiving to destroy him,
and seeing that he began to tremble under a
consciousness of his guilt, he opened his mouth and
began to speak unto him, and to establish the words of
Amulek, and to explain things beyond, or to
unfold the scriptures beyond that which Amulek had
done
2 Now the words that Alma spake unto Zeezrom were
heard by the people round about; for the multitude
was great, and he spake on this wise
3 Now Zeezrom, seeing that thou hast been taken in
thy lying and craftiness, for thou hast not lied
unto men only but thou hast lied unto God; for
behold, he knows all thy thoughts, and thou seest
that thy thoughts are made known unto us by his
Spirit
4 And thou seest that we know that thy plan was a
very subtle plan, as to the subtlety of the devil,
for to lie and to deceive this people that thou
mightest set them against us, to revile us and to
cast us out
5 Now this was a plan of thine adversary, and he
hath exercised his power in thee. Now I would that
ye should remember that what I say unto thee I say
unto all
6 And behold I say unto you all that this was a
snare of the adversary, which he has laid to catch
this people, that he might bring you into
subjection unto him, that he might encircle you about with
his chains, that he might chain you down to
everlasting destruction, according to the power of his
captivity
7 Now when Alma had spoken these words, Zeezrom
began to tremble more exceedingly, for he was
convinced more and more of the power of God; and he was
also convinced that Alma and Amulek had a
knowledge of him, for he was convinced that they knew the
thoughts and intents of his heart; for power was
given unto them that they might know of these
things according to the spirit of prophecy
8 And Zeezrom began to inquire of them diligently,
that he might know more concerning the kingdom of
God. And he said unto Alma: What does this mean
which Amulek hath spoken concerning the
resurrection of the dead, that all shall rise from the dead,
both the just and the unjust, and are brought to
stand before God to be judged according to their
works
9 And now Alma began to expound these things unto
him, saying: It is given unto many to know the
mysteries of God; nevertheless they are laid under a
strict command that they shall not impart only
according to the portion of his word which he doth
grant unto the children of men, according to the
heed and diligence which they give unto him
10 And therefore, he that will harden his heart,
the same receiveth the lesser portion of the word;
and he that will not harden his heart, to him is
given the greater portion of the word, until it is
given unto him to know the mysteries of God until
he know them in full
11 And they that will harden their hearts, to them
is given the lesser portion of the word until
they know nothing concerning his mysteries; and then
they are taken captive by the devil, and led by
his will down to destruction. Now this is what is
meant by the chains of hell
12 And Amulek hath spoken plainly concerning
death, and being raised from this mortality to a state
of immortality, and being brought before the bar
of God, to be judged according to our works
13 Then if our hearts have been hardened, yea, if
we have hardened our hearts against the word,
insomuch that it has not been found in us, then will
our state be awful, for then we shall be condemned
14 For our words will condemn us, yea, all our
works will condemn us; we shall not be found
spotless; and our thoughts will also condemn us; and in
this awful state we shall not dare to look up to our
God; and we would fain be glad if we could
command the rocks and the mountains to fall upon us to
hide us from his presence
15 But this cannot be; we must come forth and
stand before him in his glory, and in his power, and
in his might, majesty, and dominion, and
acknowledge to our everlasting shame that all his judgments
are just; that he is just in all his works, and
that he is merciful unto the children of men, and
that he has all power to save every man that
believeth on his name and bringeth forth fruit meet for
repentance
16 And now behold, I say unto you then cometh a
death, even a second death, which is a spiritual
death; then is a time that whosoever dieth in his
sins, as to a temporal death, shall also die a
spiritual death; yea, he shall die as to things
pertaining unto righteousness
17 Then is the time when their torments shall be
as a lake of fire and brimstone, whose flame
ascendeth up forever and ever; and then is the time that
they shall be chained down to an everlasting
destruction, according to the power and captivity of
Satan, he having subjected them according to his
will
18 Then, I say unto you, they shall be as though
there had been no redemption made; for they cannot
be redeemed according to God’s justice; and they
cannot die, seeing there is no more corruption
19 Now it came to pass that when Alma had made an
end of speaking these words, the people began to
be more astonished
20 But there was one Antionah, who was a chief
ruler among them, came forth and said unto him: What
is this that thou hast said, that man should rise
from the dead and be changed from this mortal to
an immortal state, that the soul can never die
21 What does the scripture mean, which saith that
God placed cherubim and a flaming sword on the
east of the garden of Eden, lest our first parents
should enter and partake of the fruit of the tree of
life, and live forever? And thus we see that
there was no possible chance that they should live
forever
22 Now Alma said unto him: This is the thing which
I was about to explain. Now we see that Adam did
fall by the partaking of the forbidden fruit,
according to the word of God; and thus we see, that by
his fall, all mankind became a lost and fallen
people
23 And now behold, I say unto you that if it had
been possible for Adam to have partaken of the
fruit of the tree of life at that time, there would
have been no death, and the word would have been
void, making God a liar, for he said: If thou eat
thou shalt surely die
24 And we see that death comes upon mankind, yea,
the death which has been spoken of by Amulek,
which is the temporal death; nevertheless there was a
space granted unto man in which he might repent;
therefore this life became a probationary state; a
time to prepare to meet God; a time to prepare for
that endless state which has been spoken of by
us, which is after the resurrection of the dead
25 Now, if it had not been for the plan of
redemption, which was laid from the foundation of the
world, there could have been no resurrection of the
dead; but there was a plan of redemption laid,
which shall bring to pass the resurrection of the
dead, of which has been spoken
26 And now behold, if it were possible that our
first parents could have gone forth and partaken of
the tree of life they would have been forever
miserable, having no preparatory state; and thus the
plan of redemption would have been frustrated, and
the word of God would have been void, taking none
effect
27 But behold, it was not so; but it was appointed
unto men that they must die; and after death,
they must come to judgment, even that same judgment
of which we have spoken, which is the end
28 And after God had appointed that these things
should come unto man, behold, then he saw that it
was expedient that man should know concerning the
things whereof he had appointed unto them
29 Therefore he sent angels to converse with them,
who caused men to behold of his glory
30 And they began from that time forth to call on
his name; therefore God conversed with men, and
made known unto them the plan of redemption, which
had been prepared from the foundation of the world;
and this he made known unto them according to
their faith and repentance and their holy works
31 Wherefore, he gave commandments unto men, they
having first transgressed the first commandments
as to things which were temporal, and becoming as
gods, knowing good from evil, placing themselves in
a state to act, or being placed in a state to act
according to their wills and pleasures, whether
to do evil or to do good
32 Therefore God gave unto them commandments,
after having made known unto them the plan of
redemption, that they should not do evil, the penalty
thereof being a second death, which was an everlasting
death as to things pertaining unto righteousness;
for on such the plan of redemption could have no
power, for the works of justice could not be
destroyed, according to the supreme goodness of God
33 But God did call on men, in the name of his
Son, (this being the plan of redemption which was
laid) saying: If ye will repent, and harden not your
hearts, then will I have mercy upon you, through
mine Only Begotten Son
34 Therefore, whosoever repenteth, and hardeneth
not his heart, he shall have claim on mercy through
mine Only Begotten Son, unto a remission of his
sins; and these shall enter into my rest
35 And whosoever will harden his heart and will do
iniquity, behold, I swear in my wrath that he
shall not enter into my rest
36 And now, my brethren, behold I say unto you,
that if ye will harden your hearts ye shall not
enter into the rest of the Lord; therefore your
iniquity provoketh him that he sendeth down his wrath
upon you as in the first provocation, yea, according
to his word in the last provocation as well as
the first, to the everlasting destruction of your
souls; therefore, according to his word, unto the
last death, as well as the first
37 And now, my brethren, seeing we know these
things, and they are true, let us repent, and harden
not our hearts, that we provoke not the Lord our
God to pull down his wrath upon us in these his
second commandments which he has given unto us; but
let us enter into the rest of God, which is prepared
according to his word.