Chapter 23 Religious freedom is proclaimed—The
Lamanites in seven lands and cities are
converted—They call themselves Anti-Nephi-Lehies and are freed
from the curse—The Amalekites and the Amulonites
reject the truth. About 90–77 B.C.
1 Behold, now it came to pass that the king of the
Lamanites sent a proclamation among all his
people, that they should not lay their hands on Ammon,
or Aaron, or Omner, or Himni, nor either of their
brethren who should go forth preaching the word of
God, in whatsoever place they should be, in any
part of their land
2 Yea, he sent a decree among them, that they
should not lay their hands on them to bind them, or to
cast them into prison; neither should they spit
upon them, nor smite them, nor cast them out of
their synagogues, nor scourge them; neither should
they cast stones at them, but that they should have
free access to their houses, and also their
temples, and their sanctuaries
3 And thus they might go forth and preach the word
according to their desires, for the king had been
converted unto the Lord, and all his household;
therefore he sent his proclamation throughout the
land unto his people, that the word of God might
have no obstruction, but that it might go forth
throughout all the land, that his people might be
convinced concerning the wicked traditions of their
fathers, and that they might be convinced that they
were all brethren, and that they ought not to
murder, nor to plunder, nor to steal, nor to commit
adultery, nor to commit any manner of wickedness
4 And now it came to pass that when the king had
sent forth this proclamation, that Aaron and his
brethren went forth from city to city, and from one
house of worship to another, establishing
churches, and consecrating priests and teachers throughout
the land among the Lamanites, to preach and to
teach the word of God among them; and thus they
began to have great success
5 And thousands were brought to the knowledge of
the Lord, yea, thousands were brought to believe in
the traditions of the Nephites; and they were
taught the records and prophecies which were handed
down even to the present time
6 And as sure as the Lord liveth, so sure as many
as believed, or as many as were brought to the
knowledge of the truth, through the preaching of
Ammon and his brethren, according to the spirit of
revelation and of prophecy, and the power of God
working miracles in them—yea, I say unto you, as the
Lord liveth, as many of the Lamanites as believed
in their preaching, and were converted unto the
Lord, never did fall away
7 For they became a righteous people; they did lay
down the weapons of their rebellion, that they
did not fight against God any more, neither against
any of their brethren
8 Now, these are they who were converted unto the
Lord
9 The people of the Lamanites who were in the land
of Ishmael
10 And also of the people of the Lamanites who
were in the land of Middoni
11 And also of the people of the Lamanites who
were in the city of Nephi
12 And also of the people of the Lamanites who
were in the land of Shilom, and who were in the land
of Shemlon, and in the city of Lemuel, and in the
city of Shimnilom
13 And these are the names of the cities of the
Lamanites which were converted unto the Lord; and
these are they that laid down the weapons of their
rebellion, yea, all their weapons of war; and they
were all Lamanites
14 And the Amalekites were not converted, save
only one; neither were any of the Amulonites; but
they did harden their hearts, and also the hearts of
the Lamanites in that part of the land wheresoever
they dwelt, yea, and all their villages and all
their cities
15 Therefore, we have named all the cities of the
Lamanites in which they did repent and come to the
knowledge of the truth, and were converted
16 And now it came to pass that the king and those
who were converted were desirous that they might
have a name, that thereby they might be
distinguished from their brethren; therefore the king
consulted with Aaron and many of their priests,
concerning the name that they should take upon them, that
they might be distinguished
17 And it came to pass that they called their
names Anti-Nephi-Lehies; and they were called by this
name and were no more called Lamanites
18 And they began to be a very industrious people;
yea, and they were friendly with the Nephites;
therefore, they did open a correspondence with them,
and the curse of God did no more follow them.