Chapter 22 Aaron teaches Lamoni’s father about the
Creation, the Fall of Adam, and the plan of
redemption through Christ—The king and all his
household are converted—The division of the land between
the Nephites and the Lamanites is explained. About
90–77 B.C.
1 Now, as Ammon was thus teaching the people of
Lamoni continually, we will return to the account of
Aaron and his brethren; for after he departed
from the land of Middoni he was led by the Spirit to
the land of Nephi, even to the house of the king
which was over all the land save it were the land
of Ishmael; and he was the father of Lamoni
2 And it came to pass that he went in unto him
into the king’s palace, with his brethren, and bowed
himself before the king, and said unto him:
Behold, O king, we are the brethren of Ammon, whom thou
hast delivered out of prison
3 And now, O king, if thou wilt spare our lives,
we will be thy servants. And the king said unto
them: Arise, for I will grant unto you your lives,
and I will not suffer that ye shall be my servants;
but I will insist that ye shall administer unto
me; for I have been somewhat troubled in mind
because of the generosity and the greatness of the words
of thy brother Ammon; and I desire to know the
cause why he has not come up out of Middoni with
thee
4 And Aaron said unto the king: Behold, the Spirit
of the Lord has called him another way; he has
gone to the land of Ishmael, to teach the people of
Lamoni
5 Now the king said unto them: What is this that
ye have said concerning the Spirit of the Lord?
Behold, this is the thing which doth trouble me
6 And also, what is this that Ammon said—If ye
will repent ye shall be saved, and if ye will not
repent, ye shall be cast off at the last day
7 And Aaron answered him and said unto him:
Believest thou that there is a God? And the king said: I
know that the Amalekites say that there is a God,
and I have granted unto them that they should
build sanctuaries, that they may assemble themselves
together to worship him. And if now thou sayest
there is a God, behold I will believe
8 And now when Aaron heard this, his heart began
to rejoice, and he said: Behold, assuredly as thou
livest, O king, there is a God
9 And the king said: Is God that Great Spirit that
brought our fathers out of the land of Jerusalem
10 And Aaron said unto him: Yea, he is that Great
Spirit, and he created all things both in heaven
and in earth. Believest thou this
11 And he said: Yea, I believe that the Great
Spirit created all things, and I desire that ye should
tell me concerning all these things, and I will
believe thy words
12 And it came to pass that when Aaron saw that
the king would believe his words, he began from the
creation of Adam, reading the scriptures unto the
king—how God created man after his own image, and
that God gave him commandments, and that because
of transgression, man had fallen
13 And Aaron did expound unto him the scriptures
from the creation of Adam, laying the fall of man
before him, and their carnal state and also the
plan of redemption, which was prepared from the
foundation of the world, through Christ, for all
whosoever would believe on his name
14 And since man had fallen he could not merit
anything of himself; but the sufferings and death of
Christ atone for their sins, through faith and
repentance, and so forth; and that he breaketh the
bands of death, that the grave shall have no
victory, and that the sting of death should be swallowed
up in the hopes of glory; and Aaron did expound
all these things unto the king
15 And it came to pass that after Aaron had
expounded these things unto him, the king said: What
shall I do that I may have this eternal life of which
thou hast spoken? Yea, what shall I do that I may
be born of God, having this wicked spirit rooted
out of my breast, and receive his Spirit, that I
may be filled with joy, that I may not be cast off
at the last day? Behold, said he, I will give up
all that I possess, yea, I will forsake my kingdom,
that I may receive this great joy
16 But Aaron said unto him: If thou desirest this
thing, if thou wilt bow down before God, yea, if
thou wilt repent of all thy sins, and will bow down
before God, and call on his name in faith,
believing that ye shall receive, then shalt thou receive
the hope which thou desirest
17 And it came to pass that when Aaron had said
these words, the king did bow down before the Lord,
upon his knees; yea, even he did prostrate himself
upon the earth, and cried mightily, saying
18 O God, Aaron hath told me that there is a God;
and if there is a God, and if thou art God, wilt
thou make thyself known unto me, and I will give
away all my sins to know thee, and that I may be
raised from the dead, and be saved at the last day.
And now when the king had said these words, he was
struck as if he were dead
19 And it came to pass that his servants ran and
told the queen all that had happened unto the king.
And she came in unto the king; and when she saw
him lay as if he were dead, and also Aaron and his
brethren standing as though they had been the
cause of his fall, she was angry with them, and
commanded that her servants, or the servants of the
king, should take them and slay them
20 Now the servants had seen the cause of the
king’s fall, therefore they durst not lay their hands
on Aaron and his brethren; and they pled with the
queen saying: Why commandest thou that we should
slay these men, when behold one of them is mightier
than us all? Therefore we shall fall before them
21 Now when the queen saw the fear of the servants
she also began to fear exceedingly, lest there
should some evil come upon her. And she commanded
her servants that they should go and call the
people, that they might slay Aaron and his brethren
22 Now when Aaron saw the determination of the
queen, he, also knowing the hardness of the hearts of
the people, feared lest that a multitude should
assemble themselves together, and there should be a
great contention and a disturbance among them;
therefore he put forth his hand and raised the king
from the earth, and said unto him: Stand. And he
stood upon his feet, receiving his strength
23 Now this was done in the presence of the queen
and many of the servants. And when they saw it
they greatly marveled, and began to fear. And the
king stood forth, and began to minister unto them.
And he did minister unto them, insomuch that his
whole household were converted unto the Lord
24 Now there was a multitude gathered together
because of the commandment of the queen, and there
began to be great murmurings among them because of
Aaron and his brethren
25 But the king stood forth among them and
administered unto them. And they were pacified towards
Aaron and those who were with him
28 Now, the more idle part of the Lamanites lived
in the wilderness, and dwelt in tents; and they
were spread through the wilderness on the west, in
the land of Nephi; yea, and also on the west of the
land of Zarahemla, in the borders by the
seashore, and on the west in the land of Nephi, in the
place of their fathers’ first inheritance, and thus
bordering along by the seashore
29 And also there were many Lamanites on the east
by the seashore, whither the Nephites had driven
them. And thus the Nephites were nearly surrounded
by the Lamanites; nevertheless the Nephites had
taken possession of all the northern parts of the
land bordering on the wilderness, at the head of the
river Sidon, from the east to the west, round
about on the wilderness side; on the north, even
until they came to the land which they called
Bountiful
30 And it bordered upon the land which they called
Desolation, it being so far northward that it
came into the land which had been peopled and been
destroyed, of whose bones we have spoken, which was
discovered by the people of Zarahemla, it being
the place of their first landing
31 And they came from there up into the south
wilderness. Thus the land on the northward was called
Desolation, and the land on the southward was
called Bountiful, it being the wilderness which is
filled with all manner of wild animals of every kind,
a part of which had come from the land northward
for food
32 And now, it was only the distance of a day and
a half’s journey for a Nephite, on the line
Bountiful and the land Desolation, from the east to the
west sea; and thus the land of Nephi and the land
of Zarahemla were nearly surrounded by water,
there being a small neck of land between the land
northward and the land southward
33 And it came to pass that the Nephites had
inhabited the land Bountiful, even from the east unto
the west sea, and thus the Nephites in their
wisdom, with their guards and their armies, had hemmed
in the Lamanites on the south, that thereby they
should have no more possession on the north, that
they might not overrun the land northward
34 Therefore the Lamanites could have no more
possessions only in the land of Nephi, and the
wilderness round about. Now this was wisdom in the
Nephites—as the Lamanites were an enemy to them, they
would not suffer their afflictions on every hand,
and also that they might have a country whither they
might flee, according to their desires
35 And now I, after having said this, return again
to the account of Ammon and Aaron, Omner and
Himni, and their brethren.