Chapter 25 Lamanite aggressions spread—The seed of
the priests of Noah perish as Abinadi
prophesied—Many Lamanites are converted and join the people
of Anti-Nephi-Lehi—They believe in Christ and keep
the law of Moses. About 90–77 B.C.
1 And behold, now it came to pass that those
Lamanites were more angry because they had slain their
brethren; therefore they swore vengeance upon the
Nephites; and they did no more attempt to slay the
people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi at that time
2 But they took their armies and went over into
the borders of the land of Zarahemla, and fell upon
the people who were in the land of Ammonihah and
destroyed them
3 And after that, they had many battles with the
Nephites, in the which they were driven and slain
4 And among the Lamanites who were slain were
almost all the seed of Amulon and his brethren, who
were the priests of Noah, and they were slain by the
hands of the Nephites
7 And it came to pass that those rulers who were
the remnant of the children of Amulon caused that
they should be put to death, yea, all those that
believed in these things
8 Now this martyrdom caused that many of their
brethren should be stirred up to anger; and there
began to be contention in the wilderness; and the
Lamanites began to hunt the seed of Amulon and his
brethren and began to slay them; and they fled into
the east wilderness
9 And behold they are hunted at this day by the
Lamanites. Thus the words of Abinadi were brought to
pass, which he said concerning the seed of the
priests who caused that he should suffer death by
fire
10 For he said unto them: What ye shall do unto me
shall be a type of things to come
13 And it came to pass that when the Lamanites saw
that they could not overpower the Nephites they
returned again to their own land; and many of them
came over to dwell in the land of Ishmael and the
land of Nephi, and did join themselves to the
people of God, who were the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi
14 And they did also bury their weapons of war,
according as their brethren had, and they began to
be a righteous people; and they did walk in the
ways of the Lord, and did observe to keep his
commandments and his statutes
15 Yea, and they did keep the law of Moses; for it
was expedient that they should keep the law of
Moses as yet, for it was not all fulfilled. But
notwithstanding the law of Moses, they did look
forward to the coming of Christ, considering that the
law of Moses was a type of his coming, and believing
that they must keep those outward performances
until the time that he should be revealed unto them