Chapter 26 Ammon glories in the Lord—The faithful
are strengthened by the Lord and are given
knowledge—By faith men may bring thousands of souls unto
repentance—God has all power and comprehends all
things. About 90–77 B.C.
1 And now, these are the words of Ammon to his
brethren, which say thus: My brothers and my
brethren, behold I say unto you, how great reason have we
to rejoice; for could we have supposed when we
started from the land of Zarahemla that God would
have granted unto us such great blessings
2 And now, I ask, what great blessings has he
bestowed upon us? Can ye tell
3 Behold, I answer for you; for our brethren, the
Lamanites, were in darkness, yea, even in the
darkest abyss, but behold, how many of them are
brought to behold the marvelous light of God! And this
is the blessing which hath been bestowed upon us,
that we have been made instruments in the hands of
God to bring about this great work
4 Behold, thousands of them do rejoice, and have
been brought into the fold of God
5 Behold, the field was ripe, and blessed are ye,
for ye did thrust in the sickle, and did reap with
your might, yea, all the day long did ye labor;
and behold the number of your sheaves! And they
shall be gathered into the garners, that they are not
wasted
6 Yea, they shall not be beaten down by the storm
at the last day; yea, neither shall they be
harrowed up by the whirlwinds; but when the storm cometh
they shall be gathered together in their place,
that the storm cannot penetrate to them; yea,
neither shall they be driven with fierce winds
whithersoever the enemy listeth to carry them
7 But behold, they are in the hands of the Lord of
the harvest, and they are his; and he will raise
them up at the last day
8 Blessed be the name of our God; let us sing to
his praise, yea, let us give thanks to his holy
name, for he doth work righteousness forever
9 For if we had not come up out of the land of
Zarahemla, these our dearly beloved brethren, who
have so dearly beloved us, would still have been
racked with hatred against us, yea, and they would
also have been strangers to God
10 And it came to pass that when Ammon had said
these words, his brother Aaron rebuked him, saying:
Ammon, I fear that thy joy doth carry thee away
unto boasting
11 But Ammon said unto him: I do not boast in my
own strength, nor in my own wisdom; but behold, my
joy is full, yea, my heart is brim with joy, and I
will rejoice in my God
12 Yea, I know that I am nothing; as to my
strength I am weak; therefore I will not boast of myself,
but I will boast of my God, for in his strength I
can do all things; yea, behold, many mighty
miracles we have wrought in this land, for which we
will praise his name forever
13 Behold, how many thousands of our brethren has
he loosed from the pains of hell; and they are
brought to sing redeeming love, and this because of
the power of his word which is in us, therefore
have we not great reason to rejoice
14 Yea, we have reason to praise him forever, for
he is the Most High God, and has loosed our
brethren from the chains of hell
15 Yea, they were encircled about with everlasting
darkness and destruction; but behold, he has
brought them into his everlasting light, yea, into
everlasting salvation; and they are encircled about
with the matchless bounty of his love; yea, and we
have been instruments in his hands of doing this
great and marvelous work
16 Therefore, let us glory, yea, we will glory in
the Lord; yea, we will rejoice, for our joy is
full; yea, we will praise our God forever. Behold,
who can glory too much in the Lord? Yea, who can say
too much of his great power, and of his mercy,
and of his long-suffering towards the children of
men? Behold, I say unto you, I cannot say the
smallest part which I feel
17 Who could have supposed that our God would have
been so merciful as to have snatched us from our
awful, sinful, and polluted state
18 Behold, we went forth even in wrath, with
mighty threatenings to destroy his church
19 Oh then, why did he not consign us to an awful
destruction, yea, why did he not let the sword of
his justice fall upon us, and doom us to eternal
despair
20 Oh, my soul, almost as it were, fleeth at the
thought. Behold, he did not exercise his justice
upon us, but in his great mercy hath brought us over
that everlasting gulf of death and misery, even
to the salvation of our souls
23 Now do ye remember, my brethren, that we said
unto our brethren in the land of Zarahemla, we go
up to the land of Nephi, to preach unto our
brethren, the Lamanites, and they laughed us to scorn
24 For they said unto us: Do ye suppose that ye
can bring the Lamanites to the knowledge of the
truth? Do ye suppose that ye can convince the
Lamanites of the incorrectness of the traditions of their
fathers, as stiffnecked a people as they are;
whose hearts delight in the shedding of blood; whose
days have been spent in the grossest iniquity;
whose ways have been the ways of a transgressor from
the beginning? Now my brethren, ye remember that
this was their language
25 And moreover they did say: Let us take up arms
against them, that we destroy them and their
iniquity out of the land, lest they overrun us and
destroy us
26 But behold, my beloved brethren, we came into
the wilderness not with the intent to destroy our
brethren, but with the intent that perhaps we might
save some few of their souls
27 Now when our hearts were depressed, and we were
about to turn back, behold, the Lord comforted
us, and said: Go amongst thy brethren, the
Lamanites, and bear with patience thine afflictions, and I
will give unto you success
28 And now behold, we have come, and been forth
amongst them; and we have been patient in our
sufferings, and we have suffered every privation; yea,
we have traveled from house to house, relying upon
the mercies of the world—not upon the mercies of
the world alone but upon the mercies of God
29 And we have entered into their houses and
taught them, and we have taught them in their streets;
yea, and we have taught them upon their hills; and
we have also entered into their temples and their
synagogues and taught them; and we have been cast
out, and mocked, and spit upon, and smote upon
our cheeks; and we have been stoned, and taken and
bound with strong cords, and cast into prison; and
through the power and wisdom of God we have been
delivered again
30 And we have suffered all manner of afflictions,
and all this, that perhaps we might be the means
of saving some soul; and we supposed that our joy
would be full if perhaps we could be the means of
saving some
31 Now behold, we can look forth and see the
fruits of our labors; and are they few? I say unto you,
Nay, they are many; yea, and we can witness of
their sincerity, because of their love towards their
brethren and also towards us
32 For behold, they had rather sacrifice their
lives than even to take the life of their enemy; and
they have buried their weapons of war deep in the
earth, because of their love towards their
brethren
33 And now behold I say unto you, has there been
so great love in all the land? Behold, I say unto
you, Nay, there has not, even among the Nephites
34 For behold, they would take up arms against
their brethren; they would not suffer themselves to
be slain. But behold how many of these have laid
down their lives; and we know that they have gone to
their God, because of their love and of their
hatred to sin
35 Now have we not reason to rejoice? Yea, I say
unto you, there never were men that had so great
reason to rejoice as we, since the world began; yea,
and my joy is carried away, even unto boasting in
my God; for he has all power, all wisdom, and all
understanding; he comprehendeth all things, and
he is a merciful Being, even unto salvation, to
those who will repent and believe on his name
36 Now if this is boasting, even so will I boast;
for this is my life and my light, my joy and my
salvation, and my redemption from everlasting wo.
Yea, blessed is the name of my God, who has been
mindful of this people, who are a branch of the tree
of Israel, and has been lost from its body in a
strange land; yea, I say, blessed be the name of my
God, who has been mindful of us, wanderers in a
strange land
37 Now my brethren, we see that God is mindful of
every people, whatsoever land they may be in; yea,
he numbereth his people, and his bowels of mercy
are over all the earth. Now this is my joy, and my
great thanksgiving; yea, and I will give thanks
unto my God forever. Amen.