Chapter 20 The Lord sends Ammon to Middoni to
deliver his imprisoned brethren—Ammon and Lamoni meet
Lamoni’s father, who is king over all the
land—Ammon compels the old king to approve the release of
his brethren. About 90 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that when they had
established a church in that land, that king Lamoni desired
that Ammon should go with him to the land of
Nephi, that he might show him unto his father
2 And the voice of the Lord came to Ammon, saying:
Thou shalt not go up to the land of Nephi, for
behold, the king will seek thy life; but thou shalt
go to the land of Middoni; for behold, thy brother
Aaron, and also Muloki and Ammah are in prison
3 Now it came to pass that when Ammon had heard
this, he said unto Lamoni: Behold, my brother and
brethren are in prison at Middoni, and I go that I
may deliver them
4 Now Lamoni said unto Ammon: I know, in the
strength of the Lord thou canst do all things. But
behold, I will go with thee to the land of Middoni;
for the king of the land of Middoni, whose name is
Antiomno, is a friend unto me; therefore I go to
the land of Middoni, that I may flatter the king of
the land, and he will cast thy brethren out of
prison. Now Lamoni said unto him: Who told thee that
thy brethren were in prison
5 And Ammon said unto him: No one hath told me,
save it be God; and he said unto me—Go and deliver
thy brethren, for they are in prison in the land of
Middoni
6 Now when Lamoni had heard this he caused that
his servants should make ready his horses and his
chariots
7 And he said unto Ammon: Come, I will go with
thee down to the land of Middoni, and there I will
plead with the king that he will cast thy brethren
out of prison
8 And it came to pass that as Ammon and Lamoni
were journeying thither, they met the father of
Lamoni, who was king over all the land
9 And behold, the father of Lamoni said unto him:
Why did ye not come to the feast on that great day
when I made a feast unto my sons, and unto my
people
10 And he also said: Whither art thou going with
this Nephite, who is one of the children of a liar
11 And it came to pass that Lamoni rehearsed unto
him whither he was going, for he feared to offend
him
12 And he also told him all the cause of his
tarrying in his own kingdom, that he did not go unto
his father to the feast which he had prepared
13 And now when Lamoni had rehearsed unto him all
these things, behold, to his astonishment, his
father was angry with him, and said: Lamoni, thou art
going to deliver these Nephites, who are sons of
a liar. Behold, he robbed our fathers; and now his
children are also come amongst us that they may,
by their cunning and their lyings, deceive us,
that they again may rob us of our property
14 Now the father of Lamoni commanded him that he
should slay Ammon with the sword. And he also
commanded him that he should not go to the land of
Middoni, but that he should return with him to the
land of Ishmael
15 But Lamoni said unto him: I will not slay
Ammon, neither will I return to the land of Ishmael,
but I go to the land of Middoni that I may release
the brethren of Ammon, for I know that they are
just men and holy prophets of the true God
16 Now when his father had heard these words, he
was angry with him, and he drew his sword that he
might smite him to the earth
17 But Ammon stood forth and said unto him:
Behold, thou shalt not slay thy son; nevertheless, it
were better that he should fall than thee, for
behold, he has repented of his sins; but if thou
shouldst fall at this time, in thine anger, thy soul
could not be saved
18 And again, it is expedient that thou shouldst
forbear; for if thou shouldst slay thy son, he
being an innocent man, his blood would cry from the
ground to the Lord his God, for vengeance to come
upon thee; and perhaps thou wouldst lose thy soul
19 Now when Ammon had said these words unto him,
he answered him, saying: I know that if I should
slay my son, that I should shed innocent blood; for
it is thou that hast sought to destroy him
20 And he stretched forth his hand to slay Ammon.
But Ammon withstood his blows, and also smote his
arm that he could not use it
21 Now when the king saw that Ammon could slay
him, he began to plead with Ammon that he would spare
his life
22 But Ammon raised his sword, and said unto him:
Behold, I will smite thee except thou wilt grant
unto me that my brethren may be cast out of prison
23 Now the king, fearing he should lose his life,
said: If thou wilt spare me I will grant unto thee
whatsoever thou wilt ask, even to half of the
kingdom
24 Now when Ammon saw that he had wrought upon the
old king according to his desire, he said unto
him: If thou wilt grant that my brethren may be cast
out of prison, and also that Lamoni may retain
his kingdom, and that ye be not displeased with him,
but grant that he may do according to his own
desires in whatsoever thing he thinketh, then will I
spare thee; otherwise I will smite thee to the
earth
25 Now when Ammon had said these words, the king
began to rejoice because of his life
26 And when he saw that Ammon had no desire to
destroy him, and when he also saw the great love he
had for his son Lamoni, he was astonished
exceedingly, and said: Because this is all that thou hast
desired, that I would release thy brethren, and
suffer that my son Lamoni should retain his kingdom,
behold, I will grant unto you that my son may
retain his kingdom from this time and forever; and I
will govern him no more
27 And I will also grant unto thee that thy
brethren may be cast out of prison, and thou and thy
brethren may come unto me, in my kingdom; for I shall
greatly desire to see thee. For the king was
greatly astonished at the words which he had spoken,
and also at the words which had been spoken by his
son Lamoni, therefore he was desirous to learn
them
28 And it came to pass that Ammon and Lamoni
proceeded on their journey towards the land of Middoni.
And Lamoni found favor in the eyes of the king of
the land; therefore the brethren of Ammon were
brought forth out of prison