Chapter 27 The Lord commands Ammon to lead the
people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi to safety—Upon meeting
Alma, Ammon’s joy exhausts his strength—The Nephites
give the Anti-Nephi-Lehies the land of Jershon—They
are called the people of Ammon. About 90–77 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that when those Lamanites
who had gone to war against the Nephites had found,
after their many struggles to destroy them, that
it was in vain to seek their destruction, they
returned again to the land of Nephi
2 And it came to pass that the Amalekites, because
of their loss, were exceedingly angry. And when
they saw that they could not seek revenge from the
Nephites, they began to stir up the people in
anger against their brethren, the people of
Anti-Nephi-Lehi; therefore they began again to destroy them
3 Now this people again refused to take their
arms, and they suffered themselves to be slain
according to the desires of their enemies
4 Now when Ammon and his brethren saw this work of
destruction among those whom they so dearly
beloved, and among those who had so dearly beloved
them—for they were treated as though they were angels
sent from God to save them from everlasting
destruction—therefore, when Ammon and his brethren saw
this great work of destruction, they were moved
with compassion, and they said unto the king
5 Let us gather together this people of the Lord,
and let us go down to the land of Zarahemla to our
brethren the Nephites, and flee out of the hands
of our enemies, that we be not destroyed
6 But the king said unto them: Behold, the
Nephites will destroy us, because of the many murders and
sins we have committed against them
7 And Ammon said: I will go and inquire of the
Lord, and if he say unto us, go down unto our
brethren, will ye go
8 And the king said unto him: Yea, if the Lord
saith unto us go, we will go down unto our brethren,
and we will be their slaves until we repair unto
them the many murders and sins which we have
committed against them
9 But Ammon said unto him: It is against the law
of our brethren, which was established by my
father, that there should be any slaves among them;
therefore let us go down and rely upon the mercies of
our brethren
10 But the king said unto him: Inquire of the
Lord, and if he saith unto us go, we will go;
otherwise we will perish in the land
11 And it came to pass that Ammon went and
inquired of the Lord, and the Lord said unto him
12 Get this people out of this land, that they
perish not; for Satan has great hold on the hearts of
the Amalekites, who do stir up the Lamanites to
anger against their brethren to slay them;
therefore get thee out of this land; and blessed are this
people in this generation, for I will preserve
them
13 And now it came to pass that Ammon went and
told the king all the words which the Lord had said
unto him
14 And they gathered together all their people,
yea, all the people of the Lord, and did gather
together all their flocks and herds, and departed out
of the land, and came into the wilderness which
divided the land of Nephi from the land of
Zarahemla, and came over near the borders of the land
15 And it came to pass that Ammon said unto them:
Behold, I and my brethren will go forth into the
land of Zarahemla, and ye shall remain here until
we return; and we will try the hearts of our
brethren, whether they will that ye shall come into
their land
16 And it came to pass that as Ammon was going
forth into the land, that he and his brethren met
Alma, over in the place of which has been spoken; and
behold, this was a joyful meeting
17 Now the joy of Ammon was so great even that he
was full; yea, he was swallowed up in the joy of
his God, even to the exhausting of his strength;
and he fell again to the earth
18 Now was not this exceeding joy? Behold, this is
joy which none receiveth save it be the truly
penitent and humble seeker of happiness
19 Now the joy of Alma in meeting his brethren was
truly great, and also the joy of Aaron, of Omner,
and Himni; but behold their joy was not that to
exceed their strength
20 And now it came to pass that Alma conducted his
brethren back to the land of Zarahemla; even to
his own house. And they went and told the chief
judge all the things that had happened unto them in
the land of Nephi, among their brethren, the
Lamanites
21 And it came to pass that the chief judge sent a
proclamation throughout all the land, desiring
the voice of the people concerning the admitting
their brethren, who were the people of
Anti-Nephi-Lehi
22 And it came to pass that the voice of the
people came, saying: Behold, we will give up the land
of Jershon, which is on the east by the sea, which
joins the land Bountiful, which is on the south of
the land Bountiful; and this land Jershon is the
land which we will give unto our brethren for an
inheritance
23 And behold, we will set our armies between the
land Jershon and the land Nephi, that we may
protect our brethren in the land Jershon; and this we
do for our brethren, on account of their fear to
take up arms against their brethren lest they should
commit sin; and this their great fear came
because of their sore repentance which they had, on
account of their many murders and their awful
wickedness
24 And now behold, this will we do unto our
brethren, that they may inherit the land Jershon; and we
will guard them from their enemies with our
armies, on condition that they will give us a portion
of their substance to assist us that we may
maintain our armies
25 Now, it came to pass that when Ammon had heard
this, he returned to the people of
Anti-Nephi-Lehi, and also Alma with him, into the wilderness,
where they had pitched their tents, and made known
unto them all these things. And Alma also related
unto them his conversion, with Ammon and Aaron, and
his brethren
26 And it came to pass that it did cause great joy
among them. And they went down into the land of
Jershon, and took possession of the land of
Jershon; and they were called by the Nephites the people
of Ammon; therefore they were distinguished by
that name ever after
27 And they were among the people of Nephi, and
also numbered among the people who were of the
church of God. And they were also distinguished for
their zeal towards God, and also towards men; for
they were perfectly honest and upright in all things;
and they were firm in the faith of Christ, even
unto the end
28 And they did look upon shedding the blood of
their brethren with the greatest abhorrence; and
they never could be prevailed upon to take up arms
against their brethren; and they never did look upon
death with any degree of terror, for their hope
and views of Christ and the resurrection;
therefore, death was swallowed up to them by the victory of
Christ over it