Chapter 24 The Lamanites come against the people
of God—The Anti-Nephi-Lehies rejoice in Christ and
are visited by angels—They choose to suffer death
rather than to defend themselves—More Lamanites
are converted. About 90–77 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that the Amalekites and the
Amulonites and the Lamanites who were in the land
of Amulon, and also in the land of Helam, and who
were in the land of Jerusalem, and in fine, in all
the land round about, who had not been converted
and had not taken upon them the name of
Anti-Nephi-Lehi, were stirred up by the Amalekites and by
the Amulonites to anger against their brethren
2 And their hatred became exceedingly sore against
them, even insomuch that they began to rebel
against their king, insomuch that they would not that
he should be their king; therefore, they took up
arms against the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi
3 Now the king conferred the kingdom upon his son,
and he called his name Anti-Nephi-Lehi
4 And the king died in that selfsame year that the
Lamanites began to make preparations for war
against the people of God
5 Now when Ammon and his brethren and all those
who had come up with him saw the preparations of the
Lamanites to destroy their brethren, they came
forth to the land of Midian, and there Ammon met all
his brethren; and from thence they came to the
land of Ishmael that they might hold a council with
Lamoni and also with his brother Anti-Nephi-Lehi,
what they should do to defend themselves against
the Lamanites
6 Now there was not one soul among all the people
who had been converted unto the Lord that would
take up arms against their brethren; nay, they would
not even make any preparations for war; yea, and
also their king commanded them that they should
not
7 Now, these are the words which he said unto the
people concerning the matter: I thank my God, my
beloved people, that our great God has in goodness
sent these our brethren, the Nephites, unto us to
preach unto us, and to convince us of the
traditions of our wicked fathers
8 And behold, I thank my great God that he has
given us a portion of his Spirit to soften our
hearts, that we have opened a correspondence with these
brethren, the Nephites
9 And behold, I also thank my God, that by opening
this correspondence we have been convinced of our
sins, and of the many murders which we have
committed
10 And I also thank my God, yea, my great God,
that he hath granted unto us that we might repent of
these things, and also that he hath forgiven us of
those our many sins and murders which we have
committed, and taken away the guilt from our hearts,
through the merits of his Son
11 And now behold, my brethren, since it has been
all that we could do (as we were the most lost of
all mankind) to repent of all our sins and the
many murders which we have committed, and to get God
to take them away from our hearts, for it was all
we could do to repent sufficiently before God that
he would take away our stain
12 Now, my best beloved brethren, since God hath
taken away our stains, and our swords have become
bright, then let us stain our swords no more with
the blood of our brethren
13 Behold, I say unto you, Nay, let us retain our
swords that they be not stained with the blood of
our brethren; for perhaps, if we should stain our
swords again they can no more be washed bright
through the blood of the Son of our great God, which
shall be shed for the atonement of our sins
14 And the great God has had mercy on us, and made
these things known unto us that we might not
perish; yea, and he has made these things known unto
us beforehand, because he loveth our souls as well
as he loveth our children; therefore, in his mercy
he doth visit us by his angels, that the plan of
salvation might be made known unto us as well as
unto future generations
15 Oh, how merciful is our God! And now behold,
since it has been as much as we could do to get our
stains taken away from us, and our swords are made
bright, let us hide them away that they may be
kept bright, as a testimony to our God at the last
day, or at the day that we shall be brought to
stand before him to be judged, that we have not
stained our swords in the blood of our brethren since he
imparted his word unto us and has made us clean
thereby
16 And now, my brethren, if our brethren seek to
destroy us, behold, we will hide away our swords,
yea, even we will bury them deep in the earth, that
they may be kept bright, as a testimony that we
have never used them, at the last day; and if our
brethren destroy us, behold, we shall go to our God
and shall be saved
17 And now it came to pass that when the king had
made an end of these sayings, and all the people
were assembled together, they took their swords,
and all the weapons which were used for the shedding
of man’s blood, and they did bury them up deep in
the earth
18 And this they did, it being in their view a
testimony to God, and also to men, that they never
would use weapons again for the shedding of man’s
blood; and this they did, vouching and covenanting
with God, that rather than shed the blood of their
brethren they would give up their own lives; and
rather than take away from a brother they would
give unto him; and rather than spend their days in
idleness they would labor abundantly with their
hands
19 And thus we see that, when these Lamanites were
brought to believe and to know the truth, they
were firm, and would suffer even unto death rather
than commit sin; and thus we see that they buried
their weapons of peace, or they buried the weapons
of war, for peace
20 And it came to pass that their brethren, the
Lamanites, made preparations for war, and came up to
the land of Nephi for the purpose of destroying
the king, and to place another in his stead, and
also of destroying the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi out
of the land
21 Now when the people saw that they were coming
against them they went out to meet them, and
prostrated themselves before them to the earth, and
began to call on the name of the Lord; and thus they
were in this attitude when the Lamanites began to
fall upon them, and began to slay them with the
sword
22 And thus without meeting any resistance, they
did slay a thousand and five of them; and we know
that they are blessed, for they have gone to dwell
with their God
23 Now when the Lamanites saw that their brethren
would not flee from the sword, neither would they
turn aside to the right hand or to the left, but
that they would lie down and perish, and praised
God even in the very act of perishing under the
sword
26 And it came to pass that the people of God were
joined that day by more than the number who had
been slain; and those who had been slain were
righteous people, therefore we have no reason to doubt
but what they were saved
27 And there was not a wicked man slain among
them; but there were more than a thousand brought to
the knowledge of the truth; thus we see that the
Lord worketh in many ways to the salvation of his
people
28 Now the greatest number of those of the
Lamanites who slew so many of their brethren were
Amalekites and Amulonites, the greatest number of whom
were after the order of the Nehors
29 Now, among those who joined the people of the
Lord, there were none who were Amalekites or
Amulonites, or who were of the order of Nehor, but they
were actual descendants of Laman and Lemuel
30 And thus we can plainly discern, that after a
people have been once enlightened by the Spirit of
God, and have had great knowledge of things
pertaining to righteousness, and then have fallen away
into sin and transgression, they become more
hardened, and thus their state becomes worse than though
they had never known these things.