Chapter 29 Alma desires to cry repentance with
angelic zeal—The Lord grants teachers for all
nations—Alma glories in the Lord’s work and in the
success of Ammon and his brethren. About 76 B.C.
1 O that I were an angel, and could have the wish
of mine heart, that I might go forth and speak
with the trump of God, with a voice to shake the
earth, and cry repentance unto every people
2 Yea, I would declare unto every soul, as with
the voice of thunder, repentance and the plan of
redemption, that they should repent and come unto our
God, that there might not be more sorrow upon all
the face of the earth
3 But behold, I am a man, and do sin in my wish;
for I ought to be content with the things which the
Lord hath allotted unto me
4 I ought not to harrow up in my desires the firm
decree of a just God, for I know that he granteth
unto men according to their desire, whether it be
unto death or unto life; yea, I know that he
allotteth unto men, yea, decreeth unto them decrees
which are unalterable, according to their wills,
whether they be unto salvation or unto destruction
5 Yea, and I know that good and evil have come
before all men; he that knoweth not good from evil is
blameless; but he that knoweth good and evil, to
him it is given according to his desires, whether
he desireth good or evil, life or death, joy or
remorse of conscience
6 Now, seeing that I know these things, why should
I desire more than to perform the work to which I
have been called
7 Why should I desire that I were an angel, that I
could speak unto all the ends of the earth
8 For behold, the Lord doth grant unto all
nations, of their own nation and tongue, to teach his
word, yea, in wisdom, all that he seeth fit that they
should have; therefore we see that the Lord doth
counsel in wisdom, according to that which is just
and true
9 I know that which the Lord hath commanded me,
and I glory in it. I do not glory of myself, but I
glory in that which the Lord hath commanded me;
yea, and this is my glory, that perhaps I may be an
instrument in the hands of God to bring some soul
to repentance; and this is my joy
10 And behold, when I see many of my brethren
truly penitent, and coming to the Lord their God, then
is my soul filled with joy; then do I remember
what the Lord has done for me, yea, even that he
hath heard my prayer; yea, then do I remember his
merciful arm which he extended towards me
11 Yea, and I also remember the captivity of my
fathers; for I surely do know that the Lord did
deliver them out of bondage, and by this did establish
his church; yea, the Lord God, the God of
Abraham, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob, did
deliver them out of bondage
12 Yea, I have always remembered the captivity of
my fathers; and that same God who delivered them
out of the hands of the Egyptians did deliver them
out of bondage
13 Yea, and that same God did establish his church
among them; yea, and that same God hath called me
by a holy calling, to preach the word unto this
people, and hath given me much success, in the
which my joy is full
16 Now, when I think of the success of these my
brethren my soul is carried away, even to the
separation of it from the body, as it were, so great is
my joy
17 And now may God grant unto these, my brethren,
that they may sit down in the kingdom of God; yea,
and also all those who are the fruit of their
labors that they may go no more out, but that they
may praise him forever. And may God grant that it
may be done according to my words, even as I have
spoken. Amen.