Chapter 28 The Lamanites are defeated in a
tremendous battle—Tens of thousands are slain—The wicked
are consigned to a state of endless woe; the
righteous attain a never-ending happiness. About
77–76 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that after the people of
Ammon were established in the land of Jershon,
and a church also established in the land of
Jershon, and the armies of the Nephites were set round
about the land of Jershon, yea, in all the borders
round about the land of Zarahemla; behold the
armies of the Lamanites had followed their brethren
into the wilderness
2 And thus there was a tremendous battle; yea,
even such an one as never had been known among all
the people in the land from the time Lehi left
Jerusalem; yea, and tens of thousands of the Lamanites
were slain and scattered abroad
3 Yea, and also there was a tremendous slaughter
among the people of Nephi; nevertheless, the
Lamanites were driven and scattered, and the people of
Nephi returned again to their land
4 And now this was a time that there was a great
mourning and lamentation heard throughout all the
land, among all the people of Nephi
5 Yea, the cry of widows mourning for their
husbands, and also of fathers mourning for their sons,
and the daughter for the brother, yea, the brother
for the father; and thus the cry of mourning was
heard among all of them, mourning for their kindred
who had been slain
6 And now surely this was a sorrowful day; yea, a
time of solemnity, and a time of much fasting and
prayer
7 And thus endeth the fifteenth year of the reign
of the judges over the people of Nephi
8 And this is the account of Ammon and his
brethren, their journeyings in the land of Nephi, their
sufferings in the land, their sorrows, and their
afflictions, and their incomprehensible joy, and the
reception and safety of the brethren in the land
of Jershon. And now may the Lord, the Redeemer of
all men, bless their souls forever
9 And this is the account of the wars and
contentions among the Nephites, and also the wars between
the Nephites and the Lamanites; and the fifteenth
year of the reign of the judges is ended
12 While many thousands of others truly mourn for
the loss of their kindred, yet they rejoice and
exult in the hope, and even know, according to the
promises of the Lord, that they are raised to dwell
at the right hand of God, in a state of
never-ending happiness
13 And thus we see how great the inequality of man
is because of sin and transgression, and the
power of the devil, which comes by the cunning plans
which he hath devised to ensnare the hearts of men
14 And thus we see the great call of diligence of
men to labor in the vineyards of the Lord; and
thus we see the great reason of sorrow, and also of
rejoicing—sorrow because of death and destruction
among men, and joy because of the light of Christ
unto life.