Chapter 2 Amlici seeks to be king and is
rejected by the voice of the people—His
followers make him king—The Amlicites make
war on the Nephites and are defeated—The
Lamanites and Amlicites join forces and
are defeated—Alma slays Amlici. About 87 B.C.
1 And it came to pass in the
commencement of the fifth year of their reign
there began to be a contention among
the people; for a certain man, being
called Amlici, he being a very cunning
man, yea, a wise man as to the wisdom of
the world, he being after the order
of the man that slew Gideon by the
sword, who was executed according to the law—
2 Now this Amlici had, by his
cunning, drawn away much people
after him; even so much that they
began to be very powerful; and they
began to endeavor to establish
Amlici to be a king over the people.
3 Now this was alarming to the
people of the church, and
also to all those who had not
been drawn away after the
persuasions of Amlici; for they knew
that according to their law
that such things must be
established by the voice of the people.
4 Therefore, if it were
possible that Amlici should
gain the voice of the people,
he, being a wicked man,
would deprive them of their
rights and privileges of the
church; for it was his
intent to destroy the church of God.
5 And it came to pass
that the people assembled
themselves together
throughout all the land,
every man according to his
mind, whether it were
for or against Amlici, in
separate bodies, having
much dispute and
wonderful contentions one with another.
6 And thus they did
assemble themselves
together to cast in their
voices concerning the
matter; and they were
laid before the judges.
7 And it came to
pass that the voice
of the people came
against Amlici, that
he was not made
king over the people.
8 Now this did
cause much joy in
the hearts of
those who were
against him; but Amlici
did stir up
those who were in his
favor to anger
against those who
were not in his favor.
9 And it came
to pass that
they gathered
themselves
together, and did
consecrate Amlici to
be their king.
10 Now when
Amlici was made
king over them he
commanded them
that they
should take up arms
against their
brethren; and
this he did that
he might
subject them to him.
11 Now the
people of Amlici
were
distinguished by the
name of Amlici,
being called
Amlicites; and
the remainder
were called
Nephites, or the
people of God.
12 Therefore
the people of
the Nephites
were aware of
the intent of
the Amlicites,
and therefore
they did
prepare to meet
them; yea, they
did arm
themselves with
swords, and with
cimeters, and
with bows, and
with arrows, and
with stones,
and with
slings, and with
all manner of
weapons of war,
of every kind.
13 And thus
they were
prepared to meet
the Amlicites
at the time
of their
coming. And there
were
appointed captains,
and higher
captains, and
chief
captains, according
to their numbers.
14 And it
came to pass
that Amlici
did arm his
men with all
manner of
weapons of war
of every
kind; and he
also
appointed rulers and
leaders
over his
people, to lead
them to war
against their brethren.
15 And it
came to pass
that the
Amlicites
came upon the
hill
Amnihu, which
was east of
the river
Sidon, which
ran by the
land of
Zarahemla, and
there they
began to
make war with the Nephites.
16 Now
Alma, being
the chief
judge and
the
governor of the
people of
Nephi,
therefore he
went up
with his
people, yea,
captains,
and chief
yea, at the
head of
his armies,
against
the Amlicites to battle.
17 And
they began
to slay
the
Amlicites upon
the hill
east of
Sidon. And
the
Amlicites did
contend
with the
Nephites
with
great
strength,
insomuch that
many of
the
Nephites did
fall before the Amlicites.
Nevertheless
the Lord
did
strengthen the
hand of
the
Nephites, that
they slew
the
Amlicites with
great
slaughter,
that they
began to
flee
before them.
19 And
it came
to pass
that the
Nephites
did
pursue the
Amlicites all
that day,
and did
slay
them with
much
slaughter,
insomuch
that
there were
slain of
the
Amlicites
twelve
thousand
five
hundred
thirty and
two
souls; and
there were
slain
of the
Nephites
six
thousand five hundred sixty and two souls.
20 And
it came
to pass
that when
Alma
could
pursue the
Amlicites
no
longer he
caused
that his
people
should
pitch their
tents in
the
valley of
Gideon,
the
valley being
called
after
that Gideon
who was
slain
by the
hand of
Nehor with
the
sword; and
in this
valley
the
Nephites did
pitch
their
tents for
the night.
21 And
Alma
sent
spies to
follow
the
remnant of
Amlicites,
that he
might
know of
their
plans
and
their
plots,
whereby he
might
guard
himself
against
them,
that he
might
preserve
his people from being destroyed.
22 Now
those
whom
he had
sent
out to
watch
the
camp of
Amlicites
were
called
Zeram,
and
Amnor, and
Manti, and
Limher;
these were
they
who
went out
with
their
men to
watch the camp of the Amlicites.
23 And
it
came to
pass
that on
the
morrow
they
returned into
the
camp of
Nephites in
great
haste,
being
greatly
astonished, and
struck
with
much
fear,
saying:
Behold,
we
followed
the
camp of
Amlicites, and
to our
great
astonishment, in
the
land of
Minon,
above
the
land of
Zarahemla,
in the
course of
the
land of
Nephi,
we saw
a
numerous
host
of the
Lamanites;
and
behold,
the
Amlicites
have
joined
them;
And
they are
upon
our
brethren
in
that
land;
and
they are
fleeing
before
them
with
their
flocks,
and
their
wives, and
children,
towards
our
city;
and
except
we
make
haste
they
obtain
possession of
our
city,
and
our
fathers, and our wives, and our children be slain.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
people
of
Nephi
took
their
tents,
and
departed
out
of
the
valley
of
Gideon
towards
their
city, which was the city of Zarahemla.
And
behold,
as
they
were
crossing
the
river
Sidon,
the
Lamanites
and
the
Amlicites,
being
as
numerous
almost,
as
it
were,
as
the
sands of the sea, came upon them to destroy them.
Nevertheless,
the
Nephites
being
strengthened
by
the
hand
of
the
Lord,
having
prayed
mightily
to
him
that
he
would
deliver
them
out
of
the
hands
of
their
enemies,
therefore
the
Lord
did
hear their cries, and did strengthen them, and the Lamanites and the Amlicites did fall before them.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma
fought
with
Amlici
the
sword,
face
to
face;
and
they
did
contend
mightily,
one
with
another.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma,
being
a
man
of
God,
being
exercised
with
much
faith,
cried,
saying:
O
Lord,
have
mercy
and
spare
my
life,
that
I
may
be
an
instrument
in
thy
hands
to
save
and
preserve
this
people.
31 Now when Alma had said these words he contended again with Amlici; and he was strengthened, insomuch that he slew Amlici with the
Now
when
Alma
had
said
these
words
he
contended
again
with
Amlici;
and he was strengthened, insomuch that he slew Amlici with the sword.
32 And he also contended with the king of the Lamanites; but the king of the Lamanites fled back from before Alma and sent his guards to contend with
And
he
also
contended
with
the
king
of
the
Lamanites;
but
the
king
of
the
Lamanites
fled
back
from
before
Alma
and
sent
his
guards
to
contend
with
Alma.
33 But Alma, with his guards, contended with the guards of the king of the Lamanites until he slew and drove them
But
Alma,
with
his
guards,
contended
with
the
guards
of
the
king
of
the
Lamanites
until
he
slew
and
drove
them
back.
34 And thus he cleared the ground, or rather the bank, which was on the west of the river Sidon, throwing the bodies of the Lamanites who had been slain into the waters of Sidon, that thereby his people might have room to cross and contend with the Lamanites and the Amlicites on the west side of the river
And
thus
he
cleared
the
ground,
or
rather
the
bank,
which
was
on
the
west
of
the
river
Sidon,
throwing
the
bodies
of
the
Lamanites
who
had
been
slain
into
the
waters
of
Sidon,
that
thereby
his
people
might
have
room
to
cross
and
contend
with
the
Lamanites
and
the
Amlicites
on
the
west
side
of
the
river
Sidon.
35 And it came to pass that when they had all crossed the river Sidon that the Lamanites and the Amlicites began to flee before them, notwithstanding they were so numerous that they could not be
And
it
came
to
pass
that
when
they
had
all
crossed
the
river
Sidon
that
the
Lamanites
and
the
Amlicites
began
to
flee
before
them,
notwithstanding
they
were
so
numerous
that
they
could
not
be
numbered.
36 And they fled before the Nephites towards the wilderness which was west and north, away beyond the borders of the land; and the Nephites did pursue them with their might, and did slay
And
they
fled
before
the
Nephites
towards
the
wilderness
which
was
west
and
north,
away
beyond
the
borders
of
the
land;
and
the
Nephites
did
pursue
them
with
their
might,
and
did
slay
them.
37 Yea, they were met on every hand, and slain and driven, until they were scattered on the west, and on the north, until they had reached the wilderness, which was called Hermounts; and it was that part of the wilderness which was infested by wild and ravenous
Yea,
they
were
met
on
every
hand,
and
slain
driven,
until
they
were
scattered
on
the
west,
and
on
the
north,
until
they
had
reached
the
wilderness,
which
was
called
Hermounts;
and
it
was
that
part
of
the
wilderness
which
was
infested
by
wild
and
ravenous
beasts.
38 And it came to pass that many died in the wilderness of their wounds, and were devoured by those beasts and also the vultures of the air; and their bones have been found, and have been heaped up on the earth.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
many
died
in
the
wilderness
of
their
wounds,
and
were
devoured
by
those
beasts
and
also
the
vultures
of
the
air;
and
their
bones
have
been
found,
and
have
been
heaped
up
on
the
earth.