An account of the preaching of Aaron, and Muloki,
and their brethren, to the Lamanites. Comprising
chapters 21 through 25.Chapter 21 Aaron teaches the
Amalekites about Christ and His Atonement—Aaron
and his brethren are imprisoned in Middoni—After
their deliverance, they teach in the synagogues and
make many converts—Lamoni grants religious freedom
to the people in the land of Ishmael. About
90–77 B.C.
1 Now when Ammon and his brethren separated
themselves in the borders of the land of the Lamanites,
behold Aaron took his journey towards the land
which was called by the Lamanites, Jerusalem, calling
it after the land of their fathers’ nativity; and
it was away joining the borders of Mormon
2 Now the Lamanites and the Amalekites and the
people of Amulon had built a great city, which was
called Jerusalem
3 Now the Lamanites of themselves were
sufficiently hardened, but the Amalekites and the Amulonites
were still harder; therefore they did cause the
Lamanites that they should harden their hearts, that
they should wax strong in wickedness and their
abominations
4 And it came to pass that Aaron came to the city
of Jerusalem, and first began to preach to the
Amalekites. And he began to preach to them in their
synagogues, for they had built synagogues after the
order of the Nehors; for many of the Amalekites
and the Amulonites were after the order of the
Nehors
5 Therefore, as Aaron entered into one of their
synagogues to preach unto the people, and as he was
speaking unto them, behold there arose an
Amalekite and began to contend with him, saying: What is
that thou hast testified? Hast thou seen an angel?
Why do not angels appear unto us? Behold are not
this people as good as thy people
6 Thou also sayest, except we repent we shall
perish. How knowest thou the thought and intent of our
hearts? How knowest thou that we have cause to
repent? How knowest thou that we are not a righteous
people? Behold, we have built sanctuaries, and we
do assemble ourselves together to worship God. We
do believe that God will save all men
7 Now Aaron said unto him: Believest thou that the
Son of God shall come to redeem mankind from
their sins
8 And the man said unto him: We do not believe
that thou knowest any such thing. We do not believe
in these foolish traditions. We do not believe that
thou knowest of things to come, neither do we
believe that thy fathers and also that our fathers
did know concerning the things which they spake, of
that which is to come
9 Now Aaron began to open the scriptures unto them
concerning the coming of Christ, and also
concerning the resurrection of the dead, and that there
could be no redemption for mankind save it were
through the death and sufferings of Christ, and the
atonement of his blood
10 And it came to pass as he began to expound
these things unto them they were angry with him, and
began to mock him; and they would not hear the
words which he spake
11 Therefore, when he saw that they would not hear
his words, he departed out of their synagogue,
and came over to a village which was called
Ani-Anti, and there he found Muloki preaching the word
unto them; and also Ammah and his brethren. And they
contended with many about the word
12 And it came to pass that they saw that the
people would harden their hearts, therefore they
departed and came over into the land of Middoni. And
they did preach the word unto many, and few believed
on the words which they taught
13 Nevertheless, Aaron and a certain number of his
brethren were taken and cast into prison, and the
remainder of them fled out of the land of Middoni
unto the regions round about
14 And those who were cast into prison suffered
many things, and they were delivered by the hand of
Lamoni and Ammon, and they were fed and clothed
15 And they went forth again to declare the word,
and thus they were delivered for the first time
out of prison; and thus they had suffered
16 And they went forth whithersoever they were led
by the Spirit of the Lord, preaching the word of
God in every synagogue of the Amalekites, or in
every assembly of the Lamanites where they could be
admitted
17 And it came to pass that the Lord began to
bless them, insomuch that they brought many to the
knowledge of the truth; yea, they did convince many
of their sins, and of the traditions of their
fathers, which were not correct
18 And it came to pass that Ammon and Lamoni
returned from the land of Middoni to the land of
Ishmael, which was the land of their inheritance
19 And king Lamoni would not suffer that Ammon
should serve him, or be his servant
20 But he caused that there should be synagogues
built in the land of Ishmael; and he caused that
his people, or the people who were under his reign,
should assemble themselves together
21 And he did rejoice over them, and he did teach
them many things. And he did also declare unto
them that they were a people who were under him, and
that they were a free people, that they were free
from the oppressions of the king, his father; for
that his father had granted unto him that he might
reign over the people who were in the land of
Ishmael, and in all the land round about
22 And he also declared unto them that they might
have the liberty of worshiping the Lord their God
according to their desires, in whatsoever place
they were in, if it were in the land which was under
the reign of king Lamoni
23 And Ammon did preach unto the people of king
Lamoni; and it came to pass that he did teach them
all things concerning things pertaining to
righteousness. And he did exhort them daily, with all
diligence; and they gave heed unto his word, and they
were zealous for keeping the commandments of God.