Chapter 30 Korihor, the anti-Christ, ridicules
Christ, the Atonement, and the spirit of prophecy—He
teaches that there is no God, no fall of man, no
penalty for sin, and no Christ—Alma testifies that
Christ will come and that all things denote there
is a God—Korihor demands a sign and is struck
dumb—The devil had appeared to Korihor as an angel and
taught him what to say—Korihor is trodden down
and dies. About 76–74 B.C.
1 Behold, now it came to pass that after the
people of Ammon were established in the land of
Jershon, yea, and also after the Lamanites were driven
out of the land, and their dead were buried by the
people of the land
2 Now their dead were not numbered because of the
greatness of their numbers; neither were the dead
of the Nephites numbered—but it came to pass after
they had buried their dead, and also after the
days of fasting, and mourning, and prayer, (and it
was in the sixteenth year of the reign of the
judges over the people of Nephi) there began to be
continual peace throughout all the land
3 Yea, and the people did observe to keep the
commandments of the Lord; and they were strict in
observing the ordinances of God, according to the law
of Moses; for they were taught to keep the law of
Moses until it should be fulfilled
4 And thus the people did have no disturbance in
all the sixteenth year of the reign of the judges
over the people of Nephi
5 And it came to pass that in the commencement of
the seventeenth year of the reign of the judges,
there was continual peace
6 But it came to pass in the latter end of the
seventeenth year, there came a man into the land of
Zarahemla, and he was Anti-Christ, for he began to
preach unto the people against the prophecies
which had been spoken by the prophets, concerning the
coming of Christ
7 Now there was no law against a man’s belief; for
it was strictly contrary to the commands of God
that there should be a law which should bring men
on to unequal grounds
8 For thus saith the scripture: Choose ye this
day, whom ye will serve
9 Now if a man desired to serve God, it was his
privilege; or rather, if he believed in God it was
his privilege to serve him; but if he did not
believe in him there was no law to punish him
10 But if he murdered he was punished unto death;
and if he robbed he was also punished; and if he
stole he was also punished; and if he committed
adultery he was also punished; yea, for all this
wickedness they were punished
11 For there was a law that men should be judged
according to their crimes. Nevertheless, there was
no law against a man’s belief; therefore, a man
was punished only for the crimes which he had done;
therefore all men were on equal grounds
12 And this Anti-Christ, whose name was Korihor,
(and the law could have no hold upon him) began to
preach unto the people that there should be no
Christ. And after this manner did he preach, saying
13 O ye that are bound down under a foolish and a
vain hope, why do ye yoke yourselves with such
foolish things? Why do ye look for a Christ? For no
man can know of anything which is to come
14 Behold, these things which ye call prophecies,
which ye say are handed down by holy prophets,
behold, they are foolish traditions of your fathers
15 How do ye know of their surety? Behold, ye
cannot know of things which ye do not see; therefore
ye cannot know that there shall be a Christ
16 Ye look forward and say that ye see a remission
of your sins. But behold, it is the effect of a
frenzied mind; and this derangement of your minds
comes because of the traditions of your fathers,
which lead you away into a belief of things which
are not so
17 And many more such things did he say unto them,
telling them that there could be no atonement
made for the sins of men, but every man fared in this
life according to the management of the creature;
therefore every man prospered according to his
genius, and that every man conquered according to
his strength; and whatsoever a man did was no crime
18 And thus he did preach unto them, leading away
the hearts of many, causing them to lift up their
heads in their wickedness, yea, leading away many
women, and also men, to commit whoredoms—telling
them that when a man was dead, that was the end
thereof
19 Now this man went over to the land of Jershon
also, to preach these things among the people of
Ammon, who were once the people of the Lamanites
20 But behold they were more wise than many of the
Nephites; for they took him, and bound him, and
carried him before Ammon, who was a high priest
over that people
21 And it came to pass that he caused that he
should be carried out of the land. And he came over
into the land of Gideon, and began to preach unto
them also; and here he did not have much success,
for he was taken and bound and carried before the
high priest, and also the chief judge over the land
22 And it came to pass that the high priest said
unto him: Why do ye go about perverting the ways of
the Lord? Why do ye teach this people that there
shall be no Christ, to interrupt their rejoicings?
Why do ye speak against all the prophecies of the
holy prophets
23 Now the high priest’s name was Giddonah. And
Korihor said unto him: Because I do not teach the
foolish traditions of your fathers, and because I do
not teach this people to bind themselves down
under the foolish ordinances and performances which
are laid down by ancient priests, to usurp power
and authority over them, to keep them in ignorance,
that they may not lift up their heads, but be
brought down according to thy words
24 Ye say that this people is a free people.
Behold, I say they are in bondage. Ye say that those
ancient prophecies are true. Behold, I say that ye
do not know that they are true
25 Ye say that this people is a guilty and a
fallen people, because of the transgression of a
parent. Behold, I say that a child is not guilty because
of its parents
26 And ye also say that Christ shall come. But
behold, I say that ye do not know that there shall be
a Christ. And ye say also that he shall be slain
for the sins of the world
27 And thus ye lead away this people after the
foolish traditions of your fathers, and according to
your own desires; and ye keep them down, even as
it were in bondage, that ye may glut yourselves
with the labors of their hands, that they durst not
look up with boldness, and that they durst not
enjoy their rights and privileges
28 Yea, they durst not make use of that which is
their own lest they should offend their priests,
who do yoke them according to their desires, and
have brought them to believe, by their traditions and
their dreams and their whims and their visions
and their pretended mysteries, that they should, if
they did not do according to their words, offend
some unknown being, who they say is God—a being who
never has been seen or known, who never was nor
ever will be
29 Now when the high priest and the chief judge
saw the hardness of his heart, yea, when they saw
that he would revile even against God, they would
not make any reply to his words; but they caused
that he should be bound; and they delivered him up
into the hands of the officers, and sent him to the
land of Zarahemla, that he might be brought before
Alma, and the chief judge who was governor over
all the land
30 And it came to pass that when he was brought
before Alma and the chief judge, he did go on in the
same manner as he did in the land of Gideon; yea,
he went on to blaspheme
31 And he did rise up in great swelling words
before Alma, and did revile against the priests and
teachers, accusing them of leading away the people
after the silly traditions of their fathers, for
the sake of glutting on the labors of the people
32 Now Alma said unto him: Thou knowest that we do
not glut ourselves upon the labors of this
people; for behold I have labored even from the
commencement of the reign of the judges until now, with
mine own hands for my support, notwithstanding my
many travels round about the land to declare the
word of God unto my people
33 And notwithstanding the many labors which I
have performed in the church, I have never received
so much as even one senine for my labor; neither
has any of my brethren, save it were in the
judgment-seat; and then we have received only according to
law for our time
36 And Korihor answered him, Yea
37 And then Alma said unto him: Believest thou
that there is a God
38 And he answered, Nay
39 Now Alma said unto him: Will ye deny again that
there is a God, and also deny the Christ? For
behold, I say unto you, I know there is a God, and
also that Christ shall come
40 And now what evidence have ye that there is no
God, or that Christ cometh not? I say unto you
that ye have none, save it be your word only
41 But, behold, I have all things as a testimony
that these things are true; and ye also have all
things as a testimony unto you that they are true;
and will ye deny them? Believest thou that these
things are true
42 Behold, I know that thou believest, but thou
art possessed with a lying spirit, and ye have put
off the Spirit of God that it may have no place in
you; but the devil has power over you, and he doth
carry you about, working devices that he may
destroy the children of God
43 And now Korihor said unto Alma: If thou wilt
show me a sign, that I may be convinced that there
is a God, yea, show unto me that he hath power, and
then will I be convinced of the truth of thy
words
44 But Alma said unto him: Thou hast had signs
enough; will ye tempt your God? Will ye say, Show
unto me a sign, when ye have the testimony of all
these thy brethren, and also all the holy prophets?
The scriptures are laid before thee, yea, and all
things denote there is a God; yea, even the earth,
and all things that are upon the face of it, yea,
and its motion, yea, and also all the planets
which move in their regular form do witness that there
is a Supreme Creator
45 And yet do ye go about, leading away the hearts
of this people, testifying unto them there is no
God? And yet will ye deny against all these
witnesses? And he said: Yea, I will deny, except ye
shall show me a sign
46 And now it came to pass that Alma said unto
him: Behold, I am grieved because of the hardness of
your heart, yea, that ye will still resist the
spirit of the truth, that thy soul may be destroyed
47 But behold, it is better that thy soul should
be lost than that thou shouldst be the means of
bringing many souls down to destruction, by thy lying
and by thy flattering words; therefore if thou
shalt deny again, behold God shall smite thee, that
thou shalt become dumb, that thou shalt never open
thy mouth any more, that thou shalt not deceive
this people any more
48 Now Korihor said unto him: I do not deny the
existence of a God, but I do not believe that there
is a God; and I say also, that ye do not know that
there is a God; and except ye show me a sign, I
will not believe
49 Now Alma said unto him: This will I give unto
thee for a sign, that thou shalt be struck dumb,
according to my words; and I say, that in the name
of God, ye shall be struck dumb, that ye shall no
more have utterance
50 Now when Alma had said these words, Korihor was
struck dumb, that he could not have utterance,
according to the words of Alma
51 And now when the chief judge saw this, he put
forth his hand and wrote unto Korihor, saying: Art
thou convinced of the power of God? In whom did ye
desire that Alma should show forth his sign?
Would ye that he should afflict others, to show unto
thee a sign? Behold, he has showed unto you a sign;
and now will ye dispute more
52 And Korihor put forth his hand and wrote,
saying: I know that I am dumb, for I cannot speak; and
I know that nothing save it were the power of God
could bring this upon me; yea, and I always knew
that there was a God
53 But behold, the devil hath deceived me; for he
appeared unto me in the form of an angel, and said
unto me: Go and reclaim this people, for they
have all gone astray after an unknown God. And he
said unto me: There is no God; yea, and he taught me
that which I should say. And I have taught his
words; and I taught them because they were pleasing
unto the carnal mind; and I taught them, even until
I had much success, insomuch that I verily
believed that they were true; and for this cause I
withstood the truth, even until I have brought this
great curse upon me
54 Now when he had said this, he besought that
Alma should pray unto God, that the curse might be
taken from him
55 But Alma said unto him: If this curse should be
taken from thee thou wouldst again lead away the
hearts of this people; therefore, it shall be unto
thee even as the Lord will
56 And it came to pass that the curse was not
taken off of Korihor; but he was cast out, and went
about from house to house begging for his food
57 Now the knowledge of what had happened unto
Korihor was immediately published throughout all the
land; yea, the proclamation was sent forth by the
chief judge to all the people in the land,
declaring unto those who had believed in the words of
Korihor that they must speedily repent, lest the same
judgments would come unto them
58 And it came to pass that they were all
convinced of the wickedness of Korihor; therefore they
were all converted again unto the Lord; and this put
an end to the iniquity after the manner of
Korihor. And Korihor did go about from house to house,
begging food for his support
59 And it came to pass that as he went forth among
the people, yea, among a people who had separated
themselves from the Nephites and called
themselves Zoramites, being led by a man whose name was
Zoram—and as he went forth amongst them, behold, he
was run upon and trodden down, even until he was
dead
60 And thus we see the end of him who perverteth
the ways of the Lord; and thus we see that the
devil will not support his children at the last day,
but doth speedily drag them down to hell.