Chapter 3 The Amlicites had marked themselves
according to the prophetic word—The Lamanites had been
cursed for their rebellion—Men bring their own
curses upon themselves—The Nephites defeat another
Lamanite army. About 87–86 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that the Nephites who were
not slain by the weapons of war, after having
buried those who had been slain—now the number of the
slain were not numbered, because of the greatness
of their number—after they had finished burying
their dead they all returned to their lands, and to
their houses, and their wives, and their children
2 Now many women and children had been slain with
the sword, and also many of their flocks and their
herds; and also many of their fields of grain
were destroyed, for they were trodden down by the
hosts of men
3 And now as many of the Lamanites and the
Amlicites who had been slain upon the bank of the river
Sidon were cast into the waters of Sidon; and
behold their bones are in the depths of the sea, and
they are many
4 And the Amlicites were distinguished from the
Nephites, for they had marked themselves with red in
their foreheads after the manner of the
Lamanites; nevertheless they had not shorn their heads like
unto the Lamanites
5 Now the heads of the Lamanites were shorn; and
they were naked, save it were skin which was girded
about their loins, and also their armor, which
was girded about them, and their bows, and their
arrows, and their stones, and their slings, and so
forth
6 And the skins of the Lamanites were dark,
according to the mark which was set upon their fathers,
which was a curse upon them because of their
transgression and their rebellion against their
brethren, who consisted of Nephi, Jacob, and Joseph, and
Sam, who were just and holy men
7 And their brethren sought to destroy them,
therefore they were cursed; and the Lord God set a mark
upon them, yea, upon Laman and Lemuel, and also
the sons of Ishmael, and Ishmaelitish women
8 And this was done that their seed might be
distinguished from the seed of their brethren, that
thereby the Lord God might preserve his people, that
they might not mix and believe in incorrect
traditions which would prove their destruction
9 And it came to pass that whosoever did mingle
his seed with that of the Lamanites did bring the
same curse upon his seed
10 Therefore, whosoever suffered himself to be led
away by the Lamanites was called under that head,
and there was a mark set upon him
11 And it came to pass that whosoever would not
believe in the tradition of the Lamanites, but
believed those records which were brought out of the
land of Jerusalem, and also in the tradition of
their fathers, which were correct, who believed in the
commandments of God and kept them, were called
the Nephites, or the people of Nephi, from that time
forth
12 And it is they who have kept the records which
are true of their people, and also of the people
of the Lamanites
13 Now we will return again to the Amlicites, for
they also had a mark set upon them; yea, they set
the mark upon themselves, yea, even a mark of red
upon their foreheads
14 Thus the word of God is fulfilled, for these
are the words which he said to Nephi: Behold, the
Lamanites have I cursed, and I will set a mark on
them that they and their seed may be separated from
thee and thy seed, from this time henceforth and
forever, except they repent of their wickedness and
turn to me that I may have mercy upon them
15 And again: I will set a mark upon him that
mingleth his seed with thy brethren, that they may be
cursed also
16 And again: I will set a mark upon him that
fighteth against thee and thy seed
17 And again, I say he that departeth from thee
shall no more be called thy seed; and I will bless
thee, and whomsoever shall be called thy seed,
henceforth and forever; and these were the promises of
the Lord unto Nephi and to his seed
18 Now the Amlicites knew not that they were
fulfilling the words of God when they began to mark
themselves in their foreheads; nevertheless they had
come out in open rebellion against God; therefore
it was expedient that the curse should fall upon
them
19 Now I would that ye should see that they
brought upon themselves the curse; and even so doth
every man that is cursed bring upon himself his own
condemnation
20 Now it came to pass that not many days after
the battle which was fought in the land of
Zarahemla, by the Lamanites and the Amlicites, that there
was another army of the Lamanites came in upon the
people of Nephi, in the same place where the first
army met the Amlicites
21 And it came to pass that there was an army sent
to drive them out of their land
22 Now Alma himself being afflicted with a wound
did not go up to battle at this time against the
Lamanites
23 But he sent up a numerous army against them;
and they went up and slew many of the Lamanites, and
drove the remainder of them out of the borders of
their land
24 And then they returned again and began to
establish peace in the land, being troubled no more for
a time with their enemies
25 Now all these things were done, yea, all these
wars and contentions were commenced and ended in
the fifth year of the reign of the judges
26 And in one year were thousands and tens of
thousands of souls sent to the eternal world, that
they might reap their rewards according to their
works, whether they were good or whether they were
bad, to reap eternal happiness or eternal misery,
according to the spirit which they listed to obey,
whether it be a good spirit or a bad one
27 For every man receiveth wages of him whom he
listeth to obey, and this according to the words of
the spirit of prophecy; therefore let it be
according to the truth. And thus endeth the fifth year
of the reign of the judges.