The commandments of Alma to his son Helaman.
Comprising chapters 36 and 37.Chapter 36 Alma testifies
to Helaman of his conversion after seeing an
angel—He suffered the pains of a damned soul; he
called upon the name of Jesus, and was then born of
God—Sweet joy filled his soul—He saw concourses of
angels praising God—Many converts have tasted and
seen as he has tasted and seen. About 74 B.C.
1 My son, give ear to my words; for I swear unto
you, that inasmuch as ye shall keep the
commandments of God ye shall prosper in the land
2 I would that ye should do as I have done, in
remembering the captivity of our fathers; for they
were in bondage, and none could deliver them except
it was the God of Abraham, and the God of Isaac,
and the God of Jacob; and he surely did deliver
them in their afflictions
3 And now, O my son Helaman, behold, thou art in
thy youth, and therefore, I beseech of thee that
thou wilt hear my words and learn of me; for I do
know that whosoever shall put their trust in God
shall be supported in their trials, and their
troubles, and their afflictions, and shall be lifted up
at the last day
4 And I would not that ye think that I know of
myself—not of the temporal but of the spiritual, not
of the carnal mind but of God
5 Now, behold, I say unto you, if I had not been
born of God I should not have known these things;
but God has, by the mouth of his holy angel, made
these things known unto me, not of any worthiness
of myself
6 For I went about with the sons of Mosiah,
seeking to destroy the church of God; but behold, God
sent his holy angel to stop us by the way
7 And behold, he spake unto us, as it were the
voice of thunder, and the whole earth did tremble
beneath our feet; and we all fell to the earth, for
the fear of the Lord came upon us
8 But behold, the voice said unto me: Arise. And I
arose and stood up, and beheld the angel
9 And he said unto me: If thou wilt of thyself be
destroyed, seek no more to destroy the church of
God
10 And it came to pass that I fell to the earth;
and it was for the space of three days and three
nights that I could not open my mouth, neither had I
the use of my limbs
11 And the angel spake more things unto me, which
were heard by my brethren, but I did not hear
them; for when I heard the words—If thou wilt be
destroyed of thyself, seek no more to destroy the
church of God—I was struck with such great fear and
amazement lest perhaps I should be destroyed, that I
fell to the earth and I did hear no more
12 But I was racked with eternal torment, for my
soul was harrowed up to the greatest degree and
racked with all my sins
13 Yea, I did remember all my sins and iniquities,
for which I was tormented with the pains of hell;
yea, I saw that I had rebelled against my God,
and that I had not kept his holy commandments
16 And now, for three days and for three nights
was I racked, even with the pains of a damned soul
17 And it came to pass that as I was thus racked
with torment, while I was harrowed up by the memory
of my many sins, behold, I remembered also to
have heard my father prophesy unto the people
concerning the coming of one Jesus Christ, a Son of God,
to atone for the sins of the world
18 Now, as my mind caught hold upon this thought,
I cried within my heart: O Jesus, thou Son of God,
have mercy on me, who am in the gall of
bitterness, and am encircled about by the everlasting
chains of death
19 And now, behold, when I thought this, I could
remember my pains no more; yea, I was harrowed up
by the memory of my sins no more
20 And oh, what joy, and what marvelous light I
did behold; yea, my soul was filled with joy as
exceeding as was my pain
21 Yea, I say unto you, my son, that there could
be nothing so exquisite and so bitter as were my
pains. Yea, and again I say unto you, my son, that
on the other hand, there can be nothing so
exquisite and sweet as was my joy
22 Yea, methought I saw, even as our father Lehi
saw, God sitting upon his throne, surrounded with
numberless concourses of angels, in the attitude of
singing and praising their God; yea, and my soul
did long to be there
23 But behold, my limbs did receive their strength
again, and I stood upon my feet, and did manifest
unto the people that I had been born of God
24 Yea, and from that time even until now, I have
labored without ceasing, that I might bring souls
unto repentance; that I might bring them to taste
of the exceeding joy of which I did taste; that
they might also be born of God, and be filled with
the Holy Ghost
25 Yea, and now behold, O my son, the Lord doth
give me exceedingly great joy in the fruit of my
labors
26 For because of the word which he has imparted
unto me, behold, many have been born of God, and
have tasted as I have tasted, and have seen eye to
eye as I have seen; therefore they do know of these
things of which I have spoken, as I do know; and
the knowledge which I have is of God
27 And I have been supported under trials and
troubles of every kind, yea, and in all manner of
afflictions; yea, God has delivered me from prison,
and from bonds, and from death; yea, and I do put my
trust in him, and he will still deliver me
28 And I know that he will raise me up at the last
day, to dwell with him in glory; yea, and I will
praise him forever, for he has brought our fathers
out of Egypt, and he has swallowed up the
Egyptians in the Red Sea; and he led them by his power
into the promised land; yea, and he has delivered
them out of bondage and captivity from time to time
29 Yea, and he has also brought our fathers out of
the land of Jerusalem; and he has also, by his
everlasting power, delivered them out of bondage and
captivity, from time to time even down to the
present day; and I have always retained in
remembrance their captivity; yea, and ye also ought to
retain in remembrance, as I have done, their captivity
30 But behold, my son, this is not all; for ye
ought to know as I do know, that inasmuch as ye shall
keep the commandments of God ye shall prosper in
the land; and ye ought to know also, that inasmuch
as ye will not keep the commandments of God ye
shall be cut off from his presence. Now this is
according to his word.