Chapter 34 Amulek testifies that the word is in
Christ unto salvation—Unless an atonement is made,
all mankind must perish—The whole law of Moses
points toward the sacrifice of the Son of God—The
eternal plan of redemption is based on faith and
repentance—Pray for temporal and spiritual
blessings—This life is the time for men to prepare to meet
God—Work out your salvation with fear before God.
About 74 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that after Alma had
spoken these words unto them he sat down upon the
ground, and Amulek arose and began to teach them,
saying
2 My brethren, I think that it is impossible that
ye should be ignorant of the things which have
been spoken concerning the coming of Christ, who is
taught by us to be the Son of God; yea, I know that
these things were taught unto you bountifully
before your dissension from among us
3 And as ye have desired of my beloved brother
that he should make known unto you what ye should do,
because of your afflictions; and he hath spoken
somewhat unto you to prepare your minds; yea, and
he hath exhorted you unto faith and to patience
4 Yea, even that ye would have so much faith as
even to plant the word in your hearts, that ye may
try the experiment of its goodness
5 And we have beheld that the great question which
is in your minds is whether the word be in the
Son of God, or whether there shall be no Christ
6 And ye also beheld that my brother has proved
unto you, in many instances, that the word is in
Christ unto salvation
7 My brother has called upon the words of Zenos,
that redemption cometh through the Son of God, and
also upon the words of Zenock; and also he has
appealed unto Moses, to prove that these things are
true
8 And now, behold, I will testify unto you of
myself that these things are true. Behold, I say unto
you, that I do know that Christ shall come among
the children of men, to take upon him the
transgressions of his people, and that he shall atone for
the sins of the world; for the Lord God hath spoken
it
9 For it is expedient that an atonement should be
made; for according to the great plan of the
Eternal God there must be an atonement made, or else
all mankind must unavoidably perish; yea, all are
hardened; yea, all are fallen and are lost, and must
perish except it be through the atonement which
it is expedient should be made
10 For it is expedient that there should be a
great and last sacrifice; yea, not a sacrifice of man,
neither of beast, neither of any manner of fowl;
for it shall not be a human sacrifice; but it must
be an infinite and eternal sacrifice
11 Now there is not any man that can sacrifice his
own blood which will atone for the sins of
another. Now, if a man murdereth, behold will our law,
which is just, take the life of his brother? I say
unto you, Nay
12 But the law requireth the life of him who hath
murdered; therefore there can be nothing which is
short of an infinite atonement which will suffice
for the sins of the world
13 Therefore, it is expedient that there should be
a great and last sacrifice, and then shall there
be, or it is expedient there should be, a stop to
the shedding of blood; then shall the law of Moses
be fulfilled; yea, it shall be all fulfilled,
every jot and tittle, and none shall have passed
away
14 And behold, this is the whole meaning of the
law, every whit pointing to that great and last
sacrifice; and that great and last sacrifice will be
the Son of God, yea, infinite and eternal
15 And thus he shall bring salvation to all those
who shall believe on his name; this being the
intent of this last sacrifice, to bring about the
bowels of mercy, which overpowereth justice, and
bringeth about means unto men that they may have faith
unto repentance
16 And thus mercy can satisfy the demands of
justice, and encircles them in the arms of safety,
while he that exercises no faith unto repentance is
exposed to the whole law of the demands of justice;
therefore only unto him that has faith unto
repentance is brought about the great and eternal plan
of redemption
17 Therefore may God grant unto you, my brethren,
that ye may begin to exercise your faith unto
repentance, that ye begin to call upon his holy name,
that he would have mercy upon you
18 Yea, cry unto him for mercy; for he is mighty
to save
19 Yea, humble yourselves, and continue in prayer
unto him
20 Cry unto him when ye are in your fields, yea,
over all your flocks
21 Cry unto him in your houses, yea, over all your
household, both morning, mid-day, and evening
22 Yea, cry unto him against the power of your
enemies
23 Yea, cry unto him against the devil, who is an
enemy to all righteousness
24 Cry unto him over the crops of your fields,
that ye may prosper in them
25 Cry over the flocks of your fields, that they
may increase
26 But this is not all; ye must pour out your
souls in your closets, and your secret places, and in
your wilderness
27 Yea, and when you do not cry unto the Lord, let
your hearts be full, drawn out in prayer unto him
continually for your welfare, and also for the
welfare of those who are around you
28 And now behold, my beloved brethren, I say unto
you, do not suppose that this is all; for after
ye have done all these things, if ye turn away the
needy, and the naked, and visit not the sick and
afflicted, and impart of your substance, if ye
have, to those who stand in need—I say unto you, if ye
do not any of these things, behold, your prayer
is vain, and availeth you nothing, and ye are as
hypocrites who do deny the faith
29 Therefore, if ye do not remember to be
charitable, ye are as dross, which the refiners do cast
out, (it being of no worth) and is trodden under
foot of men
30 And now, my brethren, I would that, after ye
have received so many witnesses, seeing that the
holy scriptures testify of these things, ye come
forth and bring fruit unto repentance
31 Yea, I would that ye would come forth and
harden not your hearts any longer; for behold, now is
the time and the day of your salvation; and
therefore, if ye will repent and harden not your hearts,
immediately shall the great plan of redemption be
brought about unto you
32 For behold, this life is the time for men to
prepare to meet God; yea, behold the day of this
life is the day for men to perform their labors
33 And now, as I said unto you before, as ye have
had so many witnesses, therefore, I beseech of you
that ye do not procrastinate the day of your
repentance until the end; for after this day of life,
which is given us to prepare for eternity, behold,
if we do not improve our time while in this life,
then cometh the night of darkness wherein there
can be no labor performed
34 Ye cannot say, when ye are brought to that
awful crisis, that I will repent, that I will return
to my God. Nay, ye cannot say this; for that same
spirit which doth possess your bodies at the time
that ye go out of this life, that same spirit will
have power to possess your body in that eternal
world
35 For behold, if ye have procrastinated the day
of your repentance even until death, behold, ye
have become subjected to the spirit of the devil, and
he doth seal you his; therefore, the Spirit of
the Lord hath withdrawn from you, and hath no place
in you, and the devil hath all power over you; and
this is the final state of the wicked
38 That ye contend no more against the Holy Ghost,
but that ye receive it, and take upon you the
name of Christ; that ye humble yourselves even to the
dust, and worship God, in whatsoever place ye may
be in, in spirit and in truth; and that ye live
in thanksgiving daily, for the many mercies and
blessings which he doth bestow upon you
39 Yea, and I also exhort you, my brethren, that
ye be watchful unto prayer continually, that ye may
not be led away by the temptations of the devil,
that he may not overpower you, that ye may not
become his subjects at the last day; for behold, he
rewardeth you no good thing
40 And now my beloved brethren, I would exhort you
to have patience, and that ye bear with all
manner of afflictions; that ye do not revile against
those who do cast you out because of your exceeding
poverty, lest ye become sinners like unto them
41 But that ye have patience, and bear with those
afflictions, with a firm hope that ye shall one
day rest from all your afflictions.