Chapter 33 Zenos taught that men should pray and
worship in all places, and that judgments are
turned away because of the Son—Zenock taught that mercy
is bestowed because of the Son—Moses had lifted
up in the wilderness a type of the Son of God.
About 74 B.C.
1 Now after Alma had spoken these words, they sent
forth unto him desiring to know whether they
should believe in one God, that they might obtain this
fruit of which he had spoken, or how they should
plant the seed, or the word of which he had
spoken, which he said must be planted in their hearts;
or in what manner they should begin to exercise
their faith
2 And Alma said unto them: Behold, ye have said
that ye could not worship your God because ye are
cast out of your synagogues. But behold, I say unto
you, if ye suppose that ye cannot worship God, ye
do greatly err, and ye ought to search the
scriptures; if ye suppose that they have taught you this,
ye do not understand them
3 Do ye remember to have read what Zenos, the
prophet of old, has said concerning prayer or worship
4 For he said: Thou art merciful, O God, for thou
hast heard my prayer, even when I was in the
wilderness; yea, thou wast merciful when I prayed
concerning those who were mine enemies, and thou didst
turn them to me
5 Yea, O God, and thou wast merciful unto me when
I did cry unto thee in my field; when I did cry
unto thee in my prayer, and thou didst hear me
6 And again, O God, when I did turn to my house
thou didst hear me in my prayer
7 And when I did turn unto my closet, O Lord, and
prayed unto thee, thou didst hear me
8 Yea, thou art merciful unto thy children when
they cry unto thee, to be heard of thee and not of
men, and thou wilt hear them
9 Yea, O God, thou hast been merciful unto me, and
heard my cries in the midst of thy congregations
12 And now Alma said unto them: Do ye believe
those scriptures which have been written by them of
old
13 Behold, if ye do, ye must believe what Zenos
said; for, behold he said: Thou hast turned away thy
judgments because of thy Son
14 Now behold, my brethren, I would ask if ye have
read the scriptures? If ye have, how can ye
disbelieve on the Son of God
15 For it is not written that Zenos alone spake of
these things, but Zenock also spake of these
things
16 For behold, he said: Thou art angry, O Lord,
with this people, because they will not understand
thy mercies which thou hast bestowed upon them
because of thy Son
17 And now, my brethren, ye see that a second
prophet of old has testified of the Son of God, and
because the people would not understand his words
they stoned him to death
18 But behold, this is not all; these are not the
only ones who have spoken concerning the Son of
God
21 O my brethren, if ye could be healed by merely
casting about your eyes that ye might be healed,
would ye not behold quickly, or would ye rather
harden your hearts in unbelief, and be slothful, that
ye would not cast about your eyes, that ye might
perish
22 If so, wo shall come upon you; but if not so,
then cast about your eyes and begin to believe in
the Son of God, that he will come to redeem his
people, and that he shall suffer and die to atone for
their sins; and that he shall rise again from the
dead, which shall bring to pass the resurrection,
that all men shall stand before him, to be judged
at the last and judgment day, according to their
works
23 And now, my brethren, I desire that ye shall
plant this word in your hearts, and as it beginneth
to swell even so nourish it by your faith. And
behold, it will become a tree, springing up in you
unto everlasting life. And then may God grant unto
you that your burdens may be light, through the joy
of his Son. And even all this can ye do if ye
will. Amen.