Chapter 31 Alma heads a mission to reclaim the
apostate Zoramites—The Zoramites deny Christ, believe
in a false concept of election, and worship with
set prayers—The missionaries are filled with the
Holy Spirit—Their afflictions are swallowed up in
the joy of Christ. About 74 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that after the end of
Korihor, Alma having received tidings that the Zoramites
were perverting the ways of the Lord, and that
Zoram, who was their leader, was leading the hearts
of the people to bow down to dumb idols, his heart
again began to sicken because of the iniquity of
the people
2 For it was the cause of great sorrow to Alma to
know of iniquity among his people; therefore his
heart was exceedingly sorrowful because of the
separation of the Zoramites from the Nephites
3 Now the Zoramites had gathered themselves
together in a land which they called Antionum, which was
east of the land of Zarahemla, which lay nearly
bordering upon the seashore, which was south of the
land of Jershon, which also bordered upon the
wilderness south, which wilderness was full of the
Lamanites
4 Now the Nephites greatly feared that the
Zoramites would enter into a correspondence with the
Lamanites, and that it would be the means of great
loss on the part of the Nephites
5 And now, as the preaching of the word had a
great tendency to lead the people to do that which was
just—yea, it had had more powerful effect upon
the minds of the people than the sword, or anything
else, which had happened unto them—therefore Alma
thought it was expedient that they should try the
virtue of the word of God
6 Therefore he took Ammon, and Aaron, and Omner;
and Himni he did leave in the church in Zarahemla;
but the former three he took with him, and also
Amulek and Zeezrom, who were at Melek; and he also
took two of his sons
7 Now the eldest of his sons he took not with him,
and his name was Helaman; but the names of those
whom he took with him were Shiblon and Corianton;
and these are the names of those who went with him
among the Zoramites, to preach unto them the
word
8 Now the Zoramites were dissenters from the
Nephites; therefore they had had the word of God
preached unto them
9 But they had fallen into great errors, for they
would not observe to keep the commandments of God,
and his statutes, according to the law of Moses
10 Neither would they observe the performances of
the church, to continue in prayer and supplication
to God daily, that they might not enter into
temptation
11 Yea, in fine, they did pervert the ways of the
Lord in very many instances; therefore, for this
cause, Alma and his brethren went into the land to
preach the word unto them
12 Now, when they had come into the land, behold,
to their astonishment they found that the
Zoramites had built synagogues, and that they did gather
themselves together on one day of the week, which
day they did call the day of the Lord; and they did
worship after a manner which Alma and his
brethren had never beheld
13 For they had a place built up in the center of
their synagogue, a place for standing, which was
high above the head; and the top thereof would only
admit one person
16 Holy God, we believe that thou hast separated
us from our brethren; and we do not believe in the
tradition of our brethren, which was handed down
to them by the childishness of their fathers; but
we believe that thou hast elected us to be thy holy
children; and also thou hast made it known unto
us that there shall be no Christ
17 But thou art the same yesterday, today, and
forever; and thou hast elected us that we shall be
saved, whilst all around us are elected to be cast
by thy wrath down to hell; for the which holiness,
O God, we thank thee; and we also thank thee that
thou hast elected us, that we may not be led away
after the foolish traditions of our brethren,
which doth bind them down to a belief of Christ, which
doth lead their hearts to wander far from thee,
our God
18 And again we thank thee, O God, that we are a
chosen and a holy people. Amen
19 Now it came to pass that after Alma and his
brethren and his sons had heard these prayers, they
were astonished beyond all measure
20 For behold, every man did go forth and offer up
these same prayers
21 Now the place was called by them Rameumptom,
which, being interpreted, is the holy stand
22 Now, from this stand they did offer up, every
man, the selfsame prayer unto God, thanking their
God that they were chosen of him, and that he did
not lead them away after the tradition of their
brethren, and that their hearts were not stolen away
to believe in things to come, which they knew
nothing about
23 Now, after the people had all offered up thanks
after this manner, they returned to their homes,
never speaking of their God again until they had
assembled themselves together again to the holy
stand, to offer up thanks after their manner
24 Now when Alma saw this his heart was grieved;
for he saw that they were a wicked and a perverse
people; yea, he saw that their hearts were set upon
gold, and upon silver, and upon all manner of
fine goods
25 Yea, and he also saw that their hearts were
lifted up unto great boasting, in their pride
26 And he lifted up his voice to heaven, and
cried, saying: O, how long, O Lord, wilt thou suffer
that thy servants shall dwell here below in the
flesh, to behold such gross wickedness among the
children of men
27 Behold, O God, they cry unto thee, and yet
their hearts are swallowed up in their pride. Behold,
O God, they cry unto thee with their mouths, while
they are puffed up, even to greatness, with the
vain things of the world
28 Behold, O my God, their costly apparel, and
their ringlets, and their bracelets, and their
ornaments of gold, and all their precious things which
they are ornamented with; and behold, their hearts
are set upon them, and yet they cry unto thee and
say—We thank thee, O God, for we are a chosen
people unto thee, while others shall perish
31 O Lord, my heart is exceedingly sorrowful; wilt
thou comfort my soul in Christ. O Lord, wilt thou
grant unto me that I may have strength, that I
may suffer with patience these afflictions which
shall come upon me, because of the iniquity of this
people
32 O Lord, wilt thou comfort my soul, and give
unto me success, and also my fellow laborers who are
with me—yea, Ammon, and Aaron, and Omner, and also
Amulek and Zeezrom, and also my two sons—yea,
even all these wilt thou comfort, O Lord. Yea, wilt
thou comfort their souls in Christ
33 Wilt thou grant unto them that they may have
strength, that they may bear their afflictions which
shall come upon them because of the iniquities of
this people
34 O Lord, wilt thou grant unto us that we may
have success in bringing them again unto thee in
Christ
35 Behold, O Lord, their souls are precious, and
many of them are our brethren; therefore, give unto
us, O Lord, power and wisdom that we may bring
these, our brethren, again unto thee
36 Now it came to pass that when Alma had said
these words, that he clapped his hands upon all them
who were with him. And behold, as he clapped his
hands upon them, they were filled with the Holy
Spirit
37 And after that they did separate themselves one
from another, taking no thought for themselves
what they should eat, or what they should drink, or
what they should put on
38 And the Lord provided for them that they should
hunger not, neither should they thirst; yea, and
he also gave them strength, that they should
suffer no manner of afflictions, save it were swallowed
up in the joy of Christ. Now this was according
to the prayer of Alma; and this because he prayed
in faith.