Chapter 37 The plates of brass and other
scriptures are preserved to bring souls to salvation—The
Jaredites were destroyed because of their
wickedness—Their secret oaths and covenants must be kept
from the people—Counsel with the Lord in all your
doings—As the Liahona guided the Nephites, so the
word of Christ leads men to eternal life. About
74 B.C.
1 And now, my son Helaman, I command you that ye
take the records which have been entrusted with me
2 And I also command you that ye keep a record of
this people, according as I have done, upon the
plates of Nephi, and keep all these things sacred
which I have kept, even as I have kept them; for it
is for a wise purpose that they are kept
3 And these plates of brass, which contain these
engravings, which have the records of the holy
scriptures upon them, which have the genealogy of our
forefathers, even from the beginning
4 Behold, it has been prophesied by our fathers,
that they should be kept and handed down from one
generation to another, and be kept and preserved by
the hand of the Lord until they should go forth
unto every nation, kindred, tongue, and people,
that they shall know of the mysteries contained
thereon
5 And now behold, if they are kept they must
retain their brightness; yea, and they will retain
their brightness; yea, and also shall all the plates
which do contain that which is holy writ
6 Now ye may suppose that this is foolishness in
me; but behold I say unto you, that by small and
simple things are great things brought to pass; and
small means in many instances doth confound the
wise
7 And the Lord God doth work by means to bring
about his great and eternal purposes; and by very
small means the Lord doth confound the wise and
bringeth about the salvation of many souls
8 And now, it has hitherto been wisdom in God that
these things should be preserved; for behold,
they have enlarged the memory of this people, yea,
and convinced many of the error of their ways, and
brought them to the knowledge of their God unto the
salvation of their souls
9 Yea, I say unto you, were it not for these
things that these records do contain, which are on
these plates, Ammon and his brethren could not have
convinced so many thousands of the Lamanites of the
incorrect tradition of their fathers; yea, these
records and their words brought them unto
repentance; that is, they brought them to the knowledge of
the Lord their God, and to rejoice in Jesus Christ
their Redeemer
10 And who knoweth but what they will be the means
of bringing many thousands of them, yea, and also
many thousands of our stiffnecked brethren, the
Nephites, who are now hardening their hearts in sin
and iniquities, to the knowledge of their
Redeemer
11 Now these mysteries are not yet fully made
known unto me; therefore I shall forbear
12 And it may suffice if I only say they are
preserved for a wise purpose, which purpose is known
unto God; for he doth counsel in wisdom over all his
works, and his paths are straight, and his course
is one eternal round
13 O remember, remember, my son Helaman, how
strict are the commandments of God. And he said: If ye
will keep my commandments ye shall prosper in the
land—but if ye keep not his commandments ye shall
be cut off from his presence
14 And now remember, my son, that God has
entrusted you with these things, which are sacred, which
he has kept sacred, and also which he will keep and
preserve for a wise purpose in him, that he may
show forth his power unto future generations
15 And now behold, I tell you by the spirit of
prophecy, that if ye transgress the commandments of
God, behold, these things which are sacred shall be
taken away from you by the power of God, and ye
shall be delivered up unto Satan, that he may sift
you as chaff before the wind
18 For he promised unto them that he would
preserve these things for a wise purpose in him, that he
might show forth his power unto future
generations
19 And now behold, one purpose hath he fulfilled,
even to the restoration of many thousands of the
Lamanites to the knowledge of the truth; and he
hath shown forth his power in them, and he will also
still show forth his power in them unto future
generations; therefore they shall be preserved
20 Therefore I command you, my son Helaman, that
ye be diligent in fulfilling all my words, and that
ye be diligent in keeping the commandments of God
as they are written
21 And now, I will speak unto you concerning those
twenty-four plates, that ye keep them, that the
mysteries and the works of darkness, and their
secret works, or the secret works of those people who
have been destroyed, may be made manifest unto
this people; yea, all their murders, and robbings,
and their plunderings, and all their wickedness and
abominations, may be made manifest unto this
people; yea, and that ye preserve these interpreters
22 For behold, the Lord saw that his people began
to work in darkness, yea, work secret murders and
abominations; therefore the Lord said, if they did
not repent they should be destroyed from off the
face of the earth
23 And the Lord said: I will prepare unto my
servant Gazelem, a stone, which shall shine forth in
darkness unto light, that I may discover unto my
people who serve me, that I may discover unto them
the works of their brethren, yea, their secret
works, their works of darkness, and their wickedness
and abominations
24 And now, my son, these interpreters were
prepared that the word of God might be fulfilled, which
he spake, saying
25 I will bring forth out of darkness unto light
all their secret works and their abominations; and
except they repent I will destroy them from off
the face of the earth; and I will bring to light all
their secrets and abominations, unto every nation
that shall hereafter possess the land
26 And now, my son, we see that they did not
repent; therefore they have been destroyed, and thus
far the word of God has been fulfilled; yea, their
secret abominations have been brought out of
darkness and made known unto us
27 And now, my son, I command you that ye retain
all their oaths, and their covenants, and their
agreements in their secret abominations; yea, and all
their signs and their wonders ye shall keep from
this people, that they know them not, lest
peradventure they should fall into darkness also and be
destroyed
28 For behold, there is a curse upon all this
land, that destruction shall come upon all those
workers of darkness, according to the power of God,
when they are fully ripe; therefore I desire that
this people might not be destroyed
29 Therefore ye shall keep these secret plans of
their oaths and their covenants from this people,
and only their wickedness and their murders and
their abominations shall ye make known unto them; and
ye shall teach them to abhor such wickedness and
abominations and murders; and ye shall also teach
them that these people were destroyed on account
of their wickedness and abominations and their
murders
30 For behold, they murdered all the prophets of
the Lord who came among them to declare unto them
concerning their iniquities; and the blood of those
whom they murdered did cry unto the Lord their
God for vengeance upon those who were their
murderers; and thus the judgments of God did come upon
these workers of darkness and secret combinations
31 Yea, and cursed be the land forever and ever
unto those workers of darkness and secret
combinations, even unto destruction, except they repent
before they are fully ripe
32 And now, my son, remember the words which I
have spoken unto you; trust not those secret plans
unto this people, but teach them an everlasting
hatred against sin and iniquity
35 O, remember, my son, and learn wisdom in thy
youth; yea, learn in thy youth to keep the
commandments of God
36 Yea, and cry unto God for all thy support; yea,
let all thy doings be unto the Lord, and
whithersoever thou goest let it be in the Lord; yea, let
all thy thoughts be directed unto the Lord; yea,
let the affections of thy heart be placed upon the
Lord forever
37 Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he
will direct thee for good; yea, when thou liest
down at night lie down unto the Lord, that he may
watch over you in your sleep; and when thou risest
in the morning let thy heart be full of thanks
unto God; and if ye do these things, ye shall be
lifted up at the last day
38 And now, my son, I have somewhat to say
concerning the thing which our fathers call a ball, or
director—or our fathers called it Liahona, which is,
being interpreted, a compass; and the Lord
prepared it
39 And behold, there cannot any man work after the
manner of so curious a workmanship. And behold,
it was prepared to show unto our fathers the course
which they should travel in the wilderness
40 And it did work for them according to their
faith in God; therefore, if they had faith to believe
that God could cause that those spindles should
point the way they should go, behold, it was done;
therefore they had this miracle, and also many
other miracles wrought by the power of God, day by
day
41 Nevertheless, because those miracles were
worked by small means it did show unto them marvelous
works. They were slothful, and forgot to exercise
their faith and diligence and then those marvelous
works ceased, and they did not progress in their
journey
42 Therefore, they tarried in the wilderness, or
did not travel a direct course, and were afflicted
with hunger and thirst, because of their
transgressions
43 And now, my son, I would that ye should
understand that these things are not without a shadow;
for as our fathers were slothful to give heed to
this compass (now these things were temporal) they
did not prosper; even so it is with things which are
spiritual
44 For behold, it is as easy to give heed to the
word of Christ, which will point to you a straight
course to eternal bliss, as it was for our fathers
to give heed to this compass, which would point
unto them a straight course to the promised land
45 And now I say, is there not a type in this
thing? For just as surely as this director did bring
our fathers, by following its course, to the
promised land, shall the words of Christ, if we follow
their course, carry us beyond this vale of sorrow
into a far better land of promise
46 O my son, do not let us be slothful because of
the easiness of the way; for so was it with our
fathers; for so was it prepared for them, that if
they would look they might live; even so it is with
us. The way is prepared, and if we will look we
may live forever
47 And now, my son, see that ye take care of these
sacred things, yea, see that ye look to God and
live. Go unto this people and declare the word, and
be sober. My son, farewell.