Chapter 32 Alma teaches the poor whose afflictions
had humbled them—Faith is a hope in that which is
not seen which is true—Alma testifies that angels
minister to men, women, and children—Alma
compares the word unto a seed—It must be planted and
nourished—Then it grows into a tree from which the
fruit of eternal life is picked. About 74 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that they did go forth, and
began to preach the word of God unto the people,
entering into their synagogues, and into their
houses; yea, and even they did preach the word in
their streets
2 And it came to pass that after much labor among
them, they began to have success among the poor
class of people; for behold, they were cast out of
the synagogues because of the coarseness of their
apparel
3 Therefore they were not permitted to enter into
their synagogues to worship God, being esteemed as
filthiness; therefore they were poor; yea, they
were esteemed by their brethren as dross; therefore
they were poor as to things of the world; and
also they were poor in heart
4 Now, as Alma was teaching and speaking unto the
people upon the hill Onidah, there came a great
multitude unto him, who were those of whom we have
been speaking, of whom were poor in heart, because
of their poverty as to the things of the world
5 And they came unto Alma; and the one who was the
foremost among them said unto him: Behold, what
shall these my brethren do, for they are despised
of all men because of their poverty, yea, and more
especially by our priests; for they have cast us
out of our synagogues which we have labored
abundantly to build with our own hands; and they have
cast us out because of our exceeding poverty; and we
have no place to worship our God; and behold, what
shall we do
6 And now when Alma heard this, he turned him
about, his face immediately towards him, and he beheld
with great joy; for he beheld that their
afflictions had truly humbled them, and that they were in
a preparation to hear the word
7 Therefore he did say no more to the other
multitude; but he stretched forth his hand, and cried
unto those whom he beheld, who were truly penitent,
and said unto them
8 I behold that ye are lowly in heart; and if so,
blessed are ye
9 Behold thy brother hath said, What shall we
do?—for we are cast out of our synagogues, that we
cannot worship our God
10 Behold I say unto you, do ye suppose that ye
cannot worship God save it be in your synagogues
only
11 And moreover, I would ask, do ye suppose that
ye must not worship God only once in a week
12 I say unto you, it is well that ye are cast out
of your synagogues, that ye may be humble, and
that ye may learn wisdom; for it is necessary that
ye should learn wisdom; for it is because that ye
are cast out, that ye are despised of your brethren
because of your exceeding poverty, that ye are
brought to a lowliness of heart; for ye are
necessarily brought to be humble
13 And now, because ye are compelled to be humble
blessed are ye; for a man sometimes, if he is
compelled to be humble, seeketh repentance; and now
surely, whosoever repenteth shall find mercy; and he
that findeth mercy and endureth to the end the
same shall be saved
14 And now, as I said unto you, that because ye
were compelled to be humble ye were blessed, do ye
not suppose that they are more blessed who truly
humble themselves because of the word
15 Yea, he that truly humbleth himself, and
repenteth of his sins, and endureth to the end, the same
shall be blessed—yea, much more blessed than they
who are compelled to be humble because of their
exceeding poverty
16 Therefore, blessed are they who humble
themselves without being compelled to be humble; or
rather, in other words, blessed is he that believeth in
the word of God, and is baptized without
stubbornness of heart, yea, without being brought to know
the word, or even compelled to know, before they
will believe
17 Yea, there are many who do say: If thou wilt
show unto us a sign from heaven, then we shall know
of a surety; then we shall believe
18 Now I ask, is this faith? Behold, I say unto
you, Nay; for if a man knoweth a thing he hath no
cause to believe, for he knoweth it
19 And now, how much more cursed is he that
knoweth the will of God and doeth it not, than he that
only believeth, or only hath cause to believe, and
falleth into transgression
20 Now of this thing ye must judge. Behold, I say
unto you, that it is on the one hand even as it is
on the other; and it shall be unto every man
according to his work
21 And now as I said concerning faith—faith is not
to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore
if ye have faith ye hope for things which are not
seen, which are true
22 And now, behold, I say unto you, and I would
that ye should remember, that God is merciful unto
all who believe on his name; therefore he desireth,
in the first place, that ye should believe, yea,
even on his word
23 And now, he imparteth his word by angels unto
men, yea, not only men but women also. Now this is
not all; little children do have words given unto
them many times, which confound the wise and the
learned
24 And now, my beloved brethren, as ye have
desired to know of me what ye shall do because ye are
afflicted and cast out—now I do not desire that ye
should suppose that I mean to judge you only
according to that which is true
25 For I do not mean that ye all of you have been
compelled to humble yourselves; for I verily
believe that there are some among you who would humble
themselves, let them be in whatsoever
circumstances they might
26 Now, as I said concerning faith—that it was not
a perfect knowledge—even so it is with my words.
Ye cannot know of their surety at first, unto
perfection, any more than faith is a perfect
knowledge
27 But behold, if ye will awake and arouse your
faculties, even to an experiment upon my words, and
exercise a particle of faith, yea, even if ye can
no more than desire to believe, let this desire
work in you, even until ye believe in a manner that
ye can give place for a portion of my words
28 Now, we will compare the word unto a seed. Now,
if ye give place, that a seed may be planted in
your heart, behold, if it be a true seed, or a good
seed, if ye do not cast it out by your unbelief,
that ye will resist the Spirit of the Lord,
behold, it will begin to swell within your breasts; and
when you feel these swelling motions, ye will
begin to say within yourselves—It must needs be that
this is a good seed, or that the word is good, for
it beginneth to enlarge my soul; yea, it beginneth
to enlighten my understanding, yea, it beginneth
to be delicious to me
29 Now behold, would not this increase your faith?
I say unto you, Yea; nevertheless it hath not
grown up to a perfect knowledge
30 But behold, as the seed swelleth, and
sprouteth, and beginneth to grow, then you must needs say
that the seed is good; for behold it swelleth, and
sprouteth, and beginneth to grow. And now, behold,
will not this strengthen your faith? Yea, it will
strengthen your faith: for ye will say I know
that this is a good seed; for behold it sprouteth and
beginneth to grow
33 And now, behold, because ye have tried the
experiment, and planted the seed, and it swelleth and
sprouteth, and beginneth to grow, ye must needs
know that the seed is good
34 And now, behold, is your knowledge perfect?
Yea, your knowledge is perfect in that thing, and
your faith is dormant; and this because you know, for
ye know that the word hath swelled your souls,
and ye also know that it hath sprouted up, that your
understanding doth begin to be enlightened, and
your mind doth begin to expand
35 O then, is not this real? I say unto you, Yea,
because it is light; and whatsoever is light, is
good, because it is discernible, therefore ye must
know that it is good; and now behold, after ye
have tasted this light is your knowledge perfect
36 Behold I say unto you, Nay; neither must ye lay
aside your faith, for ye have only exercised your
faith to plant the seed that ye might try the
experiment to know if the seed was good
37 And behold, as the tree beginneth to grow, ye
will say: Let us nourish it with great care, that
it may get root, that it may grow up, and bring
forth fruit unto us. And now behold, if ye nourish it
with much care it will get root, and grow up, and
bring forth fruit
38 But if ye neglect the tree, and take no thought
for its nourishment, behold it will not get any
root; and when the heat of the sun cometh and
scorcheth it, because it hath no root it withers away,
and ye pluck it up and cast it out
39 Now, this is not because the seed was not good,
neither is it because the fruit thereof would not
be desirable; but it is because your ground is
barren, and ye will not nourish the tree, therefore
ye cannot have the fruit thereof
40 And thus, if ye will not nourish the word,
looking forward with an eye of faith to the fruit
thereof, ye can never pluck of the fruit of the tree
of life
41 But if ye will nourish the word, yea, nourish
the tree as it beginneth to grow, by your faith
with great diligence, and with patience, looking
forward to the fruit thereof, it shall take root; and
behold it shall be a tree springing up unto
everlasting life
42 And because of your diligence and your faith
and your patience with the word in nourishing it,
that it may take root in you, behold, by and by ye
shall pluck the fruit thereof, which is most
precious, which is sweet above all that is sweet, and
which is white above all that is white, yea, and
pure above all that is pure; and ye shall feast upon
this fruit even until ye are filled, that ye
hunger not, neither shall ye thirst
43 Then, my brethren, ye shall reap the rewards of
your faith, and your diligence, and patience, and
long-suffering, waiting for the tree to bring
forth fruit unto you.