The commandments of Alma to his son Shiblon.
Comprising chapter 38.Chapter 38 Shiblon was persecuted
for righteousness’ sake—Salvation is in Christ,
who is the life and the light of the world—Bridle
all your passions. About 74 B.C.
1 My son, give ear to my words, for I say unto
you, even as I said unto Helaman, that inasmuch as ye
shall keep the commandments of God ye shall
prosper in the land; and inasmuch as ye will not keep
the commandments of God ye shall be cut off from
his presence
2 And now, my son, I trust that I shall have great
joy in you, because of your steadiness and your
faithfulness unto God; for as you have commenced in
your youth to look to the Lord your God, even so
I hope that you will continue in keeping his
commandments; for blessed is he that endureth to the
end
3 I say unto you, my son, that I have had great
joy in thee already, because of thy faithfulness and
thy diligence, and thy patience and thy
long-suffering among the people of the Zoramites
4 For I know that thou wast in bonds; yea, and I
also know that thou wast stoned for the word’s
sake; and thou didst bear all these things with
patience because the Lord was with thee; and now thou
knowest that the Lord did deliver thee
5 And now my son, Shiblon, I would that ye should
remember, that as much as ye shall put your trust
in God even so much ye shall be delivered out of
your trials, and your troubles, and your
afflictions, and ye shall be lifted up at the last day
6 Now, my son, I would not that ye should think
that I know these things of myself, but it is the
Spirit of God which is in me which maketh these
things known unto me; for if I had not been born of
God I should not have known these things
7 But behold, the Lord in his great mercy sent his
angel to declare unto me that I must stop the
work of destruction among his people; yea, and I have
seen an angel face to face, and he spake with me,
and his voice was as thunder, and it shook the
whole earth
8 And it came to pass that I was three days and
three nights in the most bitter pain and anguish of
soul; and never, until I did cry out unto the Lord
Jesus Christ for mercy, did I receive a remission
of my sins. But behold, I did cry unto him and I
did find peace to my soul
11 See that ye are not lifted up unto pride; yea,
see that ye do not boast in your own wisdom, nor
of your much strength
12 Use boldness, but not overbearance; and also
see that ye bridle all your passions, that ye may be
filled with love; see that ye refrain from
idleness
15 And may the Lord bless your soul, and receive
you at the last day into his kingdom, to sit down
in peace. Now go, my son, and teach the word unto
this people. Be sober. My son, farewell.