Chapter 35 The preaching of the word destroys the
craft of the Zoramites—They expel the converts,
who then join the people of Ammon in Jershon—Alma
sorrows because of the wickedness of the people.
About 74 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that after Amulek had made
an end of these words, they withdrew themselves
from the multitude and came over into the land of
Jershon
2 Yea, and the rest of the brethren, after they
had preached the word unto the Zoramites, also came
over into the land of Jershon
3 And it came to pass that after the more popular
part of the Zoramites had consulted together
concerning the words which had been preached unto them,
they were angry because of the word, for it did
destroy their craft; therefore they would not
hearken unto the words
4 And they sent and gathered together throughout
all the land all the people, and consulted with
them concerning the words which had been spoken
5 Now their rulers and their priests and their
teachers did not let the people know concerning their
desires; therefore they found out privily the
minds of all the people
6 And it came to pass that after they had found
out the minds of all the people, those who were in
favor of the words which had been spoken by Alma
and his brethren were cast out of the land; and they
were many; and they came over also into the land
of Jershon
9 And he breathed out many threatenings against
them. And now the people of Ammon did not fear their
words; therefore they did not cast them out, but
they did receive all the poor of the Zoramites
that came over unto them; and they did nourish them,
and did clothe them, and did give unto them lands
for their inheritance; and they did administer
unto them according to their wants
10 Now this did stir up the Zoramites to anger
against the people of Ammon, and they began to mix
with the Lamanites and to stir them up also to anger
against them
11 And thus the Zoramites and the Lamanites began
to make preparations for war against the people of
Ammon, and also against the Nephites
12 And thus ended the seventeenth year of the
reign of the judges over the people of Nephi
13 And the people of Ammon departed out of the
land of Jershon, and came over into the land of
Melek, and gave place in the land of Jershon for the
armies of the Nephites, that they might contend with
the armies of the Lamanites and the armies of the
Zoramites; and thus commenced a war betwixt the
Lamanites and the Nephites, in the eighteenth year
of the reign of the judges; and an account shall
be given of their wars hereafter
14 And Alma, and Ammon, and their brethren, and
also the two sons of Alma returned to the land of
Zarahemla, after having been instruments in the
hands of God of bringing many of the Zoramites to
repentance; and as many as were brought to repentance
were driven out of their land; but they have lands
for their inheritance in the land of Jershon, and
they have taken up arms to defend themselves, and
their wives, and children, and their lands