The commandments of Alma to his son Corianton.
Comprising chapters 39 through 42.Chapter 39 Sexual
sin is an abomination—Corianton’s sins kept the
Zoramites from receiving the word—Christ’s redemption
is retroactive in saving the faithful who
preceded it. About 74 B.C.
1 And now, my son, I have somewhat more to say
unto thee than what I said unto thy brother; for
behold, have ye not observed the steadiness of thy
brother, his faithfulness, and his diligence in
keeping the commandments of God? Behold, has he not set
a good example for thee
2 For thou didst not give so much heed unto my
words as did thy brother, among the people of the
Zoramites. Now this is what I have against thee; thou
didst go on unto boasting in thy strength and thy
wisdom
3 And this is not all, my son. Thou didst do that
which was grievous unto me; for thou didst forsake
the ministry, and did go over into the land of
Siron among the borders of the Lamanites, after the
harlot Isabel
4 Yea, she did steal away the hearts of many; but
this was no excuse for thee, my son. Thou shouldst
have tended to the ministry wherewith thou wast
entrusted
5 Know ye not, my son, that these things are an
abomination in the sight of the Lord; yea, most
abominable above all sins save it be the shedding of
innocent blood or denying the Holy Ghost
6 For behold, if ye deny the Holy Ghost when it
once has had place in you, and ye know that ye deny
it, behold, this is a sin which is unpardonable;
yea, and whosoever murdereth against the light and
knowledge of God, it is not easy for him to obtain
forgiveness; yea, I say unto you, my son, that it
is not easy for him to obtain a forgiveness
7 And now, my son, I would to God that ye had not
been guilty of so great a crime. I would not dwell
upon your crimes, to harrow up your soul, if it
were not for your good
8 But behold, ye cannot hide your crimes from God;
and except ye repent they will stand as a
testimony against you at the last day
9 Now my son, I would that ye should repent and
forsake your sins, and go no more after the lusts of
your eyes, but cross yourself in all these
things; for except ye do this ye can in nowise inherit
the kingdom of God. Oh, remember, and take it upon
you, and cross yourself in these things
10 And I command you to take it upon you to
counsel with your elder brothers in your undertakings;
for behold, thou art in thy youth, and ye stand in
need to be nourished by your brothers. And give
heed to their counsel
13 That ye turn to the Lord with all your mind,
might, and strength; that ye lead away the hearts of
no more to do wickedly; but rather return unto
them, and acknowledge your faults and that wrong
which ye have done
14 Seek not after riches nor the vain things of
this world; for behold, you cannot carry them with
you
15 And now, my son, I would say somewhat unto you
concerning the coming of Christ. Behold, I say
unto you, that it is he that surely shall come to
take away the sins of the world; yea, he cometh to
declare glad tidings of salvation unto his people
16 And now, my son, this was the ministry unto
which ye were called, to declare these glad tidings
unto this people, to prepare their minds; or rather
that salvation might come unto them, that they
may prepare the minds of their children to hear the
word at the time of his coming
17 And now I will ease your mind somewhat on this
subject. Behold, you marvel why these things
should be known so long beforehand. Behold, I say unto
you, is not a soul at this time as precious unto
God as a soul will be at the time of his coming
18 Is it not as necessary that the plan of
redemption should be made known unto this people as well
as unto their children
19 Is it not as easy at this time for the Lord to
send his angel to declare these glad tidings unto
us as unto our children, or as after the time of
his coming?