Chapter 42 Mortality is a probationary time to
enable man to repent and serve God—The Fall brought
temporal and spiritual death upon all
mankind—Redemption comes through repentance—God Himself atones
for the sins of the world—Mercy is for those who
repent—All others are subject to God’s
justice—Mercy comes because of the Atonement—Only the truly
penitent are saved. About 74 B.C.
1 And now, my son, I perceive there is somewhat
more which doth worry your mind, which ye cannot
understand—which is concerning the justice of God in
the punishment of the sinner; for ye do try to
suppose that it is injustice that the sinner should
be consigned to a state of misery
2 Now behold, my son, I will explain this thing
unto thee. For behold, after the Lord God sent our
first parents forth from the garden of Eden, to
till the ground, from whence they were taken—yea, he
drew out the man, and he placed at the east end of
the garden of Eden, cherubim, and a flaming sword
which turned every way, to keep the tree of life
3 Now, we see that the man had become as God,
knowing good and evil; and lest he should put forth
his hand, and take also of the tree of life, and eat
and live forever, the Lord God placed cherubim
and the flaming sword, that he should not partake of
the fruit
4 And thus we see, that there was a time granted
unto man to repent, yea, a probationary time, a
time to repent and serve God
5 For behold, if Adam had put forth his hand
immediately, and partaken of the tree of life, he would
have lived forever, according to the word of God,
having no space for repentance; yea, and also the
word of God would have been void, and the great
plan of salvation would have been frustrated
6 But behold, it was appointed unto man to
die—therefore, as they were cut off from the tree of life
they should be cut off from the face of the
earth—and man became lost forever, yea, they became
fallen man
7 And now, ye see by this that our first parents
were cut off both temporally and spiritually from
the presence of the Lord; and thus we see they
became subjects to follow after their own will
8 Now behold, it was not expedient that man should
be reclaimed from this temporal death, for that
would destroy the great plan of happiness
9 Therefore, as the soul could never die, and the
fall had brought upon all mankind a spiritual
death as well as a temporal, that is, they were cut
off from the presence of the Lord, it was expedient
that mankind should be reclaimed from this
spiritual death
10 Therefore, as they had become carnal, sensual,
and devilish, by nature, this probationary state
became a state for them to prepare; it became a
preparatory state
11 And now remember, my son, if it were not for
the plan of redemption, (laying it aside) as soon as
they were dead their souls were miserable, being
cut off from the presence of the Lord
12 And now, there was no means to reclaim men from
this fallen state, which man had brought upon
himself because of his own disobedience
13 Therefore, according to justice, the plan of
redemption could not be brought about, only on
conditions of repentance of men in this probationary
state, yea, this preparatory state; for except it
were for these conditions, mercy could not take
effect except it should destroy the work of justice.
Now the work of justice could not be destroyed; if
so, God would cease to be God
14 And thus we see that all mankind were fallen,
and they were in the grasp of justice; yea, the
justice of God, which consigned them forever to be
cut off from his presence
15 And now, the plan of mercy could not be brought
about except an atonement should be made;
therefore God himself atoneth for the sins of the world,
to bring about the plan of mercy, to appease the
demands of justice, that God might be a perfect,
just God, and a merciful God also
16 Now, repentance could not come unto men except
there were a punishment, which also was eternal as
the life of the soul should be, affixed opposite
to the plan of happiness, which was as eternal
also as the life of the soul
17 Now, how could a man repent except he should
sin? How could he sin if there was no law? How could
there be a law save there was a punishment
18 Now, there was a punishment affixed, and a just
law given, which brought remorse of conscience
unto man
21 And if there was no law given, if men sinned
what could justice do, or mercy either, for they
would have no claim upon the creature
22 But there is a law given, and a punishment
affixed, and a repentance granted; which repentance,
mercy claimeth; otherwise, justice claimeth the
creature and executeth the law, and the law
inflicteth the punishment; if not so, the works of justice
would be destroyed, and God would cease to be God
23 But God ceaseth not to be God, and mercy
claimeth the penitent, and mercy cometh because of the
atonement; and the atonement bringeth to pass the
resurrection of the dead; and the resurrection of
the dead bringeth back men into the presence of
God; and thus they are restored into his presence, to
be judged according to their works, according to
the law and justice
24 For behold, justice exerciseth all his demands,
and also mercy claimeth all which is her own; and
thus, none but the truly penitent are saved
25 What, do ye suppose that mercy can rob justice?
I say unto you, Nay; not one whit. If so, God
would cease to be God
26 And thus God bringeth about his great and
eternal purposes, which were prepared from the
foundation of the world. And thus cometh about the
salvation and the redemption of men, and also their
destruction and misery
27 Therefore, O my son, whosoever will come may
come and partake of the waters of life freely; and
whosoever will not come the same is not compelled
to come; but in the last day it shall be restored
unto him according to his deeds
28 If he has desired to do evil, and has not
repented in his days, behold, evil shall be done unto
him, according to the restoration of God
29 And now, my son, I desire that ye should let
these things trouble you no more, and only let your
sins trouble you, with that trouble which shall
bring you down unto repentance
30 O my son, I desire that ye should deny the
justice of God no more. Do not endeavor to excuse
yourself in the least point because of your sins, by
denying the justice of God; but do you let the
justice of God, and his mercy, and his long-suffering
have full sway in your heart; and let it bring you
down to the dust in humility
31 And now, O my son, ye are called of God to
preach the word unto this people. And now, my son, go
thy way, declare the word with truth and
soberness, that thou mayest bring souls unto repentance,
that the great plan of mercy may have claim upon
them. And may God grant unto you even according to my
words. Amen.