Chapter 41 In the Resurrection men come forth to a
state of endless happiness or endless
misery—Wickedness never was happiness—Carnal men are without
God in the world—Every person receives again in
the Restoration the characteristics and attributes
acquired in mortality. About 74 B.C.
1 And now, my son, I have somewhat to say
concerning the restoration of which has been spoken; for
behold, some have wrested the scriptures, and have
gone far astray because of this thing. And I
perceive that thy mind has been worried also concerning
this thing. But behold, I will explain it unto
thee
2 I say unto thee, my son, that the plan of
restoration is requisite with the justice of God; for it
is requisite that all things should be restored
to their proper order. Behold, it is requisite and
just, according to the power and resurrection of
Christ, that the soul of man should be restored to
its body, and that every part of the body should
be restored to itself
3 And it is requisite with the justice of God that
men should be judged according to their works;
and if their works were good in this life, and the
desires of their hearts were good, that they should
also, at the last day, be restored unto that
which is good
4 And if their works are evil they shall be
restored unto them for evil. Therefore, all things shall
be restored to their proper order, every thing to
its natural frame—mortality raised to
immortality, corruption to incorruption—raised to endless
happiness to inherit the kingdom of God, or to
endless misery to inherit the kingdom of the devil, the
one on one hand, the other on the other
5 The one raised to happiness according to his
desires of happiness, or good according to his
desires of good; and the other to evil according to his
desires of evil; for as he has desired to do evil
all the day long even so shall he have his reward
of evil when the night cometh
6 And so it is on the other hand. If he hath
repented of his sins, and desired righteousness until
the end of his days, even so he shall be rewarded
unto righteousness
7 These are they that are redeemed of the Lord;
yea, these are they that are taken out, that are
delivered from that endless night of darkness; and
thus they stand or fall; for behold, they are their
own judges, whether to do good or do evil
8 Now, the decrees of God are unalterable;
therefore, the way is prepared that whosoever will may
walk therein and be saved
9 And now behold, my son, do not risk one more
offense against your God upon those points of
doctrine, which ye have hitherto risked to commit sin
10 Do not suppose, because it has been spoken
concerning restoration, that ye shall be restored from
sin to happiness. Behold, I say unto you,
wickedness never was happiness
11 And now, my son, all men that are in a state of
nature, or I would say, in a carnal state, are in
the gall of bitterness and in the bonds of
iniquity; they are without God in the world, and they
have gone contrary to the nature of God; therefore,
they are in a state contrary to the nature of
happiness
12 And now behold, is the meaning of the word
restoration to take a thing of a natural state and
place it in an unnatural state, or to place it in a
state opposite to its nature
13 O, my son, this is not the case; but the
meaning of the word restoration is to bring back again
evil for evil, or carnal for carnal, or devilish
for devilish—good for that which is good; righteous
for that which is righteous; just for that which
is just; merciful for that which is merciful
14 Therefore, my son, see that you are merciful
unto your brethren; deal justly, judge righteously,
and do good continually; and if ye do all these
things then shall ye receive your reward; yea, ye
shall have mercy restored unto you again; ye shall
have justice restored unto you again; ye shall have
a righteous judgment restored unto you again; and
ye shall have good rewarded unto you again
15 For that which ye do send out shall return unto
you again, and be restored; therefore, the word
restoration more fully condemneth the sinner, and
justifieth him not at all.