Chapter 44 Moroni commands the Lamanites to make a
covenant of peace or be destroyed—Zerahemnah
rejects the offer, and the battle resumes—Moroni’s
armies defeat the Lamanites. About 74–73 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that they did stop and
withdrew a pace from them. And Moroni said unto
Zerahemnah: Behold, Zerahemnah, that we do not desire to
be men of blood. Ye know that ye are in our hands,
yet we do not desire to slay you
2 Behold, we have not come out to battle against
you that we might shed your blood for power;
neither do we desire to bring any one to the yoke of
bondage. But this is the very cause for which ye have
come against us; yea, and ye are angry with us
because of our religion
3 But now, ye behold that the Lord is with us; and
ye behold that he has delivered you into our
hands. And now I would that ye should understand that
this is done unto us because of our religion and
our faith in Christ. And now ye see that ye cannot
destroy this our faith
4 Now ye see that this is the true faith of God;
yea, ye see that God will support, and keep, and
preserve us, so long as we are faithful unto him,
and unto our faith, and our religion; and never will
the Lord suffer that we shall be destroyed except
we should fall into transgression and deny our
faith
5 And now, Zerahemnah, I command you, in the name
of that all-powerful God, who has strengthened our
arms that we have gained power over you, by our
faith, by our religion, and by our rites of
worship, and by our church, and by the sacred support
which we owe to our wives and our children, by that
liberty which binds us to our lands and our
country; yea, and also by the maintenance of the sacred
word of God, to which we owe all our happiness; and
by all that is most dear unto us
6 Yea, and this is not all; I command you by all
the desires which ye have for life, that ye deliver
up your weapons of war unto us, and we will seek
not your blood, but we will spare your lives, if
ye will go your way and come not again to war
against us
7 And now, if ye do not this, behold, ye are in
our hands, and I will command my men that they shall
fall upon you, and inflict the wounds of death in
your bodies, that ye may become extinct; and then
we will see who shall have power over this
people; yea, we will see who shall be brought into
bondage
8 And now it came to pass that when Zerahemnah had
heard these sayings he came forth and delivered
up his sword and his cimeter, and his bow into the
hands of Moroni, and said unto him: Behold, here
are our weapons of war; we will deliver them up
unto you, but we will not suffer ourselves to take an
oath unto you, which we know that we shall break,
and also our children; but take our weapons of
war, and suffer that we may depart into the
wilderness; otherwise we will retain our swords, and we
will perish or conquer
9 Behold, we are not of your faith; we do not
believe that it is God that has delivered us into your
hands; but we believe that it is your cunning
that has preserved you from our swords. Behold, it is
your breastplates and your shields that have
preserved you
10 And now when Zerahemnah had made an end of
speaking these words, Moroni returned the sword and
the weapons of war, which he had received, unto
Zerahemnah, saying: Behold, we will end the conflict
11 Now I cannot recall the words which I have
spoken, therefore as the Lord liveth, ye shall not
depart except ye depart with an oath that ye will not
return again against us to war. Now as ye are in
our hands we will spill your blood upon the
ground, or ye shall submit to the conditions which I
have proposed
12 And now when Moroni had said these words,
Zerahemnah retained his sword, and he was angry with
Moroni, and he rushed forward that he might slay
Moroni; but as he raised his sword, behold, one of
Moroni’s soldiers smote it even to the earth, and it
broke by the hilt; and he also smote Zerahemnah
that he took off his scalp and it fell to the
earth. And Zerahemnah withdrew from before them into
the midst of his soldiers
13 And it came to pass that the soldier who stood
by, who smote off the scalp of Zerahemnah, took up
the scalp from off the ground by the hair, and
laid it upon the point of his sword, and stretched
it forth unto them, saying unto them with a loud
voice
14 Even as this scalp has fallen to the earth,
which is the scalp of your chief, so shall ye fall to
the earth except ye will deliver up your weapons
of war and depart with a covenant of peace
15 Now there were many, when they heard these
words and saw the scalp which was upon the sword, that
were struck with fear; and many came forth and
threw down their weapons of war at the feet of
Moroni, and entered into a covenant of peace. And as
many as entered into a covenant they suffered to
depart into the wilderness
16 Now it came to pass that Zerahemnah was
exceedingly wroth, and he did stir up the remainder of
his soldiers to anger, to contend more powerfully
against the Nephites
17 And now Moroni was angry, because of the
stubbornness of the Lamanites; therefore he commanded
his people that they should fall upon them and slay
them. And it came to pass that they began to slay
them; yea, and the Lamanites did contend with
their swords and their might
18 But behold, their naked skins and their bare
heads were exposed to the sharp swords of the
Nephites; yea, behold they were pierced and smitten,
yea, and did fall exceedingly fast before the swords
of the Nephites; and they began to be swept down,
even as the soldier of Moroni had prophesied
19 Now Zerahemnah, when he saw that they were all
about to be destroyed, cried mightily unto Moroni,
promising that he would covenant and also his
people with them, if they would spare the remainder
of their lives, that they never would come to war
again against them
22 And it came to pass that they did cast their
dead into the waters of Sidon, and they have gone
forth and are buried in the depths of the sea
23 And the armies of the Nephites, or of Moroni,
returned and came to their houses and their lands
24 And thus ended the eighteenth year of the reign
of the judges over the people of Nephi. And thus
ended the record of Alma, which was written upon
the plates of Nephi.