Chapter 40 Christ brings to pass the resurrection
of all men—The righteous dead go to paradise and
the wicked to outer darkness to await the day of
their resurrection—All things will be restored to
their proper and perfect frame in the Resurrection.
About 74 B.C.
1 Now my son, here is somewhat more I would say
unto thee; for I perceive that thy mind is worried
concerning the resurrection of the dead
2 Behold, I say unto you, that there is no
resurrection—or, I would say, in other words, that this
mortal does not put on immortality, this corruption
does not put on incorruption—until after the
coming of Christ
3 Behold, he bringeth to pass the resurrection of
the dead. But behold, my son, the resurrection is
not yet. Now, I unfold unto you a mystery;
nevertheless, there are many mysteries which are kept,
that no one knoweth them save God himself. But I
show unto you one thing which I have inquired
diligently of God that I might know—that is concerning
the resurrection
4 Behold, there is a time appointed that all shall
come forth from the dead. Now when this time
cometh no one knows; but God knoweth the time which is
appointed
5 Now, whether there shall be one time, or a
second time, or a third time, that men shall come forth
from the dead, it mattereth not; for God knoweth
all these things; and it sufficeth me to know that
this is the case—that there is a time appointed
that all shall rise from the dead
6 Now there must needs be a space betwixt the time
of death and the time of the resurrection
7 And now I would inquire what becometh of the
souls of men from this time of death to the time
appointed for the resurrection
8 Now whether there is more than one time
appointed for men to rise it mattereth not; for all do not
die at once, and this mattereth not; all is as
one day with God, and time only is measured unto
men
9 Therefore, there is a time appointed unto men
that they shall rise from the dead; and there is a
space between the time of death and the
resurrection. And now, concerning this space of time, what
becometh of the souls of men is the thing which I
have inquired diligently of the Lord to know; and
this is the thing of which I do know
10 And when the time cometh when all shall rise,
then shall they know that God knoweth all the times
which are appointed unto man
11 Now, concerning the state of the soul between
death and the resurrection—Behold, it has been made
known unto me by an angel, that the spirits of
all men, as soon as they are departed from this
mortal body, yea, the spirits of all men, whether they
be good or evil, are taken home to that God who
gave them life
12 And then shall it come to pass, that the
spirits of those who are righteous are received into a
state of happiness, which is called paradise, a
state of rest, a state of peace, where they shall
rest from all their troubles and from all care, and
sorrow
13 And then shall it come to pass, that the
spirits of the wicked, yea, who are evil—for behold,
they have no part nor portion of the Spirit of the
Lord; for behold, they chose evil works rather than
good; therefore the spirit of the devil did enter
into them, and take possession of their house—and
these shall be cast out into outer darkness; there
shall be weeping, and wailing, and gnashing of
teeth, and this because of their own iniquity, being
led captive by the will of the devil
14 Now this is the state of the souls of the
wicked, yea, in darkness, and a state of awful, fearful
looking for the fiery indignation of the wrath of
God upon them; thus they remain in this state, as
well as the righteous in paradise, until the time
of their resurrection
15 Now, there are some that have understood that
this state of happiness and this state of misery of
the soul, before the resurrection, was a first
resurrection. Yea, I admit it may be termed a
resurrection, the raising of the spirit or the soul and
their consignation to happiness or misery,
according to the words which have been spoken
16 And behold, again it hath been spoken, that
there is a first resurrection, a resurrection of all
those who have been, or who are, or who shall be,
down to the resurrection of Christ from the dead
19 Now, whether the souls and the bodies of those
of whom has been spoken shall all be reunited at
once, the wicked as well as the righteous, I do not
say; let it suffice, that I say that they all
come forth; or in other words, their resurrection
cometh to pass before the resurrection of those who
die after the resurrection of Christ
20 Now, my son, I do not say that their
resurrection cometh at the resurrection of Christ; but
behold, I give it as my opinion, that the souls and the
bodies are reunited, of the righteous, at the
resurrection of Christ, and his ascension into
heaven
21 But whether it be at his resurrection or after,
I do not say; but this much I say, that there is
a space between death and the resurrection of the
body, and a state of the soul in happiness or in
misery until the time which is appointed of God
that the dead shall come forth, and be reunited, both
soul and body, and be brought to stand before
God, and be judged according to their works
22 Yea, this bringeth about the restoration of
those things of which has been spoken by the mouths
of the prophets
23 The soul shall be restored to the body, and the
body to the soul; yea, and every limb and joint
shall be restored to its body; yea, even a hair of
the head shall not be lost; but all things shall
be restored to their proper and perfect frame
24 And now, my son, this is the restoration of
which has been spoken by the mouths of the prophets
25 And then shall the righteous shine forth in the
kingdom of God
26 But behold, an awful death cometh upon the
wicked; for they die as to things pertaining to things
of righteousness; for they are unclean, and no
unclean thing can inherit the kingdom of God; but
they are cast out, and consigned to partake of the
fruits of their labors or their works, which have
been evil; and they drink the dregs of a bitter
cup.