Chapter 4 Alma baptizes thousands of
converts—Iniquity enters the Church, and the Church’s progress
is hindered—Nephihah is appointed chief
judge—Alma, as high priest, devotes himself to the ministry.
About 86–83 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass in the sixth year of the
reign of the judges over the people of Nephi, there
were no contentions nor wars in the land of
Zarahemla
2 But the people were afflicted, yea, greatly
afflicted for the loss of their brethren, and also for
the loss of their flocks and herds, and also for
the loss of their fields of grain, which were
trodden under foot and destroyed by the Lamanites
3 And so great were their afflictions that every
soul had cause to mourn; and they believed that it
was the judgments of God sent upon them because of
their wickedness and their abominations;
therefore they were awakened to a remembrance of their
duty
4 And they began to establish the church more
fully; yea, and many were baptized in the waters of
Sidon and were joined to the church of God; yea,
they were baptized by the hand of Alma, who had been
consecrated the high priest over the people of the
church, by the hand of his father Alma
5 And it came to pass in the seventh year of the
reign of the judges there were about three thousand
five hundred souls that united themselves to the
church of God and were baptized. And thus ended
the seventh year of the reign of the judges over the
people of Nephi; and there was continual peace in
all that time
6 And it came to pass in the eighth year of the
reign of the judges, that the people of the church
began to wax proud, because of their exceeding
riches, and their fine silks, and their fine-twined
linen, and because of their many flocks and herds,
and their gold and their silver, and all manner of
precious things, which they had obtained by their
industry; and in all these things were they lifted
up in the pride of their eyes, for they began to
wear very costly apparel
7 Now this was the cause of much affliction to
Alma, yea, and to many of the people whom Alma had
consecrated to be teachers, and priests, and elders
over the church; yea, many of them were sorely
grieved for the wickedness which they saw had begun
to be among their people
8 For they saw and beheld with great sorrow that
the people of the church began to be lifted up in
the pride of their eyes, and to set their hearts
upon riches and upon the vain things of the world,
that they began to be scornful, one towards
another, and they began to persecute those that did not
believe according to their own will and pleasure
9 And thus, in this eighth year of the reign of
the judges, there began to be great contentions
among the people of the church; yea, there were
envyings, and strife, and malice, and persecutions, and
pride, even to exceed the pride of those who did
not belong to the church of God
10 And thus ended the eighth year of the reign of
the judges; and the wickedness of the church was a
great stumbling-block to those who did not belong
to the church; and thus the church began to fail
in its progress
11 And it came to pass in the commencement of the
ninth year, Alma saw the wickedness of the church,
and he saw also that the example of the church
began to lead those who were unbelievers on from one
piece of iniquity to another, thus bringing on
the destruction of the people
12 Yea, he saw great inequality among the people,
some lifting themselves up with their pride,
despising others, turning their backs upon the needy
and the naked and those who were hungry, and those
who were athirst, and those who were sick and
afflicted
13 Now this was a great cause for lamentations
among the people, while others were abasing
themselves, succoring those who stood in need of their
succor, such as imparting their substance to the poor
and the needy, feeding the hungry, and suffering
all manner of afflictions, for Christ’s sake, who
should come according to the spirit of prophecy
14 Looking forward to that day, thus retaining a
remission of their sins; being filled with great
joy because of the resurrection of the dead,
according to the will and power and deliverance of Jesus
Christ from the bands of death
15 And now it came to pass that Alma, having seen
the afflictions of the humble followers of God,
and the persecutions which were heaped upon them by
the remainder of his people, and seeing all their
inequality, began to be very sorrowful;
nevertheless the Spirit of the Lord did not fail him
16 And he selected a wise man who was among the
elders of the church, and gave him power according
to the voice of the people, that he might have
power to enact laws according to the laws which had
been given, and to put them in force according to
the wickedness and the crimes of the people
17 Now this man’s name was Nephihah, and he was
appointed chief judge; and he sat in the
judgment-seat to judge and to govern the people
18 Now Alma did not grant unto him the office of
being high priest over the church, but he retained
the office of high priest unto himself; but he
delivered the judgment-seat unto Nephihah
19 And this he did that he himself might go forth
among his people, or among the people of Nephi,
that he might preach the word of God unto them, to
stir them up in remembrance of their duty, and that
he might pull down, by the word of God, all the
pride and craftiness and all the contentions which
were among his people, seeing no way that he might
reclaim them save it were in bearing down in pure
testimony against them
20 And thus in the commencement of the ninth year
of the reign of the judges over the people of
Nephi, Alma delivered up the judgment-seat to
Nephihah, and confined himself wholly to the high
priesthood of the holy order of God, to the testimony of
the word, according to the spirit of revelation and
prophecy.