Chapter 43 Alma and his sons preach the word—The
Zoramites and other Nephite dissenters become
Lamanites—The Lamanites come against the Nephites in
war—Moroni arms the Nephites with defensive
armor—The Lord reveals to Alma the strategy of the
Lamanites—The Nephites defend their homes, liberties,
families, and religion—The armies of Moroni and Lehi
surround the Lamanites. About 74 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that the sons of Alma
did go forth among the people, to declare the word
unto them. And Alma, also, himself, could not rest,
and he also went forth
2 Now we shall say no more concerning their
preaching, except that they preached the word, and the
truth, according to the spirit of prophecy and
revelation; and they preached after the holy order of
God by which they were called
3 And now I return to an account of the wars
between the Nephites and the Lamanites, in the
eighteenth year of the reign of the judges
4 For behold, it came to pass that the Zoramites
became Lamanites; therefore, in the commencement of
the eighteenth year the people of the Nephites
saw that the Lamanites were coming upon them;
therefore they made preparations for war; yea, they
gathered together their armies in the land of Jershon
5 And it came to pass that the Lamanites came with
their thousands; and they came into the land of
Antionum, which is the land of the Zoramites; and a
man by the name of Zerahemnah was their leader
6 And now, as the Amalekites were of a more wicked
and murderous disposition than the Lamanites
were, in and of themselves, therefore, Zerahemnah
appointed chief captains over the Lamanites, and they
were all Amalekites and Zoramites
7 Now this he did that he might preserve their
hatred towards the Nephites, that he might bring them
into subjection to the accomplishment of his
designs
8 For behold, his designs were to stir up the
Lamanites to anger against the Nephites; this he did
that he might usurp great power over them, and also
that he might gain power over the Nephites by
bringing them into bondage
9 And now the design of the Nephites was to
support their lands, and their houses, and their wives,
and their children, that they might preserve them
from the hands of their enemies; and also that
they might preserve their rights and their
privileges, yea, and also their liberty, that they might
worship God according to their desires
10 For they knew that if they should fall into the
hands of the Lamanites, that whosoever should
worship God in spirit and in truth, the true and the
living God, the Lamanites would destroy
11 Yea, and they also knew the extreme hatred of
the Lamanites towards their brethren, who were the
people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi, who were called the
people of Ammon—and they would not take up arms, yea,
they had entered into a covenant and they would
not break it—therefore, if they should fall into
the hands of the Lamanites they would be destroyed
12 And the Nephites would not suffer that they
should be destroyed; therefore they gave them lands
for their inheritance
13 And the people of Ammon did give unto the
Nephites a large portion of their substance to support
their armies; and thus the Nephites were
compelled, alone, to withstand against the Lamanites, who
were a compound of Laman and Lemuel, and the sons
of Ishmael, and all those who had dissented from
the Nephites, who were Amalekites and Zoramites, and
the descendants of the priests of Noah
14 Now those descendants were as numerous, nearly,
as were the Nephites; and thus the Nephites were
obliged to contend with their brethren, even unto
bloodshed
15 And it came to pass as the armies of the
Lamanites had gathered together in the land of Antionum,
behold, the armies of the Nephites were prepared
to meet them in the land of Jershon
16 Now, the leader of the Nephites, or the man who
had been appointed to be the chief captain over
the Nephites—now the chief captain took the command
of all the armies of the Nephites—and his name
was Moroni
17 And Moroni took all the command, and the
government of their wars. And he was only twenty and
five years old when he was appointed chief captain
over the armies of the Nephites
18 And it came to pass that he met the Lamanites
in the borders of Jershon, and his people were
armed with swords, and with cimeters, and all manner
of weapons of war
19 And when the armies of the Lamanites saw that
the people of Nephi, or that Moroni, had prepared
his people with breastplates and with arm-shields,
yea, and also shields to defend their heads, and
also they were dressed with thick clothing
20 Now the army of Zerahemnah was not prepared
with any such thing; they had only their swords and
their cimeters, their bows and their arrows, their
stones and their slings; and they were naked, save
it were a skin which was girded about their
loins; yea, all were naked, save it were the Zoramites
and the Amalekites
21 But they were not armed with breastplates, nor
shields—therefore, they were exceedingly afraid of
the armies of the Nephites because of their
armor, notwithstanding their number being so much
greater than the Nephites
22 Behold, now it came to pass that they durst not
come against the Nephites in the borders of
Jershon; therefore they departed out of the land of
Antionum into the wilderness, and took their journey
round about in the wilderness, away by the head of
the river Sidon, that they might come into the
land of Manti and take possession of the land; for
they did not suppose that the armies of Moroni
would know whither they had gone
23 But it came to pass, as soon as they had
departed into the wilderness Moroni sent spies into the
wilderness to watch their camp; and Moroni, also,
knowing of the prophecies of Alma, sent certain
men unto him, desiring him that he should inquire of
the Lord whither the armies of the Nephites
should go to defend themselves against the Lamanites
24 And it came to pass that the word of the Lord
came unto Alma, and Alma informed the messengers of
Moroni, that the armies of the Lamanites were
marching round about in the wilderness, that they
might come over into the land of Manti, that they
might commence an attack upon the weaker part of the
people. And those messengers went and delivered
the message unto Moroni
27 And it came to pass that Moroni caused that his
army should be secreted in the valley which was
near the bank of the river Sidon, which was on the
west of the river Sidon in the wilderness
28 And Moroni placed spies round about, that he
might know when the camp of the Lamanites should
come
29 And now, as Moroni knew the intention of the
Lamanites, that it was their intention to destroy
their brethren, or to subject them and bring them
into bondage that they might establish a kingdom
unto themselves over all the land
30 And he also knowing that it was the only desire
of the Nephites to preserve their lands, and
their liberty, and their church, therefore he thought
it no sin that he should defend them by stratagem;
therefore, he found by his spies which course the
Lamanites were to take
31 Therefore, he divided his army and brought a
part over into the valley, and concealed them on the
east, and on the south of the hill Riplah
32 And the remainder he concealed in the west
valley, on the west of the river Sidon, and so down
into the borders of the land Manti
33 And thus having placed his army according to
his desire, he was prepared to meet them
34 And it came to pass that the Lamanites came up
on the north of the hill, where a part of the army
of Moroni was concealed
35 And as the Lamanites had passed the hill
Riplah, and came into the valley, and began to cross the
river Sidon, the army which was concealed on the
south of the hill, which was led by a man whose
name was Lehi, and he led his army forth and
encircled the Lamanites about on the east in their rear
36 And it came to pass that the Lamanites, when
they saw the Nephites coming upon them in their
rear, turned them about and began to contend with the
army of Lehi
37 And the work of death commenced on both sides,
but it was more dreadful on the part of the
Lamanites, for their nakedness was exposed to the heavy
blows of the Nephites with their swords and their
cimeters, which brought death almost at every
stroke
38 While on the other hand, there was now and then
a man fell among the Nephites, by their swords
and the loss of blood, they being shielded from the
more vital parts of the body, or the more vital
parts of the body being shielded from the strokes of
the Lamanites, by their breastplates, and their
armshields, and their head-plates; and thus the
Nephites did carry on the work of death among the
Lamanites
39 And it came to pass that the Lamanites became
frightened, because of the great destruction among
them, even until they began to flee towards the
river Sidon
40 And they were pursued by Lehi and his men; and
they were driven by Lehi into the waters of Sidon,
and they crossed the waters of Sidon. And Lehi
retained his armies upon the bank of the river Sidon
that they should not cross
41 And it came to pass that Moroni and his army
met the Lamanites in the valley, on the other side
of the river Sidon, and began to fall upon them and
to slay them
42 And the Lamanites did flee again before them,
towards the land of Manti; and they were met again
by the armies of Moroni
43 Now in this case the Lamanites did fight
exceedingly; yea, never had the Lamanites been known to
fight with such exceedingly great strength and
courage, no, not even from the beginning
44 And they were inspired by the Zoramites and the
Amalekites, who were their chief captains and
leaders, and by Zerahemnah, who was their chief
captain, or their chief leader and commander; yea, they
did fight like dragons, and many of the Nephites
were slain by their hands, yea, for they did smite
in two many of their head-plates, and they did
pierce many of their breastplates, and they did
smite off many of their arms; and thus the Lamanites
did smite in their fierce anger
45 Nevertheless, the Nephites were inspired by a
better cause, for they were not fighting for
monarchy nor power but they were fighting for their
homes and their liberties, their wives and their
children, and their all, yea, for their rites of
worship and their church
46 And they were doing that which they felt was
the duty which they owed to their God; for the Lord
had said unto them, and also unto their fathers,
that: Inasmuch as ye are not guilty of the first
offense, neither the second, ye shall not suffer
yourselves to be slain by the hands of your enemies
47 And again, the Lord has said that: Ye shall
defend your families even unto bloodshed. Therefore
for this cause were the Nephites contending with
the Lamanites, to defend themselves, and their
families, and their lands, their country, and their
rights, and their religion
48 And it came to pass that when the men of Moroni
saw the fierceness and the anger of the
Lamanites, they were about to shrink and flee from them.
And Moroni, perceiving their intent, sent forth and
inspired their hearts with these thoughts—yea, the
thoughts of their lands, their liberty, yea,
their freedom from bondage
49 And it came to pass that they turned upon the
Lamanites, and they cried with one voice unto the
Lord their God, for their liberty and their freedom
from bondage
52 Therefore the armies of Moroni encircled them
about, yea, even on both sides of the river, for
behold, on the east were the men of Lehi
53 Therefore when Zerahemnah saw the men of Lehi
on the east of the river Sidon, and the armies of
Moroni on the west of the river Sidon, that they
were encircled about by the Nephites, they were
struck with terror
54 Now Moroni, when he saw their terror, commanded
his men that they should stop shedding their
blood.