The words which Alma, the High Priest according to
the holy order of God, delivered to the people in
their cities and villages throughout the land.
Beginning with chapter 5.Chapter 5 To gain
salvation, men must repent and keep the commandments, be
born again, cleanse their garments through the blood
of Christ, be humble and strip themselves of
pride and envy, and do the works of righteousness—The
Good Shepherd calls His people—Those who do evil
works are children of the devil—Alma testifies of
the truth of his doctrine and commands men to
repent—The names of the righteous will be written in
the book of life. About 83 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that Alma began to deliver
the word of God unto the people, first in the land
of Zarahemla, and from thence throughout all the
land
2 And these are the words which he spake to the
people in the church which was established in the
city of Zarahemla, according to his own record,
saying
3 I, Alma, having been consecrated by my father,
Alma, to be a high priest over the church of God,
he having power and authority from God to do these
things, behold, I say unto you that he began to
establish a church in the land which was in the
borders of Nephi; yea, the land which was called the
land of Mormon; yea, and he did baptize his
brethren in the waters of Mormon
4 And behold, I say unto you, they were delivered
out of the hands of the people of king Noah, by
the mercy and power of God
5 And behold, after that, they were brought into
bondage by the hands of the Lamanites in the
wilderness; yea, I say unto you, they were in captivity,
and again the Lord did deliver them out of
bondage by the power of his word; and we were brought
into this land, and here we began to establish the
church of God throughout this land also
6 And now behold, I say unto you, my brethren, you
that belong to this church, have you sufficiently
retained in remembrance the captivity of your
fathers? Yea, and have you sufficiently retained in
remembrance his mercy and long-suffering towards
them? And moreover, have ye sufficiently retained in
remembrance that he has delivered their souls
from hell
7 Behold, he changed their hearts; yea, he
awakened them out of a deep sleep, and they awoke unto
God. Behold, they were in the midst of darkness;
nevertheless, their souls were illuminated by the
light of the everlasting word; yea, they were
encircled about by the bands of death, and the chains of
hell, and an everlasting destruction did await
them
8 And now I ask of you, my brethren, were they
destroyed? Behold, I say unto you, Nay, they were
not
9 And again I ask, were the bands of death broken,
and the chains of hell which encircled them
about, were they loosed? I say unto you, Yea, they were
loosed, and their souls did expand, and they did
sing redeeming love. And I say unto you that they
are saved
10 And now I ask of you on what conditions are
they saved? Yea, what grounds had they to hope for
salvation? What is the cause of their being loosed
from the bands of death, yea, and also the chains
of hell
11 Behold, I can tell you—did not my father Alma
believe in the words which were delivered by the
mouth of Abinadi? And was he not a holy prophet? Did
he not speak the words of God, and my father Alma
believe them
12 And according to his faith there was a mighty
change wrought in his heart. Behold I say unto you
that this is all true
13 And behold, he preached the word unto your
fathers, and a mighty change was also wrought in their
hearts, and they humbled themselves and put their
trust in the true and living God. And behold,
they were faithful until the end; therefore they were
saved
14 And now behold, I ask of you, my brethren of
the church, have ye spiritually been born of God?
Have ye received his image in your countenances?
Have ye experienced this mighty change in your
hearts
15 Do ye exercise faith in the redemption of him
who created you? Do you look forward with an eye of
faith, and view this mortal body raised in
immortality, and this corruption raised in incorruption,
to stand before God to be judged according to the
deeds which have been done in the mortal body
16 I say unto you, can you imagine to yourselves
that ye hear the voice of the Lord, saying unto
you, in that day: Come unto me ye blessed, for
behold, your works have been the works of righteousness
upon the face of the earth
17 Or do ye imagine to yourselves that ye can lie
unto the Lord in that day, and say—Lord, our works
have been righteous works upon the face of the
earth—and that he will save you
18 Or otherwise, can ye imagine yourselves brought
before the tribunal of God with your souls filled
with guilt and remorse, having a remembrance of
all your guilt, yea, a perfect remembrance of all
your wickedness, yea, a remembrance that ye have
set at defiance the commandments of God
19 I say unto you, can ye look up to God at that
day with a pure heart and clean hands? I say unto
you, can you look up, having the image of God
engraven upon your countenances
20 I say unto you, can ye think of being saved
when you have yielded yourselves to become subjects
to the devil
21 I say unto you, ye will know at that day that
ye cannot be saved; for there can no man be saved
except his garments are washed white; yea, his
garments must be purified until they are cleansed from
all stain, through the blood of him of whom it
has been spoken by our fathers, who should come to
redeem his people from their sins
22 And now I ask of you, my brethren, how will any
of you feel, if ye shall stand before the bar of
God, having your garments stained with blood and
all manner of filthiness? Behold, what will these
things testify against you
23 Behold will they not testify that ye are
murderers, yea, and also that ye are guilty of all
manner of wickedness
24 Behold, my brethren, do ye suppose that such an
one can have a place to sit down in the kingdom
of God, with Abraham, with Isaac, and with Jacob,
and also all the holy prophets, whose garments are
cleansed and are spotless, pure and white
25 I say unto you, Nay; except ye make our Creator
a liar from the beginning, or suppose that he is
a liar from the beginning, ye cannot suppose that
such can have place in the kingdom of heaven; but
they shall be cast out for they are the children
of the kingdom of the devil
26 And now behold, I say unto you, my brethren, if
ye have experienced a change of heart, and if ye
have felt to sing the song of redeeming love, I
would ask, can ye feel so now
27 Have ye walked, keeping yourselves blameless
before God? Could ye say, if ye were called to die
at this time, within yourselves, that ye have been
sufficiently humble? That your garments have been
cleansed and made white through the blood of
Christ, who will come to redeem his people from their
sins
28 Behold, are ye stripped of pride? I say unto
you, if ye are not ye are not prepared to meet God.
Behold ye must prepare quickly; for the kingdom of
heaven is soon at hand, and such an one hath not
eternal life
29 Behold, I say, is there one among you who is
not stripped of envy? I say unto you that such an
one is not prepared; and I would that he should
prepare quickly, for the hour is close at hand, and he
knoweth not when the time shall come; for such an
one is not found guiltless
30 And again I say unto you, is there one among
you that doth make a mock of his brother, or that
heapeth upon him persecutions
31 Wo unto such an one, for he is not prepared,
and the time is at hand that he must repent or he
cannot be saved
32 Yea, even wo unto all ye workers of iniquity;
repent, repent, for the Lord God hath spoken it
33 Behold, he sendeth an invitation unto all men,
for the arms of mercy are extended towards them,
and he saith: Repent, and I will receive you
34 Yea, he saith: Come unto me and ye shall
partake of the fruit of the tree of life; yea, ye shall
eat and drink of the bread and the waters of life
freely
35 Yea, come unto me and bring forth works of
righteousness, and ye shall not be hewn down and cast
into the fire
36 For behold, the time is at hand that whosoever
bringeth forth not good fruit, or whosoever doeth
not the works of righteousness, the same have
cause to wail and mourn
37 O ye workers of iniquity; ye that are puffed up
in the vain things of the world, ye that have
professed to have known the ways of righteousness
nevertheless have gone astray, as sheep having no
shepherd, notwithstanding a shepherd hath called
after you and is still calling after you, but ye will
not hearken unto his voice
38 Behold, I say unto you, that the good shepherd
doth call you; yea, and in his own name he doth
call you, which is the name of Christ; and if ye
will not hearken unto the voice of the good shepherd,
to the name by which ye are called, behold, ye
are not the sheep of the good shepherd
39 And now if ye are not the sheep of the good
shepherd, of what fold are ye? Behold, I say unto
you, that the devil is your shepherd, and ye are of
his fold; and now, who can deny this? Behold, I say
unto you, whosoever denieth this is a liar and a
child of the devil
40 For I say unto you that whatsoever is good
cometh from God, and whatsoever is evil cometh from
the devil
41 Therefore, if a man bringeth forth good works
he hearkeneth unto the voice of the good shepherd,
and he doth follow him; but whosoever bringeth
forth evil works, the same becometh a child of the
devil, for he hearkeneth unto his voice, and doth
follow him
42 And whosoever doeth this must receive his wages
of him; therefore, for his wages he receiveth
death, as to things pertaining unto righteousness,
being dead unto all good works
43 And now, my brethren, I would that ye should
hear me, for I speak in the energy of my soul; for
behold, I have spoken unto you plainly that ye
cannot err, or have spoken according to the
commandments of God
44 For I am called to speak after this manner,
according to the holy order of God, which is in
Christ Jesus; yea, I am commanded to stand and testify
unto this people the things which have been spoken
by our fathers concerning the things which are to
come
45 And this is not all. Do ye not suppose that I
know of these things myself? Behold, I testify unto
you that I do know that these things whereof I
have spoken are true. And how do ye suppose that I
know of their surety
46 Behold, I say unto you they are made known unto
me by the Holy Spirit of God. Behold, I have
fasted and prayed many days that I might know these
things of myself. And now I do know of myself that
they are true; for the Lord God hath made them
manifest unto me by his Holy Spirit; and this is the
spirit of revelation which is in me
47 And moreover, I say unto you that it has thus
been revealed unto me, that the words which have
been spoken by our fathers are true, even so
according to the spirit of prophecy which is in me, which
is also by the manifestation of the Spirit of
God
48 I say unto you, that I know of myself that
whatsoever I shall say unto you, concerning that which
is to come, is true; and I say unto you, that I
know that Jesus Christ shall come, yea, the Son,
the Only Begotten of the Father, full of grace, and
mercy, and truth. And behold, it is he that cometh
to take away the sins of the world, yea, the sins
of every man who steadfastly believeth on his
name
49 And now I say unto you that this is the order
after which I am called, yea, to preach unto my
beloved brethren, yea, and every one that dwelleth in
the land; yea, to preach unto all, both old and
young, both bond and free; yea, I say unto you the
aged, and also the middle aged, and the rising
generation; yea, to cry unto them that they must
repent and be born again
50 Yea, thus saith the Spirit: Repent, all ye ends
of the earth, for the kingdom of heaven is soon
at hand; yea, the Son of God cometh in his glory,
in his might, majesty, power, and dominion. Yea, my
beloved brethren, I say unto you, that the Spirit
saith: Behold the glory of the King of all the
earth; and also the King of heaven shall very soon
shine forth among all the children of men
51 And also the Spirit saith unto me, yea, crieth
unto me with a mighty voice, saying: Go forth and
say unto this people—Repent, for except ye repent
ye can in nowise inherit the kingdom of heaven
52 And again I say unto you, the Spirit saith:
Behold, the ax is laid at the root of the tree;
therefore every tree that bringeth not forth good fruit
shall be hewn down and cast into the fire, yea, a
fire which cannot be consumed, even an
unquenchable fire. Behold, and remember, the Holy One hath
spoken it
53 And now my beloved brethren, I say unto you,
can ye withstand these sayings; yea, can ye lay
aside these things, and trample the Holy One under
your feet; yea, can ye be puffed up in the pride of
your hearts; yea, will ye still persist in the
wearing of costly apparel and setting your hearts upon
the vain things of the world, upon your riches
54 Yea, will ye persist in supposing that ye are
better one than another; yea, will ye persist in
the persecution of your brethren, who humble
themselves and do walk after the holy order of God,
wherewith they have been brought into this church,
having been sanctified by the Holy Spirit, and they do
bring forth works which are meet for repentance
55 Yea, and will you persist in turning your backs
upon the poor, and the needy, and in withholding
your substance from them
56 And finally, all ye that will persist in your
wickedness, I say unto you that these are they who
shall be hewn down and cast into the fire except
they speedily repent
57 And now I say unto you, all you that are
desirous to follow the voice of the good shepherd, come
ye out from the wicked, and be ye separate, and
touch not their unclean things; and behold, their
names shall be blotted out, that the names of the
wicked shall not be numbered among the names of the
righteous, that the word of God may be fulfilled,
which saith: The names of the wicked shall not be
mingled with the names of my people
58 For the names of the righteous shall be written
in the book of life, and unto them will I grant
an inheritance at my right hand. And now, my
brethren, what have ye to say against this? I say unto
you, if ye speak against it, it matters not, for
the word of God must be fulfilled
59 For what shepherd is there among you having
many sheep doth not watch over them, that the wolves
enter not and devour his flock? And behold, if a
wolf enter his flock doth he not drive him out?
Yea, and at the last, if he can, he will destroy him
60 And now I say unto you that the good shepherd
doth call after you; and if you will hearken unto
his voice he will bring you into his fold, and ye
are his sheep; and he commandeth you that ye suffer
no ravenous wolf to enter among you, that ye may
not be destroyed
61 And now I, Alma, do command you in the language
of him who hath commanded me, that ye observe to
do the words which I have spoken unto you
62 I speak by way of command unto you that belong
to the church; and unto those who do not belong to
the church I speak by way of invitation, saying:
Come and be baptized unto repentance, that ye also
may be partakers of the fruit of the tree of
life.