Chapter 6 The Church in Zarahemla is cleansed and
set in order—Alma goes to Gideon to preach. About
83 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that after Alma had made
an end of speaking unto the people of the church,
which was established in the city of Zarahemla,
he ordained priests and elders, by laying on his
hands according to the order of God, to preside and
watch over the church
2 And it came to pass that whosoever did not
belong to the church who repented of their sins were
baptized unto repentance, and were received into the
church
3 And it also came to pass that whosoever did
belong to the church that did not repent of their
wickedness and humble themselves before God—I mean
those who were lifted up in the pride of their
hearts—the same were rejected, and their names were
blotted out, that their names were not numbered among
those of the righteous
4 And thus they began to establish the order of
the church in the city of Zarahemla
5 Now I would that ye should understand that the
word of God was liberal unto all, that none were
deprived of the privilege of assembling themselves
together to hear the word of God
6 Nevertheless the children of God were commanded
that they should gather themselves together oft,
and join in fasting and mighty prayer in behalf of
the welfare of the souls of those who knew not
God
7 And now it came to pass that when Alma had made
these regulations he departed from them, yea, from
the church which was in the city of Zarahemla,
and went over upon the east of the river Sidon, into
the valley of Gideon, there having been a city
built, which was called the city of Gideon, which
was in the valley that was called Gideon, being
called after the man who was slain by the hand of
Nehor with the sword
8 And Alma went and began to declare the word of
God unto the church which was established in the
valley of Gideon, according to the revelation of the
truth of the word which had been spoken by his
fathers, and according to the spirit of prophecy
which was in him, according to the testimony of Jesus
Christ, the Son of God, who should come to redeem
his people from their sins, and the holy order by
which he was called. And thus it is written.
Amen.