The words of Alma which he delivered to the people
in Gideon, according to his own record.
Comprising chapter 7.Chapter 7 Christ will be born of
Mary—He will loose the bands of death and bear the sins
of His people—Those who repent, are baptized, and
keep the commandments will have eternal
life—Filthiness cannot inherit the kingdom of God—Humility,
faith, hope, and charity are required. About
83 B.C.
1 Behold my beloved brethren, seeing that I have
been permitted to come unto you, therefore I
attempt to address you in my language; yea, by my own
mouth, seeing that it is the first time that I have
spoken unto you by the words of my mouth, I having
been wholly confined to the judgment-seat, having
had much business that I could not come unto you
2 And even I could not have come now at this time
were it not that the judgment-seat hath been given
to another, to reign in my stead; and the Lord in
much mercy hath granted that I should come unto
you
3 And behold, I have come having great hopes and
much desire that I should find that ye had humbled
yourselves before God, and that ye had continued
in the supplicating of his grace, that I should
find that ye were blameless before him, that I should
find that ye were not in the awful dilemma that
our brethren were in at Zarahemla
4 But blessed be the name of God, that he hath
given me to know, yea, hath given unto me the
exceedingly great joy of knowing that they are
established again in the way of his righteousness
5 And I trust, according to the Spirit of God
which is in me, that I shall also have joy over you;
nevertheless I do not desire that my joy over you
should come by the cause of so much afflictions and
sorrow which I have had for the brethren at
Zarahemla, for behold, my joy cometh over them after
wading through much affliction and sorrow
6 But behold, I trust that ye are not in a state
of so much unbelief as were your brethren; I trust
that ye are not lifted up in the pride of your
hearts; yea, I trust that ye have not set your hearts
upon riches and the vain things of the world;
yea, I trust that you do not worship idols, but that
ye do worship the true and the living God, and
that ye look forward for the remission of your sins,
with an everlasting faith, which is to come
7 For behold, I say unto you there be many things
to come; and behold, there is one thing which is
of more importance than they all—for behold, the
time is not far distant that the Redeemer liveth and
cometh among his people
8 Behold, I do not say that he will come among us
at the time of his dwelling in his mortal
tabernacle; for behold, the Spirit hath not said unto me
that this should be the case. Now as to this thing
I do not know; but this much I do know, that the
Lord God hath power to do all things which are
according to his word
9 But behold, the Spirit hath said this much unto
me, saying: Cry unto this people, saying—Repent
ye, and prepare the way of the Lord, and walk in his
paths, which are straight; for behold, the
kingdom of heaven is at hand, and the Son of God cometh
upon the face of the earth
10 And behold, he shall be born of Mary, at
Jerusalem which is the land of our forefathers, she
being a virgin, a precious and chosen vessel, who
shall be overshadowed and conceive by the power of the
Holy Ghost, and bring forth a son, yea, even the
Son of God
11 And he shall go forth, suffering pains and
afflictions and temptations of every kind; and this
that the word might be fulfilled which saith he will
take upon him the pains and the sicknesses of his
people
12 And he will take upon him death, that he may
loose the bands of death which bind his people; and
he will take upon him their infirmities, that his
bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the
flesh, that he may know according to the flesh how
to succor his people according to their
infirmities
13 Now the Spirit knoweth all things; nevertheless
the Son of God suffereth according to the flesh
that he might take upon him the sins of his people,
that he might blot out their transgressions
according to the power of his deliverance; and now
behold, this is the testimony which is in me
14 Now I say unto you that ye must repent, and be
born again; for the Spirit saith if ye are not
born again ye cannot inherit the kingdom of heaven;
therefore come and be baptized unto repentance,
that ye may be washed from your sins, that ye may
have faith on the Lamb of God, who taketh away the
sins of the world, who is mighty to save and to
cleanse from all unrighteousness
15 Yea, I say unto you come and fear not, and lay
aside every sin, which easily doth beset you,
which doth bind you down to destruction, yea, come and
go forth, and show unto your God that ye are
willing to repent of your sins and enter into a
covenant with him to keep his commandments, and witness
it unto him this day by going into the waters of
baptism
16 And whosoever doeth this, and keepeth the
commandments of God from thenceforth, the same will
remember that I say unto him, yea, he will remember
that I have said unto him, he shall have eternal
life, according to the testimony of the Holy Spirit,
which testifieth in me
17 And now my beloved brethren, do you believe
these things? Behold, I say unto you, yea, I know
that ye believe them; and the way that I know that ye
believe them is by the manifestation of the
Spirit which is in me. And now because your faith is
strong concerning that, yea, concerning the things
which I have spoken, great is my joy
18 For as I said unto you from the beginning, that
I had much desire that ye were not in the state
of dilemma like your brethren, even so I have found
that my desires have been gratified
19 For I perceive that ye are in the paths of
righteousness; I perceive that ye are in the path
which leads to the kingdom of God; yea, I perceive
that ye are making his paths straight
20 I perceive that it has been made known unto
you, by the testimony of his word, that he cannot
walk in crooked paths; neither doth he vary from that
which he hath said; neither hath he a shadow of
turning from the right to the left, or from that
which is right to that which is wrong; therefore,
his course is one eternal round
21 And he doth not dwell in unholy temples;
neither can filthiness or anything which is unclean be
received into the kingdom of God; therefore I say
unto you the time shall come, yea, and it shall be
at the last day, that he who is filthy shall
remain in his filthiness
22 And now my beloved brethren, I have said these
things unto you that I might awaken you to a sense
of your duty to God, that ye may walk blameless
before him, that ye may walk after the holy order
of God, after which ye have been received
23 And now I would that ye should be humble, and
be submissive and gentle; easy to be entreated;
full of patience and long-suffering; being temperate
in all things; being diligent in keeping the
commandments of God at all times; asking for whatsoever
things ye stand in need, both spiritual and
temporal; always returning thanks unto God for
whatsoever things ye do receive
24 And see that ye have faith, hope, and charity,
and then ye will always abound in good works
25 And may the Lord bless you, and keep your
garments spotless, that ye may at last be brought to
sit down with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, and the
holy prophets who have been ever since the world
began, having your garments spotless even as their
garments are spotless, in the kingdom of heaven to go
no more out
26 And now my beloved brethren, I have spoken
these words unto you according to the Spirit which
testifieth in me; and my soul doth exceedingly
rejoice, because of the exceeding diligence and heed
which ye have given unto my word
27 And now, may the peace of God rest upon you,
and upon your houses and lands, and upon your flocks
and herds, and all that you possess, your women
and your children, according to your faith and good
works, from this time forth and forever. And thus
I have spoken. Amen.