Chapter 8 Alma preaches and baptizes in Melek—He
is rejected in Ammonihah and leaves—An angel
commands him to return and cry repentance unto the
people—He is received by Amulek, and the two of them
preach in Ammonihah. About 82 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that Alma returned from
the land of Gideon, after having taught the people
of Gideon many things which cannot be written,
having established the order of the church,
according as he had before done in the land of Zarahemla,
yea, he returned to his own house at Zarahemla to
rest himself from the labors which he had
performed
2 And thus ended the ninth year of the reign of
the judges over the people of Nephi
3 And it came to pass in the commencement of the
tenth year of the reign of the judges over the
people of Nephi, that Alma departed from thence and
took his journey over into the land of Melek, on the
west of the river Sidon, on the west by the
borders of the wilderness
4 And he began to teach the people in the land of
Melek according to the holy order of God, by which
he had been called; and he began to teach the
people throughout all the land of Melek
5 And it came to pass that the people came to him
throughout all the borders of the land which was
by the wilderness side. And they were baptized
throughout all the land
6 So that when he had finished his work at Melek
he departed thence, and traveled three days’
journey on the north of the land of Melek; and he came
to a city which was called Ammonihah
7 Now it was the custom of the people of Nephi to
call their lands, and their cities, and their
villages, yea, even all their small villages, after
the name of him who first possessed them; and thus
it was with the land of Ammonihah
8 And it came to pass that when Alma had come to
the city of Ammonihah he began to preach the word
of God unto them
9 Now Satan had gotten great hold upon the hearts
of the people of the city of Ammonihah; therefore
they would not hearken unto the words of Alma
10 Nevertheless Alma labored much in the spirit,
wrestling with God in mighty prayer, that he would
pour out his Spirit upon the people who were in
the city; that he would also grant that he might
baptize them unto repentance
11 Nevertheless, they hardened their hearts,
saying unto him: Behold, we know that thou art Alma;
and we know that thou art high priest over the
church which thou hast established in many parts of the
land, according to your tradition; and we are not
of thy church, and we do not believe in such
foolish traditions
12 And now we know that because we are not of thy
church we know that thou hast no power over us;
and thou hast delivered up the judgment-seat unto
Nephihah; therefore thou art not the chief judge
over us
13 Now when the people had said this, and
withstood all his words, and reviled him, and spit upon
him, and caused that he should be cast out of their
city, he departed thence and took his journey
towards the city which was called Aaron
14 And it came to pass that while he was
journeying thither, being weighed down with sorrow, wading
through much tribulation and anguish of soul,
because of the wickedness of the people who were in
the city of Ammonihah, it came to pass while Alma
was thus weighed down with sorrow, behold an angel
of the Lord appeared unto him, saying
15 Blessed art thou, Alma; therefore, lift up thy
head and rejoice, for thou hast great cause to
rejoice; for thou hast been faithful in keeping the
commandments of God from the time which thou
receivedst thy first message from him. Behold, I am he
that delivered it unto you
16 And behold, I am sent to command thee that thou
return to the city of Ammonihah, and preach again
unto the people of the city; yea, preach unto
them. Yea, say unto them, except they repent the Lord
God will destroy them
17 For behold, they do study at this time that
they may destroy the liberty of thy people, (for thus
saith the Lord) which is contrary to the
statutes, and judgments, and commandments which he has
given unto his people
18 Now it came to pass that after Alma had
received his message from the angel of the Lord he
returned speedily to the land of Ammonihah. And he
entered the city by another way, yea, by the way which
is on the south of the city of Ammonihah
19 And as he entered the city he was an hungered,
and he said to a man: Will ye give to an humble
servant of God something to eat
20 And the man said unto him: I am a Nephite, and
I know that thou art a holy prophet of God, for
thou art the man whom an angel said in a vision:
Thou shalt receive. Therefore, go with me into my
house and I will impart unto thee of my food; and I
know that thou wilt be a blessing unto me and my
house
21 And it came to pass that the man received him
into his house; and the man was called Amulek; and
he brought forth bread and meat and set before
Alma
22 And it came to pass that Alma ate bread and was
filled; and he blessed Amulek and his house, and
he gave thanks unto God
23 And after he had eaten and was filled he said
unto Amulek: I am Alma, and am the high priest over
the church of God throughout the land
24 And behold, I have been called to preach the
word of God among all this people, according to the
spirit of revelation and prophecy; and I was in
this land and they would not receive me, but they
cast me out and I was about to set my back towards
this land forever
25 But behold, I have been commanded that I should
turn again and prophesy unto this people, yea,
and to testify against them concerning their
iniquities
26 And now, Amulek, because thou hast fed me and
taken me in, thou art blessed; for I was an
hungered, for I had fasted many days
27 And Alma tarried many days with Amulek before
he began to preach unto the people
28 And it came to pass that the people did wax
more gross in their iniquities
29 And the word came to Alma, saying: Go; and also
say unto my servant Amulek, go forth and prophesy
unto this people, saying—Repent ye, for thus
saith the Lord, except ye repent I will visit this
people in mine anger; yea, and I will not turn my
fierce anger away
30 And Alma went forth, and also Amulek, among the
people, to declare the words of God unto them;
and they were filled with the Holy Ghost
31 And they had power given unto them, insomuch
that they could not be confined in dungeons; neither
was it possible that any man could slay them;
nevertheless they did not exercise their power until
they were bound in bands and cast into prison.
Now, this was done that the Lord might show forth his
power in them
32 And it came to pass that they went forth and
began to preach and to prophesy unto the people,
according to the spirit and power which the Lord had
given them.