The words of Alma, and also the words of Amulek,
which were declared unto the people who were in the
land of Ammonihah. And also they are cast into
prison, and delivered by the miraculous power of God
which was in them, according to the record of
Alma. Comprising chapters 9 through 14.Chapter 9 Alma
commands the people of Ammonihah to repent—The
Lord will be merciful to the Lamanites in the last
days—If the Nephites forsake the light, they will
be destroyed by the Lamanites—The Son of God will
come soon—He will redeem those who repent, are
baptized, and have faith in His name. About 82 B.C.
1 And again, I, Alma, having been commanded of God
that I should take Amulek and go forth and preach
again unto this people, or the people who were in
the city of Ammonihah, it came to pass as I began
to preach unto them, they began to contend with
me, saying
2 Who art thou? Suppose ye that we shall believe
the testimony of one man, although he should preach
unto us that the earth should pass away
3 Now they understood not the words which they
spake; for they knew not that the earth should pass
away
4 And they said also: We will not believe thy
words if thou shouldst prophesy that this great city
should be destroyed in one day
5 Now they knew not that God could do such
marvelous works, for they were a hard-hearted and a
stiffnecked people
6 And they said: Who is God, that sendeth no more
authority than one man among this people, to
declare unto them the truth of such great and marvelous
things
7 And they stood forth to lay their hands on me;
but behold, they did not. And I stood with boldness
to declare unto them, yea, I did boldly testify
unto them, saying
8 Behold, O ye wicked and perverse generation, how
have ye forgotten the tradition of your fathers;
yea, how soon ye have forgotten the commandments
of God
9 Do ye not remember that our father, Lehi, was
brought out of Jerusalem by the hand of God? Do ye
not remember that they were all led by him through
the wilderness
10 And have ye forgotten so soon how many times he
delivered our fathers out of the hands of their
enemies, and preserved them from being destroyed,
even by the hands of their own brethren
11 Yea, and if it had not been for his matchless
power, and his mercy, and his long-suffering
towards us, we should unavoidably have been cut off from
the face of the earth long before this period of
time, and perhaps been consigned to a state of
endless misery and woe
12 Behold, now I say unto you that he commandeth
you to repent; and except ye repent, ye can in
nowise inherit the kingdom of God. But behold, this is
not all—he has commanded you to repent, or he
will utterly destroy you from off the face of the
earth; yea, he will visit you in his anger, and in
his fierce anger he will not turn away
13 Behold, do ye not remember the words which he
spake unto Lehi, saying that: Inasmuch as ye shall
keep my commandments, ye shall prosper in the
land? And again it is said that: Inasmuch as ye will
not keep my commandments ye shall be cut off from
the presence of the Lord
14 Now I would that ye should remember, that
inasmuch as the Lamanites have not kept the
commandments of God, they have been cut off from the presence
of the Lord. Now we see that the word of the Lord
has been verified in this thing, and the
Lamanites have been cut off from his presence, from the
beginning of their transgressions in the land
15 Nevertheless I say unto you, that it shall be
more tolerable for them in the day of judgment than
for you, if ye remain in your sins, yea, and even
more tolerable for them in this life than for
you, except ye repent
16 For there are many promises which are extended
to the Lamanites; for it is because of the
traditions of their fathers that caused them to remain in
their state of ignorance; therefore the Lord will
be merciful unto them and prolong their existence
in the land
17 And at some period of time they will be brought
to believe in his word, and to know of the
incorrectness of the traditions of their fathers; and
many of them will be saved, for the Lord will be
merciful unto all who call on his name
18 But behold, I say unto you that if ye persist
in your wickedness that your days shall not be
prolonged in the land, for the Lamanites shall be sent
upon you; and if ye repent not they shall come in
a time when you know not, and ye shall be visited
with utter destruction; and it shall be according
to the fierce anger of the Lord
19 For he will not suffer you that ye shall live
in your iniquities, to destroy his people. I say
unto you, Nay; he would rather suffer that the
Lamanites might destroy all his people who are called
the people of Nephi, if it were possible that they
could fall into sins and transgressions, after
having had so much light and so much knowledge given
unto them of the Lord their God
20 Yea, after having been such a highly favored
people of the Lord; yea, after having been favored
above every other nation, kindred, tongue, or
people; after having had all things made known unto
them, according to their desires, and their faith,
and prayers, of that which has been, and which is,
and which is to come
21 Having been visited by the Spirit of God;
having conversed with angels, and having been spoken
unto by the voice of the Lord; and having the spirit
of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation, and
also many gifts, the gift of speaking with tongues,
and the gift of preaching, and the gift of the
Holy Ghost, and the gift of translation
22 Yea, and after having been delivered of God out
of the land of Jerusalem, by the hand of the
Lord; having been saved from famine, and from
sickness, and all manner of diseases of every kind; and
they having waxed strong in battle, that they might
not be destroyed; having been brought out of
bondage time after time, and having been kept and
preserved until now; and they have been prospered until
they are rich in all manner of things
23 And now behold I say unto you, that if this
people, who have received so many blessings from the
hand of the Lord, should transgress contrary to
the light and knowledge which they do have, I say
unto you that if this be the case, that if they
should fall into transgression, it would be far more
tolerable for the Lamanites than for them
24 For behold, the promises of the Lord are
extended to the Lamanites, but they are not unto you if
ye transgress; for has not the Lord expressly
promised and firmly decreed, that if ye will rebel
against him that ye shall utterly be destroyed from
off the face of the earth
25 And now for this cause, that ye may not be
destroyed, the Lord has sent his angel to visit many
of his people, declaring unto them that they must
go forth and cry mightily unto this people, saying:
Repent ye, for the kingdom of heaven is nigh at
hand
26 And not many days hence the Son of God shall
come in his glory; and his glory shall be the glory
of the Only Begotten of the Father, full of grace,
equity, and truth, full of patience, mercy, and
long-suffering, quick to hear the cries of his
people and to answer their prayers
27 And behold, he cometh to redeem those who will
be baptized unto repentance, through faith on his
name
28 Therefore, prepare ye the way of the Lord, for
the time is at hand that all men shall reap a
reward of their works, according to that which they
have been—if they have been righteous they shall
reap the salvation of their souls, according to the
power and deliverance of Jesus Christ; and if they
have been evil they shall reap the damnation of
their souls, according to the power and captivation
of the devil
29 Now behold, this is the voice of the angel,
crying unto the people
30 And now, my beloved brethren, for ye are my
brethren, and ye ought to be beloved, and ye ought to
bring forth works which are meet for repentance,
seeing that your hearts have been grossly hardened
against the word of God, and seeing that ye are a
lost and a fallen people
31 Now it came to pass that when I, Alma, had
spoken these words, behold, the people were wroth with
me because I said unto them that they were a
hard-hearted and a stiffnecked people
32 And also because I said unto them that they
were a lost and a fallen people they were angry with
me, and sought to lay their hands upon me, that
they might cast me into prison
33 But it came to pass that the Lord did not
suffer them that they should take me at that time and
cast me into prison
34 And it came to pass that Amulek went and stood
forth, and began to preach unto them also. And now
the words of Amulek are not all written,
nevertheless a part of his words are written in this book.