Chapter 3 Elders ordain priests and teachers
by the laying on of hands. About A.D. 401–21.
1 The manner which the disciples,
who were called the elders of the
church, ordained priests and teachers—
2 After they had prayed unto the
Father in the name of Christ, they
laid their hands upon them, and said:
3 In the name of Jesus Christ I
ordain you to be a priest (or if
he be a teacher, I ordain you to
be a teacher) to preach repentance
and remission of sins through
Jesus Christ, by the endurance of
faith on his name to the end. Amen.
4 And after this manner did
they ordain priests and teachers,
according to the gifts and
callings of God unto men; and they
ordained them by the power of
the Holy Ghost, which was in them.