The second epistle of Mormon to his son
Moroni. Comprising chapter 9.Chapter 9 Both
the Nephites and the Lamanites are depraved
and degenerate—They torture and murder each
other—Mormon prays that grace and goodness
may rest upon Moroni forever. About A.D. 401.
1 My beloved son, I write unto you again
that ye may know that I am yet alive; but I
write somewhat of that which is grievous.
2 For behold, I have had a sore battle
with the Lamanites, in which we did not
conquer; and Archeantus has fallen by the
sword, and also Luram and Emron; yea, and
we have lost a great number of our choice men.
3 And now behold, my son, I fear
lest the Lamanites shall destroy
this people; for they do not
repent, and Satan stirreth them up
continually to anger one with another.
4 Behold, I am laboring with
them continually; and when I
speak the word of God with
sharpness they tremble and anger
against me; and when I use no
sharpness they harden their
hearts against it; wherefore, I
fear lest the Spirit of the Lord
hath ceased striving with them.
5 For so exceedingly do
they anger that it seemeth me
that they have no fear of
death; and they have lost
their love, one towards
another; and they thirst after
blood and revenge continually.
6 And now, my beloved son,
notwithstanding their
hardness, let us labor
diligently; for if we should
cease to labor, we should be
brought under
condemnation; for we have a labor to
perform whilst in this
tabernacle of clay, that we
may conquer the enemy of all
righteousness, and rest
our souls in the kingdom of God.
7 And now I write
somewhat concerning the
sufferings of this people.
For according to the
knowledge which I have
received from Amoron,
behold, the Lamanites have
many prisoners, which
they took from the
tower of Sherrizah; and
there were men, women, and children.
8 And the husbands
and fathers of those
women and children they
have slain; and they
feed the women upon
the flesh of their
husbands, and the
children upon the flesh of
their fathers; and
no water, save a
little, do they give unto them.
9 And
notwithstanding this great
abomination of the
Lamanites, it doth not
exceed that of our people
in Moriantum. For
behold, many of the
daughters of the
Lamanites have they
taken prisoners; and
after depriving them of
that which was most
dear and precious
above all things,
which is chastity and virtue—
10 And after they
had done this
thing, they did murder
them in a most
cruel manner,
torturing their bodies
even unto death;
and after they have
done this, they
devour their flesh
like unto wild
beasts, because of the
hardness of their
hearts; and they
do it for a token of bravery.
11 O my beloved
son, how can a
people like
this, that are
without civilization—
12 (And only a
few years have
passed away,
and they were a
civil and a
delightsome people)
13 But O my
son, how can a
people like
this, whose
delight is in so
much abomination—
14 How can
we expect
that God will
stay his hand
in judgment
against us?
15 Behold,
my heart
cries: Wo
unto this
people. Come
out in
judgment, O God,
and hide
their sins,
and
wickedness, and
abominations
from before thy face!
16 And
again, my
son, there
are many
widows and
their
daughters who
remain in
Sherrizah;
and that
part of the
provisions
which the
Lamanites
did not
carry away,
behold,
the army of
Zenephi
has carried
away, and
left them
to wander
whithersoever they
can for
food; and
many old
women do faint by the way and die.
17 And
the army
which is
with me is
weak; and
the
armies of the
Lamanites are
betwixt
Sherrizah and
me; and
as many
as have
fled to the
army of
Aaron
have fallen
victims
to their awful brutality.
18 O the
depravity of my
people!
They
are
without order
and
without
mercy.
Behold, I am
but a
man, and I
have
but the
strength
of a man,
and I
cannot
any longer
enforce my commands.
19 And
they
have
become
strong in
their
perversion; and
they
are alike
brutal,
sparing
none,
neither old
nor
young; and
they
delight
in
everything
save
that
which is
good; and
the
suffering
of our
women
and our
children upon
all
the face
of this
land
doth
exceed
everything; yea,
tongue cannot tell, neither can it be written.
20 And
now,
my
son, I
dwell no
longer upon
this
horrible
scene.
Behold,
thou
knowest
the
wickedness of
this
people; thou
knowest
that they
are
without
principle,
and
past
feeling;
and
their
wickedness doth exceed that of the Lamanites.
Behold,
my
son, I
cannot
recommend
them
unto
God
lest he
should smite me.
But
behold,
my
son, I
recommend
thee
unto
God,
and I
trust in
Christ
that
thou
wilt
be
saved;
and
I
pray
unto
God
that he
will
spare
thy
life, to
witness
the
return
of
his
people
unto
him,
or
their
utter
destruction;
for
I
know
that they must perish except they repent and return unto him.
And
if
they
perish
it
will
be
like
unto
the
Jaredites,
because
of
the
wilfulness
of
their
hearts, seeking for blood and revenge.
that
they
perish,
we
know
that
many
of
our
brethren
have
deserted
over
unto
the
Lamanites,
and
many
more
will
also
desert
over
unto
them;
wherefore,
write
somewhat
a
few
things,
if
thou
art
spared
and
I
shall
perish
and
not
see
thee;
but I
trust
that
I
may
see
thee
soon;
for
I
have
sacred
records
that
I
would
deliver
up
unto
thee.
My
son,
be
faithful
in
Christ;
and
may
not
the
things
which
I
have
written
grieve
thee,
to
weigh
thee
down
unto
death;
but
may
Christ
lift
thee
up,
and
may
his
sufferings
and
death,
the
showing
his
body
unto
our
fathers, and his mercy and long-suffering, and the hope of his glory and of eternal life, rest in your mind forever.
And
may
the
grace
of
God
the
Father,
whose
throne
is
high
in
the
heavens,
and
our
Lord
Jesus
Christ,
who
sitteth
on
the
right
hand
of
his
power,
until
all
things
shall
become
subject
unto
him,
be,
and
abide
with
you
forever.
Amen.