Chapter 2 Jesus gave the twelve
Nephite disciples power to confer the gift
of the Holy Ghost. About A.D. 401–21.
1 The words of Christ, which
he spake unto his disciples,
the twelve whom he had chosen,
as he laid his hands upon them—
2 And he called them by
name, saying: Ye shall call on
the Father in my name, in
mighty prayer; and after ye
have done this ye shall have
power that to him upon whom ye
shall lay your hands, ye
shall give the Holy Ghost; and
in my name shall ye give
it, for thus do mine apostles.
3 Now Christ spake these
words unto them at the
time of his first
appearing; and the multitude
heard it not, but the
disciples heard it; and on
as many as they laid
their hands, fell the Holy Ghost.