The Book of MoroniChapter 1 Moroni writes for the
benefit of the Lamanites—The Nephites who will not
deny Christ are put to death. About A.D. 401–21.
1 Now I, Moroni, after having made an end of
abridging the account of the people of Jared, I
had supposed not to have written more, but I
have not as yet perished; and I make not myself
known to the Lamanites lest they should destroy me.
2 For behold, their wars are
exceedingly fierce among themselves; and because
of their hatred they put to death every
Nephite that will not deny the Christ.
3 And I, Moroni, will not deny the
Christ; wherefore, I wander whithersoever
I can for the safety of mine own life.
4 Wherefore, I write a few more
things, contrary to that which I had
supposed; for I had supposed not to
have written any more; but I write
a few more things, that perhaps
they may be of worth unto my brethren,
the Lamanites, in some future day,
according to the will of the Lord.