Chapter 4 How elders and priests administer the
sacramental bread is explained. About A.D. 401–21.
1 The manner of their elders and priests
administering the flesh and blood of Christ unto the
church; and they administered it according to the
commandments of Christ; wherefore we know the manner to
be true; and the elder or priest did minister it
2 And they did kneel down with the church, and
pray to the Father in the name of Christ, saying
3 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the
name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify
this bread to the souls of all those who partake
of it; that they may eat in remembrance of the
body of thy Son, and witness unto thee, O God, the
Eternal Father, that they are willing to take upon
them the name of thy Son, and always remember him,
and keep his commandments which he hath given
them, that they may always have his Spirit to be with
them. Amen.