Chapter 7 An invitation is given to enter into the
rest of the Lord—Pray with real intent—The Spirit
of Christ enables men to know good from
evil—Satan persuades men to deny Christ and do evil—The
prophets manifest the coming of Christ—By faith,
miracles are wrought and angels minister—Men should
hope for eternal life and cleave unto charity. About
A.D. 401–21.
1 And now I, Moroni, write a few of the words of
my father Mormon, which he spake concerning faith,
hope, and charity; for after this manner did he
speak unto the people, as he taught them in the
synagogue which they had built for the place of
worship
2 And now I, Mormon, speak unto you, my beloved
brethren; and it is by the grace of God the Father,
and our Lord Jesus Christ, and his holy will,
because of the gift of his calling unto me, that I am
permitted to speak unto you at this time
3 Wherefore, I would speak unto you that are of
the church, that are the peaceable followers of
Christ, and that have obtained a sufficient hope by
which ye can enter into the rest of the Lord, from
this time henceforth until ye shall rest with him
in heaven
4 And now my brethren, I judge these things of you
because of your peaceable walk with the children
of men
5 For I remember the word of God which saith by
their works ye shall know them; for if their works
be good, then they are good also
6 For behold, God hath said a man being evil
cannot do that which is good; for if he offereth a
gift, or prayeth unto God, except he shall do it with
real intent it profiteth him nothing
7 For behold, it is not counted unto him for
righteousness
8 For behold, if a man being evil giveth a gift,
he doeth it grudgingly; wherefore it is counted
unto him the same as if he had retained the gift;
wherefore he is counted evil before God
9 And likewise also is it counted evil unto a man,
if he shall pray and not with real intent of
heart; yea, and it profiteth him nothing, for God
receiveth none such
10 Wherefore, a man being evil cannot do that
which is good; neither will he give a good gift
11 For behold, a bitter fountain cannot bring
forth good water; neither can a good fountain bring
forth bitter water; wherefore, a man being a servant
of the devil cannot follow Christ; and if he
follow Christ he cannot be a servant of the devil
12 Wherefore, all things which are good cometh of
God; and that which is evil cometh of the devil;
for the devil is an enemy unto God, and fighteth
against him continually, and inviteth and enticeth
to sin, and to do that which is evil continually
13 But behold, that which is of God inviteth and
enticeth to do good continually; wherefore, every
thing which inviteth and enticeth to do good, and
to love God, and to serve him, is inspired of God
14 Wherefore, take heed, my beloved brethren, that
ye do not judge that which is evil to be of God,
or that which is good and of God to be of the
devil
15 For behold, my brethren, it is given unto you
to judge, that ye may know good from evil; and the
way to judge is as plain, that ye may know with a
perfect knowledge, as the daylight is from the
dark night
16 For behold, the Spirit of Christ is given to
every man, that he may know good from evil;
wherefore, I show unto you the way to judge; for every
thing which inviteth to do good, and to persuade to
believe in Christ, is sent forth by the power and
gift of Christ; wherefore ye may know with a
perfect knowledge it is of God
17 But whatsoever thing persuadeth men to do evil,
and believe not in Christ, and deny him, and
serve not God, then ye may know with a perfect
knowledge it is of the devil; for after this manner doth
the devil work, for he persuadeth no man to do
good, no, not one; neither do his angels; neither do
they who subject themselves unto him
18 And now, my brethren, seeing that ye know the
light by which ye may judge, which light is the
light of Christ, see that ye do not judge wrongfully;
for with that same judgment which ye judge ye
shall also be judged
19 Wherefore, I beseech of you, brethren, that ye
should search diligently in the light of Christ
that ye may know good from evil; and if ye will lay
hold upon every good thing, and condemn it not, ye
certainly will be a child of Christ
20 And now, my brethren, how is it possible that
ye can lay hold upon every good thing
21 And now I come to that faith, of which I said I
would speak; and I will tell you the way whereby
ye may lay hold on every good thing
22 For behold, God knowing all things, being from
everlasting to everlasting, behold, he sent angels
to minister unto the children of men, to make
manifest concerning the coming of Christ; and in
Christ there should come every good thing
23 And God also declared unto prophets, by his own
mouth, that Christ should come
24 And behold, there were divers ways that he did
manifest things unto the children of men, which
were good; and all things which are good cometh of
Christ; otherwise men were fallen, and there could
no good thing come unto them
25 Wherefore, by the ministering of angels, and by
every word which proceeded forth out of the mouth
of God, men began to exercise faith in Christ;
and thus by faith, they did lay hold upon every good
thing; and thus it was until the coming of
Christ
26 And after that he came men also were saved by
faith in his name; and by faith, they become the
sons of God. And as surely as Christ liveth he spake
these words unto our fathers, saying: Whatsoever
thing ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is
good, in faith believing that ye shall receive,
behold, it shall be done unto you
27 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, have miracles
ceased because Christ hath ascended into heaven,
and hath sat down on the right hand of God, to claim
of the Father his rights of mercy which he hath
upon the children of men
28 For he hath answered the ends of the law, and
he claimeth all those who have faith in him; and
they who have faith in him will cleave unto every
good thing; wherefore he advocateth the cause of the
children of men; and he dwelleth eternally in the
heavens
29 And because he hath done this, my beloved
brethren, have miracles ceased? Behold I say unto you,
Nay; neither have angels ceased to minister unto
the children of men
30 For behold, they are subject unto him, to
minister according to the word of his command, showing
themselves unto them of strong faith and a firm
mind in every form of godliness
31 And the office of their ministry is to call men
unto repentance, and to fulfil and to do the work
of the covenants of the Father, which he hath
made unto the children of men, to prepare the way
among the children of men, by declaring the word of
Christ unto the chosen vessels of the Lord, that
they may bear testimony of him
32 And by so doing, the Lord God prepareth the way
that the residue of men may have faith in Christ,
that the Holy Ghost may have place in their
hearts, according to the power thereof; and after this
manner bringeth to pass the Father, the covenants
which he hath made unto the children of men
33 And Christ hath said: If ye will have faith in
me ye shall have power to do whatsoever thing is
expedient in me
34 And he hath said: Repent all ye ends of the
earth, and come unto me, and be baptized in my name,
and have faith in me, that ye may be saved
35 And now, my beloved brethren, if this be the
case that these things are true which I have spoken
unto you, and God will show unto you, with power
and great glory at the last day, that they are
true, and if they are true has the day of miracles
ceased
36 Or have angels ceased to appear unto the
children of men? Or has he withheld the power of the
Holy Ghost from them? Or will he, so long as time
shall last, or the earth shall stand, or there shall
be one man upon the face thereof to be saved
37 Behold I say unto you, Nay; for it is by faith
that miracles are wrought; and it is by faith that
angels appear and minister unto men; wherefore,
if these things have ceased wo be unto the children
of men, for it is because of unbelief, and all is
vain
38 For no man can be saved, according to the words
of Christ, save they shall have faith in his
name; wherefore, if these things have ceased, then has
faith ceased also; and awful is the state of man,
for they are as though there had been no
redemption made
39 But behold, my beloved brethren, I judge better
things of you, for I judge that ye have faith in
Christ because of your meekness; for if ye have
not faith in him then ye are not fit to be numbered
among the people of his church
40 And again, my beloved brethren, I would speak
unto you concerning hope. How is it that ye can
attain unto faith, save ye shall have hope
41 And what is it that ye shall hope for? Behold I
say unto you that ye shall have hope through the
atonement of Christ and the power of his
resurrection, to be raised unto life eternal, and this
because of your faith in him according to the promise
42 Wherefore, if a man have faith he must needs
have hope; for without faith there cannot be any
hope
43 And again, behold I say unto you that he cannot
have faith and hope, save he shall be meek, and
lowly of heart
44 If so, his faith and hope is vain, for none is
acceptable before God, save the meek and lowly in
heart; and if a man be meek and lowly in heart,
and confesses by the power of the Holy Ghost that
Jesus is the Christ, he must needs have charity; for
if he have not charity he is nothing; wherefore
he must needs have charity
45 And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and
envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her
own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and
rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the
truth, beareth all things, believeth all things,
hopeth all things, endureth all things
46 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not
charity, ye are nothing, for charity never
faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the
greatest of all, for all things must fail
47 But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it
endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of
it at the last day, it shall be well with him
48 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the
Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be
filled with this love, which he hath bestowed
upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus
Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when
he shall appear we shall be like him, for we
shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope;
that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.