Chapter 8 The baptism of little children is
an evil abomination—Little children are
alive in Christ because of the Atonement—Faith,
repentance, meekness and lowliness of heart,
receiving the Holy Ghost, and enduring to
the end lead to salvation. About A.D. 401–21.
1 An epistle of my father Mormon, written
to me, Moroni; and it was written unto me
soon after my calling to the ministry. And
on this wise did he write unto me, saying:
2 My beloved son, Moroni, I rejoice
exceedingly that your Lord Jesus Christ hath
been mindful of you, and hath called
you to his ministry, and to his holy work.
3 I am mindful of you always in my
prayers, continually praying unto God the
Father in the name of his Holy Child,
Jesus, that he, through his infinite goodness
and grace, will keep you through the
endurance of faith on his name to the end.
4 And now, my son, I speak unto you
concerning that which grieveth me
exceedingly; for it grieveth me that
there should disputations rise among you.
5 For, if I have learned the
truth, there have been
disputations among you concerning the
baptism of your little children.
6 And now, my son, I desire
that ye should labor
diligently, that this gross
error should be removed from
among you; for, for this
intent I have written this epistle.
7 For immediately after I
had learned these things
of you I inquired of the
Lord concerning the
matter. And the word of the
Lord came to me by the
power of the Holy Ghost, saying:
8 Listen to the words of
Christ, your Redeemer,
your Lord and your God.
Behold, I came into the
world not to call the
righteous but sinners to
repentance; the whole
need no physician, but they
that are sick;
wherefore, little children are
whole, for they are not
capable of committing
sin; wherefore the curse of
Adam is taken from them
in me, that it hath no
power over them; and the
law of circumcision is done away in me.
9 And after this manner
did the Holy Ghost
manifest the word of God
unto me; wherefore, my
beloved son, I know that
it is solemn mockery
before God, that ye
should baptize little children.
10 Behold I say unto
you that this thing
shall ye
teach—repentance and baptism unto
those who are
accountable and capable of
committing sin; yea,
teach parents that
they must repent and be
baptized, and humble
themselves as their
little children, and
they shall all be
saved with their little children.
11 And their little
children need no
repentance, neither
baptism. Behold,
baptism is unto repentance
to the fulfilling
the commandments unto
the remission of sins.
12 But little
children are alive in
Christ, even from
the foundation of
the world; if not
so, God is a
partial God, and also a
changeable God,
and a respecter to
persons; for how
many little
children have died without baptism!
13 Wherefore,
if little
children could not be
saved without
baptism, these
must have gone
to an endless hell.
14 Behold I
say unto you,
that he that
supposeth that
little children
need baptism
is in the gall
of bitterness
and in the
bonds of
iniquity; for he hath
neither faith,
hope, nor
charity;
wherefore, should he
be cut off
while in the
thought, he must go down to hell.
15 For awful
is the
wickedness to
suppose that
God saveth
one child
because of
baptism, and the
other must
perish
because he hath no baptism.
16 Wo be
unto them
that shall
pervert the
ways of the
Lord after
this manner,
for they
shall perish
except
they repent.
Behold, I
speak with
boldness,
having
authority from
God; and I
fear not what
man can do;
for
perfect love casteth out all fear.
17 And I
am filled
with
charity, which
is
everlasting love;
wherefore,
all
children are
alike unto
me;
wherefore, I love
little
children
with a
perfect love;
and they are
all alike
and partakers of salvation.
18 For I
know that
God is not
a partial
God,
neither a
changeable
being; but he
is
unchangeable from
all
eternity to all
eternity.
19 Little
children
cannot
repent;
wherefore,
it is
awful
wickedness to
deny the
pure
mercies of God
unto
them, for
they are
all alive
in him
because of his mercy.
20 And
he that
saith
that little
children need
baptism
denieth
the
mercies of
Christ,
and
setteth at
naught the
atonement of him
and the
power of his redemption.
21 Wo
unto
such, for
they
are in
danger of
death,
hell,
and an
endless
torment. I
speak it
boldly;
God
hath
commanded
me.
Listen unto
them
and give
heed,
or they
stand
against
you at
the judgment-seat of Christ.
22 For
behold that
all
little
children are
alive
in
Christ,
and
also all
they
that
are
without
the
law. For
power of
redemption
cometh
on
all them
that
have
no law;
wherefore,
he
that is
not
condemned, or
he that
is
under no
condemnation,
cannot
repent; and unto such baptism availeth nothing—
But it
is
mockery
before
God,
denying
the
mercies of
Christ,
and
the
power of
his
Holy
Spirit,
and
putting trust in dead works.
Behold,
my
son,
this
thing
ought
not
to
be;
for
repentance is
unto
them
that
are
under
condemnation
and
under the curse of a broken law.
And
the
first
fruits
of
repentance
is
baptism;
and
baptism
cometh
by
faith
unto
the
fulfilling
commandments;
and
the
fulfilling the commandments bringeth remission of sins;
And
the
remission
of
sins
bringeth
meekness,
and
lowliness
of
heart;
and
because
of
meekness
and
lowliness
of
heart
cometh
the
visitation
of
the
Holy
Ghost,
which
Comforter
filleth
with
hope
and
perfect
love,
which love endureth by diligence unto prayer, until the end shall come, when all the saints shall dwell with God.
Behold,
my
son,
I
will
write
unto
you
again
soon
against
the
Lamanites.
Behold,
the
pride
of
this
nation,
or
the
people
of
the
Nephites,
hath
proven
their
destruction
except
they
should
repent.
28 Pray for them, my son, that repentance may come unto them. But behold, I fear lest the Spirit hath ceased striving with them; and in this part of the land they are also seeking to put down all power and authority which cometh from God; and they are denying the Holy
Pray
for
them,
my
son,
that
repentance
may
come
unto
them.
But
behold,
I
fear
lest
the
Spirit
hath
ceased
striving
with
them;
and
in
this part of the land they are also seeking to put down all power and authority which cometh from God; and they are denying the Holy Ghost.
29 And after rejecting so great a knowledge, my son, they must perish soon, unto the fulfilling of the prophecies which were spoken by the prophets, as well as the words of our Savior
And
after
rejecting
so
great
a
knowledge,
my
son,
they
must
perish
soon,
unto
the
fulfilling
of
the
prophecies
which
were
spoken
by
the
prophets,
as
well
the
words
of
our
Savior
himself.
30 Farewell, my son, until I shall write unto you, or shall meet you again. Amen.
Farewell,
my
son,
until
I
shall
write
unto
you,
or
shall
meet
you
again.
Amen.