Chapter 6 Repentant persons are baptized and
fellowshipped—Church members who repent are
forgiven—Meetings are conducted by the power of the Holy
Ghost. About A.D. 401–21.
1 And now I speak concerning baptism. Behold,
elders, priests, and teachers were baptized; and they
were not baptized save they brought forth fruit
meet that they were worthy of it
2 Neither did they receive any unto baptism save
they came forth with a broken heart and a contrite
spirit, and witnessed unto the church that they
truly repented of all their sins
3 And none were received unto baptism save they
took upon them the name of Christ, having a
determination to serve him to the end
4 And after they had been received unto baptism,
and were wrought upon and cleansed by the power of
the Holy Ghost, they were numbered among the
people of the church of Christ; and their names were
taken, that they might be remembered and nourished
by the good word of God, to keep them in the right
way, to keep them continually watchful unto
prayer, relying alone upon the merits of Christ, who was
the author and the finisher of their faith
5 And the church did meet together oft, to fast
and to pray, and to speak one with another
concerning the welfare of their souls
6 And they did meet together oft to partake of
bread and wine, in remembrance of the Lord Jesus
9 And their meetings were conducted by the church
after the manner of the workings of the Spirit,
and by the power of the Holy Ghost; for as the power
of the Holy Ghost led them whether to preach, or
to exhort, or to pray, or to supplicate, or to
sing, even so it was done.