Chapter 22 Plans are made for the people to
escape from Lamanite bondage—The Lamanites are made
drunk—The people escape, return to Zarahemla, and
become subject to King Mosiah. About 121–120 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that Ammon and
king Limhi began to consult with the people
how they should deliver themselves out of
bondage; and even they did cause that all
the people should gather themselves
together; and this they did that they might
have the voice of the people concerning the matter.
2 And it came to pass that they could
find no way to deliver themselves out
of bondage, except it were to take
their women and children, and their
flocks, and their herds, and their tents,
and depart into the wilderness; for the
Lamanites being so numerous, it was
impossible for the people of Limhi to
contend with them, thinking to deliver
themselves out of bondage by the sword.
3 Now it came to pass that Gideon
went forth and stood before the king,
and said unto him: Now O king, thou
hast hitherto hearkened unto my
words many times when we have been
contending with our brethren, the Lamanites.
4 And now O king, if thou hast not
found me to be an unprofitable
servant, or if thou hast hitherto
listened to my words in any degree,
and they have been of service to
thee, even so I desire that thou
wouldst listen to my words at this
time, and I will be thy servant and
deliver this people out of bondage.
5 And the king granted
unto him that he might speak.
And Gideon said unto him:
6 Behold the back pass,
through the back wall, on
the back side of the
city. The Lamanites, or the
guards of the Lamanites,
by night are drunken;
therefore let us send a
proclamation among all this
people that they gather
together their flocks and
herds, that they may drive
them into the wilderness by night.
7 And I will go
according to thy command and pay
the last tribute of
wine to the Lamanites, and
they will be drunken;
and we will pass through
the secret pass on the
left of their camp when
they are drunken and asleep.
8 Thus we will depart
with our women and
our children, our
flocks, and our herds
into the wilderness; and
we will travel
around the land of Shilom.
9 And it came to
pass that the
king hearkened unto
the words of Gideon.
10 And king
Limhi caused that
his people should
gather their
flocks together;
and he sent the
tribute of wine to
the Lamanites;
and he also sent
more wine, as a
present unto
them; and they did
drink freely of
the wine which
king Limhi did send unto them.
11 And it came
to pass that
the people of
king Limhi did
depart by night
into the
wilderness with their
flocks and their
herds, and
they went round
about the land of
Shilom in the
wilderness, and
bent their
course towards the
land of
Zarahemla, being led
by Ammon and his brethren.
12 And they
had taken all
their gold, and
silver, and
their precious
things, which
they could
carry, and also
their provisions
with them,
into the
wilderness; and they
pursued their journey.
13 And after
being many
days in the
wilderness they
arrived in
the land of
Zarahemla, and
joined
Mosiah’s people, and
became his subjects.
14 And it
came to pass
that Mosiah
received them
with joy;
and he also
received
their records,
and also the
records
which had been
found by the
people of Limhi.
15 And now
it came to
pass when
the
Lamanites had found
that the
people of
Limhi had
departed out
of the land
by night,
that they
sent an army
into the
wilderness to pursue them;
16 And
after they
had pursued
them two
days, they
could no
longer
follow their
tracks;
therefore
they were
lost in the wilderness.