Chapter 15 How Christ is both the Father and the
Son—He will make intercession and bear the
transgressions of His people—They and all the holy
prophets are His seed—He brings to pass the
Resurrection—Little children have eternal life. About 148 B.C.
1 And now Abinadi said unto them: I
would that ye should understand that God
himself shall come down among the
children of men, and shall redeem his people.
2 And because he dwelleth in
flesh he shall be called the Son
of God, and having subjected
the flesh to the will of the
Father, being the Father and the Son—
3 The Father, because he
was conceived by the
power of God; and the Son,
because of the flesh; thus
becoming the Father and Son—
4 And they are one
God, yea, the very
Eternal Father of
heaven and of earth.
5 And thus the
flesh becoming
subject to the Spirit,
or the Son to the
Father, being one
God, suffereth
temptation, and
yieldeth not to the
temptation, but
suffereth himself to be
mocked, and
scourged, and cast out,
and disowned by his people.
6 And after all
this, after
working many mighty
miracles among the
children of men,
he shall be led,
yea, even as
Isaiah said, as a
sheep before the
shearer is dumb, so
he opened not his mouth.
7 Yea, even so
he shall be led,
crucified, and
slain, the flesh
becoming subject
even unto
death, the will of
the Son being
swallowed up in the
will of the Father.
8 And thus God
breaketh the
bands of
death, having
gained the victory
over death;
giving the Son
power to make
intercession
for the children of men—
9 Having
ascended into
heaven, having
the bowels of
mercy; being
filled with
compassion
towards the
children of men;
standing
betwixt them and
justice;
having broken the
bands of
death, taken
upon himself
their iniquity
and their
transgressions,
having
redeemed them, and
satisfied the demands of justice.
10 And now I
say unto you,
who shall
declare his
generation?
Behold, I say
unto you, that
when his soul
has been made
an offering
for sin he
shall see his
seed. And now
what say ye?
And who shall
be his seed?
11 Behold I
say unto
you, that
whosoever has
heard the words
of the
prophets, yea,
all the holy
prophets who
have
prophesied
concerning the
coming of the
Lord—I say
unto you, that
all those
who have
hearkened unto
their words,
and believed
that the
Lord would
redeem his
people, and have
looked
forward to that
day for a
remission of
their sins, I
say unto
you, that these
are his
seed, or they
are the heirs of the kingdom of God.
12 For
these are they
whose sins
he has
borne; these
are they for
whom he has
died, to
redeem them
from their
transgressions. And
now, are they
not his seed?
13 Yea,
and are not
the
prophets, every
one that
has opened
his mouth
to
prophesy, that
has not
fallen into
transgression, I mean
all the
holy
prophets ever
since the
world began?
I say unto
you that they are his seed.
14 And
these are
they who
have
published
peace, who
have
brought good
tidings of
good, who
have
published
salvation;
and said
unto
Zion: Thy God reigneth!
15 And O
how
beautiful
upon the
mountains were
their feet!
16 And
again,
how
beautiful
upon
the
mountains
are the
feet of
those
that are
still
publishing peace!
17 And
again,
how
beautiful
upon
the
mountains
are the
feet of
those
who
shall
hereafter
publish
peace,
yea,
from this
time
henceforth and
forever!
18 And
behold, I
say
unto you,
this
is not
all.
For O
how
beautiful upon
the
mountains are
feet of
him
that
bringeth
good
tidings,
that is
the
founder
of
peace,
yea, even
the
Lord,
who has
redeemed
his
people;
yea, him
who has granted salvation unto his people;
For
were it
not
for
the
redemption
which
he
hath
made for
his
people,
which
was
prepared
from the
foundation of
the
world,
I
say
unto
you,
were it
not
for
this, all mankind must have perished.
But
behold,
the
bands
of
death
shall
be
broken,
and
the
Son
reigneth,
and
hath
power
over
the
dead;
therefore, he
bringeth to
pass the resurrection of the dead.
And
there
cometh
a
resurrection,
even
a
first
resurrection;
yea,
even
a
resurrection
of
those
that
have
been,
and
who
are,
and
who
shall
be,
even
until
the
resurrection
of
Christ—for so
shall
he be
called.
And
now,
the
resurrection
of
all
the
prophets,
and
all
those
that
have
believed
in
their
words,
or
all
those
that
have
kept
the
commandments
of
God,
shall
come
forth
in
the
first resurrection; therefore, they are the first resurrection.
They
are
raised
to
dwell
with
God
who
has
redeemed
them;
thus
they
have
eternal
life
through
Christ,
who
has
broken
the
bands
of
death.
And
these
are
those
who
have
part
in
the
first
resurrection;
and
these
are
they
that
have
died
before
Christ
came,
in
their
ignorance,
not
having
salvation
declared
unto
them.
And
thus
the
Lord
bringeth
about
the
restoration of these; and they have a part in the first resurrection, or have eternal life, being redeemed by the Lord.
And
little
children
also
have
eternal
life.
But
behold,
and
fear,
tremble
before
God,
for
ye
ought
to
tremble;
for
the
Lord
redeemeth
none
such
that
rebel
against
him
and
die
in
their
sins;
yea,
even
all
those
that
have
perished
in
their
sins
ever
since
the
world
began,
that
have
wilfully
rebelled
against
God,
that
have
known
the
commandments
of
God,
and
would
not
keep
them;
these
are
they
that
have
no
part
in
the
first
resurrection.
27 Therefore ought ye not to tremble? For salvation cometh to none such; for the Lord hath redeemed none such; yea, neither can the Lord redeem such; for he cannot deny himself; for he cannot deny justice when it has its
Therefore
ought
ye
not
to
tremble?
For
salvation
cometh
to
none
such;
for
the
Lord
hath
redeemed
none
such;
yea, neither can the Lord redeem such; for he cannot deny himself; for he cannot deny justice when it has its claim.
28 And now I say unto you that the time shall come that the salvation of the Lord shall be declared to every nation, kindred, tongue, and
And
now
I
say
unto
you
that
the
time
shall
come
that
the
salvation
of
the
Lord
shall
be
declared
to
every
nation,
kindred,
tongue,
and
people.
29 Yea, Lord, thy watchmen shall lift up their voice; with the voice together shall they sing; for they shall see eye to eye, when the Lord shall bring again
Yea,
Lord,
thy
watchmen
shall
lift
up
their
voice;
with
the
voice
together
shall
they
sing;
for
they
shall
see
eye
to
eye,
when
the
Lord
shall
bring
again
Zion.
30 Break forth into joy, sing together, ye waste places of Jerusalem; for the Lord hath comforted his people, he hath redeemed
Break
forth
into
joy,
sing
together,
ye
waste
places
of
Jerusalem;
for
the
Lord
hath
comforted
his
people,
he
hath
redeemed
Jerusalem.
31 The Lord hath made bare his holy arm in the eyes of all the nations; and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of our God.
The
Lord
hath
made
bare
his
holy
arm
in
the
eyes
of
all
the
nations;
and
all
the
ends
of
the
earth
shall
see
the
salvation
of
our
God.