Chapter 18 Alma preaches in private—He sets
forth the covenant of baptism and baptizes at the
waters of Mormon—He organizes the Church of Christ
and ordains priests—They support themselves and
teach the people—Alma and his people flee from
King Noah into the wilderness. About 147–145 B.C.
1 And now, it came to pass that Alma,
who had fled from the servants of king
Noah, repented of his sins and iniquities,
and went about privately among the
people, and began to teach the words of Abinadi—
2 Yea, concerning that which was to
come, and also concerning the
resurrection of the dead, and the redemption
of the people, which was to be
brought to pass through the power, and
sufferings, and death of Christ, and his
resurrection and ascension into heaven.
3 And as many as would hear his
word he did teach. And he taught
them privately, that it might not
come to the knowledge of the
king. And many did believe his words.
4 And it came to pass that as
many as did believe him did
go forth to a place which was
called Mormon, having
received its name from the king,
being in the borders of the
land having been infested, by
times or at seasons, by wild beasts.
5 Now, there was in
Mormon a fountain of pure
water, and Alma resorted
thither, there being near the
water a thicket of small
trees, where he did hide
himself in the daytime
from the searches of the king.
6 And it came to
pass that as many as
believed him went
thither to hear his words.
7 And it came to
pass after many days
there were a goodly
number gathered
together at the place
of Mormon, to hear
the words of Alma.
Yea, all were
gathered together that
believed on his
word, to hear him. And
he did teach them,
and did preach
unto them repentance,
and redemption, and
faith on the Lord.
8 And it came to
pass that he said
unto them:
Behold, here are the
waters of Mormon
(for thus were
they called) and
now, as ye are
desirous to come into
the fold of God,
and to be called
his people, and
are willing to
bear one another’s
burdens, that they may be light;
9 Yea, and are
willing to mourn
with those that
mourn; yea, and
comfort those
that stand in need
of comfort, and
to stand as
witnesses of God at
all times and
in all things,
and in all places
that ye may be
in, even until
death, that ye may
be redeemed of
God, and be
numbered with those
of the first
resurrection, that
ye may have eternal life—
10 Now I say
unto you, if this
be the desire
of your hearts,
what have you
against being
baptized in the
name of the
Lord, as a witness
before him
that ye have
entered into a
covenant with him,
that ye will
serve him and keep
his
commandments, that he may
pour out his
Spirit more abundantly upon you?
11 And now
when the people
had heard these
words, they
clapped their
hands for joy,
and exclaimed:
This is the
desire of our hearts.
12 And now it
came to pass
that Alma
took Helam, he
being one of
the first,
and went and
stood forth in
the water,
and cried,
saying: O Lord,
pour out thy
Spirit upon
thy servant,
that he may do
this work
with holiness of heart.
13 And when
he had said
these words,
the Spirit
of the Lord
was upon
him, and he
said: Helam, I
baptize
thee, having
authority from
the Almighty
God, as a
testimony
that ye have
entered into a
covenant to
serve him
until you are
dead as to
the mortal
body; and may
the Spirit
of the Lord
be poured
out upon you;
and may he
grant unto
you eternal
life, through
the
redemption of
Christ, whom he
has prepared from the foundation of the world.
14 And
after Alma had
said these
words, both
Alma and
Helam were
buried in
the water;
and they
arose and came
forth out
of the water
rejoicing,
being
filled with the Spirit.
15 And
again, Alma
took
another, and
went forth a
second
time into the
water,
and baptized
him
according to
the first,
only he did
not bury
himself
again in the water.
16 And
after this
manner he
did
baptize every
one that
went
forth to the
place of
Mormon;
and they
were in
number
about two
hundred and
four
souls; yea,
and they
were
baptized in
the waters
of
Mormon, and
were filled with the grace of God.
17 And
they were
called the
church
of God, or
the
church of
Christ, from
that
time
forward. And it
came to
pass that
whosoever
was
baptized by
the power
and
authority of
God was
added to
his church.
18 And it
came to
pass that
Alma,
having
authority
from God,
ordained
priests;
even one
priest to
every
fifty of
their number
did he
ordain to
preach
unto them,
and to
teach them
concerning
the
things
pertaining to
the
kingdom of God.
19 And
he
commanded them
that
they
should teach
nothing
save it
were the
things
which he
had
taught, and
which
had been
spoken
by the
mouth of the holy prophets.
20 Yea,
even
he
commanded
them that
they
should
preach
nothing
save it
were
repentance and
faith
on the
Lord,
who had
redeemed his people.
21 And
he
commanded them
that
there
should
be no
contention
one
with
another,
but
that
they
should
look
forward
with one
eye,
having
one
faith
and one
baptism,
having
their
hearts
knit
together in
unity and in love one towards another.
And
thus he
commanded
them
to
preach.
And
thus
they
became the
children of God.
And he
commanded
them
that
they
should
observe
the
sabbath
day, and
keep
it
holy,
and
also
every
day
they
should
give
thanks to
the
Lord
their
God.
And he
also
commanded
them
that
the
priests
whom he
had
ordained
should
labor
with
their own
hands for
their
support.
And
there
was one
day
in
every
week
that
was
set
apart
that
they
should
gather
themselves
together to
teach
the
people,
and to
worship
the
Lord
their
God,
and
also, as
often as
it
was in
their
power, to
assemble
themselves
together.
And
the
priests
were
not
to
depend
upon
the
people
for
their
support;
but
for
their
labor
they
were
to
receive
the
grace
of
God,
that
they
might
wax
strong
in
the
Spirit,
having
the
knowledge
of
God,
that they might teach with power and authority from God.
And
again
Alma
commanded
that
the
people
of
the
church
should
impart
of
their
substance,
every
one
according
to
that
which
he
had;
if
he
have
more
abundantly
he
should
impart
more
abundantly;
and
of
him
that
had
but
little, but little should be required; and to him that had not should be given.
And
thus
they
should
impart
of
their
substance
of
their
own
free
will
and
good
desires
towards
God,
and
to
those
priests
that
stood
in
need,
yea,
and
to
every
needy,
naked
soul.
And
this
he
said
unto
them,
having
been
commanded
of
God;
and
they
did
walk
uprightly
before
God,
imparting
to
one
another
both
temporally and spiritually according to their needs and their wants.
And
now
it
came
to
pass
that
all
this
was
done
in
Mormon,
yea,
by
the
waters
of
Mormon,
in
the
forest
that
was
near
the
waters
of
Mormon;
yea,
the
place
of
Mormon,
the
waters
of
Mormon,
the
forest
of
Mormon,
how
beautiful
are
they
to
the
eyes
of
them
who
there
came
to
the
knowledge
of
their
Redeemer;
yea,
and
how
blessed
are
they,
for
they
shall
sing
to
his
praise
forever.
And
these
things
were
done
in
the
borders
of
the
land,
that
they
might
not
come
to
the
knowledge
of
the
king.
32 But behold, it came to pass that the king, having discovered a movement among the people, sent his servants to watch them. Therefore on the day that they were assembling themselves together to hear the word of the Lord they were discovered unto the
But
behold,
it
came
to
pass
that
the
king,
having
discovered
a
movement
among
the
people,
sent
his
servants
to
watch
them.
Therefore on the day that they were assembling themselves together to hear the word of the Lord they were discovered unto the king.
33 And now the king said that Alma was stirring up the people to rebellion against him; therefore he sent his army to destroy
And
now
the
king
said
that
Alma
was
stirring
up
the
people
to
rebellion
against
him;
therefore
he
sent
his
army
to
destroy
them.
34 And it came to pass that Alma and the people of the Lord were apprised of the coming of the king’s army; therefore they took their tents and their families and departed into the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma
and
the
people
of
the
Lord
were
apprised
of
the
coming
of
the
king’s
army;
therefore
they
took
their
tents
and
their
families
and
departed
into
the
wilderness.
35 And they were in number about four hundred and fifty souls.
And
they
were
in
number
about
four
hundred
and
fifty
souls.