Chapter 25 The descendants of Mulek at
Zarahemla become Nephites—They learn of the
people of Alma and of Zeniff—Alma baptizes Limhi
and all his people—Mosiah authorizes Alma to
organize the Church of God. About 120 B.C.
1 And now king Mosiah caused that all
the people should be gathered together.
2 Now there were not so many of the
children of Nephi, or so many of those
who were descendants of Nephi, as
there were of the people of Zarahemla,
who was a descendant of Mulek, and
those who came with him into the wilderness.
3 And there were not so many
of the people of Nephi and of
the people of Zarahemla as
there were of the Lamanites; yea,
they were not half so numerous.
4 And now all the people of
Nephi were assembled
together, and also all the people
of Zarahemla, and they were
gathered together in two bodies.
5 And it came to pass
that Mosiah did read, and
caused to be read, the
records of Zeniff to his
people; yea, he read the
records of the people of
Zeniff, from the time they
left the land of Zarahemla
until they returned again.
6 And he also read the
account of Alma and his
brethren, and all
their afflictions, from the
time they left the
land of Zarahemla until
the time they returned again.
7 And now, when Mosiah
had made an end of
reading the records, his
people who tarried in
the land were struck
with wonder and amazement.
8 For they knew not
what to think; for
when they beheld
those that had been
delivered out of bondage
they were filled
with exceedingly great joy.
9 And again, when
they thought of
their brethren who
had been slain by
the Lamanites they
were filled with
sorrow, and even
shed many tears of sorrow.
10 And again,
when they thought
of the immediate
goodness of
God, and his power
in delivering
Alma and his
brethren out of the
hands of the
Lamanites and of
bondage, they did
raise their
voices and give thanks to God.
11 And again,
when they
thought upon the
Lamanites, who were
their
brethren, of their
sinful and polluted
state, they
were filled with
pain and
anguish for the
welfare of their souls.
12 And it came
to pass that
those who were
the children
of Amulon and
his brethren,
who had taken
to wife the
daughters of the
Lamanites,
were displeased
with the
conduct of their
fathers, and
they would no
longer be called
by the names
of their
fathers, therefore
they took upon
themselves the
name of
Nephi, that they
might be called
the children
of Nephi and be
numbered
among those who were called Nephites.
13 And now
all the people
of Zarahemla
were numbered
with the
Nephites, and
this because
the kingdom had
been
conferred upon none
but those who
were
descendants of Nephi.
14 And now
it came to
pass that when
Mosiah had
made an end
of speaking
and reading
to the
people, he
desired that Alma
should also
speak to the people.
15 And Alma
did speak
unto them,
when they
were
assembled together
in large
bodies, and
he went
from one body
to another,
preaching
unto the
people
repentance and
faith on the Lord.
16 And he
did exhort
the
people of Limhi
and his
brethren,
all those
that had
been
delivered out of
bondage,
that they
should
remember that
it was the
Lord that
did deliver them.
17 And it
came to
pass that
after
Alma had
taught the
people
many
things, and had
made an
end of
speaking to
them,
that king
Limhi was
desirous
that he
might be
baptized;
and all
his people
were
desirous
that they might be baptized also.
Therefore,
Alma did
go forth
into the
water
and did
baptize
them;
yea, he did
baptize
them
after the
manner
he did
his
brethren in
the waters
of
Mormon; yea,
and as
many as
he did
baptize
did
belong to the
church
of God;
and this
because
of their belief on the words of Alma.
19 And
it came
to
pass that
king
Mosiah
granted
unto
Alma that
he
might
establish
churches
throughout all
the
land of
Zarahemla; and
gave
him power
to
ordain
priests
and teachers over every church.
20 Now
this
was
done
because
there
were so
many
people
that
they
could
not all
be
governed
by
one
teacher;
neither
could
they
all
hear the
word of God in one assembly;
Therefore
they
did
assemble
themselves
together
in
different
bodies,
being
called
churches;
every
church
having
their
priests
and
their
teachers,
and
every
priest
preaching
the
word
according
as it
was delivered to him by the mouth of Alma.
And
thus,
notwithstanding
there
being
many
churches
they
were
all
one
church,
yea,
even
the
church of
God;
for
there
was
nothing
preached
in
all
the
churches
except it were repentance and faith in God.
And
now
there
were
seven
churches
in
the
land
of
Zarahemla.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
whosoever
were
desirous
to
take
upon
them
the
name
of
Christ, or of God, they did join the churches of God;
And
they
were
called
the
people
of
God.
And
the
Lord
did
pour
out
his
Spirit
upon
them,
and
they
were
blessed,
and
prospered
in
the
land.