Chapter 12 Abinadi is imprisoned for prophesying
the destruction of the people and the death of King
Noah—The false priests quote the scriptures and
pretend to keep the law of Moses—Abinadi begins to
teach them the Ten Commandments. About 148 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that after the space of two
years that Abinadi came among them in disguise,
that they knew him not, and began to prophesy among
them, saying: Thus has the Lord commanded me,
saying—Abinadi, go and prophesy unto this my people,
for they have hardened their hearts against my
words; they have repented not of their evil doings;
therefore, I will visit them in my anger, yea, in my
fierce anger will I visit them in their
iniquities and abominations
2 Yea, wo be unto this generation! And the Lord
said unto me: Stretch forth thy hand and prophesy,
saying: Thus saith the Lord, it shall come to pass
that this generation, because of their iniquities,
shall be brought into bondage, and shall be
smitten on the cheek; yea, and shall be driven by men,
and shall be slain; and the vultures of the air,
and the dogs, yea, and the wild beasts, shall
devour their flesh
3 And it shall come to pass that the life of king
Noah shall be valued even as a garment in a hot
furnace; for he shall know that I am the Lord
4 And it shall come to pass that I will smite this
my people with sore afflictions, yea, with famine
and with pestilence; and I will cause that they
shall howl all the day long
5 Yea, and I will cause that they shall have
burdens lashed upon their backs; and they shall be
driven before like a dumb ass
6 And it shall come to pass that I will send forth
hail among them, and it shall smite them; and
they shall also be smitten with the east wind; and
insects shall pester their land also, and devour
their grain
7 And they shall be smitten with a great
pestilence—and all this will I do because of their
iniquities and abominations
8 And it shall come to pass that except they
repent I will utterly destroy them from off the face of
the earth; yet they shall leave a record behind
them, and I will preserve them for other nations
which shall possess the land; yea, even this will I
do that I may discover the abominations of this
people to other nations. And many things did Abinadi
prophesy against this people
9 And it came to pass that they were angry with
him; and they took him and carried him bound before
the king, and said unto the king: Behold, we have
brought a man before thee who has prophesied evil
concerning thy people, and saith that God will
destroy them
10 And he also prophesieth evil concerning thy
life, and saith that thy life shall be as a garment
in a furnace of fire
11 And again, he saith that thou shalt be as a
stalk, even as a dry stalk of the field, which is run
over by the beasts and trodden under foot
12 And again, he saith thou shalt be as the
blossoms of a thistle, which, when it is fully ripe, if
the wind bloweth, it is driven forth upon the face
of the land. And he pretendeth the Lord hath
spoken it. And he saith all this shall come upon thee
except thou repent, and this because of thine
iniquities
13 And now, O king, what great evil hast thou
done, or what great sins have thy people committed,
that we should be condemned of God or judged of this
man
14 And now, O king, behold, we are guiltless, and
thou, O king, hast not sinned; therefore, this man
has lied concerning you, and he has prophesied in
vain
15 And behold, we are strong, we shall not come
into bondage, or be taken captive by our enemies;
yea, and thou hast prospered in the land, and thou
shalt also prosper
16 Behold, here is the man, we deliver him into
thy hands; thou mayest do with him as seemeth thee
good
17 And it came to pass that king Noah caused that
Abinadi should be cast into prison; and he
commanded that the priests should gather themselves
together that he might hold a council with them what he
should do with him
18 And it came to pass that they said unto the
king: Bring him hither that we may question him; and
the king commanded that he should be brought
before them
19 And they began to question him, that they might
cross him, that thereby they might have wherewith
to accuse him; but he answered them boldly, and
withstood all their questions, yea, to their
astonishment; for he did withstand them in all their
questions, and did confound them in all their words
20 And it came to pass that one of them said unto
him: What meaneth the words which are written, and
which have been taught by our fathers, saying
21 How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet
of him that bringeth good tidings; that publisheth
peace; that bringeth good tidings of good; that
publisheth salvation; that saith unto Zion, Thy God
reigneth
22 Thy watchmen shall lift up the voice; with the
voice together shall they sing; for they shall see
eye to eye when the Lord shall bring again Zion
23 Break forth into joy; sing together ye waste
places of Jerusalem; for the Lord hath comforted his
people, he hath redeemed Jerusalem
24 The Lord hath made bare his holy arm in the
eyes of all the nations, and all the ends of the
earth shall see the salvation of our God
25 And now Abinadi said unto them: Are you
priests, and pretend to teach this people, and to
understand the spirit of prophesying, and yet desire to
know of me what these things mean
26 I say unto you, wo be unto you for perverting
the ways of the Lord! For if ye understand these
things ye have not taught them; therefore, ye have
perverted the ways of the Lord
27 Ye have not applied your hearts to
understanding; therefore, ye have not been wise. Therefore,
what teach ye this people
28 And they said: We teach the law of Moses
29 And again he said unto them: If ye teach the
law of Moses why do ye not keep it? Why do ye set
your hearts upon riches? Why do ye commit whoredoms
and spend your strength with harlots, yea, and
cause this people to commit sin, that the Lord has
cause to send me to prophesy against this people,
yea, even a great evil against this people
30 Know ye not that I speak the truth? Yea, ye
know that I speak the truth; and you ought to tremble
before God
31 And it shall come to pass that ye shall be
smitten for your iniquities, for ye have said that ye
teach the law of Moses. And what know ye
concerning the law of Moses? Doth salvation come by the law
of Moses? What say ye
32 And they answered and said that salvation did
come by the law of Moses
33 But now Abinadi said unto them: I know if ye
keep the commandments of God ye shall be saved; yea,
if ye keep the commandments which the Lord
delivered unto Moses in the mount of Sinai, saying
34 I am the Lord thy God, who hath brought thee
out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of
bondage
35 Thou shalt have no other God before me
36 Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven image,
or any likeness of any thing in heaven above, or
things which are in the earth beneath
37 Now Abinadi said unto them, Have ye done all
this? I say unto you, Nay, ye have not. And have ye
taught this people that they should do all these
things? I say unto you, Nay, ye have not.