Chapter 28 The sons of Mosiah go to preach to
the Lamanites—Using the two seer stones,
Mosiah translates the Jaredite plates. About 92 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that after the sons of
Mosiah had done all these things, they took a
small number with them and returned to their
father, the king, and desired of him that he
would grant unto them that they might, with these
whom they had selected, go up to the land of
Nephi that they might preach the things which
they had heard, and that they might impart the
word of God to their brethren, the Lamanites—
2 That perhaps they might bring them to
the knowledge of the Lord their God, and
convince them of the iniquity of their
fathers; and that perhaps they might cure them
of their hatred towards the Nephites, that
they might also be brought to rejoice in
the Lord their God, that they might become
friendly to one another, and that there
should be no more contentions in all the
land which the Lord their God had given them.
3 Now they were desirous that salvation
should be declared to every creature,
for they could not bear that any human
soul should perish; yea, even the very
thoughts that any soul should endure endless
torment did cause them to quake and tremble.
4 And thus did the Spirit of the
Lord work upon them, for they were the
very vilest of sinners. And the Lord
saw fit in his infinite mercy to
spare them; nevertheless they suffered
much anguish of soul because of
their iniquities, suffering much and
fearing that they should be cast off forever.
5 And it came to pass that
they did plead with their
father many days that they
might go up to the land of Nephi.
6 And king Mosiah went
and inquired of the
Lord if he should let his
sons go up among the
Lamanites to preach the word.
7 And the Lord said
unto Mosiah: Let them go
up, for many shall
believe on their words, and
they shall have eternal
life; and I will
deliver thy sons out of the
hands of the Lamanites.
8 And it came to
pass that Mosiah
granted that they might
go and do
according to their request.
9 And they took
their journey into
the wilderness
to go up to preach
the word among
the Lamanites; and
I shall give an
account of their
proceedings hereafter.
10 Now king
Mosiah had no one
to confer the
kingdom upon,
for there was not
any of his
sons who would
accept of the kingdom.
11 Therefore
he took the
records which
were engraven on
the plates of
brass, and
also the plates
of Nephi, and
all the things
which he had
kept and
preserved according
to the
commandments of God,
after having
translated and
caused to be
written the
records which
were on the
plates of gold
which had been
found by the
people of Limhi,
which were
delivered to him by the hand of Limhi;
12 And this
he did because
of the great
anxiety of
his people;
for they were
desirous
beyond measure to
know
concerning those
people who had
been destroyed.
13 And now
he translated
them by the
means of
those two
stones which
were fastened
into the two
rims of a bow.
14 Now
these things
were prepared
from the
beginning,
and were
handed down
from
generation to
generation, for
the purpose
of
interpreting languages;
15 And
they have
been kept and
preserved
by the
hand of the
Lord, that
he should
discover
to every
creature
who should
possess the
land the
iniquities
and
abominations of his people;
16 And
whosoever has
these
things is
called seer,
after the
manner of
old times.
17 Now
after
Mosiah had
finished
translating
these
records,
behold, it
gave an
account of
the
people who
were
destroyed, from
the time
that they
were
destroyed
back to the
building
of the
great
tower, at the
time the
Lord
confounded
the
language of the
people
and they
were
scattered
abroad upon
the face
of all the
earth,
yea, and
even from
that time back until the creation of Adam.
18 Now
this
account did
cause the
people of
Mosiah to
mourn
exceedingly,
yea,
they were
filled with
sorrow;
nevertheless it
gave them
much
knowledge, in
the which
they did
rejoice.
19 And
this
account
shall be
written
hereafter;
for
behold, it
is
expedient that
all
people
should know
the
things which
are
written in this account.
20 And
now, as
I said
unto
you,
that after
king
Mosiah
had done
these
things,
he
took the
plates
of
brass, and
all the
things
which
he had
kept,
and
conferred
them upon
Alma,
who was
the
son of
Alma;
yea, all
the
records,
and also
the
interpreters, and
conferred
them upon
him,
and
commanded
him that
he
should keep
and
preserve
them,
and also
keep a
record
of the
people,
handing them
down
from one
generation to
another, even
as
they had been handed down from the time that Lehi left Jerusalem.