Chapter 4 King Benjamin continues his
address—Salvation comes because of the
Atonement—Believe in God to be saved—Retain a
remission of your sins through
faithfulness—Impart of your substance to the poor—Do all
things in wisdom and order. About 124 B.C.
1 And now, it came to pass that when
king Benjamin had made an end of speaking
the words which had been delivered unto
him by the angel of the Lord, that he
cast his eyes round about on the multitude,
and behold they had fallen to the
earth, for the fear of the Lord had come upon them.
2 And they had viewed themselves in
their own carnal state, even less than
the dust of the earth. And they all
cried aloud with one voice, saying: O
have mercy, and apply the atoning
blood of Christ that we may receive
forgiveness of our sins, and our hearts
may be purified; for we believe in
Jesus Christ, the Son of God, who
created heaven and earth, and all things;
who shall come down among the children of men.
3 And it came to pass that after
they had spoken these words the
Spirit of the Lord came upon them,
and they were filled with joy,
having received a remission of their
sins, and having peace of
conscience, because of the exceeding faith
which they had in Jesus Christ who
should come, according to the
words which king Benjamin had spoken unto them.
4 And king Benjamin again opened
his mouth and began to speak
unto them, saying: My friends and
my brethren, my kindred and my
people, I would again call your
attention, that ye may hear and
understand the remainder of my
words which I shall speak unto you.
5 For behold, if the knowledge
of the goodness of God at
this time has awakened you to a
sense of your nothingness, and
your worthless and fallen state—
6 I say unto you, if ye have
come to a knowledge of the
goodness of God, and his
matchless power, and his
wisdom, and his patience, and his
long-suffering towards the
children of men; and also,
the atonement which has been
prepared from the foundation
of the world, that thereby
salvation might come to him
that should put his trust in
the Lord, and should be
diligent in keeping his
commandments, and continue in the
faith even unto the end of his
life, I mean the life of the mortal body—
7 I say, that this is the
man who receiveth salvation,
through the atonement
which was prepared from the
foundation of the world for
all mankind, which ever were
since the fall of Adam, or
who are, or who ever shall
be, even unto the end of the world.
8 And this is the means
whereby salvation
cometh. And there is none
other salvation save this
which hath been spoken of;
neither are there any
conditions whereby man
can be saved except the
conditions which I have told you.
9 Believe in God;
believe that he is, and that
he created all things,
both in heaven and in
earth; believe that he
has all wisdom, and all
power, both in heaven
and in earth; believe
that man doth not
comprehend all the things
which the Lord can comprehend.
10 And again, believe
that ye must repent of
your sins and forsake
them, and humble
yourselves before God; and
ask in sincerity of
heart that he would
forgive you; and now, if
you believe all these
things see that ye do them.
11 And again I say
unto you as I have said
before, that as ye
have come to the
knowledge of the glory of
God, or if ye have
known of his goodness
and have tasted of his
love, and have
received a remission of
your sins, which
causeth such exceedingly
great joy in your
souls, even so I would
that ye should remember,
and always retain in
remembrance, the
greatness of God, and
your own nothingness,
and his goodness and
long-suffering towards
you, unworthy
creatures, and humble
yourselves even in the
depths of humility,
calling on the name of
the Lord daily, and
standing steadfastly in
the faith of that
which is to come, which
was spoken by the mouth of the angel.
12 And behold, I
say unto you that if
ye do this ye shall
always rejoice,
and be filled with
the love of God, and
always retain a
remission of your
sins; and ye shall grow
in the knowledge
of the glory of him
that created you,
or in the knowledge
of that which is just and true.
13 And ye will
not have a mind to
injure one
another, but to live
peaceably, and to
render to every
man according to
that which is his due.
14 And ye will
not suffer your
children that
they go hungry, or
naked; neither
will ye suffer
that they
transgress the laws of
God, and fight
and quarrel one
with another, and
serve the devil,
who is the
master of sin, or
who is the evil
spirit which hath
been spoken of
by our fathers,
he being an enemy
to all righteousness.
15 But ye will
teach them to
walk in the ways
of truth and
soberness; ye
will teach them
to love one
another, and to
serve one another.
16 And also, ye
yourselves
will succor those
that stand in
need of your
succor; ye will
administer of
your substance
unto him that
standeth in need;
and ye will not
suffer that the
beggar putteth
up his
petition to you in
vain, and turn him
out to perish.
17 Perhaps
thou shalt say:
The man has
brought upon
himself his
misery; therefore I
will stay my
hand, and will
not give unto
him of my
food, nor impart
unto him of my
substance that
he may not
suffer, for his
punishments are just—
18 But I say
unto you, O
man, whosoever
doeth this
the same hath
great cause
to repent; and
except he
repenteth of
that which he
hath done he
perisheth
forever, and hath
no interest
in the kingdom of God.
19 For
behold, are we
not all
beggars? Do we not
all depend
upon the
same Being,
even God, for
all the
substance which
we have, for
both food
and raiment,
and for gold,
and for
silver, and for
all the
riches which we
have of every kind?
20 And
behold, even at
this time,
ye have
been calling
on his
name, and
begging for a
remission of
your sins.
And has he
suffered
that ye have
begged in
vain? Nay;
he has
poured out his
Spirit upon
you, and
has caused
that your
hearts should
be filled
with joy,
and has
caused that your
mouths
should be
stopped that ye
could not
find
utterance, so exceedingly great was your joy.
21 And
now, if God,
who has
created you,
on whom
you are
dependent for
your
lives and for
all that
ye have and
are, doth
grant
unto you
whatsoever ye
ask that
is right,
in faith,
believing
that ye
shall
receive, O then,
how ye
ought to
impart of the
substance
that ye have one to another.
22 And if
ye judge
the man
who
putteth up his
petition
to you
for your
substance
that he
perish
not, and
condemn him,
how much
more
just will be
your
condemnation
for
withholding
your
substance,
which doth
not belong
to you
but to
God, to whom
also
your life
belongeth;
and yet
ye put up
no
petition, nor
repent of the thing which thou hast done.
23 I say
unto
you, wo be
that man,
for his
substance shall
perish
with him;
and
now, I say
these
things
unto those
who are
rich as
pertaining to
the things of this world.
24 And
again,
I say
unto the
poor,
ye who
have
not and
yet have
sufficient,
that ye
remain
from
day to
day; I
mean all
you who
deny
the
beggar,
because ye
have
not; I
would
that ye
say in
your
hearts
that: I
give not
because
I have not, but if I had I would give.
25 And
now,
if ye
say
this in
your
hearts
ye
remain
guiltless,
otherwise
ye
are
condemned;
and
your
condemnation
is just
for
ye
covet that
which ye have not received.
And
now, for
the
sake
of
these
things
which I
have
spoken
unto
you—that
is,
for
the
sake of
retaining
a
remission of
your
sins
from
day
to
day,
that ye
may
walk
guiltless
before
God—I
would
that ye
should
impart
of
your
substance to
the
poor,
every man
according
to
that
which
he
hath,
such
as
feeding
the
hungry,
clothing
the
naked,
visiting
the
sick
and
administering to their relief, both spiritually and temporally, according to their wants.
And
see
that
all
these
things
are
done in
wisdom
and
order;
for
it is
not
requisite
that
a
man
should
run
faster
than
he
has
strength.
And
again,
it
is
expedient
that he
should
be
diligent,
that
thereby he
might
win the prize; therefore, all things must be done in order.
And
I
would
that
ye
should
remember,
that
whosoever
among
you
borroweth
of
his
neighbor
should
return
the
thing
that
he
borroweth,
according
as
he
doth
agree,
or
else
thou
shalt
commit
sin; and perhaps thou shalt cause thy neighbor to commit sin also.
And
finally,
I
cannot
tell
you
all
the
things
whereby
ye
may
commit
sin;
for
there
are
divers
ways and means, even so many that I cannot number them.
30 But this much I can tell you, that if ye do not watch yourselves, and your thoughts, and your words, and your deeds, and observe the commandments of God, and continue in the faith of what ye have heard concerning the coming of our Lord, even unto the end of your lives, ye must perish. And now, O man, remember, and perish not.
But
this
much
I
can
tell
you,
that
if
ye
do
not
watch
yourselves,
and
your
thoughts,
and
your
words,
and
your
deeds,
and
observe
the
commandments
of
God,
and
continue in the faith of what ye have heard concerning the coming of our Lord, even unto the end of your lives, ye must perish. And now, O man, remember, and perish not.