Chapter 11 King Noah rules in
wickedness—He revels in riotous living with his wives
and concubines—Abinadi prophesies that the
people will be taken into bondage—His
life is sought by King Noah. About 160–150 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that
Zeniff conferred the kingdom upon Noah,
one of his sons; therefore Noah
began to reign in his stead; and he
did not walk in the ways of his father.
2 For behold, he did not keep the
commandments of God, but he did
walk after the desires of his own
heart. And he had many wives and
concubines. And he did cause his
people to commit sin, and do that
which was abominable in the sight of
the Lord. Yea, and they did commit
whoredoms and all manner of wickedness.
3 And he laid a tax of one
fifth part of all they possessed,
a fifth part of their gold
and of their silver, and a fifth
part of their ziff, and of
their copper, and of their brass
and their iron; and a fifth
part of their fatlings; and
also a fifth part of all their grain.
4 And all this did he take
to support himself, and
his wives and his
concubines; and also his priests,
and their wives and their
concubines; thus he had
changed the affairs of the kingdom.
5 For he put down all
the priests that had been
consecrated by his
father, and consecrated new
ones in their stead, such
as were lifted up in
the pride of their hearts.
6 Yea, and thus they
were supported in their
laziness, and in their
idolatry, and in their
whoredoms, by the taxes
which king Noah had put
upon his people; thus
did the people labor
exceedingly to support iniquity.
7 Yea, and they also
became idolatrous,
because they were
deceived by the vain and
flattering words of
the king and priests;
for they did speak
flattering things unto them.
8 And it came to
pass that king Noah
built many elegant and
spacious buildings;
and he ornamented
them with fine work of
wood, and of all
manner of precious
things, of gold, and of
silver, and of
iron, and of brass, and
of ziff, and of copper;
9 And he also built
him a spacious
palace, and a throne
in the midst
thereof, all of which was
of fine wood and
was ornamented with
gold and silver and
with precious things.
10 And he also
caused that his
workmen should work all
manner of fine
work within the
walls of the temple,
of fine wood, and
of copper, and of brass.
11 And the seats
which were set
apart for the high
priests, which
were above all the
other seats, he
did ornament with
pure gold; and he
caused a
breastwork to be built
before them, that
they might rest
their bodies and
their arms upon
while they should
speak lying and
vain words to his people.
12 And it came
to pass that he
built a tower
near the temple;
yea, a very high
tower, even so
high that he could
stand upon the
top thereof and
overlook the
land of Shilom, and
also the land
of Shemlon, which
was possessed
by the Lamanites;
and he could
even look over all
the land round about.
13 And it came
to pass that he
caused many
buildings to be
built in the
land Shilom; and
he caused a
great tower to be
built on the
hill north of the
land Shilom,
which had been a
resort for the
children of
Nephi at the time
they fled out
of the land; and
thus he did do
with the
riches which he
obtained by the taxation of his people.
14 And it came
to pass that
he placed his
heart upon his
riches, and
he spent his
time in riotous
living with
his wives and
his concubines;
and so did
also his priests
spend their
time with harlots.
15 And it
came to pass
that he planted
vineyards
round about in
the land; and
he built
wine-presses, and
made wine in
abundance;
and therefore
he became a
wine-bibber,
and also his people.
16 And it
came to pass
that the
Lamanites began
to come in
upon his
people, upon
small numbers,
and to slay
them in
their fields,
and while they
were
tending their flocks.
17 And king
Noah sent
guards round
about the
land to keep
them off; but
he did not
send a
sufficient number,
and the
Lamanites came
upon them
and killed
them, and drove
many of
their flocks
out of the
land; thus the
Lamanites
began to
destroy them, and
to exercise
their
hatred upon them.
18 And it
came to pass
that king
Noah sent
his armies
against
them, and they
were driven
back, or
they drove
them back
for a time;
therefore,
they
returned rejoicing
in their spoil.
19 And now,
because of
this great
victory
they were
lifted up in
the pride of
their
hearts; they
did boast in
their own
strength,
saying that
their fifty
could stand
against
thousands of
the
Lamanites; and
thus they did
boast, and
did delight
in blood,
and the
shedding of
the blood of
their
brethren, and
this because
of the
wickedness of
their king
and priests.
20 And it
came to
pass that
there was a
man among
them whose
name was
Abinadi;
and he went
forth
among them,
and began
to
prophesy, saying:
Behold,
thus saith
the Lord,
and thus
hath he
commanded me,
saying, Go
forth,
and say unto
this
people, thus
saith the
Lord—Wo be
unto this
people,
for I have
seen their
abominations, and
their
wickedness, and
whoredoms; and
except
they repent I will visit them in mine anger.
21 And
except they
repent
and turn
to the
Lord their
God,
behold, I will
deliver
them into
the
hands of
their
enemies; yea,
and they
shall be
brought
into
bondage; and
they shall
be
afflicted by the
hand of their enemies.
22 And
it shall
come to
pass
that they
shall
know that I
am the
Lord
their God,
and am a
jealous
God,
visiting
the
iniquities of my people.
23 And
it
shall come
to pass
that
except
this
people
repent and
turn
unto the
Lord
their
God, they
shall
be
brought
into
bondage; and
none
shall
deliver
them,
except it
be the Lord the Almighty God.
Yea, and
it
shall
come to
pass
that
when they
shall
cry
unto me
I
will be
slow to
hear
their
cries;
yea,
and I
will
suffer
them
that
they be
smitten by their enemies.
And
except
they
repent
in
sackcloth
and
ashes,
cry
mightily to
the
Lord
their
God,
I
will not
hear
their
prayers,
neither
will I
deliver
them
out of
their
afflictions;
and
thus
saith
the Lord, and thus hath he commanded me.
Now it
came
to
pass
that
when
Abinadi
had
spoken
these
words
unto
them
they
were
wroth
with
him,
and
sought
to
take
away
his
life;
but
the
Lord
delivered him
out
of
their
hands.
Now
when
king
Noah had
heard of
the
words
which
Abinadi
had
spoken
unto
the
people, he
was
also
wroth;
and
he
said:
Who is
Abinadi,
that
I and
my
people
should be
judged of
him,
or
who is
the
Lord,
that
shall
bring
upon my
people
such
great
affliction?
28 I
command
you
to
bring
Abinadi
hither,
that I
may
slay
him,
for
he
has
said
these
things
that
he
might
stir
up my
people
to
anger
one
with
another,
and
to
raise
contentions among my people; therefore I will slay him.
Now
the
eyes
of
the
people
were
blinded;
therefore
they
hardened
their
hearts
against
the
words
of
Abinadi,
and
they
sought
from
that
time
forward to
take
him.
And
king
Noah
hardened
his
heart
against
the
word
of
the
Lord,
and he
did
not
repent
of
his
evil
doings.