Chapter 5 The Saints become the sons and
daughters of Christ through faith—They
are then called by the name of Christ—King
Benjamin exhorts them to be steadfast and
immovable in good works. About 124 B.C.
1 And now, it came to pass that when
king Benjamin had thus spoken to his
people, he sent among them, desiring to
know of his people if they believed
the words which he had spoken unto them.
2 And they all cried with one voice,
saying: Yea, we believe all the
words which thou hast spoken unto us;
and also, we know of their surety and
truth, because of the Spirit of the
Lord Omnipotent, which has wrought
a mighty change in us, or in our
hearts, that we have no more
disposition to do evil, but to do good continually.
3 And we, ourselves, also,
through the infinite goodness of God,
and the manifestations of his
Spirit, have great views of that
which is to come; and were it
expedient, we could prophesy of all things.
4 And it is the faith which we
have had on the things which
our king has spoken unto us that
has brought us to this great
knowledge, whereby we do rejoice
with such exceedingly great joy.
5 And we are willing to enter
into a covenant with our God
to do his will, and to be
obedient to his commandments in all
things that he shall command
us, all the remainder of our
days, that we may not bring
upon ourselves a never-ending
torment, as has been spoken by
the angel, that we may not drink
out of the cup of the wrath of God.
6 And now, these are the
words which king Benjamin
desired of them; and therefore he
said unto them: Ye have
spoken the words that I
desired; and the covenant which ye
have made is a righteous covenant.
7 And now, because of the
covenant which ye have
made ye shall be called the
children of Christ, his
sons, and his daughters; for
behold, this day he hath
spiritually begotten you;
for ye say that your hearts
are changed through faith
on his name; therefore,
ye are born of him and have
become his sons and his daughters.
8 And under this head ye
are made free, and there
is no other head whereby
ye can be made free.
There is no other name given
whereby salvation cometh;
therefore, I would that
ye should take upon you
the name of Christ, all
you that have entered into
the covenant with God
that ye should be obedient
unto the end of your lives.
9 And it shall come to
pass that whosoever
doeth this shall be found
at the right hand of
God, for he shall know
the name by which he is
called; for he shall be
called by the name of Christ.
10 And now it shall
come to pass, that
whosoever shall not take
upon him the name of
Christ must be called by
some other name;
therefore, he findeth
himself on the left hand of God.
11 And I would that
ye should remember
also, that this is
the name that I said I
should give unto
you that never should
be blotted out,
except it be through
transgression;
therefore, take heed that ye
do not transgress,
that the name be not
blotted out of your hearts.
12 I say unto you,
I would that ye
should remember to
retain the name
written always in your
hearts, that ye are
not found on the
left hand of God, but
that ye hear and
know the voice by
which ye shall be
called, and also, the
name by which he shall call you.
13 For how knoweth
a man the master
whom he has not
served, and who is a
stranger unto
him, and is far from
the thoughts and
intents of his heart?
14 And again,
doth a man take an
ass which
belongeth to his
neighbor, and keep him? I
say unto you,
Nay; he will not
even suffer that he
shall feed among
his flocks, but
will drive him
away, and cast him
out. I say unto
you, that even so
shall it be among
you if ye know
not the name by
which ye are called.
15 Therefore, I
would that ye
should be
steadfast and immovable,
always
abounding in good works,
that Christ,
the Lord God
Omnipotent, may seal
you his, that
you may be brought
to heaven, that
ye may have
everlasting
salvation and eternal
life, through the
wisdom, and
power, and justice,
and mercy of
him who created
all things, in
heaven and in
earth, who is God above all. Amen.