Chapter 26 Many members of the Church are led
into sin by unbelievers—Alma is promised
eternal life—Those who repent and are baptized gain
forgiveness—Church members in sin who repent
and confess to Alma and to the Lord will be
forgiven; otherwise, they will not be numbered
among the people of the Church. About 120–100 B.C.
1 Now it came to pass that there were
many of the rising generation that could
not understand the words of king
Benjamin, being little children at the time
he spake unto his people; and they did
not believe the tradition of their fathers.
2 They did not believe what had
been said concerning the resurrection
of the dead, neither did they
believe concerning the coming of Christ.
3 And now because of their
unbelief they could not
understand the word of God;
and their hearts were hardened.
4 And they would not be
baptized; neither would they
join the church. And they
were a separate people as
to their faith, and
remained so ever after, even in
their carnal and sinful
state; for they would not
call upon the Lord their God.
5 And now in the reign
of Mosiah they were not
half so numerous as
the people of God; but
because of the
dissensions among the brethren
they became more numerous.
6 For it came to pass
that they did
deceive many with their
flattering words, who
were in the church, and
did cause them to
commit many sins;
therefore it became
expedient that those who
committed sin, that
were in the church,
should be admonished by the church.
7 And it came to
pass that they were
brought before the
priests, and delivered
up unto the priests
by the teachers; and
the priests brought
them before Alma,
who was the high priest.
8 Now king
Mosiah had given
Alma the
authority over the church.
9 And it came
to pass that
Alma did not
know concerning
them; but
there were many
witnesses
against them; yea,
the people
stood and
testified of their
iniquity in abundance.
10 Now there
had not any
such thing
happened before in
the church;
therefore Alma
was troubled in
his spirit,
and he caused
that they should
be brought
before the king.
11 And he
said unto the
king: Behold,
here are many
whom we have
brought
before thee, who
are accused of
their
brethren; yea, and
they have
been taken in
divers
iniquities. And they
do not repent
of their
iniquities;
therefore we have
brought them
before thee,
that thou
mayest judge
them according to their crimes.
12 But king
Mosiah said
unto Alma:
Behold, I
judge them not;
therefore I
deliver
them into thy
hands to be judged.
13 And now
the spirit
of Alma was
again
troubled; and
he went and
inquired of
the Lord
what he
should do
concerning this
matter, for
he feared
that he
should do
wrong in the sight of God.
14 And it
came to
pass that
after he had
poured
out his
whole soul to
God, the
voice of
the Lord
came to him, saying:
15 Blessed
art thou,
Alma, and
blessed
are they
who were
baptized in
the waters
of Mormon.
Thou art
blessed
because of
thy
exceeding faith
in the
words alone of
my
servant Abinadi.
16 And
blessed are
they
because of
their
exceeding
faith in the
words
alone which
thou
hast spoken unto them.
17 And
blessed
art thou
because
thou
hast
established a
church
among
this
people; and
they shall
be
established,
and
they shall be my people.
18 Yea,
blessed is
this
people who
are
willing to
bear
my name;
for in
my
name shall
they
be
called; and they are mine.
19 And
because
thou hast
inquired of
me
concerning the
transgressor,
thou art blessed.
Thou art
my
servant;
and I
covenant
with thee
that
thou
shalt
have
eternal
life;
and
thou
shalt
serve me
and go
forth
in my
name,
and
shalt
gather
together my
sheep.
And he
that
will
hear
my
voice
shall
be my
sheep;
and him
shall ye
receive
into
the
church,
and
him will I also receive.
For
behold,
this
is
my
church;
whosoever
is
baptized
shall be
unto
repentance.
And
whomsoever ye
receive
shall
believe
in my
name; and him will I freely forgive.
For
it
is
I
that
taketh
upon
me
the
sins
of
the
world;
for
it
is I
that
hath
created
them;
and
it
is I
that
granteth
unto
him
that
believeth unto the end a place at my right hand.
For
behold,
in
my
name
are
they
called;
and
if
they
know
me
they
shall
come
forth,
and
shall have a place eternally at my right hand.
And
it
shall
come
to
pass
that
when
the
second
trump
shall
sound
then
shall
they
that
never
knew
me
come
forth
and
shall
stand
before
me.
26 And then shall they know that I am the Lord their God, that I am their Redeemer; but they would not be
And
then
shall
they
know
that
I
am
the
Lord
their
God,
that I am their Redeemer; but they would not be redeemed.
27 And then I will confess unto them that I never knew them; and they shall depart into everlasting fire prepared for the devil and his
And
then
I
will
confess
unto
them
that
I
never
knew
them;
and
they
shall
depart
into
everlasting
fire
prepared
for
the
devil
and
his
angels.
28 Therefore I say unto you, that he that will not hear my voice, the same shall ye not receive into my church, for him I will not receive at the last
Therefore
I
say
unto
you,
that
he
will
not
hear
my
voice,
the
same
shall
ye
not
receive
into
my
church,
for
him
I
will
not
receive
at
the
last
day.
29 Therefore I say unto you, Go; and whosoever transgresseth against me, him shall ye judge according to the sins which he has committed; and if he confess his sins before thee and me, and repenteth in the sincerity of his heart, him shall ye forgive, and I will forgive him
Therefore
I
say
unto
you,
Go;
and
whosoever
transgresseth
against
me,
him
shall
ye
judge
according
to
the
sins
which
he
has
committed;
and
if
he
confess
his
sins
before
thee
and
me,
repenteth
in
the
sincerity
of
his
heart,
him
shall
ye
forgive,
and
I
will
forgive
him
also.
30 Yea, and as often as my people repent will I forgive them their trespasses against
Yea,
and
as
often
my
people
repent
will
I
forgive
them
their
trespasses
against
me.
31 And ye shall also forgive one another your trespasses; for verily I say unto you, he that forgiveth not his neighbor’s trespasses when he says that he repents, the same hath brought himself under
And
ye
shall
also
forgive
one
another
your
trespasses;
for
verily
I
say
unto
you,
he
that
forgiveth
not
his
neighbor’s
trespasses
when
he
says
that
he
repents,
the
same
hath
brought
himself
under
condemnation.
32 Now I say unto you, Go; and whosoever will not repent of his sins the same shall not be numbered among my people; and this shall be observed from this time
Now
I
say
unto
you,
Go;
and
whosoever
will
not
repent
of
his
sins
the
same
shall
not
be
numbered
among
my
people;
and
this
shall
be
observed
from
this
time
forward.
33 And it came to pass when Alma had heard these words he wrote them down that he might have them, and that he might judge the people of that church according to the commandments of
And
it
came
to
pass
when
Alma
had
heard
these
words
he
wrote
them
down
that
he
might
have
them,
and
that
he
might
judge
the
people
of
that
church
according
to
the
commandments
of
God.
34 And it came to pass that Alma went and judged those that had been taken in iniquity, according to the word of the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma
went
and
judged
those
that
had
been
taken
in
iniquity,
according
to
the
word
of
the
Lord.
35 And whosoever repented of their sins and did confess them, them he did number among the people of the
And
whosoever
repented
of
their
sins
and
did
confess
them,
them
he
did
number
among
the
people
of
the
church;
36 And those that would not confess their sins and repent of their iniquity, the same were not numbered among the people of the church, and their names were blotted
And
those
that
would
not
confess
their
sins
and
repent
of
their
iniquity,
the
same
were
not
numbered
among
the
people
of
the
church,
and
their
names
were
blotted
out.
37 And it came to pass that Alma did regulate all the affairs of the church; and they began again to have peace and to prosper exceedingly in the affairs of the church, walking circumspectly before God, receiving many, and baptizing
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma
did
regulate
all
the
affairs
of
the
church;
and
they
began
again
to
have
peace
and
to
prosper
exceedingly
in
the
affairs
of
the
church,
walking
circumspectly
before
God,
receiving
many,
and
baptizing
many.
38 And now all these things did Alma and his fellow laborers do who were over the church, walking in all diligence, teaching the word of God in all things, suffering all manner of afflictions, being persecuted by all those who did not belong to the church of
And
now
all
these
things
did
Alma
and
his
fellow
laborers
do
who
were
over
the
church,
walking
in
all
diligence,
teaching
the
word
of
God
in
all
things,
suffering
all
manner
of
afflictions,
being
persecuted
by
all
those
who
did
not
belong
to
the
church
of
God.
39 And they did admonish their brethren; and they were also admonished, every one by the word of God, according to his sins, or to the sins which he had committed, being commanded of God to pray without ceasing, and to give thanks in all things.
And
they
did
admonish
their
brethren;
and
they
were
also
admonished,
every
one
by
the
word
of
God,
according
to
his
sins,
or
to
the
sins
which
he
had
committed,
being
commanded
of
God
to
pray
without
ceasing,
and
to
give
thanks
in
all
things.