Chapter 20 Some Lamanite daughters are abducted by
the priests of Noah—The Lamanites wage war upon
Limhi and his people—The Lamanite hosts are
repulsed and pacified. About 145–123 B.C.
1 Now there was a place in Shemlon where the
daughters of the Lamanites did gather themselves
together to sing, and to dance, and to make themselves
merry
2 And it came to pass that there was one day a
small number of them gathered together to sing and to
dance
3 And now the priests of king Noah, being ashamed
to return to the city of Nephi, yea, and also
fearing that the people would slay them, therefore
they durst not return to their wives and their
children
4 And having tarried in the wilderness, and having
discovered the daughters of the Lamanites, they
laid and watched them
5 And when there were but few of them gathered
together to dance, they came forth out of their
secret places and took them and carried them into the
wilderness; yea, twenty and four of the daughters
of the Lamanites they carried into the wilderness
6 And it came to pass that when the Lamanites
found that their daughters had been missing, they were
angry with the people of Limhi, for they thought
it was the people of Limhi
7 Therefore they sent their armies forth; yea,
even the king himself went before his people; and
they went up to the land of Nephi to destroy the
people of Limhi
8 And now Limhi had discovered them from the
tower, even all their preparations for war did he
discover; therefore he gathered his people together,
and laid wait for them in the fields and in the
forests
9 And it came to pass that when the Lamanites had
come up, that the people of Limhi began to fall
upon them from their waiting places, and began to
slay them
10 And it came to pass that the battle became
exceedingly sore, for they fought like lions for their
prey
11 And it came to pass that the people of Limhi
began to drive the Lamanites before them; yet they
were not half so numerous as the Lamanites. But
they fought for their lives, and for their wives, and
for their children; therefore they exerted
themselves and like dragons did they fight
12 And it came to pass that they found the king of
the Lamanites among the number of their dead; yet
he was not dead, having been wounded and left
upon the ground, so speedy was the flight of his
people
13 And they took him and bound up his wounds, and
brought him before Limhi, and said: Behold, here
is the king of the Lamanites; he having received a
wound has fallen among their dead, and they have
left him; and behold, we have brought him before
you; and now let us slay him
14 But Limhi said unto them: Ye shall not slay
him, but bring him hither that I may see him. And
they brought him. And Limhi said unto him: What cause
have ye to come up to war against my people?
Behold, my people have not broken the oath that I made
unto you; therefore, why should ye break the oath
which ye made unto my people
15 And now the king said: I have broken the oath
because thy people did carry away the daughters of
my people; therefore, in my anger I did cause my
people to come up to war against thy people
16 And now Limhi had heard nothing concerning this
matter; therefore he said: I will search among my
people and whosoever has done this thing shall
perish. Therefore he caused a search to be made
among his people
17 Now when Gideon had heard these things, he
being the king’s captain, he went forth and said unto
the king: I pray thee forbear, and do not search
this people, and lay not this thing to their
charge
18 For do ye not remember the priests of thy
father, whom this people sought to destroy? And are
they not in the wilderness? And are not they the ones
who have stolen the daughters of the Lamanites
19 And now, behold, and tell the king of these
things, that he may tell his people that they may be
pacified towards us; for behold they are already
preparing to come against us; and behold also there
are but few of us
20 And behold, they come with their numerous
hosts; and except the king doth pacify them towards us
we must perish
21 For are not the words of Abinadi fulfilled,
which he prophesied against us—and all this because
we would not hearken unto the words of the Lord,
and turn from our iniquities
22 And now let us pacify the king, and we fulfil
the oath which we have made unto him; for it is
better that we should be in bondage than that we
should lose our lives; therefore, let us put a stop to
the shedding of so much blood
23 And now Limhi told the king all the things
concerning his father, and the priests that had fled
into the wilderness, and attributed the carrying
away of their daughters to them
24 And it came to pass that the king was pacified
towards his people; and he said unto them: Let us
go forth to meet my people, without arms; and I
swear unto you with an oath that my people shall not
slay thy people
25 And it came to pass that they followed the
king, and went forth without arms to meet the
Lamanites. And it came to pass that they did meet the
Lamanites; and the king of the Lamanites did bow
himself down before them, and did plead in behalf of
the people of Limhi
26 And when the Lamanites saw the people of Limhi,
that they were without arms, they had compassion
on them and were pacified towards them, and
returned with their king in peace to their own land.