Chapter 8 Ammon teaches the people of
Limhi—He learns of the twenty-four Jaredite
plates—Ancient records can be translated by seers—No
gift is greater than seership. About 121 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that after king Limhi
had made an end of speaking to his people,
for he spake many things unto them and only a
few of them have I written in this book, he
told his people all the things concerning
their brethren who were in the land of Zarahemla.
2 And he caused that Ammon should stand
up before the multitude, and rehearse
unto them all that had happened unto their
brethren from the time that Zeniff went
up out of the land even until the time
that he himself came up out of the land.
3 And he also rehearsed unto them the
last words which king Benjamin had
taught them, and explained them to the
people of king Limhi, so that they might
understand all the words which he spake.
4 And it came to pass that after
he had done all this, that king
Limhi dismissed the multitude,
and caused that they should
return every one unto his own house.
5 And it came to pass that
he caused that the plates
which contained the record of
his people from the time that
they left the land of
Zarahemla, should be brought
before Ammon, that he might read them.
6 Now, as soon as Ammon
had read the record, the
king inquired of him to
know if he could
interpret languages, and Ammon
told him that he could not.
7 And the king said
unto him: Being grieved
for the afflictions of my
people, I caused that
forty and three of my
people should take a
journey into the
wilderness, that thereby they
might find the land of
Zarahemla, that we might
appeal unto our
brethren to deliver us out of bondage.
8 And they were lost
in the wilderness for
the space of many days,
yet they were
diligent, and found not the
land of Zarahemla but
returned to this land,
having traveled in a
land among many waters,
having discovered a
land which was covered
with bones of men, and
of beasts, and was
also covered with ruins
of buildings of every
kind, having
discovered a land which had
been peopled with a
people who were as numerous
as the hosts of Israel.
9 And for a
testimony that the things
that they had said are
true they have
brought twenty-four
plates which are filled
with engravings, and
they are of pure gold.
10 And behold,
also, they have
brought breastplates,
which are large,
and they are of
brass and of copper,
and are perfectly sound.
11 And again,
they have brought
swords, the hilts
thereof have
perished, and the
blades thereof were
cankered with
rust; and there is no
one in the land
that is able to
interpret the
language or the
engravings that are on
the plates.
Therefore I said unto
thee: Canst thou translate?
12 And I say
unto thee again:
Knowest thou of
any one that can
translate? For I
am desirous that
these records
should be
translated into our
language; for,
perhaps, they will
give us a
knowledge of a remnant
of the people
who have been
destroyed, from
whence these records
came; or,
perhaps, they will
give us a
knowledge of this very
people who have
been destroyed;
and I am desirous
to know the cause of their destruction.
13 Now Ammon
said unto him: I
can assuredly
tell thee, O
king, of a man
that can translate
the records;
for he has
wherewith that he
can look, and
translate all
records that are of
ancient date;
and it is a
gift from God. And
the things are
called
interpreters, and no
man can look in
them except he
be commanded,
lest he should
look for that he
ought not and
he should
perish. And
whosoever is commanded
to look in them, the same is called seer.
14 And behold,
the king of
the people who
are in the
land of Zarahemla
is the man
that is
commanded to do these
things, and
who has this
high gift from God.
15 And the
king said
that a seer
is greater
than a prophet.
16 And
Ammon said
that a seer
is a
revelator and a
prophet
also; and a
gift
which is
greater can no
man have,
except he
should
possess the
power of
God, which
no man can;
yet a man
may have
great
power given him from God.
17 But a
seer can
know of
things
which are
past, and
also of
things
which are to
come, and
by them
shall all
things
be
revealed, or,
rather,
shall secret
things
be made
manifest,
and hidden
things
shall come
to
light, and
things which
are not
known
shall be
made known
by them,
and also
things
shall be
made known
by them which otherwise could not be known.
18 Thus
God has
provided
a means
that
man,
through
faith, might
work
mighty
miracles;
therefore
he
becometh a
great
benefit to
his fellow beings.
19 And
now, when
Ammon
had made
an end
of
speaking these
words
the king
rejoiced
exceedingly,
and gave
thanks to
God,
saying:
Doubtless
a great
mystery
is
contained
within
these
plates, and
interpreters
were
doubtless
prepared
for the
purpose
of
unfolding
all such
mysteries
to the
children
of men.
20 O
how
marvelous
are the
works of
the
Lord, and
how
long doth
he
suffer
with his
people;
yea,
and how
blind
and
impenetrable
are
the
understandings of
children of
men;
for they
will
not seek
wisdom,
neither do
they
desire that she should rule over them!
Yea, they
are
as a
wild
flock
which
fleeth
from the
shepherd,
and
scattereth, and
are
driven,
and
are
devoured
by the
beasts of the forest.