The Book of MosiahChapter 1 King Benjamin teaches
his sons the language and prophecies of their
fathers—Their religion and civilization have been
preserved because of the records kept on the various
plates—Mosiah is chosen as king and is given
custody of the records and other things. About
130–124 B.C.
1 And now there was no more contention in all the
land of Zarahemla, among all the people who
belonged to king Benjamin, so that king Benjamin had
continual peace all the remainder of his days
2 And it came to pass that he had three sons; and
he called their names Mosiah, and Helorum, and
Helaman. And he caused that they should be taught in
all the language of his fathers, that thereby they
might become men of understanding; and that they
might know concerning the prophecies which had
been spoken by the mouths of their fathers, which
were delivered them by the hand of the Lord
3 And he also taught them concerning the records
which were engraven on the plates of brass, saying:
My sons, I would that ye should remember that
were it not for these plates, which contain these
records and these commandments, we must have suffered
in ignorance, even at this present time, not
knowing the mysteries of God
4 For it were not possible that our father, Lehi,
could have remembered all these things, to have
taught them to his children, except it were for the
help of these plates; for he having been taught in
the language of the Egyptians therefore he could
read these engravings, and teach them to his
children, that thereby they could teach them to their
children, and so fulfilling the commandments of
God, even down to this present time
5 I say unto you, my sons, were it not for these
things, which have been kept and preserved by the
hand of God, that we might read and understand of
his mysteries, and have his commandments always
before our eyes, that even our fathers would have
dwindled in unbelief, and we should have been like
unto our brethren, the Lamanites, who know nothing
concerning these things, or even do not believe
them when they are taught them, because of the
traditions of their fathers, which are not correct
6 O my sons, I would that ye should remember that
these sayings are true, and also that these
records are true. And behold, also the plates of Nephi,
which contain the records and the sayings of our
fathers from the time they left Jerusalem until
now, and they are true; and we can know of their
surety because we have them before our eyes
7 And now, my sons, I would that ye should
remember to search them diligently, that ye may profit
thereby; and I would that ye should keep the
commandments of God, that ye may prosper in the land
according to the promises which the Lord made unto our
fathers
8 And many more things did king Benjamin teach his
sons, which are not written in this book
9 And it came to pass that after king Benjamin had
made an end of teaching his sons, that he waxed
old, and he saw that he must very soon go the way
of all the earth; therefore, he thought it
expedient that he should confer the kingdom upon one of
his sons
10 Therefore, he had Mosiah brought before him;
and these are the words which he spake unto him,
saying: My son, I would that ye should make a
proclamation throughout all this land among all this
people, or the people of Zarahemla, and the people of
Mosiah who dwell in the land, that thereby they
may be gathered together; for on the morrow I shall
proclaim unto this my people out of mine own mouth
that thou art a king and a ruler over this
people, whom the Lord our God hath given us
11 And moreover, I shall give this people a name,
that thereby they may be distinguished above all
the people which the Lord God hath brought out of
the land of Jerusalem; and this I do because they
have been a diligent people in keeping the
commandments of the Lord
12 And I give unto them a name that never shall be
blotted out, except it be through transgression
13 Yea, and moreover I say unto you, that if this
highly favored people of the Lord should fall into
transgression, and become a wicked and an
adulterous people, that the Lord will deliver them up,
that thereby they become weak like unto their
brethren; and he will no more preserve them by his
matchless and marvelous power, as he has hitherto
preserved our fathers
14 For I say unto you, that if he had not extended
his arm in the preservation of our fathers they
must have fallen into the hands of the Lamanites,
and become victims to their hatred
15 And it came to pass that after king Benjamin
had made an end of these sayings to his son, that he
gave him charge concerning all the affairs of the
kingdom
16 And moreover, he also gave him charge
concerning the records which were engraven on the plates of
brass; and also the plates of Nephi; and also,
the sword of Laban, and the ball or director, which
led our fathers through the wilderness, which was
prepared by the hand of the Lord that thereby they
might be led, every one according to the heed and
diligence which they gave unto him
17 Therefore, as they were unfaithful they did not
prosper nor progress in their journey, but were
driven back, and incurred the displeasure of God
upon them; and therefore they were smitten with
famine and sore afflictions, to stir them up in
remembrance of their duty
18 And now, it came to pass that Mosiah went and
did as his father had commanded him, and proclaimed
unto all the people who were in the land of
Zarahemla that thereby they might gather themselves
together, to go up to the temple to hear the words
which his father should speak unto them.