Chapter 29 Mosiah proposes that judges be
chosen in place of a king—Unrighteous kings lead
their people into sin—Alma the younger is
chosen chief judge by the voice of the
people—He is also the high priest over the
Church—Alma the elder and Mosiah die. About 92–91 B.C.
1 Now when Mosiah had done this he
sent out throughout all the land, among
all the people, desiring to know their
will concerning who should be their king.
2 And it came to pass that the
voice of the people came, saying:
We are desirous that Aaron thy son
should be our king and our ruler.
3 Now Aaron had gone up to the
land of Nephi, therefore the king
could not confer the kingdom
upon him; neither would Aaron take
upon him the kingdom; neither
were any of the sons of Mosiah
willing to take upon them the kingdom.
4 Therefore king Mosiah sent
again among the people; yea, even
a written word sent he among
the people. And these were the
words that were written, saying:
5 Behold, O ye my people, or
my brethren, for I esteem you
as such, I desire that ye
should consider the cause which
ye are called to
consider—for ye are desirous to have a king.
6 Now I declare unto you
that he to whom the
kingdom doth rightly belong
has declined, and will not
take upon him the kingdom.
7 And now if there
should be another appointed
in his stead, behold I
fear there would rise
contentions among you.
And who knoweth but
what my son, to whom the
kingdom doth belong,
should turn to be angry
and draw away a part of
this people after him,
which would cause wars
and contentions among
you, which would be the
cause of shedding much
blood and perverting the
way of the Lord, yea,
and destroy the souls of many people.
8 Now I say unto you
let us be wise and
consider these things,
for we have no right
to destroy my son,
neither should we have
any right to destroy
another if he should
be appointed in his stead.
9 And if my son
should turn again to his
pride and vain
things he would recall
the things which he
had said, and claim
his right to the
kingdom, which would
cause him and also this
people to commit much sin.
10 And now let us
be wise and look
forward to these
things, and do that
which will make for the
peace of this people.
11 Therefore I
will be your king the
remainder of my
days; nevertheless,
let us appoint
judges, to judge
this people according
to our law; and
we will newly
arrange the affairs of
this people, for
we will appoint
wise men to be
judges, that will judge
this people
according to the commandments of God.
12 Now it is
better that a man
should be judged of
God than of man,
for the judgments
of God are
always just, but the
judgments of man
are not always just.
13 Therefore, if
it were
possible that you could
have just men
to be your kings,
who would
establish the laws of
God, and judge
this people
according to his
commandments, yea,
if ye could have
men for your
kings who would do
even as my
father Benjamin did
for this
people—I say unto you,
if this could
always be the case
then it would
be expedient that
ye should
always have kings to rule over you.
14 And even I
myself have
labored with all
the power and
faculties which I
have possessed,
to teach you
the commandments
of God, and to
establish
peace throughout
the land, that
there should be
no wars nor
contentions, no
stealing, nor
plundering, nor
murdering, nor any
manner of iniquity;
15 And
whosoever has
committed iniquity,
him have I
punished according
to the crime
which he has
committed,
according to the
law which has
been given to
us by our fathers.
16 Now I say
unto you,
that because all
men are not
just it is
not expedient
that ye should
have a king
or kings to
rule over you.
17 For
behold, how much
iniquity
doth one wicked
king cause
to be
committed, yea,
and what great
destruction!
18 Yea,
remember king
Noah, his
wickedness
and his
abominations,
and also the
wickedness
and
abominations of
his people.
Behold what
great
destruction did
come upon
them; and
also because
of their
iniquities
they were brought into bondage.
19 And
were it not
for the
interposition
of their
all-wise
Creator,
and this
because of
their
sincere
repentance, they
must
unavoidably
remain in bondage until now.
20 But
behold, he
did deliver
them
because they
did humble
themselves
before
him; and
because they
cried
mightily unto
him he did
deliver
them out of
bondage;
and thus
doth the
Lord work
with his
power in all
cases among
the
children of
men,
extending the arm
of mercy
towards
them that put
their
trust in him.
21 And
behold, now I
say unto
you, ye
cannot
dethrone an
iniquitous
king save it
be
through much
contention,
and the
shedding of
much blood.
22 For
behold, he
has his
friends in
iniquity, and he
keepeth
his guards
about
him; and he
teareth
up the
laws of
those who
have
reigned in
righteousness
before
him; and
he
trampleth under
his feet
the commandments of God;
23 And
he
enacteth laws,
and
sendeth
them forth
among
his
people, yea,
laws
after the
manner of
his own
wickedness; and
whosoever doth
not obey
his laws
he
causeth to
be
destroyed; and
whosoever doth
rebel
against
him he
will send
his
armies
against them
to war,
and if he
can he
will
destroy
them; and
thus an
unrighteous king
doth pervert the ways of all righteousness.
24 And
now
behold I
say unto
you,
it is
not
expedient
that such
abominations
should
come upon you.
Therefore,
choose
you by
the
voice of
this
people,
judges,
that ye
may be
judged
according to
the laws
which
have
been
given you
by our
fathers,
which
are
correct,
and
which were
given
them by
the
hand of
the Lord.
26 Now
it is
not
common
that
the
voice of
people
desireth
anything
contrary to
that
which is
right; but
it is
common
for
the
lesser
part of
the
people
to
desire
that
which is
not
right;
therefore this
shall
ye
observe
and
make it
your
law—to
do your business by the voice of the people.
And if
the
time
comes
that
the
voice
of
the
people
doth
choose
iniquity,
then
is
the
time
that
the
judgments of
God
will
come
upon
you;
yea,
then
is the
time
he
will
visit
you
with
great
destruction even as he has hitherto visited this land.
And
now
if ye
have
judges,
and
they
do
not
judge
you
according to
the
law
which
has
been
given,
ye
can
cause
that
they may be judged of a higher judge.
If
your
higher
judges
do
not
judge
righteous
judgments,
ye
shall
cause
that
a
small
number
of
your
lower
judges
should
be
gathered
together,
and
they
shall
judge
your higher judges, according to the voice of the people.
And
I
command
you
to
do
these
things
in
the
fear
of
the
Lord;
and
I
command
you
to
do
these
things,
and
that
ye
have
no
king;
that
if
these
people commit sins and iniquities they shall be answered upon their own heads.
31 For behold I say unto you, the sins of many people have been caused by the iniquities of their kings; therefore their iniquities are answered upon the heads of their
For
behold
I
say
unto
you,
the
sins
of
many
people
have
been
caused
by
the
iniquities of their kings; therefore their iniquities are answered upon the heads of their kings.
32 And now I desire that this inequality should be no more in this land, especially among this my people; but I desire that this land be a land of liberty, and every man may enjoy his rights and privileges alike, so long as the Lord sees fit that we may live and inherit the land, yea, even as long as any of our posterity remains upon the face of the
And
now
I
desire
that
this
inequality
should
be
no
more
in
this
land,
especially
among
this
my
people;
but
I
desire
that
this
land
be
a
land
of
liberty,
and
every
man
may
enjoy
his
rights
and
privileges
alike,
so
long
as
the
Lord
sees
fit
that
we
may
live
and
inherit
the
land,
yea,
even
as
long
any
of
our
posterity
remains
upon
the
face
of
the
land.
33 And many more things did king Mosiah write unto them, unfolding unto them all the trials and troubles of a righteous king, yea, all the travails of soul for their people, and also all the murmurings of the people to their king; and he explained it all unto
And
many
more
things
did
king
Mosiah
write
unto
them,
unfolding
unto
them
all
the
trials
and
troubles
of
a
righteous
king,
yea,
all
the
travails
of
soul
for
their
people,
and
also
all
the
murmurings
of
the
people
to
their
king;
and
he
explained
it
all
unto
them.
34 And he told them that these things ought not to be; but that the burden should come upon all the people, that every man might bear his
And
he
told
them
that
these
things
ought
not
to
be;
but
that
the
burden
should
come
upon
all
the
people,
that
every
man
might
bear
his
part.
35 And he also unfolded unto them all the disadvantages they labored under, by having an unrighteous king to rule over
And
he
also
unfolded
unto
them
all
the
disadvantages
they
labored
under,
by
having
an
unrighteous
king
to
rule
over
them;
36 Yea, all his iniquities and abominations, and all the wars, and contentions, and bloodshed, and the stealing, and the plundering, and the committing of whoredoms, and all manner of iniquities which cannot be enumerated—telling them that these things ought not to be, that they were expressly repugnant to the commandments of
Yea,
all
his
iniquities
and
abominations,
all
the
wars,
and
contentions,
bloodshed,
and
the
stealing,
and
the
plundering,
and
the
committing
of
whoredoms,
and
all
manner
of
iniquities
which
cannot
be
enumerated—telling
them
that
these
things
ought
not
to
be,
that
they
were
expressly
repugnant
to
the
commandments
of
God.
37 And now it came to pass, after king Mosiah had sent these things forth among the people they were convinced of the truth of his
And
now
it
came
to
pass,
after
king
Mosiah
had
sent
these
things
forth
among
the
people
they
were
convinced
of
the
truth
of
his
words.
38 Therefore they relinquished their desires for a king, and became exceedingly anxious that every man should have an equal chance throughout all the land; yea, and every man expressed a willingness to answer for his own
Therefore
they
relinquished
their
desires
for
a
king,
and
became
exceedingly
anxious
that
every
man
should
have
an
equal
chance
throughout
all
the
land;
yea,
and
every
man
expressed
a
willingness
to
answer
for
his
own
sins.
39 Therefore, it came to pass that they assembled themselves together in bodies throughout the land, to cast in their voices concerning who should be their judges, to judge them according to the law which had been given them; and they were exceedingly rejoiced because of the liberty which had been granted unto
Therefore,
it
came
to
pass
that
they
assembled
themselves
together
in
bodies
throughout
the
land,
to
cast
in
their
voices
concerning
who
should
be
their
judges,
to
judge
them
according
to
the
law
which
had
been
given
them;
and
they
were
exceedingly
rejoiced
because
of
the
liberty
which
had
been
granted
unto
them.
40 And they did wax strong in love towards Mosiah; yea, they did esteem him more than any other man; for they did not look upon him as a tyrant who was seeking for gain, yea, for that lucre which doth corrupt the soul; for he had not exacted riches of them, neither had he delighted in the shedding of blood; but he had established peace in the land, and he had granted unto his people that they should be delivered from all manner of bondage; therefore they did esteem him, yea, exceedingly, beyond
And
they
did
wax
strong
in
love
towards
Mosiah;
yea,
they
did
esteem
him
more
than
any
other
man;
for
they
did
not
look
upon
him
as
a
tyrant
who
was
seeking
for
gain,
yea,
for
that
lucre
which
doth
corrupt
the
soul;
for
he
had
not
exacted
riches
of
them,
neither
had
he
delighted
in
the
shedding
of
blood;
but
he
had
established
peace
in
the
land,
and
he
had
granted
unto
his
people
that
they
should
be
delivered
from
all
manner
of
bondage;
therefore
they
did
esteem
him,
yea,
exceedingly,
beyond
measure.
41 And it came to pass that they did appoint judges to rule over them, or to judge them according to the law; and this they did throughout all the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
they
did
appoint
judges
to
rule
over
them,
or
to
judge
them
according
to
the
law;
and
this
they
did
throughout
all
the
land.
42 And it came to pass that Alma was appointed to be the first chief judge, he being also the high priest, his father having conferred the office upon him, and having given him the charge concerning all the affairs of the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma
was
appointed
to
be
the
first
chief
judge,
he
being
also
the
high
priest,
his
father
having
conferred
the
office
upon
him,
and
having
given
him
the
charge
concerning
all
the
affairs
of
the
church.
43 And now it came to pass that Alma did walk in the ways of the Lord, and he did keep his commandments, and he did judge righteous judgments; and there was continual peace through the
And
now
it
came
to
pass
that
Alma
did
walk
in
the
ways
of
the
Lord,
and
he
did
keep
his
commandments,
and
he
did
judge
righteous
judgments;
and
there
was
continual
peace
through
the
land.
44 And thus commenced the reign of the judges throughout all the land of Zarahemla, among all the people who were called the Nephites; and Alma was the first and chief
And
thus
commenced
the
reign
of
the
judges
throughout
all
the
land
of
Zarahemla,
among
all
the
people
who
were
called
the
Nephites;
and
Alma
was
the
first
and
chief
judge.
45 And now it came to pass that his father died, being eighty and two years old, having lived to fulfil the commandments of
And
now
it
came
to
pass
that
his
father
died,
being
eighty
and
two
years
old,
having
lived
to
fulfil
the
commandments
of
God.
46 And it came to pass that Mosiah died also, in the thirty and third year of his reign, being sixty and three years old; making in the whole, five hundred and nine years from the time Lehi left
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Mosiah
died
also,
in
the
thirty
and
third
year
of
his
reign,
being
sixty
and
three
years
old;
making
in
the
whole,
five
hundred
and
nine
years
from
the
time
Lehi
left
Jerusalem.
47 And thus ended the reign of the kings over the people of Nephi; and thus ended the days of Alma, who was the founder of their church.
And
thus
ended
the
reign
of
the
kings
over
the
people
of
Nephi;
and
thus
ended
the
days
of
Alma,
who
was
the
founder
of
their
church.