Chapter 14 Isaiah speaks
messianically—The Messiah’s humiliation and sufferings
are set forth—He makes His soul an offering
for sin and makes intercession for
transgressors—Compare
Isaiah 53. About 148 B.C.
1 Yea, even doth not Isaiah say:
Who hath believed our report, and to
whom is the arm of the Lord revealed?
2 For he shall grow up before
him as a tender plant, and as a
root out of dry ground; he hath
no form nor comeliness; and
when we shall see him there is no
beauty that we should desire him.
3 He is despised and
rejected of men; a man of
sorrows, and acquainted with
grief; and we hid as it were our
faces from him; he was
despised, and we esteemed him not.
4 Surely he has borne
our griefs, and carried
our sorrows; yet we did
esteem him stricken,
smitten of God, and afflicted.
5 But he was wounded
for our transgressions,
he was bruised for
our iniquities; the
chastisement of our peace
was upon him; and with
his stripes we are healed.
6 All we, like
sheep, have gone
astray; we have turned
every one to his own
way; and the Lord
hath laid on him the
iniquities of us all.
7 He was
oppressed, and he was
afflicted, yet he
opened not his mouth;
he is brought as a
lamb to the
slaughter, and as a
sheep before her
shearers is dumb so he
opened not his mouth.
8 He was taken
from prison and
from judgment;
and who shall
declare his
generation? For he was
cut off out of
the land of the
living; for the
transgressions of
my people was he stricken.
9 And he made
his grave with
the wicked, and
with the rich
in his death;
because he had
done no evil,
neither was any
deceit in his mouth.
10 Yet it
pleased the Lord
to bruise him;
he hath put
him to grief;
when thou shalt
make his soul
an offering
for sin he shall
see his seed,
he shall
prolong his days,
and the
pleasure of the Lord
shall prosper in his hand.
11 He shall
see the
travail of his
soul, and shall
be satisfied;
by his
knowledge shall my
righteous
servant justify
many; for he
shall bear
their iniquities.
12 Therefore
will I
divide him a
portion with
the great, and
he shall
divide the
spoil with the
strong;
because he hath
poured out
his soul unto
death; and
he was
numbered with the
transgressors; and he
bore the sins
of many,
and made
intercession for the transgressors.