Chapter 10 King Laman dies—His people
are wild and ferocious and believe in
false traditions—Zeniff and his people
prevail against them. About 187–160 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that we again
began to establish the kingdom and we
again began to possess the land in
peace. And I caused that there should be
weapons of war made of every kind, that
thereby I might have weapons for my
people against the time the Lamanites
should come up again to war against my people.
2 And I set guards round about the
land, that the Lamanites might not
come upon us again unawares and
destroy us; and thus I did guard my people
and my flocks, and keep them from
falling into the hands of our enemies.
3 And it came to pass that we
did inherit the land of our
fathers for many years, yea, for
the space of twenty and two years.
4 And I did cause that the men
should till the ground, and
raise all manner of grain and
all manner of fruit of every kind.
5 And I did cause that the
women should spin, and toil,
and work, and work all
manner of fine linen, yea, and
cloth of every kind, that we
might clothe our nakedness;
and thus we did prosper in
the land—thus we did have
continual peace in the land for
the space of twenty and two years.
6 And it came to pass that
king Laman died, and his
son began to reign in his
stead. And he began to
stir his people up in
rebellion against my people;
therefore they began to
prepare for war, and to come up
to battle against my people.
7 But I had sent my
spies out round about the
land of Shemlon, that I
might discover their
preparations, that I might
guard against them, that
they might not come upon
my people and destroy them.
8 And it came to pass
that they came up upon
the north of the land of
Shilom, with their
numerous hosts, men armed
with bows, and with
arrows, and with swords,
and with cimeters, and
with stones, and with
slings; and they had
their heads shaved that
they were naked; and they
were girded with a
leathern girdle about their loins.
9 And it came to pass
that I caused that the
women and children of
my people should be
hid in the wilderness;
and I also caused that
all my old men that
could bear arms, and
also all my young men
that were able to bear
arms, should gather
themselves together to go
to battle against the
Lamanites; and I did
place them in their
ranks, every man according to his age.
10 And it came to
pass that we did go up
to battle against
the Lamanites; and I,
even I, in my old
age, did go up to
battle against the
Lamanites. And it came
to pass that we did
go up in the strength
of the Lord to battle.
11 Now, the
Lamanites knew nothing
concerning the Lord,
nor the strength of
the Lord, therefore
they depended upon
their own
strength. Yet they were a
strong people, as to
the strength of men.
12 They were a
wild, and ferocious,
and a blood-thirsty
people, believing in
the tradition of
their fathers, which
is this—Believing
that they were
driven out of the land
of Jerusalem
because of the iniquities
of their fathers,
and that they were
wronged in the
wilderness by their
brethren, and they
were also wronged
while crossing the sea;
13 And again, that
they were wronged
while in the land
of their first
inheritance, after
they had crossed
the sea, and all
this because that
Nephi was more
faithful in keeping the
commandments of
the Lord—therefore
he was favored of
the Lord, for the
Lord heard his
prayers and answered
them, and he took
the lead of their
journey in the wilderness.
14 And his
brethren were wroth
with him because
they understood not
the dealings of
the Lord; they
were also wroth with
him upon the
waters because they
hardened their
hearts against the Lord.
15 And again,
they were wroth
with him when they
had arrived in
the promised
land, because they
said that he had
taken the
ruling of the people
out of their
hands; and they
sought to kill him.
16 And again,
they were
wroth with him
because he
departed into the
wilderness as
the Lord had
commanded him,
and took the
records which
were engraven on
the plates of
brass, for
they said that he robbed them.
17 And thus
they have
taught their
children that
they should hate
them, and
that they
should murder
them, and that
they should rob
and plunder
them, and do
all they
could to destroy
them;
therefore they have
an eternal
hatred towards
the children of Nephi.
18 For this
very cause
has king
Laman, by his
cunning, and
lying
craftiness, and his
fair
promises, deceived
me, that I
have brought
this my
people up into
this land,
that they may
destroy
them; yea, and
we have
suffered these
many years in the land.
19 And now
I, Zeniff,
after
having told all
these
things unto my
people
concerning the
Lamanites, I
did
stimulate them to
go to
battle with
their might,
putting
their trust in
the Lord;
therefore,
we did
contend with them, face to face.
20 And it
came to
pass that we
did drive
them
again out of
our land;
and we slew
them with
a great
slaughter,
even so
many that we
did not number them.
21 And it
came to
pass that
we
returned again
to our
own land,
and my
people
again began
to tend
their
flocks, and to
till their ground.
22 And
now I,
being old,
did confer
the
kingdom upon
one of my
sons;
therefore, I
say no
more. And
may the
Lord bless
my
people. Amen.