Chapter 2 King Benjamin addresses his people—He
recounts the equity, fairness, and spirituality of
his reign—He counsels them to serve their Heavenly
King—Those who rebel against God will suffer
anguish like unquenchable fire. About 124 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that after Mosiah had done
as his father had commanded him, and had made a
proclamation throughout all the land, that the people
gathered themselves together throughout all the
land, that they might go up to the temple to hear
the words which king Benjamin should speak unto
them
2 And there were a great number, even so many that
they did not number them; for they had multiplied
exceedingly and waxed great in the land
3 And they also took of the firstlings of their
flocks, that they might offer sacrifice and burnt
offerings according to the law of Moses
4 And also that they might give thanks to the Lord
their God, who had brought them out of the land
of Jerusalem, and who had delivered them out of the
hands of their enemies, and had appointed just
men to be their teachers, and also a just man to be
their king, who had established peace in the land
of Zarahemla, and who had taught them to keep the
commandments of God, that they might rejoice and
be filled with love towards God and all men
5 And it came to pass that when they came up to
the temple, they pitched their tents round about,
every man according to his family, consisting of his
wife, and his sons, and his daughters, and their
sons, and their daughters, from the eldest down to
the youngest, every family being separate one
from another
6 And they pitched their tents round about the
temple, every man having his tent with the door
thereof towards the temple, that thereby they might
remain in their tents and hear the words which king
Benjamin should speak unto them
7 For the multitude being so great that king
Benjamin could not teach them all within the walls of
the temple, therefore he caused a tower to be
erected, that thereby his people might hear the words
which he should speak unto them
8 And it came to pass that he began to speak to
his people from the tower; and they could not all
hear his words because of the greatness of the
multitude; therefore he caused that the words which he
spake should be written and sent forth among those
that were not under the sound of his voice, that
they might also receive his words
9 And these are the words which he spake and
caused to be written, saying: My brethren, all ye that
have assembled yourselves together, you that can
hear my words which I shall speak unto you this
day; for I have not commanded you to come up hither
to trifle with the words which I shall speak, but
that you should hearken unto me, and open your ears
that ye may hear, and your hearts that ye may
understand, and your minds that the mysteries of God
may be unfolded to your view
10 I have not commanded you to come up hither that
ye should fear me, or that ye should think that I
of myself am more than a mortal man
11 But I am like as yourselves, subject to all
manner of infirmities in body and mind; yet I have
been chosen by this people, and consecrated by my
father, and was suffered by the hand of the Lord
that I should be a ruler and a king over this people;
and have been kept and preserved by his matchless
power, to serve you with all the might, mind and
strength which the Lord hath granted unto me
12 I say unto you that as I have been suffered to
spend my days in your service, even up to this
time, and have not sought gold nor silver nor any
manner of riches of you
13 Neither have I suffered that ye should be
confined in dungeons, nor that ye should make slaves
one of another, nor that ye should murder, or
plunder, or steal, or commit adultery; nor even have I
suffered that ye should commit any manner of
wickedness, and have taught you that ye should keep the
commandments of the Lord, in all things which he
hath commanded you
14 And even I, myself, have labored with mine own
hands that I might serve you, and that ye should
not be laden with taxes, and that there should
nothing come upon you which was grievous to be
borne—and of all these things which I have spoken, ye
yourselves are witnesses this day
15 Yet, my brethren, I have not done these things
that I might boast, neither do I tell these things
that thereby I might accuse you; but I tell you
these things that ye may know that I can answer a
clear conscience before God this day
16 Behold, I say unto you that because I said unto
you that I had spent my days in your service, I
do not desire to boast, for I have only been in the
service of God
17 And behold, I tell you these things that ye may
learn wisdom; that ye may learn that when ye are
in the service of your fellow beings ye are only
in the service of your God
18 Behold, ye have called me your king; and if I,
whom ye call your king, do labor to serve you,
then ought not ye to labor to serve one another
19 And behold also, if I, whom ye call your king,
who has spent his days in your service, and yet
has been in the service of God, do merit any thanks
from you, O how you ought to thank your heavenly
King
20 I say unto you, my brethren, that if you should
render all the thanks and praise which your whole
soul has power to possess, to that God who has
created you, and has kept and preserved you, and has
caused that ye should rejoice, and has granted
that ye should live in peace one with another
21 I say unto you that if ye should serve him who
has created you from the beginning, and is
preserving you from day to day, by lending you breath,
that ye may live and move and do according to your
own will, and even supporting you from one moment
to another—I say, if ye should serve him with all
your whole souls yet ye would be unprofitable
servants
22 And behold, all that he requires of you is to
keep his commandments; and he has promised you that
if ye would keep his commandments ye should
prosper in the land; and he never doth vary from that
which he hath said; therefore, if ye do keep his
commandments he doth bless you and prosper you
23 And now, in the first place, he hath created
you, and granted unto you your lives, for which ye
are indebted unto him
24 And secondly, he doth require that ye should do
as he hath commanded you; for which if ye do, he
doth immediately bless you; and therefore he hath
paid you. And ye are still indebted unto him, and
are, and will be, forever and ever; therefore, of
what have ye to boast
25 And now I ask, can ye say aught of yourselves?
I answer you, Nay. Ye cannot say that ye are even
as much as the dust of the earth; yet ye were
created of the dust of the earth; but behold, it
belongeth to him who created you
26 And I, even I, whom ye call your king, am no
better than ye yourselves are; for I am also of the
dust. And ye behold that I am old, and am about to
yield up this mortal frame to its mother earth
27 Therefore, as I said unto you that I had served
you, walking with a clear conscience before God,
even so I at this time have caused that ye should
assemble yourselves together, that I might be
found blameless, and that your blood should not come
upon me, when I shall stand to be judged of God of
the things whereof he hath commanded me concerning
you
28 I say unto you that I have caused that ye
should assemble yourselves together that I might rid my
garments of your blood, at this period of time
when I am about to go down to my grave, that I might
go down in peace, and my immortal spirit may join
the choirs above in singing the praises of a just
God
29 And moreover, I say unto you that I have caused
that ye should assemble yourselves together, that
I might declare unto you that I can no longer be
your teacher, nor your king
30 For even at this time, my whole frame doth
tremble exceedingly while attempting to speak unto
you; but the Lord God doth support me, and hath
suffered me that I should speak unto you, and hath
commanded me that I should declare unto you this day,
that my son Mosiah is a king and a ruler over you
31 And now, my brethren, I would that ye should do
as ye have hitherto done. As ye have kept my
commandments, and also the commandments of my father,
and have prospered, and have been kept from
falling into the hands of your enemies, even so if ye
shall keep the commandments of my son, or the
commandments of God which shall be delivered unto you by
him, ye shall prosper in the land, and your
enemies shall have no power over you
32 But, O my people, beware lest there shall arise
contentions among you, and ye list to obey the
evil spirit, which was spoken of by my father
Mosiah
33 For behold, there is a wo pronounced upon him
who listeth to obey that spirit; for if he listeth
to obey him, and remaineth and dieth in his sins,
the same drinketh damnation to his own soul; for
he receiveth for his wages an everlasting
punishment, having transgressed the law of God contrary to
his own knowledge
34 I say unto you, that there are not any among
you, except it be your little children that have not
been taught concerning these things, but what
knoweth that ye are eternally indebted to your
heavenly Father, to render to him all that you have and
are; and also have been taught concerning the
records which contain the prophecies which have been
spoken by the holy prophets, even down to the time
our father, Lehi, left Jerusalem
35 And also, all that has been spoken by our
fathers until now. And behold, also, they spake that
which was commanded them of the Lord; therefore,
they are just and true
36 And now, I say unto you, my brethren, that
after ye have known and have been taught all these
things, if ye should transgress and go contrary to
that which has been spoken, that ye do withdraw
yourselves from the Spirit of the Lord, that it may
have no place in you to guide you in wisdom’s paths
that ye may be blessed, prospered, and preserved
37 I say unto you, that the man that doeth this,
the same cometh out in open rebellion against God;
therefore he listeth to obey the evil spirit, and
becometh an enemy to all righteousness; therefore,
the Lord has no place in him, for he dwelleth not
in unholy temples
38 Therefore if that man repenteth not, and
remaineth and dieth an enemy to God, the demands of
divine justice do awaken his immortal soul to a lively
sense of his own guilt, which doth cause him to
shrink from the presence of the Lord, and doth fill
his breast with guilt, and pain, and anguish,
which is like an unquenchable fire, whose flame
ascendeth up forever and ever
39 And now I say unto you, that mercy hath no
claim on that man; therefore his final doom is to
endure a never-ending torment
40 O, all ye old men, and also ye young men, and
you little children who can understand my words,
for I have spoken plainly unto you that ye might
understand, I pray that ye should awake to a
remembrance of the awful situation of those that have
fallen into transgression
41 And moreover, I would desire that ye should
consider on the blessed and happy state of those that
keep the commandments of God. For behold, they
are blessed in all things, both temporal and
spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they
are received into heaven, that thereby they may
dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness.
O remember, remember that these things are true;
for the Lord God hath spoken it.