Chapter 19 Gideon seeks to slay King Noah—The
Lamanites invade the land—King Noah suffers death by
fire—Limhi rules as a tributary monarch. About
145–121 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that the army of the king
returned, having searched in vain for the people of
the Lord
2 And now behold, the forces of the king were
small, having been reduced, and there began to be a
division among the remainder of the people
3 And the lesser part began to breathe out
threatenings against the king, and there began to be a
great contention among them
4 And now there was a man among them whose name
was Gideon, and he being a strong man and an enemy
to the king, therefore he drew his sword, and swore
in his wrath that he would slay the king
5 And it came to pass that he fought with the
king; and when the king saw that he was about to
overpower him, he fled and ran and got upon the tower
which was near the temple
6 And Gideon pursued after him and was about to
get upon the tower to slay the king, and the king
cast his eyes round about towards the land of
Shemlon, and behold, the army of the Lamanites were
within the borders of the land
7 And now the king cried out in the anguish of his
soul, saying: Gideon, spare me, for the Lamanites
are upon us, and they will destroy us; yea, they
will destroy my people
8 And now the king was not so much concerned about
his people as he was about his own life;
nevertheless, Gideon did spare his life
9 And the king commanded the people that they
should flee before the Lamanites, and he himself did
go before them, and they did flee into the
wilderness, with their women and their children
10 And it came to pass that the Lamanites did
pursue them, and did overtake them, and began to slay
them
11 Now it came to pass that the king commanded
them that all the men should leave their wives and
their children, and flee before the Lamanites
12 Now there were many that would not leave them,
but had rather stay and perish with them. And the
rest left their wives and their children and fled
13 And it came to pass that those who tarried with
their wives and their children caused that their
fair daughters should stand forth and plead with
the Lamanites that they would not slay them
14 And it came to pass that the Lamanites had
compassion on them, for they were charmed with the
beauty of their women
15 Therefore the Lamanites did spare their lives,
and took them captives and carried them back to
the land of Nephi, and granted unto them that they
might possess the land, under the conditions that
they would deliver up king Noah into the hands of
the Lamanites, and deliver up their property, even
one half of all they possessed, one half of their
gold, and their silver, and all their precious
things, and thus they should pay tribute to the king
of the Lamanites from year to year
16 And now there was one of the sons of the king
among those that were taken captive, whose name was
Limhi
17 And now Limhi was desirous that his father
should not be destroyed; nevertheless, Limhi was not
ignorant of the iniquities of his father, he
himself being a just man
18 And it came to pass that Gideon sent men into
the wilderness secretly, to search for the king and
those that were with him. And it came to pass
that they met the people in the wilderness, all save
the king and his priests
19 Now they had sworn in their hearts that they
would return to the land of Nephi, and if their
wives and their children were slain, and also those
that had tarried with them, that they would seek
revenge, and also perish with them
20 And the king commanded them that they should
not return; and they were angry with the king, and
caused that he should suffer, even unto death by
fire
21 And they were about to take the priests also
and put them to death, and they fled before them
22 And it came to pass that they were about to
return to the land of Nephi, and they met the men of
Gideon. And the men of Gideon told them of all
that had happened to their wives and their children;
and that the Lamanites had granted unto them that
they might possess the land by paying a tribute to
the Lamanites of one half of all they possessed
23 And the people told the men of Gideon that they
had slain the king, and his priests had fled from
them farther into the wilderness
24 And it came to pass that after they had ended
the ceremony, that they returned to the land of
Nephi, rejoicing, because their wives and their
children were not slain; and they told Gideon what they
had done to the king
25 And it came to pass that the king of the
Lamanites made an oath unto them, that his people should
not slay them
26 And also Limhi, being the son of the king,
having the kingdom conferred upon him by the people,
made oath unto the king of the Lamanites that his
people should pay tribute unto him, even one half
of all they possessed
27 And it came to pass that Limhi began to
establish the kingdom and to establish peace among his
people
28 And the king of the Lamanites set guards round
about the land, that he might keep the people of
Limhi in the land, that they might not depart into
the wilderness; and he did support his guards out
of the tribute which he did receive from the
Nephites
29 And now king Limhi did have continual peace in
his kingdom for the space of two years, that the
Lamanites did not molest them nor seek to destroy
them.