The Record of Zeniff—An account of his
people, from the time they left the land of
Zarahemla until the time that they were delivered
out of the hands of the Lamanites. Comprising
chapters 9 through 22.Chapter 9 Zeniff leads a
group from Zarahemla to possess the land of
Lehi-Nephi—The Lamanite king permits them to
inherit the land—There is war between the
Lamanites and Zeniff’s people. About 200–187 B.C.
1 I, Zeniff, having been taught in all the
language of the Nephites, and having had a
knowledge of the land of Nephi, or of the land
of our fathers’ first inheritance, and
having been sent as a spy among the Lamanites
that I might spy out their forces, that our
army might come upon them and destroy them—but
when I saw that which was good among them I
was desirous that they should not be destroyed.
2 Therefore, I contended with my brethren
in the wilderness, for I would that our
ruler should make a treaty with them; but he
being an austere and a blood-thirsty man
commanded that I should be slain; but I
was rescued by the shedding of much blood;
for father fought against father, and
brother against brother, until the greater
number of our army was destroyed in the
wilderness; and we returned, those of us that
were spared, to the land of Zarahemla, to
relate that tale to their wives and their children.
3 And yet, I being over-zealous to
inherit the land of our fathers,
collected as many as were desirous to go up to
possess the land, and started again
on our journey into the wilderness to
go up to the land; but we were smitten
with famine and sore afflictions; for
we were slow to remember the Lord our God.
4 Nevertheless, after many days’
wandering in the wilderness we
pitched our tents in the place
where our brethren were slain, which
was near to the land of our fathers.
5 And it came to pass that I
went again with four of my men into
the city, in unto the king,
that I might know of the
disposition of the king, and that I might
know if I might go in with my
people and possess the land in peace.
6 And I went in unto the king,
and he covenanted with me that
I might possess the land of
Lehi-Nephi, and the land of Shilom.
7 And he also commanded
that his people should depart
out of the land, and I and
my people went into the
land that we might possess it.
8 And we began to build
buildings, and to
repair the walls of the
city, yea, even the walls
of the city of
Lehi-Nephi, and the city of Shilom.
9 And we began to till
the ground, yea, even
with all manner of
seeds, with seeds of
corn, and of wheat, and
of barley, and with
neas, and with sheum, and
with seeds of all
manner of fruits; and we
did begin to multiply
and prosper in the land.
10 Now it was the
cunning and the
craftiness of king Laman,
to bring my people
into bondage, that he
yielded up the land
that we might possess it.
11 Therefore it came
to pass, that after
we had dwelt in the
land for the space
of twelve years that
king Laman began to
grow uneasy, lest
by any means my
people should wax strong
in the land, and
that they could not
overpower them and
bring them into bondage.
12 Now they were a
lazy and an
idolatrous people;
therefore they were
desirous to bring us into
bondage, that they
might glut
themselves with the labors
of our hands; yea,
that they might
feast themselves upon
the flocks of our fields.
13 Therefore it
came to pass that
king Laman began
to stir up his
people that they
should contend with
my people;
therefore there began
to be wars and
contentions in the land.
14 For, in the
thirteenth year
of my reign in
the land of Nephi,
away on the
south of the land
of Shilom, when
my people were
watering and
feeding their flocks,
and tilling
their lands, a
numerous host of
Lamanites came upon
them and began
to slay them,
and to take off
their flocks, and
the corn of their fields.
15 Yea, and it
came to pass
that they fled,
all that were
not overtaken,
even into the
city of Nephi, and
did call upon
me for protection.
16 And it came
to pass that I
did arm them
with bows, and
with arrows, with
swords, and
with cimeters,
and with clubs,
and with slings,
and with all
manner of
weapons which we
could invent, and I
and my people
did go forth
against the
Lamanites to battle.
17 Yea, in the
strength of
the Lord did we
go forth to
battle against
the Lamanites;
for I and my
people did cry
mightily to
the Lord that
he would
deliver us out of
the hands of our
enemies, for
we were
awakened to a
remembrance of the
deliverance of our fathers.
18 And God
did hear our
cries and did
answer our
prayers; and we
did go forth
in his might;
yea, we did
go forth
against the
Lamanites, and in
one day and a
night we did
slay three
thousand and
forty-three;
we did slay
them even until
we had
driven them out of our land.
19 And I,
myself, with
mine own
hands, did help
to bury
their dead. And
behold, to
our great
sorrow and
lamentation, two
hundred and
seventy-nine of our
brethren were slain.