Chapter 16 God redeems men from their lost
and fallen state—Those who are carnal
remain as though there were no redemption—Christ
brings to pass a resurrection to endless
life or to endless damnation. About 148 B.C.
1 And now, it came to pass that after
Abinadi had spoken these words he stretched
forth his hand and said: The time shall come
when all shall see the salvation of the
Lord; when every nation, kindred, tongue,
and people shall see eye to eye and shall
confess before God that his judgments are just.
2 And then shall the wicked be cast
out, and they shall have cause to
howl, and weep, and wail, and gnash their
teeth; and this because they would
not hearken unto the voice of the
Lord; therefore the Lord redeemeth them not.
3 For they are carnal and
devilish, and the devil has power over
them; yea, even that old serpent
that did beguile our first
parents, which was the cause of their
fall; which was the cause of all
mankind becoming carnal, sensual,
devilish, knowing evil from good,
subjecting themselves to the devil.
4 Thus all mankind were lost;
and behold, they would have
been endlessly lost were it not
that God redeemed his people
from their lost and fallen state.
5 But remember that he that
persists in his own carnal
nature, and goes on in the
ways of sin and rebellion
against God, remaineth in
his fallen state and the
devil hath all power over him.
Therefore he is as though
there was no redemption
made, being an enemy to God;
and also is the devil an enemy to God.
6 And now if Christ had
not come into the world,
speaking of things to
come as though they had
already come, there could
have been no redemption.
7 And if Christ had
not risen from the
dead, or have broken the
bands of death that
the grave should have
no victory, and that
death should have no
sting, there could
have been no resurrection.
8 But there is a
resurrection,
therefore the grave hath
no victory, and the
sting of death is
swallowed up in Christ.
9 He is the light
and the life of
the world; yea, a
light that is
endless, that can
never be darkened;
yea, and also a
life which is
endless, that there
can be no more death.
10 Even this
mortal shall put on
immortality,
and this
corruption shall put on
incorruption, and
shall be
brought to stand
before the bar of
God, to be judged
of him according
to their works
whether they be
good or whether they be evil—
11 If they be
good, to the
resurrection of
endless life and
happiness; and
if they be
evil, to the
resurrection of
endless damnation,
being delivered
up to the
devil, who hath
subjected them,
which is damnation—
12 Having gone
according to
their own
carnal wills and
desires; having
never called
upon the Lord
while the arms
of mercy were
extended
towards them; for
the arms of
mercy were
extended towards
them, and they
would not; they
being warned
of their
iniquities and yet
they would not
depart from
them; and they
were commanded
to repent and
yet they would not repent.
13 And now,
ought ye not
to tremble and
repent of
your sins, and
remember that
only in and
through
Christ ye can be saved?
Therefore, if ye
teach the law of
Moses, also
teach that
it is a
shadow of those
things which
are to come—
15 Teach
them that
redemption
cometh through
Christ the
Lord, who
is the very
Eternal
Father. Amen.