An account of Alma and the people of the Lord, who
were driven into the wilderness by the people of
King Noah. Comprising chapters 23 and 24.Chapter
23 Alma refuses to be king—He serves as high
priest—The Lord chastens His people, and the Lamanites
conquer the land of Helam—Amulon, leader of King
Noah’s wicked priests, rules subject to the Lamanite
monarch. About 145–121 B.C.
1 Now Alma, having been warned of the Lord that
the armies of king Noah would come upon them, and
having made it known to his people, therefore they
gathered together their flocks, and took of their
grain, and departed into the wilderness before the
armies of king Noah
2 And the Lord did strengthen them, that the
people of king Noah could not overtake them to destroy
them
3 And they fled eight days’ journey into the
wilderness
4 And they came to a land, yea, even a very
beautiful and pleasant land, a land of pure water
5 And they pitched their tents, and began to till
the ground, and began to build buildings; yea,
they were industrious, and did labor exceedingly
6 And the people were desirous that Alma should be
their king, for he was beloved by his people
7 But he said unto them: Behold, it is not
expedient that we should have a king; for thus saith the
Lord: Ye shall not esteem one flesh above another,
or one man shall not think himself above another;
therefore I say unto you it is not expedient that
ye should have a king
8 Nevertheless, if it were possible that ye could
always have just men to be your kings it would be
well for you to have a king
9 But remember the iniquity of king Noah and his
priests; and I myself was caught in a snare, and
did many things which were abominable in the sight
of the Lord, which caused me sore repentance
10 Nevertheless, after much tribulation, the Lord
did hear my cries, and did answer my prayers, and
has made me an instrument in his hands in bringing
so many of you to a knowledge of his truth
11 Nevertheless, in this I do not glory, for I am
unworthy to glory of myself
12 And now I say unto you, ye have been oppressed
by king Noah, and have been in bondage to him and
his priests, and have been brought into iniquity
by them; therefore ye were bound with the bands of
iniquity
13 And now as ye have been delivered by the power
of God out of these bonds; yea, even out of the
hands of king Noah and his people, and also from the
bonds of iniquity, even so I desire that ye
should stand fast in this liberty wherewith ye have
been made free, and that ye trust no man to be a king
over you
14 And also trust no one to be your teacher nor
your minister, except he be a man of God, walking in
his ways and keeping his commandments
15 Thus did Alma teach his people, that every man
should love his neighbor as himself, that there
should be no contention among them
16 And now, Alma was their high priest, he being
the founder of their church
17 And it came to pass that none received
authority to preach or to teach except it were by him from
God. Therefore he consecrated all their priests
and all their teachers; and none were consecrated
except they were just men
18 Therefore they did watch over their people, and
did nourish them with things pertaining to
righteousness
19 And it came to pass that they began to prosper
exceedingly in the land; and they called the land
Helam
20 And it came to pass that they did multiply and
prosper exceedingly in the land of Helam; and they
built a city, which they called the city of
Helam
21 Nevertheless the Lord seeth fit to chasten his
people; yea, he trieth their patience and their
faith
22 Nevertheless—whosoever putteth his trust in him
the same shall be lifted up at the last day. Yea,
and thus it was with this people
23 For behold, I will show unto you that they were
brought into bondage, and none could deliver them
but the Lord their God, yea, even the God of
Abraham and Isaac and of Jacob
24 And it came to pass that he did deliver them,
and he did show forth his mighty power unto them,
and great were their rejoicings
25 For behold, it came to pass that while they
were in the land of Helam, yea, in the city of Helam,
while tilling the land round about, behold an
army of the Lamanites was in the borders of the land
26 Now it came to pass that the brethren of Alma
fled from their fields, and gathered themselves
together in the city of Helam; and they were much
frightened because of the appearance of the
Lamanites
27 But Alma went forth and stood among them, and
exhorted them that they should not be frightened,
but that they should remember the Lord their God
and he would deliver them
28 Therefore they hushed their fears, and began to
cry unto the Lord that he would soften the hearts
of the Lamanites, that they would spare them, and
their wives, and their children
29 And it came to pass that the Lord did soften
the hearts of the Lamanites. And Alma and his
brethren went forth and delivered themselves up into
their hands; and the Lamanites took possession of the
land of Helam
30 Now the armies of the Lamanites, which had
followed after the people of king Limhi, had been lost
in the wilderness for many days
31 And behold, they had found those priests of
king Noah, in a place which they called Amulon; and
they had begun to possess the land of Amulon and
had begun to till the ground
32 Now the name of the leader of those priests was
Amulon
33 And it came to pass that Amulon did plead with
the Lamanites; and he also sent forth their wives,
who were the daughters of the Lamanites, to plead
with their brethren, that they should not destroy
their husbands
34 And the Lamanites had compassion on Amulon and
his brethren, and did not destroy them, because of
their wives
35 And Amulon and his brethren did join the
Lamanites, and they were traveling in the wilderness in
search of the land of Nephi when they discovered
the land of Helam, which was possessed by Alma and
his brethren
36 And it came to pass that the Lamanites promised
unto Alma and his brethren, that if they would
show them the way which led to the land of Nephi
that they would grant unto them their lives and their
liberty
37 But after Alma had shown them the way that led
to the land of Nephi the Lamanites would not keep
their promise; but they set guards round about the
land of Helam, over Alma and his brethren
38 And the remainder of them went to the land of
Nephi; and a part of them returned to the land of
Helam, and also brought with them the wives and the
children of the guards who had been left in the
land
39 And the king of the Lamanites had granted unto
Amulon that he should be a king and a ruler over
his people, who were in the land of Helam;
nevertheless he should have no power to do anything
contrary to the will of the king of the Lamanites.