Chapter 17 Alma believes and writes the words of
Abinadi—Abinadi suffers death by fire—He prophesies
disease and death by fire upon his murderers.
About 148 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that when Abinadi had
finished these sayings, that the king commanded that
the priests should take him and cause that he
should be put to death
2 But there was one among them whose name was
Alma, he also being a descendant of Nephi. And he was
a young man, and he believed the words which
Abinadi had spoken, for he knew concerning the iniquity
which Abinadi had testified against them;
therefore he began to plead with the king that he would
not be angry with Abinadi, but suffer that he might
depart in peace
3 But the king was more wroth, and caused that
Alma should be cast out from among them, and sent his
servants after him that they might slay him
4 But he fled from before them and hid himself
that they found him not. And he being concealed for
many days did write all the words which Abinadi had
spoken
5 And it came to pass that the king caused that
his guards should surround Abinadi and take him; and
they bound him and cast him into prison
6 And after three days, having counseled with his
priests, he caused that he should again be brought
before him
7 And he said unto him: Abinadi, we have found an
accusation against thee, and thou art worthy of
death
8 For thou hast said that God himself should come
down among the children of men; and now, for this
cause thou shalt be put to death unless thou wilt
recall all the words which thou hast spoken evil
concerning me and my people
9 Now Abinadi said unto him: I say unto you, I
will not recall the words which I have spoken unto
you concerning this people, for they are true; and
that ye may know of their surety I have suffered
myself that I have fallen into your hands
10 Yea, and I will suffer even until death, and I
will not recall my words, and they shall stand as
a testimony against you. And if ye slay me ye will
shed innocent blood, and this shall also stand as
a testimony against you at the last day
11 And now king Noah was about to release him, for
he feared his word; for he feared that the
judgments of God would come upon him
12 But the priests lifted up their voices against
him, and began to accuse him, saying: He has
reviled the king. Therefore the king was stirred up in
anger against him, and he delivered him up that he
might be slain
13 And it came to pass that they took him and
bound him, and scourged his skin with faggots, yea,
even unto death
14 And now when the flames began to scorch him, he
cried unto them, saying
15 Behold, even as ye have done unto me, so shall
it come to pass that thy seed shall cause that
many shall suffer the pains that I do suffer, even
the pains of death by fire; and this because they
believe in the salvation of the Lord their God
16 And it will come to pass that ye shall be
afflicted with all manner of diseases because of your
iniquities
17 Yea, and ye shall be smitten on every hand, and
shall be driven and scattered to and fro, even as
a wild flock is driven by wild and ferocious
beasts
18 And in that day ye shall be hunted, and ye
shall be taken by the hand of your enemies, and then
ye shall suffer, as I suffer, the pains of death by
fire
19 Thus God executeth vengeance upon those that
destroy his people. O God, receive my soul
20 And now, when Abinadi had said these words, he
fell, having suffered death by fire; yea, having
been put to death because he would not deny the
commandments of God, having sealed the truth of his
words by his death.