Chapter 7 Ammon finds the land of Lehi-Nephi,
where Limhi is king—Limhi’s people are in bondage to
the Lamanites—Limhi recounts their history—A
prophet (Abinadi) had testified that Christ is the
God and Father of all things—Those who sow
filthiness reap the whirlwind, and those who put their
trust in the Lord will be delivered. About 121 B.C.
1 And now, it came to pass that after king
Mosiah had had continual peace for the space of
three years, he was desirous to know
concerning the people who went up to dwell in the
land of Lehi-Nephi, or in the city of
Lehi-Nephi; for his people had heard nothing from them
from the time they left the land of
Zarahemla; therefore, they wearied him with their teasings.
2 And it came to pass that king Mosiah
granted that sixteen of their strong
men might go up to the land of
Lehi-Nephi, to inquire concerning their brethren.
3 And it came to pass that on the
morrow they started to go up, having
with them one Ammon, he being a strong
and mighty man, and a descendant of
Zarahemla; and he was also their leader.
4 And now, they knew not the
course they should travel in the
wilderness to go up to the land of
Lehi-Nephi; therefore they
wandered many days in the
wilderness, even forty days did they wander.
5 And when they had
wandered forty days they came to
a hill, which is north of
the land of Shilom, and
there they pitched their tents.
6 And Ammon took three of
his brethren, and their
names were Amaleki,
Helem, and Hem, and they went
down into the land of Nephi.
7 And behold, they met
the king of the people
who were in the land of
Nephi, and in the land
of Shilom; and they
were surrounded by the
king’s guard, and were
taken, and were bound,
and were committed to prison.
8 And it came to pass
when they had been in
prison two days they
were again brought
before the king, and their
bands were loosed;
and they stood before
the king, and were
permitted, or rather
commanded, that they should
answer the questions
which he should ask them.
9 And he said unto
them: Behold, I am
Limhi, the son of Noah,
who was the son of
Zeniff, who came up out
of the land of
Zarahemla to inherit this
land, which was the
land of their fathers,
who was made a king
by the voice of the people.
10 And now, I
desire to know the cause
whereby ye were so
bold as to come
near the walls of the
city, when I,
myself, was with my
guards without the gate?
11 And now, for
this cause have I
suffered that ye
should be preserved,
that I might
inquire of you, or else
I should have
caused that my guards
should have put
you to death. Ye
are permitted to speak.
12 And now, when
Ammon saw that he
was permitted to
speak, he went
forth and bowed
himself before the
king; and rising
again he said: O
king, I am very
thankful before
God this day that I
am yet alive,
and am permitted to
speak; and I
will endeavor to
speak with boldness;
13 For I am
assured that if ye
had known me ye
would not have
suffered that I
should have worn
these bands. For
I am Ammon, and
am a descendant
of Zarahemla,
and have come up
out of the land
of Zarahemla to
inquire
concerning our brethren,
whom Zeniff
brought up out of that land.
14 And now, it
came to pass
that after Limhi
had heard the
words of Ammon,
he was
exceedingly glad, and
said: Now, I
know of a surety
that my brethren
who were in
the land of
Zarahemla are yet
alive. And now, I
will rejoice;
and on the
morrow I will cause
that my people
shall rejoice also.
15 For behold,
we are in
bondage to the
Lamanites, and
are taxed with
a tax which is
grievous to
be borne. And
now, behold,
our brethren
will deliver us
out of our
bondage, or out of
the hands of
the Lamanites,
and we will
be their
slaves; for it is
better that we
be slaves to
the Nephites
than to pay
tribute to the king of the Lamanites.
16 And now,
king Limhi
commanded his
guards that
they should no
more bind
Ammon nor his
brethren, but
caused that
they should go
to the hill
which was north
of Shilom,
and bring
their brethren
into the city,
that thereby
they might
eat, and drink,
and rest
themselves from
the labors of
their
journey; for they
had suffered
many things;
they had
suffered hunger, thirst, and fatigue.
17 And now,
it came to
pass on the
morrow that
king Limhi
sent a
proclamation among
all his
people, that
thereby they
might gather
themselves
together to
the temple, to
hear the
words which he
should speak unto them.
18 And it
came to pass
that when
they had
gathered
themselves together
that he spake
unto them
in this wise,
saying: O
ye, my
people, lift up
your heads and
be
comforted; for
behold, the time
is at hand,
or is not
far distant,
when we shall
no longer
be in
subjection to our
enemies,
notwithstanding
our many
strugglings,
which have
been in vain;
yet I trust
there
remaineth an
effectual struggle
to be made.
Therefore, lift up
your heads,
and
rejoice, and put
your trust
in God, in
that God
who was the
God of
Abraham, and
Isaac, and
Jacob; and
also, that God
who
brought the
children of
Israel out of
the land of
Egypt, and
caused that
they
should walk
through the Red
Sea on dry
ground,
and fed them
with manna
that they
might not
perish in the
wilderness; and many more things did he do for them.
20 And
again, that
same God
has brought
our
fathers out of
the land of
Jerusalem, and has
kept and
preserved
his people
even until
now; and
behold, it
is
because of our
iniquities
and
abominations
that he has
brought us into bondage.
21 And ye
all are
witnesses
this
day, that
Zeniff, who
was made
king
over this
people, he
being
over-zealous
to
inherit the
land of his
fathers,
therefore being
deceived
by the
cunning and
craftiness of king
Laman,
who having
entered
into a
treaty with
king
Zeniff, and
having
yielded up
into his
hands the
possessions of a
part of
the land,
or even
the city
of
Lehi-Nephi, and
the city of Shilom; and the land round about—
22 And
all this
he did,
for the
sole
purpose of
bringing
this
people
into
subjection or
bondage.
And
behold, we at
this
time do pay
tribute
to the
king of
the
Lamanites,
to the
amount of
one half
of our
corn,
and our
barley,
and even
all our
grain of
every
kind, and
one half
of the
increase
of our
flocks
and our
herds;
and even
one half
of all
we have
or
possess the
king of the Lamanites doth exact of us, or our lives.
23 And
now, is
not
this
grievous to
be
borne? And
is not
this,
our
affliction,
great? Now
behold,
how
great
reason we have to mourn.
Yea, I
say unto
you,
great
are
the
reasons
which we
have
to
mourn;
for
behold how
many
of our
brethren
have
been
slain, and
their
blood
has
been
spilt in
vain,
and all because of iniquity.
For if
this
people had
not
fallen
into
transgression
the
Lord
would
not
have
suffered
that
this
great
evil
should
come
upon
them.
But
behold,
they
would
not
hearken
unto
his
words;
but
there
arose
contentions
among
them,
even
so much that they did shed blood among themselves.
And a
prophet
of
the
Lord
have
they
slain;
yea, a
chosen
man
of
God,
who
told
them of
their
wickedness
and
abominations,
prophesied
of
many
things
which
are to come, yea, even the coming of Christ.
And
because
he
said
unto
them
that
Christ
was
the
God,
Father
of
all
things,
and
said
that
he
should
take
upon
him
the
image
of
man,
and
it
should
be
the
image
after
which
man
was
created
in
the
beginning;
or
in
other
words,
he
said
that
man
was
created
after
the
image
of
God,
and
that
God
should
come
down among the children of men, and take upon him flesh and blood, and go forth upon the face of the earth—
And
now,
because
he
said
this,
they
did
put
him
to
death;
and
many
more
things
did
they
do
which
brought
down
the
wrath
of
God
upon
them.
Therefore,
who
wondereth
that
they
are
in
bondage,
and
that
they
are
smitten
with
sore
afflictions?
For
behold,
the
Lord
hath
said:
I
will
not
succor
my
people
in
the
day
of
their
transgression;
but
I
will
hedge
up
their
ways
that
they
prosper not; and their doings shall be as a stumbling block before them.
30 And again, he saith: If my people shall sow filthiness they shall reap the chaff thereof in the whirlwind; and the effect thereof is
And
again,
he
saith:
If
my
people
shall
sow
filthiness
they
shall
reap the chaff thereof in the whirlwind; and the effect thereof is poison.
31 And again he saith: If my people shall sow filthiness they shall reap the east wind, which bringeth immediate
And
again
he
saith:
If
my
people
shall
sow
filthiness
they
shall
reap
the
east
wind,
which
bringeth
immediate
destruction.
32 And now, behold, the promise of the Lord is fulfilled, and ye are smitten and
And
now,
behold,
the
promise
of
the
Lord
is
fulfilled,
and
ye
are
smitten
and
afflicted.
33 But if ye will turn to the Lord with full purpose of heart, and put your trust in him, and serve him with all diligence of mind, if ye do this, he will, according to his own will and pleasure, deliver you out of bondage.
But
if
ye
will
turn
to
the
Lord
with
full
purpose
of
heart,
and
put
your
trust
in
him,
and
serve
him
with
all
diligence
of
mind,
if
ye
do
this,
he
will,
according
to
his
own
will
and
pleasure,
deliver
you
out
of
bondage.