Chapter 27 Mosiah forbids persecution and enjoins
equality—Alma the younger and the four sons of
Mosiah seek to destroy the Church—An angel appears
and commands them to cease their evil course—Alma is
struck dumb—All mankind must be born again to
gain salvation—Alma and the sons of Mosiah declare
glad tidings. About 100–92 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that the persecutions
which were inflicted on the church by the
unbelievers became so great that the church began to murmur,
and complain to their leaders concerning the
matter; and they did complain to Alma. And Alma laid
the case before their king, Mosiah. And Mosiah
consulted with his priests
2 And it came to pass that king Mosiah sent a
proclamation throughout the land round about that
there should not any unbeliever persecute any of those
who belonged to the church of God
3 And there was a strict command throughout all
the churches that there should be no persecutions
among them, that there should be an equality among
all men
4 That they should let no pride nor haughtiness
disturb their peace; that every man should esteem
his neighbor as himself, laboring with their own
hands for their support
5 Yea, and all their priests and teachers should
labor with their own hands for their support, in
all cases save it were in sickness, or in much want;
and doing these things, they did abound in the
grace of God
6 And there began to be much peace again in the
land; and the people began to be very numerous, and
began to scatter abroad upon the face of the
earth, yea, on the north and on the south, on the east
and on the west, building large cities and
villages in all quarters of the land
7 And the Lord did visit them and prosper them,
and they became a large and wealthy people
8 Now the sons of Mosiah were numbered among the
unbelievers; and also one of the sons of Alma was
numbered among them, he being called Alma, after
his father; nevertheless, he became a very wicked
and an idolatrous man. And he was a man of many
words, and did speak much flattery to the people;
therefore he led many of the people to do after the
manner of his iniquities
9 And he became a great hinderment to the
prosperity of the church of God; stealing away the hearts
of the people; causing much dissension among the
people; giving a chance for the enemy of God to
exercise his power over them
10 And now it came to pass that while he was going
about to destroy the church of God, for he did go
about secretly with the sons of Mosiah seeking to
destroy the church, and to lead astray the people
of the Lord, contrary to the commandments of God,
or even the king
11 And as I said unto you, as they were going
about rebelling against God, behold, the angel of the
Lord appeared unto them; and he descended as it
were in a cloud; and he spake as it were with a
voice of thunder, which caused the earth to shake upon
which they stood
12 And so great was their astonishment, that they
fell to the earth, and understood not the words
which he spake unto them
13 Nevertheless he cried again, saying: Alma,
arise and stand forth, for why persecutest thou the
church of God? For the Lord hath said: This is my
church, and I will establish it; and nothing shall
overthrow it, save it is the transgression of my
people
14 And again, the angel said: Behold, the Lord
hath heard the prayers of his people, and also the
prayers of his servant, Alma, who is thy father; for
he has prayed with much faith concerning thee
that thou mightest be brought to the knowledge of the
truth; therefore, for this purpose have I come to
convince thee of the power and authority of God,
that the prayers of his servants might be answered
according to their faith
15 And now behold, can ye dispute the power of
God? For behold, doth not my voice shake the earth?
And can ye not also behold me before you? And I am
sent from God
16 Now I say unto thee: Go, and remember the
captivity of thy fathers in the land of Helam, and in
the land of Nephi; and remember how great things he
has done for them; for they were in bondage, and
he has delivered them. And now I say unto thee,
Alma, go thy way, and seek to destroy the church no
more, that their prayers may be answered, and this
even if thou wilt of thyself be cast off
17 And now it came to pass that these were the
last words which the angel spake unto Alma, and he
departed
18 And now Alma and those that were with him fell
again to the earth, for great was their
astonishment; for with their own eyes they had beheld an
angel of the Lord; and his voice was as thunder,
which shook the earth; and they knew that there was
nothing save the power of God that could shake the
earth and cause it to tremble as though it would
part asunder
19 And now the astonishment of Alma was so great
that he became dumb, that he could not open his
mouth; yea, and he became weak, even that he could
not move his hands; therefore he was taken by those
that were with him, and carried helpless, even
until he was laid before his father
20 And they rehearsed unto his father all that had
happened unto them; and his father rejoiced, for
he knew that it was the power of God
21 And he caused that a multitude should be
gathered together that they might witness what the Lord
had done for his son, and also for those that were
with him
22 And he caused that the priests should assemble
themselves together; and they began to fast, and
to pray to the Lord their God that he would open
the mouth of Alma, that he might speak, and also
that his limbs might receive their strength—that the
eyes of the people might be opened to see and know
of the goodness and glory of God
23 And it came to pass after they had fasted and
prayed for the space of two days and two nights,
the limbs of Alma received their strength, and he
stood up and began to speak unto them, bidding them
to be of good comfort
24 For, said he, I have repented of my sins, and
have been redeemed of the Lord; behold I am born of
the Spirit
25 And the Lord said unto me: Marvel not that all
mankind, yea, men and women, all nations,
kindreds, tongues and people, must be born again; yea,
born of God, changed from their carnal and fallen
state, to a state of righteousness, being redeemed of
God, becoming his sons and daughters
26 And thus they become new creatures; and unless
they do this, they can in nowise inherit the
kingdom of God
27 I say unto you, unless this be the case, they
must be cast off; and this I know, because I was
like to be cast off
28 Nevertheless, after wading through much
tribulation, repenting nigh unto death, the Lord in mercy
hath seen fit to snatch me out of an everlasting
burning, and I am born of God
29 My soul hath been redeemed from the gall of
bitterness and bonds of iniquity. I was in the
darkest abyss; but now I behold the marvelous light of
God. My soul was racked with eternal torment; but I
am snatched, and my soul is pained no more
30 I rejected my Redeemer, and denied that which
had been spoken of by our fathers; but now that
they may foresee that he will come, and that he
remembereth every creature of his creating, he will
make himself manifest unto all
31 Yea, every knee shall bow, and every tongue
confess before him. Yea, even at the last day, when
all men shall stand to be judged of him, then shall
they confess that he is God; then shall they
confess, who live without God in the world, that the
judgment of an everlasting punishment is just upon
them; and they shall quake, and tremble, and
shrink beneath the glance of his all-searching eye
32 And now it came to pass that Alma began from
this time forward to teach the people, and those who
were with Alma at the time the angel appeared
unto them, traveling round about through all the
land, publishing to all the people the things which
they had heard and seen, and preaching the word of
God in much tribulation, being greatly persecuted
by those who were unbelievers, being smitten by
many of them
33 But notwithstanding all this, they did impart
much consolation to the church, confirming their
faith, and exhorting them with long-suffering and
much travail to keep the commandments of God
34 And four of them were the sons of Mosiah; and
their names were Ammon, and Aaron, and Omner, and
Himni; these were the names of the sons of Mosiah
35 And they traveled throughout all the land of
Zarahemla, and among all the people who were under
the reign of king Mosiah, zealously striving to
repair all the injuries which they had done to the
church, confessing all their sins, and publishing
all the things which they had seen, and explaining
the prophecies and the scriptures to all who
desired to hear them
36 And thus they were instruments in the hands of
God in bringing many to the knowledge of the
truth, yea, to the knowledge of their Redeemer
37 And how blessed are they! For they did publish
peace; they did publish good tidings of good; and
they did declare unto the people that the Lord
reigneth.