Chapter 3 King Benjamin continues his
address—The Lord Omnipotent will minister among men in a
tabernacle of clay—Blood will come from every
pore as He atones for the sins of the world—His is
the only name whereby salvation comes—Men can
put off the natural man and become Saints through
the Atonement—The torment of the wicked will be
as a lake of fire and brimstone. About 124 B.C.
1 And again my brethren, I would call your
attention, for I have somewhat more to
speak unto you; for behold, I have things to
tell you concerning that which is to come.
2 And the things which I shall tell you
are made known unto me by an angel
from God. And he said unto me: Awake; and
I awoke, and behold he stood before me.
3 And he said unto me: Awake, and
hear the words which I shall tell
thee; for behold, I am come to declare
unto you the glad tidings of great joy.
4 For the Lord hath heard thy
prayers, and hath judged of thy
righteousness, and hath sent me to
declare unto thee that thou
mayest rejoice; and that thou
mayest declare unto thy people, that
they may also be filled with joy.
5 For behold, the time cometh,
and is not far distant, that
with power, the Lord Omnipotent
who reigneth, who was, and is
from all eternity to all
eternity, shall come down from heaven
among the children of men, and
shall dwell in a tabernacle of
clay, and shall go forth amongst
men, working mighty miracles,
such as healing the sick,
raising the dead, causing the lame
to walk, the blind to receive
their sight, and the deaf to
hear, and curing all manner of diseases.
6 And he shall cast out
devils, or the evil
spirits which dwell in the
hearts of the children of men.
7 And lo, he shall
suffer temptations, and pain
of body, hunger, thirst,
and fatigue, even more
than man can suffer,
except it be unto death;
for behold, blood cometh
from every pore, so great
shall be his anguish
for the wickedness and the
abominations of his people.
8 And he shall be
called Jesus Christ, the
Son of God, the
Father of heaven and
earth, the Creator of all
things from the
beginning; and his mother
shall be called Mary.
9 And lo, he cometh
unto his own, that
salvation might come
unto the children of
men even through
faith on his name; and
even after all this
they shall consider
him a man, and say
that he hath a
devil, and shall scourge
him, and shall crucify him.
10 And he shall
rise the third day
from the dead; and
behold, he standeth to
judge the world;
and behold, all
these things are done
that a righteous
judgment might come
upon the children of men.
11 For behold, and
also his blood
atoneth for the sins
of those who have
fallen by the
transgression of
Adam, who have died
not knowing the will
of God concerning
them, or who have
ignorantly sinned.
12 But wo, wo
unto him who
knoweth that he
rebelleth against
God! For salvation
cometh to none
such except it be
through
repentance and faith on
the Lord Jesus Christ.
13 And the Lord
God hath sent
his holy
prophets among all
the children of
men, to declare
these things to
every kindred,
nation, and
tongue, that
thereby whosoever
should believe
that Christ
should come, the
same might
receive remission of
their sins, and
rejoice with
exceedingly
great joy, even as
though he had
already come among them.
14 Yet the
Lord God saw
that his people
were a
stiffnecked
people, and he
appointed unto
them a law,
even the law of Moses.
15 And many
signs, and
wonders, and
types, and
shadows
showed he unto
them,
concerning his
coming; and also
holy
prophets spake unto
them
concerning his
coming; and yet
they
hardened their
hearts, and
understood not
that the law
of Moses
availeth
nothing except it
were
through the atonement of his blood.
16 And even
if it were
possible
that little
children
could sin
they could not
be saved;
but I say
unto you
they are
blessed; for
behold, as in
Adam, or by
nature,
they fall,
even so the
blood of
Christ atoneth for their sins.
17 And
moreover, I
say unto
you, that
there shall
be no
other name
given nor any
other way
nor means
whereby
salvation
can come
unto the
children of
men, only
in and
through the
name of
Christ, the Lord Omnipotent.
18 For
behold he
judgeth,
and his
judgment is
just;
and the
infant
perisheth not
that
dieth in his
infancy;
but men
drink
damnation to
their own
souls
except they
humble
themselves
and
become as
little
children, and
believe
that
salvation was,
and is,
and is to
come, in
and
through the
atoning
blood of Christ, the Lord Omnipotent.
19 For
the
natural man
is an
enemy to
God, and
has been
from the
fall of
Adam,
and will
be,
forever and
ever,
unless he
yields
to the
enticings
of the
Holy
Spirit, and
putteth
off the
natural
man and
becometh
a saint
through
the
atonement
of Christ
the
Lord, and
becometh
as a
child,
submissive,
meek,
humble,
patient,
full of
love,
willing to
submit
to all
things
which the
Lord
seeth fit to
inflict
upon him, even as a child doth submit to his father.
20 And
moreover, I
say unto
you,
that the
time
shall
come when
the
knowledge
of a
Savior
shall
spread
throughout
every
nation,
kindred, tongue, and people.
21 And
behold,
when that
time
cometh, none
shall
be
found
blameless
before
God,
except it
be
little
children, only
through
repentance and
faith
on the
name
of the Lord God Omnipotent.
And
even at
this
time,
when
thou
shalt
have
taught
thy
people
the
things
which the
Lord
thy
God
hath
commanded
thee,
even
then
are
they
found
no
more
blameless in
the
sight
of
God,
only
according
to the words which I have spoken unto thee.
And
now I
have
spoken
the
words
which
the
Lord
God
hath commanded me.
And
thus
saith
the
Lord:
They
shall
stand
as
a
bright
testimony
against
this
people,
at
the
judgment
day;
whereof
they
shall
be
judged,
every
man
according
to
his works, whether they be good, or whether they be evil.
And
if
they
be
evil
they
are
consigned
to
an
awful
view
of
their
own
guilt
and
abominations,
which
doth
cause
them
to
shrink
from
the
presence
of
the
Lord
into
a
state
of
misery
and
endless
torment,
from
whence
they
can
no
more
return;
therefore
they
have
drunk
damnation
to
their
own
souls.
Therefore,
they
have
drunk
wrath
of
God,
which
justice
could
no
more
deny
unto
them
than
it
could
deny
that
Adam
should
fall
because
of
his
partaking of the forbidden fruit; therefore, mercy could have claim on them no more forever.
And
their
torment
is
as
a
lake
of
fire
and
brimstone,
whose
flames
are
unquenchable,
and
whose
smoke
ascendeth
up
forever
and
ever.
Thus
hath
the
Lord
commanded
me.
Amen.