Chapter 21 Limhi’s people are smitten and defeated
by the Lamanites—Limhi’s people meet Ammon and
are converted—They tell Ammon of the twenty-four
Jaredite plates. About 122–121 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that Limhi and his people
returned to the city of Nephi, and began to dwell in
the land again in peace
2 And it came to pass that after many days the
Lamanites began again to be stirred up in anger
against the Nephites, and they began to come into the
borders of the land round about
3 Now they durst not slay them, because of the
oath which their king had made unto Limhi; but they
would smite them on their cheeks, and exercise
authority over them; and began to put heavy burdens
upon their backs, and drive them as they would a
dumb ass
4 Yea, all this was done that the word of the Lord
might be fulfilled
5 And now the afflictions of the Nephites were
great, and there was no way that they could deliver
themselves out of their hands, for the Lamanites
had surrounded them on every side
6 And it came to pass that the people began to
murmur with the king because of their afflictions;
and they began to be desirous to go against them to
battle. And they did afflict the king sorely with
their complaints; therefore he granted unto them
that they should do according to their desires
7 And they gathered themselves together again, and
put on their armor, and went forth against the
Lamanites to drive them out of their land
8 And it came to pass that the Lamanites did beat
them, and drove them back, and slew many of them
9 And now there was a great mourning and
lamentation among the people of Limhi, the widow mourning
for her husband, the son and the daughter mourning
for their father, and the brothers for their
brethren
10 Now there were a great many widows in the land,
and they did cry mightily from day to day, for a
great fear of the Lamanites had come upon them
11 And it came to pass that their continual cries
did stir up the remainder of the people of Limhi
to anger against the Lamanites; and they went again
to battle, but they were driven back again,
suffering much loss
12 Yea, they went again even the third time, and
suffered in the like manner; and those that were
not slain returned again to the city of Nephi
13 And they did humble themselves even to the
dust, subjecting themselves to the yoke of bondage,
submitting themselves to be smitten, and to be
driven to and fro, and burdened, according to the
desires of their enemies
14 And they did humble themselves even in the
depths of humility; and they did cry mightily to God;
yea, even all the day long did they cry unto their
God that he would deliver them out of their
afflictions
15 And now the Lord was slow to hear their cry
because of their iniquities; nevertheless the Lord
did hear their cries, and began to soften the hearts
of the Lamanites that they began to ease their
burdens; yet the Lord did not see fit to deliver
them out of bondage
16 And it came to pass that they began to prosper
by degrees in the land, and began to raise grain
more abundantly, and flocks, and herds, that they
did not suffer with hunger
17 Now there was a great number of women, more
than there was of men; therefore king Limhi commanded
that every man should impart to the support of
the widows and their children, that they might not
perish with hunger; and this they did because of
the greatness of their number that had been slain
18 Now the people of Limhi kept together in a body
as much as it was possible, and secured their
grain and their flocks
19 And the king himself did not trust his person
without the walls of the city, unless he took his
guards with him, fearing that he might by some
means fall into the hands of the Lamanites
20 And he caused that his people should watch the
land round about, that by some means they might
take those priests that fled into the wilderness,
who had stolen the daughters of the Lamanites, and
that had caused such a great destruction to come
upon them
21 For they were desirous to take them that they
might punish them; for they had come into the land
of Nephi by night, and carried off their grain and
many of their precious things; therefore they
laid wait for them
22 And it came to pass that there was no more
disturbance between the Lamanites and the people of
Limhi, even until the time that Ammon and his
brethren came into the land
23 And the king having been without the gates of
the city with his guard, discovered Ammon and his
brethren; and supposing them to be priests of Noah
therefore he caused that they should be taken, and
bound, and cast into prison. And had they been
the priests of Noah he would have caused that they
should be put to death
24 But when he found that they were not, but that
they were his brethren, and had come from the land
of Zarahemla, he was filled with exceedingly
great joy
25 Now king Limhi had sent, previous to the coming
of Ammon, a small number of men to search for the
land of Zarahemla; but they could not find it,
and they were lost in the wilderness
26 Nevertheless, they did find a land which had
been peopled; yea, a land which was covered with dry
bones; yea, a land which had been peopled and
which had been destroyed; and they, having supposed
it to be the land of Zarahemla, returned to the
land of Nephi, having arrived in the borders of the
land not many days before the coming of Ammon
27 And they brought a record with them, even a
record of the people whose bones they had found; and
it was engraven on plates of ore
28 And now Limhi was again filled with joy on
learning from the mouth of Ammon that king Mosiah had
a gift from God, whereby he could interpret such
engravings; yea, and Ammon also did rejoice
29 Yet Ammon and his brethren were filled with
sorrow because so many of their brethren had been
slain
30 And also that king Noah and his priests had
caused the people to commit so many sins and
iniquities against God; and they also did mourn for the
death of Abinadi; and also for the departure of Alma
and the people that went with him, who had formed
a church of God through the strength and power of
God, and faith on the words which had been spoken
by Abinadi
31 Yea, they did mourn for their departure, for
they knew not whither they had fled. Now they would
have gladly joined with them, for they themselves
had entered into a covenant with God to serve him
and keep his commandments
32 And now since the coming of Ammon, king Limhi
had also entered into a covenant with God, and also
many of his people, to serve him and keep his
commandments
33 And it came to pass that king Limhi and many of
his people were desirous to be baptized; but
there was none in the land that had authority from
God. And Ammon declined doing this thing, considering
himself an unworthy servant
34 Therefore they did not at that time form
themselves into a church, waiting upon the Spirit of the
Lord. Now they were desirous to become even as
Alma and his brethren, who had fled into the
wilderness
35 They were desirous to be baptized as a witness
and a testimony that they were willing to serve
God with all their hearts; nevertheless they did
prolong the time; and an account of their baptism
shall be given hereafter
36 And now all the study of Ammon and his people,
and king Limhi and his people, was to deliver
themselves out of the hands of the Lamanites and from
bondage.