Chapter 6 King Benjamin records the names of the
people and appoints priests to teach them—Mosiah
reigns as a righteous king. About 124–121 B.C.
1 And now, king Benjamin thought it was expedient,
after having finished speaking to the people,
that he should take the names of all those who had
entered into a covenant with God to keep his
commandments
2 And it came to pass that there was not one soul,
except it were little children, but who had
entered into the covenant and had taken upon them the
name of Christ
3 And again, it came to pass that when king
Benjamin had made an end of all these things, and had
consecrated his son Mosiah to be a ruler and a king
over his people, and had given him all the charges
concerning the kingdom, and also had appointed
priests to teach the people, that thereby they might
hear and know the commandments of God, and to
stir them up in remembrance of the oath which they
had made, he dismissed the multitude, and they
returned, every one, according to their families, to
their own houses
4 And Mosiah began to reign in his father’s stead.
And he began to reign in the thirtieth year of
his age, making in the whole, about four hundred and
seventy-six years from the time that Lehi left
Jerusalem
7 And king Mosiah did cause his people that they
should till the earth. And he also, himself, did
till the earth, that thereby he might not become
burdensome to his people, that he might do according
to that which his father had done in all things.
And there was no contention among all his people
for the space of three years.