Chapter 24 Amulon persecutes Alma and his
people—They are to be put to death if they pray—The Lord
makes their burdens seem light—He delivers them
from bondage, and they return to Zarahemla. About
145–120 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that Amulon did gain favor
in the eyes of the king of the Lamanites;
therefore, the king of the Lamanites granted unto him and
his brethren that they should be appointed teachers
over his people, yea, even over the people who
were in the land of Shemlon, and in the land of
Shilom, and in the land of Amulon
2 For the Lamanites had taken possession of all
these lands; therefore, the king of the Lamanites
had appointed kings over all these lands
3 And now the name of the king of the Lamanites
was Laman, being called after the name of his
father; and therefore he was called king Laman. And he
was king over a numerous people
4 And he appointed teachers of the brethren of
Amulon in every land which was possessed by his
people; and thus the language of Nephi began to be
taught among all the people of the Lamanites
5 And they were a people friendly one with
another; nevertheless they knew not God; neither did the
brethren of Amulon teach them anything concerning
the Lord their God, neither the law of Moses; nor
did they teach them the words of Abinadi
6 But they taught them that they should keep their
record, and that they might write one to another
7 And thus the Lamanites began to increase in
riches, and began to trade one with another and wax
great, and began to be a cunning and a wise people,
as to the wisdom of the world, yea, a very cunning
people, delighting in all manner of wickedness
and plunder, except it were among their own
brethren
8 And now it came to pass that Amulon began to
exercise authority over Alma and his brethren, and
began to persecute him, and cause that his children
should persecute their children
9 For Amulon knew Alma, that he had been one of
the king’s priests, and that it was he that believed
the words of Abinadi and was driven out before
the king, and therefore he was wroth with him; for
he was subject to king Laman, yet he exercised
authority over them, and put tasks upon them, and put
task-masters over them
10 And it came to pass that so great were their
afflictions that they began to cry mightily to God
11 And Amulon commanded them that they should stop
their cries; and he put guards over them to watch
them, that whosoever should be found calling upon
God should be put to death
12 And Alma and his people did not raise their
voices to the Lord their God, but did pour out their
hearts to him; and he did know the thoughts of
their hearts
13 And it came to pass that the voice of the Lord
came to them in their afflictions, saying: Lift up
your heads and be of good comfort, for I know of
the covenant which ye have made unto me; and I
will covenant with my people and deliver them out of
bondage
14 And I will also ease the burdens which are put
upon your shoulders, that even you cannot feel
them upon your backs, even while you are in bondage;
and this will I do that ye may stand as witnesses
for me hereafter, and that ye may know of a surety
that I, the Lord God, do visit my people in their
afflictions
15 And now it came to pass that the burdens which
were laid upon Alma and his brethren were made
light; yea, the Lord did strengthen them that they
could bear up their burdens with ease, and they did
submit cheerfully and with patience to all the
will of the Lord
16 And it came to pass that so great was their
faith and their patience that the voice of the Lord
came unto them again, saying: Be of good comfort,
for on the morrow I will deliver you out of
bondage
17 And he said unto Alma: Thou shalt go before
this people, and I will go with thee and deliver this
people out of bondage
18 Now it came to pass that Alma and his people in
the night-time gathered their flocks together,
and also of their grain; yea, even all the
night-time were they gathering their flocks together
19 And in the morning the Lord caused a deep sleep
to come upon the Lamanites, yea, and all their
task-masters were in a profound sleep
20 And Alma and his people departed into the
wilderness; and when they had traveled all day they
pitched their tents in a valley, and they called the
valley Alma, because he led their way in the
wilderness
21 Yea, and in the valley of Alma they poured out
their thanks to God because he had been merciful
unto them, and eased their burdens, and had
delivered them out of bondage; for they were in bondage,
and none could deliver them except it were the
Lord their God
22 And they gave thanks to God, yea, all their men
and all their women and all their children that
could speak lifted their voices in the praises of
their God
23 And now the Lord said unto Alma: Haste thee and
get thou and this people out of this land, for
the Lamanites have awakened and do pursue thee;
therefore get thee out of this land, and I will stop
the Lamanites in this valley that they come no
further in pursuit of this people
24 And it came to pass that they departed out of
the valley, and took their journey into the
wilderness
25 And after they had been in the wilderness
twelve days they arrived in the land of Zarahemla; and
king Mosiah did also receive them with joy.