Fourth NephiThe Book of Nephi Who Is the Son of
Nephi—One of the Disciples of Jesus ChristAn account
of the people of Nephi, according to his
record.Chapter 1 The Nephites and the Lamanites are all
converted unto the Lord—They have all things in
common, work miracles, and prosper in the land—After
two centuries, divisions, evils, false churches,
and persecutions arise—After three hundred years,
both the Nephites and the Lamanites are
wicked—Ammaron hides up the sacred records. About A.D. 35–321.
1 And it came to pass that the thirty and fourth
year passed away, and also the thirty and fifth,
and behold the disciples of Jesus had formed a
church of Christ in all the lands round about. And as
many as did come unto them, and did truly repent of
their sins, were baptized in the name of Jesus;
and they did also receive the Holy Ghost
2 And it came to pass in the thirty and sixth
year, the people were all converted unto the Lord,
upon all the face of the land, both Nephites and
Lamanites, and there were no contentions and
disputations among them, and every man did deal justly one
with another
3 And they had all things common among them;
therefore there were not rich and poor, bond and free,
but they were all made free, and partakers of the
heavenly gift
4 And it came to pass that the thirty and seventh
year passed away also, and there still continued
to be peace in the land
5 And there were great and marvelous works wrought
by the disciples of Jesus, insomuch that they did
heal the sick, and raise the dead, and cause the
lame to walk, and the blind to receive their
sight, and the deaf to hear; and all manner of miracles
did they work among the children of men; and in
nothing did they work miracles save it were in the
name of Jesus
6 And thus did the thirty and eighth year pass
away, and also the thirty and ninth, and forty and
first, and the forty and second, yea, even until
forty and nine years had passed away, and also the
fifty and first, and the fifty and second; yea, and
even until fifty and nine years had passed away
7 And the Lord did prosper them exceedingly in the
land; yea, insomuch that they did build cities
again where there had been cities burned
8 Yea, even that great city Zarahemla did they
cause to be built again
9 But there were many cities which had been sunk,
and waters came up in the stead thereof; therefore
these cities could not be renewed
10 And now, behold, it came to pass that the
people of Nephi did wax strong, and did multiply
exceedingly fast, and became an exceedingly fair and
delightsome people
11 And they were married, and given in marriage,
and were blessed according to the multitude of the
promises which the Lord had made unto them
12 And they did not walk any more after the
performances and ordinances of the law of Moses; but
they did walk after the commandments which they had
received from their Lord and their God, continuing
in fasting and prayer, and in meeting together oft
both to pray and to hear the word of the Lord
13 And it came to pass that there was no
contention among all the people, in all the land; but there
were mighty miracles wrought among the disciples
of Jesus
14 And it came to pass that the seventy and first
year passed away, and also the seventy and second
year, yea, and in fine, till the seventy and ninth
year had passed away; yea, even an hundred years
had passed away, and the disciples of Jesus, whom
he had chosen, had all gone to the paradise of
God, save it were the three who should tarry; and
there were other disciples ordained in their stead;
and also many of that generation had passed away
15 And it came to pass that there was no
contention in the land, because of the love of God which
did dwell in the hearts of the people
16 And there were no envyings, nor strifes, nor
tumults, nor whoredoms, nor lyings, nor murders, nor
any manner of lasciviousness; and surely there
could not be a happier people among all the people
who had been created by the hand of God
17 There were no robbers, nor murderers, neither
were there Lamanites, nor any manner of -ites; but
they were in one, the children of Christ, and
heirs to the kingdom of God
18 And how blessed were they! For the Lord did
bless them in all their doings; yea, even they were
blessed and prospered until an hundred and ten
years had passed away; and the first generation from
Christ had passed away, and there was no contention
in all the land
19 And it came to pass that Nephi, he that kept
this last record, (and he kept it upon the plates of
Nephi) died, and his son Amos kept it in his
stead; and he kept it upon the plates of Nephi also
20 And he kept it eighty and four years, and there
was still peace in the land, save it were a small
part of the people who had revolted from the
church and taken upon them the name of Lamanites;
therefore there began to be Lamanites again in the
land
21 And it came to pass that Amos died also, (and
it was an hundred and ninety and four years from
the coming of Christ) and his son Amos kept the
record in his stead; and he also kept it upon the
plates of Nephi; and it was also written in the book
of Nephi, which is this book
22 And it came to pass that two hundred years had
passed away; and the second generation had all
passed away save it were a few
23 And now I, Mormon, would that ye should know
that the people had multiplied, insomuch that they
were spread upon all the face of the land, and that
they had become exceedingly rich, because of
their prosperity in Christ
24 And now, in this two hundred and first year
there began to be among them those who were lifted up
in pride, such as the wearing of costly apparel,
and all manner of fine pearls, and of the fine
things of the world
25 And from that time forth they did have their
goods and their substance no more common among them
26 And they began to be divided into classes; and
they began to build up churches unto themselves to
get gain, and began to deny the true church of
Christ
27 And it came to pass that when two hundred and
ten years had passed away there were many churches
in the land; yea, there were many churches which
professed to know the Christ, and yet they did deny
the more parts of his gospel, insomuch that they
did receive all manner of wickedness, and did
administer that which was sacred unto him to whom it
had been forbidden because of unworthiness
28 And this church did multiply exceedingly
because of iniquity, and because of the power of Satan
who did get hold upon their hearts
29 And again, there was another church which
denied the Christ; and they did persecute the true
church of Christ, because of their humility and their
belief in Christ; and they did despise them
because of the many miracles which were wrought among
them
30 Therefore they did exercise power and authority
over the disciples of Jesus who did tarry with
them, and they did cast them into prison; but by the
power of the word of God, which was in them, the
prisons were rent in twain, and they went forth
doing mighty miracles among them
31 Nevertheless, and notwithstanding all these
miracles, the people did harden their hearts, and did
seek to kill them, even as the Jews at Jerusalem
sought to kill Jesus, according to his word
32 And they did cast them into furnaces of fire,
and they came forth receiving no harm
33 And they also cast them into dens of wild
beasts, and they did play with the wild beasts even as
a child with a lamb; and they did come forth from
among them, receiving no harm
34 Nevertheless, the people did harden their
hearts, for they were led by many priests and false
prophets to build up many churches, and to do all
manner of iniquity. And they did smite upon the
people of Jesus; but the people of Jesus did not smite
again. And thus they did dwindle in unbelief and
wickedness, from year to year, even until two
hundred and thirty years had passed away
35 And now it came to pass in this year, yea, in
the two hundred and thirty and first year, there
was a great division among the people
36 And it came to pass that in this year there
arose a people who were called the Nephites, and they
were true believers in Christ; and among them
there were those who were called by the
Lamanites—Jacobites, and Josephites, and Zoramites
37 Therefore the true believers in Christ, and the
true worshipers of Christ, (among whom were the
three disciples of Jesus who should tarry) were
called Nephites, and Jacobites, and Josephites, and
Zoramites
38 And it came to pass that they who rejected the
gospel were called Lamanites, and Lemuelites, and
Ishmaelites; and they did not dwindle in unbelief,
but they did wilfully rebel against the gospel of
Christ; and they did teach their children that
they should not believe, even as their fathers, from
the beginning, did dwindle
39 And it was because of the wickedness and
abomination of their fathers, even as it was in the
beginning. And they were taught to hate the children
of God, even as the Lamanites were taught to hate
the children of Nephi from the beginning
40 And it came to pass that two hundred and forty
and four years had passed away, and thus were the
affairs of the people. And the more wicked part of
the people did wax strong, and became exceedingly
more numerous than were the people of God
41 And they did still continue to build up
churches unto themselves, and adorn them with all manner
of precious things. And thus did two hundred and
fifty years pass away, and also two hundred and
sixty years
42 And it came to pass that the wicked part of the
people began again to build up the secret oaths
and combinations of Gadianton
43 And also the people who were called the people
of Nephi began to be proud in their hearts,
because of their exceeding riches, and become vain like
unto their brethren, the Lamanites
44 And from this time the disciples began to
sorrow for the sins of the world
45 And it came to pass that when three hundred
years had passed away, both the people of Nephi and
the Lamanites had become exceedingly wicked one
like unto another
46 And it came to pass that the robbers of
Gadianton did spread over all the face of the land; and
there were none that were righteous save it were
the disciples of Jesus. And gold and silver did they
lay up in store in abundance, and did traffic in
all manner of traffic
47 And it came to pass that after three hundred
and five years had passed away, (and the people did
still remain in wickedness) Amos died; and his
brother, Ammaron, did keep the record in his stead
48 And it came to pass that when three hundred and
twenty years had passed away, Ammaron, being
constrained by the Holy Ghost, did hide up the records
which were sacred—yea, even all the sacred
records which had been handed down from generation to
generation, which were sacred—even until the three
hundred and twentieth year from the coming of
Christ
49 And he did hide them up unto the Lord, that
they might come again unto the remnant of the house
of Jacob, according to the prophecies and the
promises of the Lord. And thus is the end of the record
of Ammaron.