mother of the Son of God and learns of the
condescension of God—He sees the baptism, ministry, and crucifixion of
the Lamb of God—He sees also the call and ministry
of the Twelve Apostles of the Lamb. About 600–592 B.C.
1 For it came to pass after I had desired
to know the things that my father had seen, and
believing that the Lord was able to make them known
unto me, as I sat pondering in mine heart I
was caught away in the Spirit of the Lord, yea,
into an exceedingly high mountain, which I never had before
seen, and upon which I never had before set my
foot.
2 And the Spirit said unto me: Behold, what desirest
thou?
3 And I said: I desire to behold the things
which my father saw.
4 And the Spirit said unto me: Believest thou that
thy father saw the tree of which he hath spoken?
5 And I said: Yea, thou knowest that I believe
all the words of my father.
6 And when I had spoken these words, the Spirit
cried with a loud voice, saying: Hosanna to the Lord,
the most high God; for he is God over all
the earth, yea, even above all. And blessed art thou,
Nephi, because thou believest in the Son of the most
high God; wherefore, thou shalt behold the things which thou
hast desired.
7 And behold this thing shall be given unto thee
for a sign, that after thou hast beheld the tree
which bore the fruit which thy father tasted, thou shalt
also behold a man descending out of heaven, and him
shall ye witness; and after ye have witnessed him ye
shall bear record that it is the Son of God.
8 And it came to pass that the Spirit said
unto me: Look! And I looked and beheld a tree;
and it was like unto the tree which my father
had seen; and the beauty thereof was far beyond, yea,
exceeding of all beauty; and the whiteness thereof did exceed
the whiteness of the driven snow.
9 And it came to pass after I had seen
the tree, I said unto the Spirit: I behold thou
hast shown unto me the tree which is precious above
all.
10 And he said unto me: What desirest thou?
11 And I said unto him: To know the interpretation
thereof—for I spake unto him as a man speaketh; for
I beheld that he was in the form of a
man; yet nevertheless, I knew that it was the Spirit
of the Lord; and he spake unto me as a
man speaketh with another.
12 And it came to pass that he said unto
me: Look! And I looked as if to look upon
him, and I saw him not; for he had gone
from before my presence.
13 And it came to pass that I looked and
beheld the great city of Jerusalem, and also other cities.
And I beheld the city of Nazareth; and in the
city of Nazareth I beheld a virgin, and she was
exceedingly fair and white.
14 And it came to pass that I saw the
heavens open; and an angel came down and stood before
me; and he said unto me: Nephi, what beholdest thou?
15 And I said unto him: A virgin, most beautiful
and fair above all other virgins.
16 And he said unto me: Knowest thou the condescension
of God?
17 And I said unto him: I know that he
loveth his children; nevertheless, I do not know the meaning
of all things.
18 And he said unto me: Behold, the virgin whom
thou seest is the mother of the Son of God,
after the manner of the flesh.
19 And it came to pass that I beheld that
she was carried away in the Spirit; and after she
had been carried away in the Spirit for the space
of a time the angel spake unto me, saying: Look!
20 And I looked and beheld the virgin again, bearing
a child in her arms.
21 And the angel said unto me: Behold the Lamb
of God, yea, even the Son of the Eternal Father!
Knowest thou the meaning of the tree which thy father
saw?
22 And I answered him, saying: Yea, it is the
love of God, which sheddeth itself abroad in the hearts
of the children of men; wherefore, it is the most
desirable above all things.
23 And he spake unto me, saying: Yea, and the
most joyous to the soul.
24 And after he had said these words, he said
unto me: Look! And I looked, and I beheld the
Son of God going forth among the children of men;
and I saw many fall down at his feet and
worship him.
25 And it came to pass that I beheld that
the rod of iron, which my father had seen, was
the word of God, which led to the fountain of
living waters, or to the tree of life; which waters
are a representation of the love of God; and I
also beheld that the tree of life was a representation
of the love of God.
26 And the angel said unto me again: Look and
behold the condescension of God!
27 And I looked and beheld the Redeemer of the
world, of whom my father had spoken; and I also
beheld the prophet who should prepare the way before him.
And the Lamb of God went forth and was baptized
of him; and after he was baptized, I beheld the
heavens open, and the Holy Ghost come down out of
heaven and abide upon him in the form of a
dove.
28 And I beheld that he went forth ministering unto
the people, in power and great glory; and the multitudes
were gathered together to hear him; and I beheld that
they cast him out from among them.
29 And I also beheld twelve others following him. And
it came to pass that they were carried away in
the Spirit from before my face, and I saw them
not.
30 And it came to pass that the angel spake
unto me again, saying: Look! And I looked, and I
beheld the heavens open again, and I saw angels descending
upon the children of men; and they did minister unto
them.
31 And he spake unto me again, saying: Look! And
I looked, and I beheld the Lamb of God going
forth among the children of men. And I beheld multitudes
of people who were sick, and who were afflicted with
all manner of diseases, and with devils and unclean spirits;
and the angel spake and showed all these things unto
me. And they were healed by the power of the
Lamb of God; and the devils and the unclean spirits
were cast out.
32 And it came to pass that the angel spake
unto me again, saying: Look! And I looked and beheld
the Lamb of God, that he was taken by the
people; yea, the Son of the everlasting God was judged
of the world; and I saw and bear record.
33 And I, Nephi, saw that he was lifted up
upon the cross and slain for the sins of the
world.
34 And after he was slain I saw the multitudes
of the earth, that they were gathered together to fight
against the apostles of the Lamb; for thus were the
twelve called by the angel of the Lord.
35 And the multitude of the earth was gathered together;
and I beheld that they were in a large and
spacious building, like unto the building which my father saw.
And the angel of the Lord spake unto me again,
saying: Behold the world and the wisdom thereof; yea, behold
the house of Israel hath gathered together to fight against
the twelve apostles of the Lamb.
36 And it came to pass that I saw and
bear record, that the great and spacious building was the
pride of the world; and it fell, and the fall
thereof was exceedingly great. And the angel of the Lord
spake unto me again, saying: Thus shall be the destruction
of all nations, kindreds, tongues, and people, that shall fight
against the twelve apostles of the Lamb.