Chapter 6 The Nephites gather to the land
of Cumorah for the final battles—Mormon
hides the sacred records in the hill
Cumorah—The Lamanites are victorious, and the
Nephite nation is destroyed—Hundreds of
thousands are slain with the sword. About A.D. 385.
1 And now I finish my record
concerning the destruction of my people, the
Nephites. And it came to pass that we
did march forth before the Lamanites.
2 And I, Mormon, wrote an epistle
unto the king of the Lamanites, and
desired of him that he would grant
unto us that we might gather together
our people unto the land of Cumorah,
by a hill which was called Cumorah,
and there we could give them battle.
3 And it came to pass that the
king of the Lamanites did grant
unto me the thing which I desired.
4 And it came to pass that we
did march forth to the land of
Cumorah, and we did pitch our
tents around about the hill
Cumorah; and it was in a land
of many waters, rivers, and
fountains; and here we had hope
to gain advantage over the Lamanites.
5 And when three hundred and
eighty and four years had
passed away, we had gathered
in all the remainder of our
people unto the land of Cumorah.
6 And it came to pass that
when we had gathered in all
our people in one to the
land of Cumorah, behold I,
Mormon, began to be old; and
knowing it to be the last
struggle of my people, and
having been commanded of
the Lord that I should not
suffer the records which had
been handed down by our
fathers, which were sacred, to
fall into the hands of the
Lamanites, (for the
Lamanites would destroy them)
therefore I made this record
out of the plates of Nephi,
and hid up in the hill
Cumorah all the records which
had been entrusted to me by
the hand of the Lord, save
it were these few plates
which I gave unto my son Moroni.
7 And it came to pass
that my people, with their
wives and their
children, did now behold the
armies of the Lamanites
marching towards them; and
with that awful fear of
death which fills the
breasts of all the
wicked, did they await to receive them.
8 And it came to pass
that they came to battle
against us, and every
soul was filled with
terror because of the
greatness of their numbers.
9 And it came to
pass that they did fall
upon my people with
the sword, and with
the bow, and with
the arrow, and with
the ax, and with all
manner of weapons of war.
10 And it came to
pass that my men
were hewn down, yea,
even my ten thousand
who were with me,
and I fell wounded
in the midst; and
they passed by me
that they did not put
an end to my life.
11 And when they
had gone through
and hewn down all my
people save it
were twenty and four
of us, (among
whom was my son
Moroni) and we having
survived the dead
of our people, did
behold on the
morrow, when the
Lamanites had returned
unto their camps,
from the top of
the hill Cumorah,
the ten thousand of
my people who were
hewn down, being
led in the front by me.
12 And we also
beheld the ten
thousand of my
people who were led
by my son Moroni.
13 And behold,
the ten
thousand of
Gidgiddonah had
fallen, and he also
in the midst.
14 And Lamah
had fallen
with his ten
thousand; and
Gilgal had
fallen with his
ten thousand;
and Limhah
had fallen
with his ten
thousand; and
Jeneum had
fallen with his
ten thousand;
and
Cumenihah, and
Moronihah, and
Antionum, and
Shiblom, and
Shem, and Josh,
had fallen
with their ten thousand each.
15 And it
came to pass
that there
were ten more
who did fall
by the
sword, with
their ten
thousand each;
yea, even all
my people,
save it were
those twenty
and four who
were with
me, and also
a few who
had escaped
into the south
countries,
and a few
who had
deserted over unto
the
Lamanites, had
fallen; and
their flesh, and
bones, and
blood lay
upon the face
of the
earth, being left
by the
hands of those
who slew them
to molder
upon the
land, and to
crumble and to return to their mother earth.
16 And my
soul was
rent with
anguish,
because of
the slain
of my
people, and I cried:
17 O ye
fair ones,
how
could ye have
departed
from the
ways of
the Lord!
O ye
fair ones,
how could
ye have
rejected
that
Jesus, who
stood with
open arms to receive you!
Behold, if ye
had not
done
this, ye
would not
have
fallen.
But
behold, ye are
fallen,
and I
mourn your loss.
19 O ye
fair
sons and
daughters, ye
fathers and
mothers,
ye
husbands
and
wives, ye
fair
ones, how
is it
that ye
could have fallen!
20 But
behold, ye
are
gone,
and my
sorrows
cannot
bring your return.
And the
day
soon
cometh
that
your
mortal
must
put on
immortality,
and
these
bodies
which are
now
moldering
in
corruption
must
soon
become
incorruptible
bodies;
and
then ye
must
stand
before
the
judgment-seat
of
Christ, to
be
judged
according
to
your
works;
and
if it
so be
that
ye
are
righteous,
then are ye blessed with your fathers who have gone before you.
22 O
that ye
had
repented
before
this
great
destruction
had
come
upon
you.
But
behold,
ye
are
gone,
and
the
Father,
yea,
the
Eternal
Father
of
heaven,
knoweth
your
state;
and
he
doeth with you according to his justice and mercy.