Chapter 2 Mormon leads the Nephite armies—Blood
and carnage sweep the land—The Nephites lament
and mourn with the sorrowing of the
damned—Their day of grace is passed—Mormon obtains the
plates of Nephi—Wars continue. About A.D. 327–50.
1 And it came to pass in that same year there
began to be a war again between the Nephites
and the Lamanites. And notwithstanding I
being young, was large in stature; therefore the
people of Nephi appointed me that I should
be their leader, or the leader of their armies.
2 Therefore it came to pass that in my
sixteenth year I did go forth at the
head of an army of the Nephites, against
the Lamanites; therefore three hundred
and twenty and six years had passed away.
3 And it came to pass that in the
three hundred and twenty and seventh year
the Lamanites did come upon us with
exceedingly great power, insomuch that
they did frighten my armies; therefore
they would not fight, and they began
to retreat towards the north countries.
4 And it came to pass that we did
come to the city of Angola, and we did
take possession of the city, and make
preparations to defend ourselves
against the Lamanites. And it came to
pass that we did fortify the city with
our might; but notwithstanding all our
fortifications the Lamanites did
come upon us and did drive us out of the city.
5 And they did also drive us
forth out of the land of David.
6 And we marched forth
and came to the land of
Joshua, which was in the
borders west by the seashore.
7 And it came to pass
that we did gather
in our people as fast
as it were possible,
that we might get
them together in one body.
8 But behold, the
land was filled with
robbers and with
Lamanites; and
notwithstanding the great
destruction which hung
over my people, they
did not repent of
their evil doings;
therefore there was
blood and carnage
spread throughout all
the face of the land,
both on the part of
the Nephites and
also on the part of the
Lamanites; and it
was one complete
revolution throughout
all the face of the land.
9 And now, the
Lamanites had a king,
and his name was
Aaron; and he came
against us with an
army of forty and four
thousand. And
behold, I withstood him
with forty and two
thousand. And it
came to pass that I
beat him with my
army that he fled
before me. And behold,
all this was done,
and three hundred
and thirty years had passed away.
10 And it came to
pass that the
Nephites began to
repent of their
iniquity, and began to
cry even as had
been prophesied by
Samuel the prophet;
for behold no man
could keep that
which was his own,
for the thieves,
and the robbers, and
the murderers,
and the magic art,
and the witchcraft
which was in the land.
11 Thus there
began to be a
mourning and a
lamentation in all the
land because of
these things, and
more especially
among the people of Nephi.
12 And it came
to pass that when
I, Mormon, saw
their
lamentation and their
mourning and their
sorrow before the
Lord, my heart
did begin to
rejoice within me,
knowing the
mercies and the
long-suffering of
the Lord,
therefore supposing that
he would be
merciful unto them
that they would
again become a righteous people.
13 But behold
this my joy was
vain, for their
sorrowing was
not unto
repentance, because
of the goodness
of God; but it
was rather the
sorrowing of
the damned,
because the Lord
would not always
suffer them to
take happiness in sin.
14 And they
did not come
unto Jesus with
broken hearts
and contrite
spirits, but
they did curse
God, and wish to
die.
Nevertheless they
would struggle
with the sword
for their lives.
15 And it
came to pass
that my sorrow
did return
unto me again,
and I saw that
the day of
grace was
passed with them,
both
temporally and
spiritually; for I
saw
thousands of them
hewn down in
open rebellion
against their
God, and
heaped up as dung
upon the
face of the
land. And thus
three hundred
and forty and
four years had passed away.
16 And it
came to pass
that in the
three hundred
and forty
and fifth
year the
Nephites did begin
to flee
before the
Lamanites; and
they were
pursued until
they came
even to the
land of Jashon,
before it
was possible
to stop them in their retreat.
17 And now,
the city
of Jashon
was near the
land where
Ammaron had
deposited
the records
unto the
Lord, that
they might
not be
destroyed. And
behold I had
gone
according to the
word of
Ammaron, and
taken the
plates of
Nephi, and
did make a
record
according to the words of Ammaron.
18 And
upon the
plates of
Nephi I did
make a full
account of
all the
wickedness
and
abominations;
but upon
these plates
I did
forbear to
make a full
account of
their
wickedness and
abominations, for
behold, a
continual
scene of
wickedness
and
abominations has
been
before mine
eyes ever
since I have
been
sufficient to behold the ways of man.
19 And wo
is me
because of
their
wickedness;
for my
heart has
been
filled with
sorrow
because of
their
wickedness,
all my
days;
nevertheless, I
know that
I shall
be lifted
up at the last day.
20 And
it came
to pass
that in
this year
the
people of
Nephi
again were
hunted
and
driven. And
it came
to pass
that we
were
driven forth
until
we had
come
northward to
the land
which was called Shem.
21 And
it came
to
pass that
we did
fortify
the
city of
Shem,
and we
did
gather in
our
people as
much as
it were
possible, that
perhaps we
might
save them from destruction.
22 And
it
came to
pass
in the
three
hundred and
forty
and
sixth
year
they
began to
come upon us again.
And it
came
to
pass
that I
did
speak
unto
my
people,
and
did
urge
them
with
great
energy,
that
they
would
stand
boldly
before
the
Lamanites
and
fight
for
their
wives,
and
their
children, and their houses, and their homes.
And
my
words
did
arouse
them
somewhat
to
vigor,
insomuch
that
they
did
not
flee
from
before
the
Lamanites,
but
did
stand with boldness against them.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
did
contend
with
an
army
of
thirty
thousand
against
an
army
of
fifty
thousand.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
did
stand
before
them
with such firmness that they did flee from before us.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
when
they
had
fled
we
did
pursue
them
with
our
armies,
and
did
meet
them
again,
and
did
beat
them;
nevertheless
the
strength
of
the
Lord
was
not
with
us;
yea,
we
were
left
to
ourselves,
that
the
Spirit
of
the
Lord
did
not
abide
in
us;
therefore
we
had
become
weak
like
unto
our
brethren.
And
my
heart
did
sorrow
because
of
this
the
great
calamity
of
my
people,
because
of
their
wickedness
and
their
abominations.
But
behold,
we
did
go
forth
against
the
Lamanites
and
the
robbers
of
Gadianton,
until
we
had
again
taken
possession
of
the
lands
of
our
inheritance.
And
the
three
hundred
and
forty
ninth
year
had
passed
away.
And
in
the
three
hundred
and
fiftieth
year
we
made
a
treaty
with
the
Lamanites
and
the
robbers of Gadianton, in which we did get the lands of our inheritance divided.
And
the
Lamanites
did
give
unto
us
the
land
northward,
yea,
even
to
the
narrow
passage
which
led
into
the
land
southward.
And
we
did
give
unto
the
Lamanites
all
the
land
southward.