Chapter 8 The Lamanites seek out and
destroy the Nephites—The Book of Mormon will come
forth by the power of God—Woes pronounced
upon those who breathe out wrath and strife
against the work of the Lord—The Nephite
record will come forth in a day of
wickedness, degeneracy, and apostasy. About A.D. 400–421.
1 Behold I, Moroni, do finish the
record of my father, Mormon. Behold, I
have but few things to write, which
things I have been commanded by my father.
2 And now it came to pass that
after the great and tremendous battle
at Cumorah, behold, the Nephites
who had escaped into the country
southward were hunted by the
Lamanites, until they were all destroyed.
3 And my father also was killed
by them, and I even remain alone
to write the sad tale of the
destruction of my people. But behold,
they are gone, and I fulfil the
commandment of my father. And
whether they will slay me, I know not.
4 Therefore I will write and
hide up the records in the earth;
and whither I go it mattereth not.
5 Behold, my father hath made
this record, and he hath
written the intent thereof. And
behold, I would write it also if
I had room upon the plates,
but I have not; and ore I have
none, for I am alone. My father
hath been slain in battle,
and all my kinsfolk, and I have
not friends nor whither to go;
and how long the Lord will
suffer that I may live I know not.
6 Behold, four hundred years
have passed away since the
coming of our Lord and Savior.
7 And behold, the Lamanites
have hunted my people, the
Nephites, down from city
to city and from place to
place, even until they are no
more; and great has been
their fall; yea, great and
marvelous is the destruction
of my people, the Nephites.
8 And behold, it is the
hand of the Lord which hath
done it. And behold also,
the Lamanites are at war
one with another; and the
whole face of this land is
one continual round of
murder and bloodshed; and no
one knoweth the end of the war.
9 And now, behold, I say
no more concerning
them, for there are none
save it be the Lamanites
and robbers that do exist
upon the face of the land.
10 And there are none
that do know the true
God save it be the
disciples of Jesus, who did
tarry in the land until
the wickedness of the
people was so great that
the Lord would not
suffer them to remain with
the people; and
whether they be upon the face
of the land no man knoweth.
11 But behold, my
father and I have seen
them, and they have
ministered unto us.
12 And whoso
receiveth this record,
and shall not condemn
it because of the
imperfections which
are in it, the
same shall know of
greater things than
these. Behold, I am
Moroni; and were it
possible, I would
make all things known unto you.
13 Behold, I make
an end of
speaking concerning
this people. I am
the son of Mormon,
and my father was
a descendant of Nephi.
14 And I am the
same who hideth
up this record
unto the Lord;
the plates thereof
are of no
worth, because of the
commandment of
the Lord. For he
truly saith
that no one shall
have them to get
gain; but the
record thereof is
of great worth;
and whoso shall
bring it to
light, him will the Lord bless.
15 For none can
have power to
bring it to
light save it be
given him of
God; for God wills
that it shall
be done with an
eye single to
his glory, or
the welfare of
the ancient and
long dispersed
covenant people of the Lord.
16 And blessed
be he that
shall bring this
thing to
light; for it
shall be brought
out of darkness
unto light,
according to
the word of God;
yea, it shall
be brought
out of the
earth, and it shall
shine forth
out of
darkness, and come
unto the
knowledge of the
people; and it
shall be done by the power of God.
17 And if
there be faults
they be the
faults of a man.
But behold, we
know no fault;
nevertheless
God knoweth
all things;
therefore, he that
condemneth,
let him be
aware lest he
shall be in danger
of hell fire.
18 And he
that saith:
Show unto me,
or ye shall
be
smitten—let him
beware lest he
commandeth
that which is
forbidden of the Lord.
19 For
behold, the
same that
judgeth rashly
shall be
judged rashly
again; for
according
to his
works shall his
wages be;
therefore,
he that
smiteth shall
be smitten
again, of the Lord.
20 Behold
what the
scripture
says—man
shall not
smite,
neither shall
he judge;
for
judgment is mine,
saith the
Lord, and
vengeance
is mine
also, and I will repay.
21 And he
that
shall
breathe out
wrath and
strifes
against the
work of
the Lord,
and
against the
covenant
people of
the Lord
who are
the house
of Israel,
and
shall say: We
will
destroy the
work of
the Lord,
and the
Lord will
not
remember his
covenant
which he
hath made
unto the
house of
Israel—the same is
in
danger to be hewn down and cast into the fire;
22 For
the
eternal
purposes of
the Lord
shall
roll on,
until all
his
promises
shall be fulfilled.
Search the
prophecies
of
Isaiah.
Behold, I
cannot
write them.
Yea,
behold I
say unto
you,
that those
saints
who have
gone
before me,
who have
possessed this
land,
shall cry,
yea,
even from
the dust
will
they cry
unto the
Lord;
and as the
Lord
liveth he
will
remember
the
covenant which
he hath
made
with them.
24 And
he
knoweth
their
prayers,
that they
were
in
behalf of
their
brethren.
And he
knoweth
their
faith,
for in
his
name could
they
remove
mountains; and
in his
name
could
they cause
the
earth to
shake;
and by
the
power of
his word
did
they
cause
prisons to
tumble
to the
earth;
yea,
even the
fiery
furnace
could
not harm
them,
neither
wild
beasts
nor poisonous serpents, because of the power of his word.
25 And
behold,
their
prayers
were
also in
behalf
of him
that
the Lord
should
suffer
to
bring these
things
forth.
26 And
no
one need
say
they
shall
not
come, for
they
surely
shall,
for
the
Lord hath
spoken it;
for
out of
the
earth
shall
they
come, by
the
hand of
Lord, and
none
can
stay it;
and
it
shall come
in a
day
when it
shall
be
said that
miracles
are done
away;
and
it
shall come even as if one should speak from the dead.
And it
shall
come
in a
day
when
the
blood
of
saints
shall
cry
unto
the
Lord,
because of
secret
combinations
and the works of darkness.
Yea, it
shall
come in
a day
when
the
power
of
God
shall
be
denied,
and
churches
become
defiled
and be
lifted up
in
the
pride of
their
hearts;
yea,
even
in a
day
when
leaders of
churches
and
teachers
shall
rise in
the
pride
of
their
hearts,
even to
the
envying of
them
who
belong to
their
churches.
Yea,
it
shall
come in
a
day
when
there
shall
be
heard
of
fires,
and
tempests,
vapors
of smoke in foreign lands;
And
there
shall
also
be
heard
of
wars,
rumors
of
wars,
and
earthquakes in divers places.
Yea,
it
shall
come
in
a
day
when
there
shall
be
great
pollutions
upon
the
face
of
the
earth;
there
shall
be
murders,
and
robbing,
lying,
and
deceivings,
whoredoms,
and
all
manner
of
abominations;
when
there
shall
be
many
who
will
say,
Do
this,
or
do
that,
and
it
mattereth not, for the Lord will uphold such at the last day. But wo unto such, for they are in the gall of bitterness and in the bonds of iniquity.
32 Yea, it shall come in a day when there shall be churches built up that shall say: Come unto me, and for your money you shall be forgiven of your
Yea,
it
shall
come
in
a
day
when
there
shall
be
churches
built
up
that
shall say: Come unto me, and for your money you shall be forgiven of your sins.
33 O ye wicked and perverse and stiffnecked people, why have ye built up churches unto yourselves to get gain? Why have ye transfigured the holy word of God, that ye might bring damnation upon your souls? Behold, look ye unto the revelations of God; for behold, the time cometh at that day when all these things must be
O
ye
wicked
and
perverse
stiffnecked
people,
why
have
ye
built
up
churches
unto
yourselves
to
get
gain?
Why
have
ye
transfigured
the
holy
word
of
God,
that
ye
might
bring
damnation
upon
your
souls?
Behold,
look
ye
unto
the
revelations
of
God;
for
behold,
the
time
cometh
at
that
day
when
all
these
things
must
be
fulfilled.
34 Behold, the Lord hath shown unto me great and marvelous things concerning that which must shortly come, at that day when these things shall come forth among
Behold,
the
Lord
hath
shown
unto
me
great
and
marvelous
things
concerning
that
which
must
shortly
come,
at
that
day
when
these
things
shall
come
forth
among
you.
35 Behold, I speak unto you as if ye were present, and yet ye are not. But behold, Jesus Christ hath shown you unto me, and I know your
Behold,
I
speak
unto
you
as
if
ye
were
present,
and
yet
ye
are
not.
But
behold,
Jesus
Christ
hath
shown
you
unto
me,
and
I
know
your
doing.
36 And I know that ye do walk in the pride of your hearts; and there are none save a few only who do not lift themselves up in the pride of their hearts, unto the wearing of very fine apparel, unto envying, and strifes, and malice, and persecutions, and all manner of iniquities; and your churches, yea, even every one, have become polluted because of the pride of your
And
I
know
that
ye
do
walk
in
the
pride
of
your
hearts;
and
there
are
none
save
a
few
only
who
do
not
lift
themselves
up
in
the
pride
of
their
hearts,
unto
the
wearing
of
very
fine
apparel,
unto
envying,
and
strifes,
malice,
and
persecutions,
all
manner
of
iniquities;
and
your
churches,
yea,
even
every
one,
have
become
polluted
because
of
the
pride
of
your
hearts.
37 For behold, ye do love money, and your substance, and your fine apparel, and the adorning of your churches, more than ye love the poor and the needy, the sick and the
For
behold,
ye
do
love
money,
and
your
substance,
and
your
fine
apparel,
and
the
adorning
of
your
churches,
more
than
ye
love
the
poor
and
the
needy,
sick
and
the
afflicted.
38 O ye pollutions, ye hypocrites, ye teachers, who sell yourselves for that which will canker, why have ye polluted the holy church of God? Why are ye ashamed to take upon you the name of Christ? Why do ye not think that greater is the value of an endless happiness than that misery which never dies—because of the praise of the
O
ye
pollutions,
hypocrites,
ye
teachers,
who
sell
yourselves
for
that
which
will
canker,
why
have
ye
polluted
the
holy
church
of
God?
Why
are
ye
ashamed
to
take
upon
you
the
name
of
Christ?
Why
do
ye
not
think
that
greater
is
the
value
of
an
endless
happiness
than
that
misery
which
never
dies—because
of
the
praise
of
the
world?
39 Why do ye adorn yourselves with that which hath no life, and yet suffer the hungry, and the needy, and the naked, and the sick and the afflicted to pass by you, and notice them
Why
do
ye
adorn
yourselves
with
that
which
hath
no
life,
and
yet
suffer
the
hungry,
and
the
needy,
and
the
naked,
and
the
sick
and
the
afflicted
to
pass
by
you,
and
notice
them
not?
40 Yea, why do ye build up your secret abominations to get gain, and cause that widows should mourn before the Lord, and also orphans to mourn before the Lord, and also the blood of their fathers and their husbands to cry unto the Lord from the ground, for vengeance upon your
Yea,
why
do
ye
build
up
your
secret
abominations
to
get
gain,
and
cause
that
widows
should
mourn
before
the
Lord,
and
also
orphans
to
mourn
before
the
Lord,
and
also
the
blood
of
their
fathers
and
their
husbands
to
cry
unto
the
Lord
from
the
ground,
for
vengeance
upon
your
heads?
41 Behold, the sword of vengeance hangeth over you; and the time soon cometh that he avengeth the blood of the saints upon you, for he will not suffer their cries any longer.
Behold,
the
sword
of
vengeance
hangeth
over
you;
and
the
time
soon
cometh
that
he
avengeth
the
blood
of
the
saints
upon
you,
for
he
will
not
suffer
their
cries
any
longer.