Chapter 7 Mormon invites the Lamanites of the
latter days to believe in Christ, accept His gospel,
and be saved—All who believe the Bible will also
believe the Book of Mormon. About A.D. 385.
1 And now, behold, I would speak somewhat unto the
remnant of this people who are spared, if it so
be that God may give unto them my words, that they
may know of the things of their fathers; yea, I
speak unto you, ye remnant of the house of Israel;
and these are the words which I speak
2 Know ye that ye are of the house of Israel
3 Know ye that ye must come unto repentance, or ye
cannot be saved
4 Know ye that ye must lay down your weapons of
war, and delight no more in the shedding of blood,
and take them not again, save it be that God shall
command you
5 Know ye that ye must come to the knowledge of
your fathers, and repent of all your sins and
iniquities, and believe in Jesus Christ, that he is the
Son of God, and that he was slain by the Jews, and
by the power of the Father he hath risen again,
whereby he hath gained the victory over the grave;
and also in him is the sting of death swallowed
up
6 And he bringeth to pass the resurrection of the
dead, whereby man must be raised to stand before
his judgment-seat
7 And he hath brought to pass the redemption of
the world, whereby he that is found guiltless before
him at the judgment day hath it given unto him to
dwell in the presence of God in his kingdom, to
sing ceaseless praises with the choirs above, unto
the Father, and unto the Son, and unto the Holy
Ghost, which are one God, in a state of happiness
which hath no end
8 Therefore repent, and be baptized in the name of
Jesus, and lay hold upon the gospel of Christ,
which shall be set before you, not only in this
record but also in the record which shall come unto
the Gentiles from the Jews, which record shall come
from the Gentiles unto you
9 For behold, this is written for the intent that
ye may believe that; and if ye believe that ye
will believe this also; and if ye believe this ye
will know concerning your fathers, and also the
marvelous works which were wrought by the power of God
among them
10 And ye will also know that ye are a remnant of
the seed of Jacob; therefore ye are numbered among
the people of the first covenant; and if it so be
that ye believe in Christ, and are baptized,
first with water, then with fire and with the Holy
Ghost, following the example of our Savior, according
to that which he hath commanded us, it shall be
well with you in the day of judgment. Amen.