Chapter 4 War and carnage continue—The wicked
punish the wicked—Greater wickedness prevails than
ever before in all Israel—Women and children
are sacrificed to idols—The Lamanites begin to
sweep the Nephites before them. About A.D. 363–75.
1 And now it came to pass that in the three
hundred and sixty and third year the
Nephites did go up with their armies to battle
against the Lamanites, out of the land Desolation.
2 And it came to pass that the armies of
the Nephites were driven back again to the
land of Desolation. And while they were yet
weary, a fresh army of the Lamanites did
come upon them; and they had a sore battle,
insomuch that the Lamanites did take
possession of the city Desolation, and did slay
many of the Nephites, and did take many prisoners.
3 And the remainder did flee and
join the inhabitants of the city
Teancum. Now the city Teancum lay in
the borders by the seashore; and
it was also near the city Desolation.
4 And it was because the
armies of the Nephites went up unto
the Lamanites that they began
to be smitten; for were it
not for that, the Lamanites
could have had no power over them.
5 But, behold, the judgments
of God will overtake the
wicked; and it is by the
wicked that the wicked are
punished; for it is the wicked
that stir up the hearts of the
children of men unto bloodshed.
6 And it came to pass
that the Lamanites did
make preparations to come
against the city Teancum.
7 And it came to pass
in the three hundred
and sixty and fourth
year the Lamanites
did come against the
city Teancum, that
they might take
possession of the city Teancum also.
8 And it came to pass
that they were
repulsed and driven back
by the Nephites. And
when the Nephites saw
that they had driven
the Lamanites they
did again boast of
their own strength; and
they went forth in
their own might, and
took possession again of
the city Desolation.
9 And now all
these things had been
done, and there
had been thousands
slain on both
sides, both the
Nephites and the Lamanites.
10 And it came
to pass that the
three hundred
and sixty and
sixth year had
passed away, and the
Lamanites came
again upon the
Nephites to
battle; and yet the
Nephites repented
not of the evil
they had done,
but persisted in
their wickedness continually.
11 And it is
impossible for
the tongue to
describe, or for
man to write a
perfect
description of the
horrible scene of
the blood and
carnage which was
among the
people, both of the
Nephites and
of the
Lamanites; and every
heart was
hardened, so that they
delighted in
the shedding of blood continually.
12 And there
never had
been so great
wickedness
among all the
children of
Lehi, nor even
among all the
house of
Israel, according
to the words
of the Lord,
as was among this people.
13 And it
came to pass
that the
Lamanites did
take
possession of the
city
Desolation, and this
because their
number did
exceed the
number of the Nephites.
14 And they
did also
march
forward against
the city
Teancum, and
did drive
the
inhabitants forth
out of her,
and did take
many
prisoners both
women and
children, and
did offer
them up as
sacrifices
unto their idol gods.
15 And it
came to
pass that in
the three
hundred
and sixty
and seventh
year, the
Nephites
being
angry because
the
Lamanites had
sacrificed
their women
and their
children,
that they
did go
against the
Lamanites
with
exceedingly
great anger,
insomuch
that they
did beat
again the
Lamanites,
and drive them out of their lands.
16 And
the
Lamanites did
not come
again
against the
Nephites
until the
three
hundred and
seventy
and fifth year.
17 And
in this
year they
did
come down
against
the
Nephites with
all
their
powers; and
they were
not
numbered
because of
the
greatness of their number.
18 And
from
this time
forth
did the
Nephites gain
no
power over
the
Lamanites, but
began to
be
swept off
by them
even
as a dew before the sun.
19 And
it
came to
pass
that
the
Lamanites
did
come
down
against
the city
Desolation;
and
there
was an
exceedingly
sore
battle
fought
in
the land
Desolation,
in
the
which they did beat the Nephites.
And
they
fled
again
from
before
them,
and
they
came
to
the
city
Boaz;
and
there
they
did
stand
against
the
Lamanites
with
exceeding
boldness,
insomuch
that
the
Lamanites
did not
beat
them
until they had come again the second time.
And
when
they had
come
the
second
time,
the
Nephites
were
driven
and
slaughtered
with
an
exceedingly
great
slaughter;
their
women
and
their
children
were
again
sacrificed
unto
idols.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
Nephites
did
again
flee
from
before
them,
taking
all
the
inhabitants
with
them, both in towns and villages.
And
now
I,
Mormon,
seeing
that
the
Lamanites
were
about
to
overthrow
the
land,
therefore I
did
go
to
the
hill
Shim,
and
did
take
up
all
the records which Ammaron had hid up unto the Lord.