The Book of MormonChapter 1 Ammaron instructs
Mormon concerning the sacred records—War commences
between the Nephites and the Lamanites—The Three
Nephites are taken away—Wickedness, unbelief,
sorceries, and witchcraft prevail. About A.D. 321–26.
1 And now I, Mormon, make a record of
the things which I have both seen and
heard, and call it the Book of Mormon.
2 And about the time that Ammaron
hid up the records unto the Lord, he
came unto me, (I being about ten
years of age, and I began to be learned
somewhat after the manner of the
learning of my people) and Ammaron said
unto me: I perceive that thou art a
sober child, and art quick to observe;
3 Therefore, when ye are about
twenty and four years old I would
that ye should remember the
things that ye have observed
concerning this people; and when ye
are of that age go to the land
Antum, unto a hill which shall be
called Shim; and there have I
deposited unto the Lord all the
sacred engravings concerning this people.
4 And behold, ye shall take
the plates of Nephi unto
yourself, and the remainder
shall ye leave in the place
where they are; and ye shall
engrave on the plates of Nephi
all the things that ye have
observed concerning this people.
5 And I, Mormon, being a
descendant of Nephi, (and
my father’s name was
Mormon) I remembered the things
which Ammaron commanded me.
6 And it came to pass
that I, being eleven
years old, was carried
by my father into the
land southward, even
to the land of Zarahemla.
7 The whole face of
the land had
become covered with
buildings, and the
people were as numerous
almost, as it were
the sand of the sea.
8 And it came to
pass in this year
there began to be a
war between the
Nephites, who
consisted of the
Nephites and the
Jacobites and the
Josephites and the
Zoramites; and this war
was between the
Nephites, and the
Lamanites and the
Lemuelites and the Ishmaelites.
9 Now the
Lamanites and the
Lemuelites and the
Ishmaelites were
called
Lamanites, and the two
parties were
Nephites and Lamanites.
10 And it came
to pass that
the war began to
be among them
in the borders
of Zarahemla, by
the waters of Sidon.
11 And it came
to pass that
the Nephites
had gathered
together a great
number of
men, even to
exceed the number
of thirty
thousand. And it
came to pass
that they did
have in this
same year a
number of battles,
in which the
Nephites did
beat the
Lamanites and did slay many of them.
12 And it
came to pass
that the
Lamanites withdrew
their design,
and there was
peace
settled in the
land; and peace
did remain for
the space of
about four
years, that
there was no bloodshed.
13 But
wickedness did
prevail upon
the face of
the whole
land, insomuch
that the
Lord did take
away his
beloved
disciples, and the
work of
miracles and of
healing did
cease because
of the
iniquity of the people.
14 And
there were no
gifts from
the Lord,
and the Holy
Ghost did
not come
upon any,
because of
their
wickedness and unbelief.
15 And I,
being
fifteen years
of age and
being
somewhat of a
sober
mind,
therefore I was
visited of
the Lord,
and tasted
and knew
of the
goodness of Jesus.
16 And I
did
endeavor to
preach unto
this
people, but
my mouth
was shut,
and I
was
forbidden that I
should
preach
unto them;
for behold
they had
wilfully
rebelled
against
their
God; and the
beloved
disciples
were
taken away
out of the
land, because of their iniquity.
17 But I
did
remain
among them,
but I
was
forbidden to
preach
unto them,
because
of the
hardness
of
their
hearts; and
because of
the
hardness of
their
hearts
the land
was cursed for their sake.
18 And
these
Gadianton
robbers, who
were
among
the
Lamanites,
did
infest the
land,
insomuch
that
the
inhabitants
thereof began
to
hide up
their
treasures
in the
earth;
and
they
became
slippery,
because
the Lord
had
cursed
the land,
that
they
could not hold them, nor retain them again.
19 And
it
came to
pass
that
there
were
sorceries, and
witchcrafts,
and
magics;
the
power of
evil one
was
wrought
upon
all
the face
of
the
land, even
unto
the
fulfilling of
all
the
words of
Abinadi, and also Samuel the Lamanite.