Chapter 3 Mormon cries repentance unto the
Nephites—They gain a great victory and glory in
their own strength—Mormon refuses to lead them,
and his prayers for them are without
faith—The Book of Mormon invites the twelve tribes of
Israel to believe the gospel. About A.D. 360–62.
1 And it came to pass that the Lamanites did
not come to battle again until ten years more
had passed away. And behold, I had employed
my people, the Nephites, in preparing their
lands and their arms against the time of battle.
2 And it came to pass that the Lord did say
unto me: Cry unto this people—Repent ye, and
come unto me, and be ye baptized, and build
up again my church, and ye shall be spared.
3 And I did cry unto this people, but
it was in vain; and they did not realize
that it was the Lord that had spared
them, and granted unto them a chance for
repentance. And behold they did harden
their hearts against the Lord their God.
4 And it came to pass that after
this tenth year had passed away,
making, in the whole, three hundred and
sixty years from the coming of
Christ, the king of the Lamanites sent
an epistle unto me, which gave
unto me to know that they were
preparing to come again to battle against us.
5 And it came to pass that I did
cause my people that they should
gather themselves together at the
land Desolation, to a city which was
in the borders, by the narrow
pass which led into the land southward.
6 And there we did place our
armies, that we might stop the armies
of the Lamanites, that they
might not get possession of any of
our lands; therefore we did fortify
against them with all our force.
7 And it came to pass that in
the three hundred and sixty and
first year the Lamanites did come
down to the city of Desolation
to battle against us; and it came
to pass that in that year we
did beat them, insomuch that they
did return to their own lands again.
8 And in the three hundred and
sixty and second year they did
come down again to battle. And we
did beat them again, and did
slay a great number of them, and
their dead were cast into the sea.
9 And now, because of this
great thing which my people,
the Nephites, had done, they
began to boast in their own
strength, and began to swear
before the heavens that they
would avenge themselves of the
blood of their brethren who
had been slain by their enemies.
10 And they did swear by the
heavens, and also by the
throne of God, that they would
go up to battle against
their enemies, and would cut
them off from the face of the land.
11 And it came to pass
that I, Mormon, did
utterly refuse from this time
forth to be a commander
and a leader of this
people, because of their
wickedness and abomination.
12 Behold, I had led
them, notwithstanding
their wickedness I had
led them many times to
battle, and had loved
them, according to
the love of God which
was in me, with all my
heart; and my soul had
been poured out in
prayer unto my God all
the day long for them;
nevertheless, it was
without faith, because
of the hardness of their hearts.
13 And thrice have
I delivered them
out of the hands
of their enemies,
and they have
repented not of their sins.
14 And when they
had sworn by all
that had been
forbidden them by
our Lord and Savior
Jesus Christ,
that they would go
up unto their
enemies to battle,
and avenge
themselves of the blood
of their
brethren, behold the
voice of the Lord
came unto me, saying:
15 Vengeance is
mine, and I will
repay; and
because this people
repented not
after I had
delivered them, behold,
they shall be
cut off from the
face of the earth.
16 And it came
to pass that I
utterly refused
to go up
against mine
enemies; and I did
even as the Lord
had commanded
me; and I did
stand as an idle
witness to
manifest unto the
world the things
which I saw and
heard,
according to the
manifestations of
the Spirit which
had testified of things to come.
17 Therefore I
write unto
you, Gentiles,
and also unto
you, house of
Israel, when
the work shall
commence, that
ye shall be
about to prepare
to return to
the land of
your inheritance;
18 Yea,
behold, I write
unto all the
ends of the
earth; yea, unto
you, twelve
tribes of
Israel, who
shall be judged
according to
your works by
the twelve
whom Jesus
chose to be his
disciples in
the land of Jerusalem.
19 And I
write also unto
the remnant
of this
people, who
shall also be
judged by the
twelve whom
Jesus chose
in this
land; and they
shall be
judged by the
other twelve
whom Jesus
chose in the
land of Jerusalem.
20 And
these things
doth the
Spirit manifest
unto me;
therefore I
write unto
you all.
And for this
cause I
write unto
you, that ye
may know
that ye must
all stand
before the
judgment-seat
of Christ,
yea, every
soul who
belongs to
the whole
human family
of Adam;
and ye must
stand to be
judged of
your works,
whether they be good or evil;
21 And also
that ye
may believe
the gospel
of Jesus
Christ, which
ye shall
have among
you; and also
that the
Jews, the
covenant
people of the
Lord, shall
have other
witness
besides him
whom they saw
and heard,
that
Jesus, whom they
slew, was
the very
Christ and
the very God.
22 And I
would that
I could
persuade all
ye ends
of the
earth to
repent and
prepare to
stand before
the
judgment-seat of Christ.