Chapter 5 Mormon again leads the Nephite
armies in battles of blood and carnage—The Book
of Mormon will come forth to convince all
Israel that Jesus is the Christ—Because of
their unbelief, the Lamanites will be
scattered, and the Spirit will cease to strive with
them—They will receive the gospel from the
Gentiles in the latter days. About A.D. 375–84.
1 And it came to pass that I did go
forth among the Nephites, and did repent
of the oath which I had made that I
would no more assist them; and they
gave me command again of their armies,
for they looked upon me as though I
could deliver them from their afflictions.
2 But behold, I was without hope, for
I knew the judgments of the Lord
which should come upon them; for they
repented not of their iniquities, but
did struggle for their lives without
calling upon that Being who created them.
3 And it came to pass that the
Lamanites did come against us as we had
fled to the city of Jordan; but
behold, they were driven back that
they did not take the city at that time.
4 And it came to pass that they
came against us again, and we
did maintain the city. And there
were also other cities which were
maintained by the Nephites,
which strongholds did cut them off
that they could not get into the
country which lay before us, to
destroy the inhabitants of our land.
5 But it came to pass that
whatsoever lands we had passed
by, and the inhabitants thereof
were not gathered in, were
destroyed by the Lamanites, and
their towns, and villages, and
cities were burned with fire;
and thus three hundred and
seventy and nine years passed away.
6 And it came to pass that
in the three hundred and
eightieth year the Lamanites
did come again against us
to battle, and we did stand
against them boldly; but it
was all in vain, for so
great were their numbers that
they did tread the people
of the Nephites under their feet.
7 And it came to pass
that we did again take to
flight, and those whose
flight was swifter than the
Lamanites’ did escape,
and those whose flight did
not exceed the Lamanites’
were swept down and destroyed.
8 And now behold, I,
Mormon, do not desire to
harrow up the souls of men
in casting before them
such an awful scene of
blood and carnage as was
laid before mine eyes;
but I, knowing that these
things must surely be
made known, and that all
things which are hid
must be revealed upon the house-tops—
9 And also that a
knowledge of these things
must come unto the
remnant of these people, and
also unto the Gentiles,
who the Lord hath said
should scatter this
people, and this people
should be counted as
naught among
them—therefore I write a small
abridgment, daring not to
give a full account of
the things which I have
seen, because of the
commandment which I have
received, and also that
ye might not have too
great sorrow because of
the wickedness of this people.
10 And now behold,
this I speak unto their
seed, and also to
the Gentiles who have
care for the house of
Israel, that realize
and know from whence
their blessings come.
11 For I know that
such will sorrow for
the calamity of the
house of Israel;
yea, they will sorrow
for the destruction
of this people; they
will sorrow that
this people had not
repented that they
might have been clasped
in the arms of Jesus.
12 Now these things
are written unto
the remnant of the
house of Jacob; and
they are written
after this manner,
because it is known
of God that
wickedness will not bring
them forth unto
them; and they are to
be hid up unto the
Lord that they may
come forth in his own due time.
13 And this is the
commandment which
I have received;
and behold, they
shall come forth
according to the
commandment of the
Lord, when he shall
see fit, in his wisdom.
14 And behold,
they shall go unto
the unbelieving
of the Jews; and
for this intent
shall they go—that
they may be
persuaded that Jesus
is the Christ, the
Son of the
living God; that the
Father may bring
about, through his
most Beloved,
his great and
eternal purpose, in
restoring the Jews,
or all the house
of Israel, to
the land of their
inheritance, which
the Lord their
God hath given
them, unto the fulfilling of his covenant;
15 And also that
the seed of
this people may
more fully believe
his gospel,
which shall go forth
unto them from
the Gentiles;
for this people
shall be
scattered, and shall
become a dark, a
filthy, and a
loathsome people,
beyond the
description of that
which ever hath been
amongst us,
yea, even that
which hath been
among the Lamanites,
and this
because of their unbelief and idolatry.
16 For behold,
the Spirit of
the Lord hath
already ceased to
strive with
their fathers;
and they are
without Christ and
God in the
world; and they are
driven about
as chaff before the wind.
17 They were
once a
delightsome people,
and they had
Christ for
their
shepherd; yea, they
were led even
by God the Father.
18 But now,
behold, they
are led
about by Satan,
even as
chaff is driven
before the
wind, or as
a vessel is
tossed about
upon the
waves, without
sail or
anchor, or
without anything
wherewith
to steer her;
and even as
she is, so are they.
19 And
behold, the
Lord hath
reserved their
blessings,
which they
might have
received in
the land,
for the
Gentiles who
shall possess the land.
20 But
behold, it
shall come
to pass
that they
shall be
driven and
scattered by
the
Gentiles; and
after they
have been
driven and
scattered
by the
Gentiles,
behold, then
will the
Lord
remember the
covenant
which he made
unto
Abraham and
unto all the house of Israel.
21 And
also the
Lord will
remember
the
prayers of the
righteous, which
have been
put up
unto him for them.
22 And
then, O
ye
Gentiles, how
can ye
stand
before the
power of
God,
except ye
shall
repent and
turn
from your evil ways?
23 Know
ye not
that
ye are
in the
hands of
God?
Know ye
not
that he
hath all
power,
and at
his
great
command the
earth
shall
be
rolled together as a scroll?
Therefore,
repent
ye, and
humble
yourselves
before
him, lest
he
shall come
out in
justice
against
you—lest a
remnant
of the
seed
of Jacob
shall
go
forth among
you as
a
lion, and
tear you
in
pieces,
and there
is
none to
deliver.