Chapter 9 Moroni calls upon those who do not
believe in Christ to repent—He proclaims a
God of miracles, who gives revelations and
pours out gifts and signs upon the
faithful—Miracles cease because of unbelief—Signs follow
those who believe—Men are exhorted to be wise
and keep the commandments. About A.D. 401–21.
1 And now, I speak also concerning
those who do not believe in Christ.
2 Behold, will ye believe in the
day of your visitation—behold,
when the Lord shall come, yea, even
that great day when the earth
shall be rolled together as a
scroll, and the elements shall melt
with fervent heat, yea, in that
great day when ye shall be brought
to stand before the Lamb of
God—then will ye say that there is no God?
3 Then will ye longer deny the
Christ, or can ye behold the
Lamb of God? Do ye suppose that
ye shall dwell with him under a
consciousness of your guilt? Do
ye suppose that ye could be
happy to dwell with that holy
Being, when your souls are racked
with a consciousness of guilt
that ye have ever abused his laws?
4 Behold, I say unto you
that ye would be more miserable
to dwell with a holy and
just God, under a
consciousness of your filthiness before
him, than ye would to dwell
with the damned souls in hell.
5 For behold, when ye
shall be brought to see your
nakedness before God, and
also the glory of God, and
the holiness of Jesus
Christ, it will kindle a flame
of unquenchable fire upon you.
6 O then ye
unbelieving, turn ye unto the
Lord; cry mightily unto the
Father in the name of
Jesus, that perhaps ye
may be found spotless,
pure, fair, and white,
having been cleansed by
the blood of the Lamb,
at that great and last day.
7 And again I speak
unto you who deny the
revelations of God, and
say that they are done
away, that there are
no revelations, nor
prophecies, nor gifts,
nor healing, nor
speaking with tongues, and
the interpretation of tongues;
8 Behold I say unto
you, he that denieth
these things
knoweth not the gospel of
Christ; yea, he has
not read the
scriptures; if so, he does
not understand them.
9 For do we not
read that God is the
same yesterday,
today, and forever, and
in him there is no
variableness
neither shadow of changing?
10 And now, if ye
have imagined up
unto yourselves a
god who doth vary,
and in whom there
is shadow of
changing, then have ye
imagined up unto
yourselves a god
who is not a God of miracles.
11 But behold, I
will show unto
you a God of
miracles, even the
God of Abraham,
and the God of
Isaac, and the
God of Jacob; and
it is that same
God who created
the heavens and
the earth, and
all things that in them are.
12 Behold, he
created Adam,
and by Adam came
the fall of
man. And because
of the fall of
man came Jesus
Christ, even the
Father and the
Son; and
because of Jesus
Christ came the
redemption of man.
13 And because
of the
redemption of man,
which came by
Jesus Christ,
they are
brought back into
the presence of
the Lord; yea,
this is
wherein all men are
redeemed,
because the death
of Christ
bringeth to pass
the
resurrection, which
bringeth to pass a
redemption
from an endless
sleep, from
which sleep all
men shall be
awakened by the
power of God
when the trump
shall sound;
and they shall
come forth,
both small and
great, and all
shall stand
before his bar,
being
redeemed and loosed
from this
eternal band of death, which death is a temporal death.
14 And then
cometh the
judgment of the
Holy One upon
them; and then
cometh the time
that he that
is filthy shall
be filthy
still; and he
that is righteous
shall be
righteous still;
he that is
happy shall be
happy still; and
he that is
unhappy shall be
unhappy still.
15 And now, O
all ye that
have imagined
up unto
yourselves a god
who can do no
miracles, I
would ask of
you, have all
these things
passed, of
which I have
spoken? Has
the end come
yet? Behold I
say unto you,
Nay; and God
has not
ceased to be a God of miracles.
16 Behold,
are not the
things that God
hath wrought
marvelous in
our eyes?
Yea, and who can
comprehend
the marvelous
works of God?
17 Who shall
say that it
was not a
miracle that
by his word
the heaven
and the earth
should be;
and by the
power of his
word man was
created of
the dust of
the earth;
and by the
power of his
word have
miracles been wrought?
18 And who
shall say
that Jesus
Christ did
not do many
mighty
miracles? And
there were
many mighty
miracles
wrought by
the hands of
the apostles.
19 And if
there were
miracles
wrought
then, why
has God
ceased to be a
God of
miracles and
yet be an
unchangeable Being?
And
behold, I say
unto you he
changeth
not; if so
he would
cease to
be God; and
he
ceaseth not to
be God, and is a God of miracles.
20 And
the reason
why he
ceaseth to
do
miracles among
the
children of
men is
because that
they
dwindle in
unbelief,
and depart
from the
right
way, and
know not
the God in
whom they should trust.
Behold, I say
unto
you that
whoso
believeth
in
Christ,
doubting
nothing,
whatsoever
he shall
ask the
Father
in the
name of
Christ it
shall be
granted
him;
and this
promise
is unto
all, even
unto the ends of the earth.
22 For
behold,
thus
said
Jesus
Christ, the
Son of
God,
unto his
disciples who
should
tarry,
yea,
and also
to all
his
disciples, in
the
hearing of
multitude:
Go ye
into all
the
world,
and
preach the gospel to every creature;
23 And
he
that
believeth
and
is
baptized
shall
be
saved, but
he
that
believeth
not
shall be damned;
And
these
signs
shall
follow
them
that
believe—in my
name
shall
they
cast out
devils;
they
shall
speak
with
new
tongues;
they
shall
take
up
serpents;
and if
they
drink
any
deadly
thing it
shall not
hurt
them;
they
shall lay hands on the sick and they shall recover;
And
whosoever
shall
believe
in my
name,
doubting
nothing,
unto
him
will I
confirm
all
my
words,
even
unto the ends of the earth.
And
now,
behold,
who
can
stand
against
the
works
of
the
Lord?
Who
can
deny
his
sayings?
Who
will
rise
up
against
the
almighty
power
of
the
Lord?
Who
will
despise
the
works
of
the
Lord?
Who
will
despise
the
children
of
Christ?
Behold,
all ye who are despisers of the works of the Lord, for ye shall wonder and perish.
O
then
despise
not,
and
wonder
not,
but
hearken
unto
the
words
of
the
Lord,
and
ask
the
Father
in
the
name
of
Jesus
for
what
things
soever
ye
shall
stand
in
need.
Doubt
not,
but
be
believing,
and
begin
as
in
times
of
old,
and
come
unto
the
Lord
with
all
your
heart,
and
work
out
your
own
salvation
with
fear
and
trembling
before
him.
Be
wise
in
the
days
of
your
probation;
strip
yourselves
of
all
uncleanness;
ask
not,
that
ye
may
consume
it
on
your
lusts,
but
ask
with
a
firmness
unshaken,
that ye will yield to no temptation, but that ye will serve the true and living God.
See
that
ye
are
not
baptized
unworthily;
see
that
ye
partake
not
of
the
sacrament
of
Christ
unworthily;
but
see
that
ye
do
all
things
in
worthiness,
name
of
Jesus
Christ,
the
Son
of
the
living
God;
and
if
ye
do
this,
and
endure
to
the
end,
ye
will
in
nowise
be
cast
out.
Behold,
I
speak
unto
you
as
though
I
spake
from
the
dead;
for
I
know
that
ye
shall
have
my
words.
31 Condemn me not because of mine imperfection, neither my father, because of his imperfection, neither them who have written before him; but rather give thanks unto God that he hath made manifest unto you our imperfections, that ye may learn to be more wise than we have
Condemn
me
not
because
of
mine
imperfection,
neither
my
father,
because
of
his
imperfection,
neither
them
who
have
written
before
him;
but rather give thanks unto God that he hath made manifest unto you our imperfections, that ye may learn to be more wise than we have been.
32 And now, behold, we have written this record according to our knowledge, in the characters which are called among us the reformed Egyptian, being handed down and altered by us, according to our manner of
And
now,
behold,
we
have
written
this
record
according
to
our
knowledge,
in
the
characters
which
are
called
among
us
the
reformed
Egyptian,
being
handed
down
and
altered
by
us,
according
to
our
manner
of
speech.
33 And if our plates had been sufficiently large we should have written in Hebrew; but the Hebrew hath been altered by us also; and if we could have written in Hebrew, behold, ye would have had no imperfection in our
And
if
our
plates
had
been
sufficiently
large
we
should
have
written
in
Hebrew;
but
the
Hebrew
hath
been
altered
by
us
also;
and
if
we
could
have
written
in
Hebrew,
behold,
ye
would
have
had
no
imperfection
in
our
record.
34 But the Lord knoweth the things which we have written, and also that none other people knoweth our language; and because that none other people knoweth our language, therefore he hath prepared means for the interpretation
But
the
Lord
knoweth
the
things
which
we
have
written,
and
also
that
none
other
people
knoweth
our
language;
and
because
that
none
other
people
knoweth
our
language,
therefore
he
hath
prepared
means
for
the
interpretation
thereof.
35 And these things are written that we may rid our garments of the blood of our brethren, who have dwindled in
And
these
things
are
written
that
we
may
rid
our
garments
of
the
blood
of
our
brethren,
who
have
dwindled
in
unbelief.
36 And behold, these things which we have desired concerning our brethren, yea, even their restoration to the knowledge of Christ, are according to the prayers of all the saints who have dwelt in the
And
behold,
these
things
which
we
have
desired
concerning
our
brethren,
yea,
even
their
restoration
to
the
knowledge
of
Christ,
are
according
to
the
prayers
of
all
the
saints
who
have
dwelt
in
the
land.
37 And may the Lord Jesus Christ grant that their prayers may be answered according to their faith; and may God the Father remember the covenant which he hath made with the house of Israel; and may he bless them forever, through faith on the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.
And
may
the
Lord
Jesus
Christ
grant
that
their
prayers
may
be
answered
according
to
their
faith;
and
may
God
the
Father
remember
the
covenant
which
he
hath
made
with
the
house
of
Israel;
and
may
he
bless
them
forever,
through
faith
on
the
name
of
Jesus
Christ.
Amen.