Chapter 2 Abraham leaves Ur to go to
Canaan—Jehovah appears to him at Haran—All gospel
blessings are promised to his seed and through his
seed to all—He goes to Canaan and on to Egypt.
1 Now the Lord God caused the famine to wax
sore in the land of Ur, insomuch that
Haran, my brother, died; but Terah, my father,
yet lived in the land of Ur, of the Chaldees.
2 And it came to pass that I,
Abraham, took Sarai to wife, and
Nahor, my brother, took Milcah to
wife, who was the daughter of Haran.
3 Now the Lord had said unto
me: Abraham, get thee out of thy
country, and from thy kindred,
and from thy father’s house,
unto a land that I will show thee.
4 Therefore I left the land
of Ur, of the Chaldees, to
go into the land of Canaan;
and I took Lot, my brother’s
son, and his wife, and Sarai
my wife; and also my father
followed after me, unto the
land which we denominated Haran.
5 And the famine abated;
and my father tarried in
Haran and dwelt there, as
there were many flocks in
Haran; and my father turned
again unto his idolatry,
therefore he continued in Haran.
6 But I, Abraham, and
Lot, my brother’s son,
prayed unto the Lord, and
the Lord appeared unto
me, and said unto me:
Arise, and take Lot with
thee; for I have purposed
to take thee away out of
Haran, and to make of
thee a minister to bear my
name in a strange land
which I will give unto
thy seed after thee for
an everlasting
possession, when they hearken to my voice.
7 For I am the Lord thy
God; I dwell in
heaven; the earth is my
footstool; I stretch my hand
over the sea, and it
obeys my voice; I cause
the wind and the fire
to be my chariot; I say
to the mountains—Depart
hence—and behold, they
are taken away by a
whirlwind, in an instant, suddenly.
8 My name is
Jehovah, and I know the
end from the
beginning; therefore my
hand shall be over thee.
9 And I will make
of thee a great
nation, and I will
bless thee above
measure, and make
thy name great among
all nations, and
thou shalt be a
blessing unto thy
seed after thee,
that in their hands
they shall bear
this ministry and
Priesthood unto all nations;
10 And I will
bless them through
thy name; for as
many as receive
this Gospel shall
be called after
thy name, and shall
be accounted thy
seed, and shall
rise up and bless
thee, as their father;
11 And I will
bless them that
bless thee, and
curse them that
curse thee; and in
thee (that is,
in thy
Priesthood) and in thy
seed (that is, thy
Priesthood),
for I give unto
thee a promise
that this right
shall continue in
thee, and in thy
seed after thee
(that is to say,
the literal
seed, or the seed
of the body)
shall all the
families of the earth
be blessed, even
with the
blessings of the
Gospel, which are the
blessings of
salvation, even of life eternal.
12 Now, after
the Lord had
withdrawn from
speaking to me,
and withdrawn his
face from me,
I said in my
heart: Thy
servant has sought
thee earnestly;
now I have found thee;
13 Thou didst
send thine
angel to deliver
me from the
gods of Elkenah,
and I will do
well to
hearken unto thy
voice, therefore
let thy
servant rise up and
depart in peace.
14 So I,
Abraham, departed
as the Lord
had said unto
me, and Lot
with me; and
I, Abraham,
was sixty and
two years old
when I
departed out of Haran.
15 And I
took Sarai,
whom I took to
wife when I
was in Ur,
in Chaldea,
and Lot, my
brother’s
son, and all
our substance
that we had
gathered,
and the souls
that we had
won in
Haran, and came
forth in the
way to the
land of
Canaan, and dwelt
in tents as we came on our way;
Therefore, eternity
was our
covering and
our rock
and our
salvation, as we
journeyed
from Haran
by the way
of Jershon,
to come to
the land of Canaan.
17 Now I,
Abraham,
built an
altar in the
land of
Jershon,
and made an
offering
unto the
Lord, and
prayed that
the famine
might be
turned
away from my
father’s
house, that
they might not perish.
18 And
then we
passed from
Jershon
through
the land
unto the
place of
Sechem; it
was
situated in
the plains
of Moreh,
and we
had
already come
into the
borders of
the land
of the
Canaanites,
and I
offered
sacrifice
there in
the plains
of Moreh,
and
called on the
Lord
devoutly,
because we
had
already come
into the land of this idolatrous nation.
19 And
the Lord
appeared
unto me
in
answer to my
prayers, and
said unto
me: Unto
thy
seed will I
give this land.
20 And
I,
Abraham,
arose
from the
place of
the
altar
which I
had built
unto
the
Lord, and
removed
from
thence
unto a
mountain
on the
east of
Bethel, and
pitched
my tent
there,
Bethel
on the
west,
and Hai
on the
east;
and
there I
built
another
altar
unto the
Lord,
and called again upon the name of the Lord.
21 And
I,
Abraham,
journeyed,
going
on
still
towards
the
south;
and
there was
a
continuation of
famine in
the
land;
and I,
Abraham,
concluded
to go
down
into
Egypt,
to
sojourn
there,
for the famine became very grievous.
And it
came
to
pass
when I
was
come
near
to
enter
into
Egypt,
the
Lord
said
unto
me:
Behold,
Sarai,
thy
wife, is
a
very fair woman to look upon;
Therefore
it
shall
come
to
pass,
when
the
Egyptians
shall
see
her,
they
will
say—She
is
his
wife;
and
they
will
kill
you,
but
they
will
save
her
alive; therefore see that ye do on this wise:
Let
her
say
unto
the
Egyptians,
she
is
thy
sister,
and
thy soul shall live.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
I,
Abraham,
told
Sarai,
my
wife,
all
that
the
Lord
had
said
unto
me—Therefore
say
unto
them,
I
pray
thee,
thou
art
my
sister,
that it may be well with me for thy sake, and my soul shall live because of thee.