Chapter 5 The Gods finish Their planning
of the creation of all things—They
bring to pass the Creation according to
Their plans—Adam names every living creature.
1 And thus we will finish the heavens
and the earth, and all the hosts of them.
2 And the Gods said among
themselves: On the seventh time we will end
our work, which we have counseled; and
we will rest on the seventh time
from all our work which we have counseled.
3 And the Gods concluded upon the
seventh time, because that on the
seventh time they would rest from
all their works which they (the
Gods) counseled among themselves to
form; and sanctified it. And thus
were their decisions at the time
that they counseled among
themselves to form the heavens and the earth.
4 And the Gods came down and
formed these the
generations of the heavens and of the
earth, when they were formed
in the day that the Gods
formed the earth and the heavens,
5 According to all that
which they had said
concerning every plant of the
field before it was in the
earth, and every herb of
the field before it
grew; for the Gods had not
caused it to rain upon the
earth when they counseled
to do them, and had not
formed a man to till the ground.
6 But there went up a
mist from the earth,
and watered the
whole face of the ground.
7 And the Gods
formed man from the dust
of the ground, and
took his spirit (that
is, the man’s
spirit), and put it into
him; and breathed
into his nostrils the
breath of life, and
man became a living soul.
8 And the Gods
planted a garden,
eastward in Eden,
and there they
put the man, whose
spirit they had
put into the body
which they had formed.
9 And out of the
ground made the
Gods to grow
every tree that is
pleasant to the
sight and good
for food; the
tree of life,
also, in the midst
of the garden,
and the tree of
knowledge of good and evil.
10 There was a
river running
out of Eden, to
water the
garden, and from
thence it was
parted and became
into four heads.
11 And the
Gods took the
man and put
him in the
Garden of Eden,
to dress it
and to keep it.
12 And the
Gods
commanded the
man, saying:
Of every
tree of the
garden thou
mayest freely eat,
13 But of
the tree
of
knowledge of good
and evil,
thou shalt
not eat
of it; for
in the
time that
thou eatest
thereof,
thou shalt
surely die.
Now I,
Abraham, saw
that it
was after
the Lord’s
time,
which was
after the time
of Kolob;
for as
yet the Gods
had not
appointed unto Adam his reckoning.
14 And
the Gods
said: Let
us make an
help
meet for the
man, for
it is
not good
that the
man should
be alone,
therefore we will
form an
help meet for him.
15 And
the Gods
caused a
deep
sleep to
fall upon
Adam;
and he
slept, and
they
took one
of his
ribs, and
closed
up the
flesh in
the stead thereof;
16 And
of the
rib
which the
Gods
had taken
from
man,
formed
they a
woman, and
brought her unto the man.
17 And
Adam
said:
This
was
bone of
my
bones, and
flesh
of my
flesh; now
she
shall be
called
Woman,
because
she was taken out of man;
Therefore
shall a
man
leave
his
father and
mother,
and
shall
cleave
unto
his
wife,
and
they shall be one flesh.
And
they
were
both
naked,
the
man
and
his
wife,
and
were not ashamed.
And
out
of
the
ground
Gods
formed
every
beast
of
the
field,
and
every
fowl
of
the
air,
and
brought
them
unto
Adam
to
see
what
he
would
call
them;
and
whatsoever
Adam
called every living creature, that should be the name thereof.
And
Adam
gave
names
to
all
cattle,
to
the
fowl
of
the
air,
to
every
beast
of
the
field;
and
for Adam, there was found an help meet for him.