Chapter 3 Abraham learns about the sun,
moon, and stars by means of the Urim and
Thummim—The Lord reveals to him the eternal
nature of spirits—He learns of pre-earth life,
foreordination, the Creation, the choosing
of a Redeemer, and the second estate of man.
1 And I, Abraham, had the Urim and
Thummim, which the Lord my God had
given unto me, in Ur of the Chaldees;
2 And I saw the stars, that they
were very great, and that one
of them was nearest unto the
throne of God; and there were many
great ones which were near unto it;
3 And the Lord said unto me:
These are the governing
ones; and the name of the great
one is Kolob, because it is
near unto me, for I am the
Lord thy God: I have set
this one to govern all those
which belong to the same order
as that upon which thou standest.
4 And the Lord said unto
me, by the Urim and Thummim,
that Kolob was after the
manner of the Lord, according
to its times and seasons
in the revolutions thereof;
that one revolution was a
day unto the Lord, after his
manner of reckoning, it
being one thousand years
according to the time appointed
unto that whereon thou
standest. This is the
reckoning of the Lord’s time,
according to the reckoning of Kolob.
5 And the Lord said unto
me: The planet which is the
lesser light, lesser than
that which is to rule the
day, even the night, is
above or greater than that
upon which thou standest
in point of reckoning, for
it moveth in order more
slow; this is in order
because it standeth above the
earth upon which thou
standest, therefore the
reckoning of its time is not so
many as to its number of
days, and of months, and of years.
6 And the Lord said unto
me: Now, Abraham, these
two facts exist, behold
thine eyes see it; it is
given unto thee to know the
times of reckoning, and
the set time, yea, the
set time of the earth upon
which thou standest, and
the set time of the
greater light which is set to
rule the day, and the set
time of the lesser light
which is set to rule the night.
7 Now the set time of
the lesser light is a
longer time as to its
reckoning than the reckoning
of the time of the earth
upon which thou standest.
8 And where these two
facts exist, there
shall be another fact
above them, that is,
there shall be another
planet whose reckoning of
time shall be longer still;
9 And thus there
shall be the reckoning
of the time of one
planet above another,
until thou come
nigh unto Kolob, which
Kolob is after the
reckoning of the
Lord’s time; which Kolob
is set nigh unto
the throne of God, to
govern all those
planets which belong to
the same order as
that upon which thou standest.
10 And it is given
unto thee to know
the set time of all
the stars that are
set to give light,
until thou come
near unto the throne of God.
11 Thus I,
Abraham, talked with
the Lord, face to
face, as one man
talketh with
another; and he told
me of the works
which his hands had made;
12 And he said
unto me: My son,
my son (and his
hand was
stretched out), behold
I will show you
all these. And
he put his hand
upon mine eyes,
and I saw those
things which his
hands had made,
which were many;
and they
multiplied before mine
eyes, and I
could not see the end thereof.
13 And he said
unto me: This
is Shinehah,
which is the sun.
And he said
unto me: Kokob,
which is star.
And he said unto
me: Olea, which
is the moon.
And he said unto
me: Kokaubeam,
which
signifies stars, or all
the great
lights, which were
in the firmament of heaven.
14 And it was
in the night
time when the
Lord spake
these words unto
me: I will
multiply thee, and
thy seed
after thee, like
unto these; and
if thou canst
count the
number of sands,
so shall be
the number of thy seeds.
15 And the
Lord said unto
me: Abraham,
I show these
things unto
thee before ye
go into
Egypt, that ye
may declare all
these words.
16 If two
things exist,
and there be
one above
the other,
there shall be
greater
things above
them;
therefore Kolob is
the greatest
of all the
Kokaubeam
that thou hast
seen,
because it is nearest unto me.
17 Now, if
there be
two things,
one above
the other,
and the moon
be above
the earth,
then it may
be that a
planet or a
star may
exist above
it; and there
is nothing
that the
Lord thy God
shall take
in his
heart to do
but what he will do it.
18 Howbeit
that he
made the
greater
star; as,
also, if there
be two
spirits, and
one shall
be more
intelligent
than the
other, yet
these two
spirits,
notwithstanding one
is more
intelligent
than the
other, have
no
beginning; they
existed
before, they
shall
have no end,
they shall
exist
after, for they are gnolaum, or eternal.
19 And
the Lord
said unto
me: These
two facts
do
exist, that
there are
two
spirits, one
being more
intelligent than
the other;
there
shall be
another
more
intelligent than
they; I
am the
Lord thy
God, I am
more intelligent than they all.
20 The
Lord thy
God sent
his
angel to
deliver
thee from
the
hands of the
priest
of Elkenah.
21 I
dwell in
the
midst of
them
all; I
now,
therefore,
have
come down
unto
thee to
declare
unto
thee the
works
which my
hands
have
made,
wherein my
wisdom
excelleth
them all,
for I
rule in
the
heavens
above,
and in
the earth
beneath, in
all
wisdom and
prudence, over
all
the
intelligences thine
eyes
have
seen from
the
beginning;
I came
down
in the
beginning in the midst of all the intelligences thou hast seen.
22 Now
the
Lord had
shown
unto me,
Abraham, the
intelligences
that
were
organized
before
the world
was;
and
among all
these
there
were many
of the
noble
and
great ones;
23 And
God
saw
these
souls
that they
were
good,
and he
stood
in
the
midst of
them,
and he
said:
These
I will
make
my
rulers;
for he
stood
among
those
that
were
spirits,
and
he saw
that
they
were
good; and
he
said
unto me:
Abraham,
thou art
one of
them; thou wast chosen before thou wast born.
And
there
stood
one
among
them
that
was
like
unto
God,
and he
said
unto
those
who
were
with
him:
We
will go
down, for
there is
space
there,
and we
will
take
of
these
materials,
and
we
will make an earth whereon these may dwell;
And
we
will
prove
them
herewith,
to
see
if
they
will
do
all
things
whatsoever
the
Lord
their God shall command them;
And
they
who
keep
their
first
estate
shall
be
added
upon;
and
they
who
keep
not
their
first
estate
shall
not
have
glory
in
the
same
kingdom
with
those
who
keep
their
first
estate;
and
they
who
keep
their
second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.
And
the
Lord
said:
Whom
shall
I
send?
And
one
answered
like
unto
the
Son
of
Man:
Here
am
I,
send
me.
And
another
answered
and
said: Here am I, send me. And the Lord said: I will send the first.
28 And the second was angry, and kept not his first estate; and, at that day, many followed after him.
And
the
second
was
angry,
and
kept
not
his
first
estate; and, at that day, many followed after him.