The Book of AbrahamTranslated from the
Papyrus, by Joseph Smith A Translation of some
ancient Records that have fallen into our hands
from the catacombs of Egypt. The writings of
Abraham while he was in Egypt, called the Book
of Abraham, written by his own hand, upon
papyrus.Chapter 1 Abraham seeks the blessings
of the patriarchal order—He is persecuted by
false priests in Chaldea—Jehovah saves him—The
origins and government of Egypt are reviewed.
1 In the land of the Chaldeans, at
the residence of my fathers, I,
Abraham, saw that it was needful for me
to obtain another place of residence;
2 And, finding there was greater
happiness and peace and rest for
me, I sought for the blessings of
the fathers, and the right whereunto
I should be ordained to
administer the same; having been myself a
follower of righteousness, desiring
also to be one who possessed
great knowledge, and to be a greater
follower of righteousness, and to
possess a greater knowledge, and to
be a father of many nations, a
prince of peace, and desiring to
receive instructions, and to keep the
commandments of God, I became a
rightful heir, a High Priest,
holding the right belonging to the fathers.
3 It was conferred upon me
from the fathers; it came down
from the fathers, from the
beginning of time, yea, even from
the beginning, or before the
foundation of the earth, down to
the present time, even the
right of the firstborn, or the
first man, who is Adam, or
first father, through the fathers unto me.
4 I sought for mine
appointment unto the
Priesthood according to the
appointment of God unto the
fathers concerning the seed.
5 My fathers, having
turned from their
righteousness, and from the holy
commandments which the
Lord their God had given
unto them, unto the
worshiping of the gods of
the heathen, utterly
refused to hearken to my voice;
6 For their hearts
were set to do evil,
and were wholly turned
to the god of
Elkenah, and the god of
Libnah, and the god of
Mahmackrah, and the god
of Korash, and the
god of Pharaoh, king of Egypt;
7 Therefore they
turned their hearts to
the sacrifice of the
heathen in offering
up their children
unto these dumb
idols, and hearkened not
unto my voice, but
endeavored to take
away my life by the
hand of the priest of
Elkenah. The priest
of Elkenah was also
the priest of Pharaoh.
8 Now, at this time
it was the custom
of the priest of
Pharaoh, the king of
Egypt, to offer up
upon the altar
which was built in the
land of Chaldea,
for the offering unto
these strange
gods, men, women, and children.
9 And it came to
pass that the
priest made an
offering unto the god
of Pharaoh, and
also unto the god
of Shagreel, even
after the manner
of the
Egyptians. Now the god of
Shagreel was the sun.
10 Even the
thank-offering of a
child did the
priest of Pharaoh
offer upon the
altar which stood
by the hill
called Potiphar’s
Hill, at the head
of the plain of Olishem.
11 Now, this
priest had
offered upon this
altar three
virgins at one time,
who were the
daughters of
Onitah, one of the
royal descent
directly from
the loins of Ham.
These virgins
were offered up
because of
their virtue; they
would not bow
down to worship
gods of wood
or of stone,
therefore they
were killed upon
this altar, and
it was done
after the manner of the Egyptians.
12 And it came
to pass that
the priests
laid violence
upon me, that
they might slay
me also, as
they did those
virgins upon
this altar; and
that you may
have a
knowledge of this
altar, I will
refer you to the
representation
at the
commencement of this record.
13 It was
made after the
form of a
bedstead, such as
was had
among the
Chaldeans, and it
stood before
the gods of
Elkenah, Libnah,
Mahmackrah,
Korash, and
also a god
like unto that
of Pharaoh, king of Egypt.
14 That you
may have an
understanding of these
gods, I have
given you
the fashion of
them in the
figures at
the
beginning, which
manner of
figures is called
by the
Chaldeans
Rahleenos, which
signifies hieroglyphics.
15 And as
they lifted
up their
hands upon
me, that they
might
offer me up and
take away
my life,
behold, I
lifted up my
voice unto
the Lord my
God, and
the Lord
hearkened and
heard, and
he filled me
with the
vision of
the Almighty,
and the
angel of his
presence
stood by me,
and immediately unloosed my bands;
16 And his
voice was
unto me:
Abraham,
behold, my
name is
Jehovah, and
I have
heard thee,
and have
come down to
deliver
thee, and
to take
thee away
from thy
father’s
house, and from
all thy
kinsfolk,
into a
strange land
which thou knowest not of;
17 And
this
because they
have turned
their
hearts away
from me,
to
worship the
god of
Elkenah, and
the god
of Libnah,
and the
god of
Mahmackrah,
and the
god of
Korash, and
the god
of
Pharaoh, king
of Egypt;
therefore
I have
come down
to visit
them, and
to
destroy him
who hath
lifted up
his hand
against
thee, Abraham, my son, to take away thy life.
Behold, I
will lead
thee by
my hand,
and I
will take
thee, to
put
upon thee
my name,
even the
Priesthood of
thy
father, and
my power
shall be over thee.
19 As it
was
with Noah
so shall
it be
with thee;
but
through thy
ministry my
name shall
be known
in the
earth
forever,
for I am
thy God.
Behold,
Potiphar’s
Hill
was in
the land
of Ur,
of
Chaldea.
And the
Lord
broke
down the
altar of
Elkenah, and
of the
gods of
the
land, and
utterly
destroyed
them, and
smote
the
priest
that he
died; and
there
was
great
mourning in
Chaldea, and
also in
the
court of
Pharaoh; which Pharaoh signifies king by royal blood.
21 Now
this
king
of
Egypt was
a
descendant
from
the
loins of
Ham,
and
was a
partaker
of
the
blood of
the Canaanites by birth.
From
this
descent
sprang
all the
Egyptians, and
thus
the
blood
of
the
Canaanites
was
preserved in the land.
The
land
of
Egypt
being
first
discovered
by a
woman,
who
was
the
daughter
of
Ham,
and
the
daughter of
Egyptus,
which
in
the
Chaldean
signifies
Egypt,
which signifies that which is forbidden;
When
this
woman
discovered
the
land
it
was
under
water,
who
afterward
settled
her
sons in
it;
and
thus,
from
Ham,
sprang
that
race
which
preserved
the
curse
in
the
land.
Now
the
first
government
of
Egypt
was
established
by
Pharaoh,
the
eldest
son
of
Egyptus,
the
daughter
of
Ham,
and
it
was
after
the
manner
of the government of Ham, which was patriarchal.
Pharaoh,
being
a
righteous
man,
established
his
kingdom
and
judged
his
people
wisely
and
justly
all
his
days,
seeking
earnestly
to
imitate
that
order
established
by
the
fathers
in
the
first
generations,
in
the
days
of
the
first
patriarchal
reign,
even
in
the
reign
of
Adam,
and
also
of
Noah, his father, who blessed him with the blessings of the earth, and with the blessings of wisdom, but cursed him as pertaining to the Priesthood.
Now,
Pharaoh
being
of
that
lineage
by
which
he
could
not
have
the
right
of
Priesthood,
notwithstanding
the
Pharaohs
would
fain
claim
it
from
Noah,
through
Ham,
therefore
my
father
was
led
away
by
their
idolatry;
But
I
shall
endeavor,
hereafter,
to
delineate
the
chronology
running
back
from
myself
to
the
beginning
of
the
creation,
for
the
records
have
come
into
my
hands,
which
I
hold
unto
this
present
time.
Now,
after
the
priest
of
Elkenah
was
smitten
that
he
died,
there
came
a
fulfilment
of
those
things
which
were
said
unto
me
concerning
the
land
of
Chaldea,
that
there
should
be
a
famine
in
the
land.
30 Accordingly a famine prevailed throughout all the land of Chaldea, and my father was sorely tormented because of the famine, and he repented of the evil which he had determined against me, to take away my
Accordingly
a
famine
prevailed
throughout
all
the
land
of
Chaldea,
and
my
father
was
sorely
tormented
because of the famine, and he repented of the evil which he had determined against me, to take away my life.
31 But the records of the fathers, even the patriarchs, concerning the right of Priesthood, the Lord my God preserved in mine own hands; therefore a knowledge of the beginning of the creation, and also of the planets, and of the stars, as they were made known unto the fathers, have I kept even unto this day, and I shall endeavor to write some of these things upon this record, for the benefit of my posterity that shall come after me.
But
the
records
of
the
fathers,
even
the
patriarchs,
concerning
the
right
of
Priesthood,
the
Lord
my
God
preserved
in
mine
own
hands;
therefore
a
knowledge
of
the
beginning
of
the
creation,
and
also
of
the
planets,
and
of
the
stars,
as
they
were
made
known
unto
the
fathers,
have
I
kept
even
unto
this
day,
and
I
shall
endeavor
to
write
some
of
these
things
upon
this
record,
for
the
benefit
of
my
posterity
that
shall
come
after
me.