The Doctrine and CovenantsSection 1 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, on November 1, 1831, during a special conference
of elders of the Church, held at Hiram, Ohio. Many
revelations had been received from the Lord prior to this
time, and the compilation of these for publication in book
form was one of the principal subjects passed upon at
the conference. This section constitutes the Lord’s preface to the
doctrines, covenants, and commandments given in this dispensation.
1–7, The
voice of warning is to all people;
8–16, Apostasy and
wickedness precede the Second Coming;
17–23, Joseph Smith is called
to restore to earth the Lord’s truths and powers;
24–33,
The Book of Mormon is brought forth and the true
Church is established;
34–36, Peace will be taken from the
earth;
37–39, Search these commandments.
1 Hearken, O ye people of my church, saith the
voice of him who dwells on high, and whose eyes
are upon all men; yea, verily I say: Hearken ye
people from afar; and ye that are upon the islands
of the sea, listen together.
2 For verily the voice of the Lord is unto
all men, and there is none to escape; and there
is no eye that shall not see, neither ear that
shall not hear, neither heart that shall not be penetrated.
3 And the rebellious shall be pierced with much sorrow;
for their iniquities shall be spoken upon the housetops, and
their secret acts shall be revealed.
4 And the voice of warning shall be unto all
people, by the mouths of my disciples, whom I have
chosen in these last days.
5 And they shall go forth and none shall stay
them, for I the Lord have commanded them.
6 Behold, this is mine authority, and the authority of
my servants, and my preface unto the book of my
commandments, which I have given them to publish unto you,
O inhabitants of the earth.
7 Wherefore, fear and tremble, O ye people, for what
I the Lord have decreed in them shall be fulfilled.
8 And verily I say unto you, that they who
go forth, bearing these tidings unto the inhabitants of the
earth, to them is power given to seal both on
earth and in heaven, the unbelieving and rebellious;
9 Yea, verily, to seal them up unto the day
when the wrath of God shall be poured out upon
the wicked without measure—
10 Unto the day when the Lord shall come to
recompense unto every man according to his work, and measure
to every man according to the measure which he has
measured to his fellow man.
11 Wherefore the voice of the Lord is unto the
ends of the earth, that all that will hear may
hear:
12 Prepare ye, prepare ye for that which is to
come, for the Lord is nigh;
13 And the anger of the Lord is kindled, and
his sword is bathed in heaven, and it shall fall
upon the inhabitants of the earth.
14 And the arm of the Lord shall be revealed;
and the day cometh that they who will not hear
the voice of the Lord, neither the voice of his
servants, neither give heed to the words of the prophets
and apostles, shall be cut off from among the people;
15 For they have strayed from mine ordinances, and have
broken mine everlasting covenant;
16 They seek not the Lord to establish his righteousness,
but every man walketh in his own way, and after
the image of his own god, whose image is in
the likeness of the world, and whose substance is that
of an idol, which waxeth old and shall perish in
Babylon, even Babylon the great, which shall fall.
17 Wherefore, I the Lord, knowing the calamity which should
come upon the inhabitants of the earth, called upon my
servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and spake unto him from heaven,
and gave him commandments;
18 And also gave commandments to others, that they should
proclaim these things unto the world; and all this that
it might be fulfilled, which was written by the prophets—
19 The weak things of the world shall come forth
and break down the mighty and strong ones, that man
should not counsel his fellow man, neither trust in the
arm of flesh—
20 But that every man might speak in the name
of God the Lord, even the Savior of the world;
21 That faith also might increase in the earth;
22 That mine everlasting covenant might be established;
23 That the fulness of my gospel might be proclaimed
by the weak and the simple unto the ends of
the world, and before kings and rulers.
24 Behold, I am God and have spoken it; these
commandments are of me, and were given unto my servants
in their weakness, after the manner of their language, that
they might come to understanding.
25 And inasmuch as they erred it might be made
known;
26 And inasmuch as they sought wisdom they might be
instructed;
27 And inasmuch as they sinned they might be chastened,
that they might repent;
28 And inasmuch as they were humble they might be
made strong, and blessed from on high, and receive knowledge
from time to time.
29 And after having received the record of the Nephites,
yea, even my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., might have power
to translate through the mercy of God, by the power
of God, the Book of Mormon.
30 And also those to whom these commandments were given,
might have power to lay the foundation of this church,
and to bring it forth out of obscurity and out
of darkness, the only true and living church upon the
face of the whole earth, with which I, the Lord,
am well pleased, speaking unto the church collectively and not
individually—
31 For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with
the least degree of allowance;
32 Nevertheless, he that repents and does the commandments of
the Lord shall be forgiven;
33 And he that repents not, from him shall be
taken even the light which he has received; for my
Spirit shall not always strive with man, saith the Lord
of Hosts.
34 And again, verily I say unto you, O inhabitants
of the earth: I the Lord am willing to make
these things known unto all flesh;
35 For I am no respecter of persons, and will
that all men shall know that the day speedily cometh;
the hour is not yet, but is nigh at hand,
when peace shall be taken from the earth, and the
devil shall have power over his own dominion.
36 And also the Lord shall have power over his
saints, and shall reign in their midst, and shall come
down in judgment upon Idumea, or the world.
37 Search these commandments, for they are true and faithful,
and the prophecies and promises which are in them shall
all be fulfilled.
38 What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken,
and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and
the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away,
but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice
or by the voice of my servants, it is the
same.
39 For behold, and lo, the Lord is God, and
the Spirit beareth record, and the record is true, and
the truth abideth forever and ever. Amen.