Section 41 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to the Church, at Kirtland, Ohio,
February 4, 1831. This revelation instructs the Prophet
and Church elders to pray to receive God’s “law”
(see
section 42). Joseph Smith had just arrived
in Kirtland from New York, and Leman Copley, a
Church member in nearby Thompson, Ohio, “requested
Brother Joseph and Sidney [Rigdon] … live with him
and he would furnish them houses and provisions.”
The following revelation clarifies where Joseph and
Sidney should live and also calls Edward Partridge
to be the Church’s first bishop.
1–3, The elders
will govern the Church by the spirit of
revelation;
4–6, True disciples will receive and keep the
Lord’s law;
7–12, Edward Partridge is named as a
bishop unto the Church.
1 Hearken and hear, O ye my people, saith the Lord
and your God, ye whom I delight to bless with the
greatest of all blessings, ye that hear me; and
ye that hear me not will I curse, that have
professed my name, with the heaviest of all cursings
2 Hearken, O ye elders of my church whom I have
called, behold I give unto you a commandment, that
ye shall assemble yourselves together to agree upon
my word
3 And by the prayer of your faith ye shall receive
my law, that ye may know how to govern my church
and have all things right before me
4 And I will be your ruler when I come; and
behold, I come quickly, and ye shall see that my law is
kept
5 He that receiveth my law and doeth it, the same
is my disciple; and he that saith he receiveth it
and doeth it not, the same is not my disciple, and
shall be cast out from among you
6 For it is not meet that the things which belong
to the children of the kingdom should be given to
them that are not worthy, or to dogs, or the
pearls to be cast before swine
7 And again, it is meet that my servant Joseph
Smith, Jun., should have a house built, in which to
live and translate
8 And again, it is meet that my servant Sidney
Rigdon should live as seemeth him good, inasmuch as
he keepeth my commandments
9 And again, I have called my servant Edward
Partridge; and I give a commandment, that he should be
appointed by the voice of the church, and ordained
a bishop unto the church, to leave his
merchandise and to spend all his time in the labors of the
church
10 To see to all things as it shall be appointed
unto him in my laws in the day that I shall give
them
11 And this because his heart is pure before me,
for he is like unto Nathanael of old, in whom there
is no guile
12 These words are given unto you, and they are
pure before me; wherefore, beware how you hold them,
for they are to be answered upon your souls in
the day of judgment. Even so. Amen.