Section 113 Answers to certain questions on the
writings of Isaiah, given by Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at or near Far West, Missouri, March 1838.
1–6, The Stem of Jesse, the rod coming therefrom, and
the root of Jesse are identified;
7–10, The
scattered remnants of Zion have a right to the
priesthood and are called to return to the Lord.
1st,
2d, 3d, 4th, and 5th verses of the 11th chapter of
Isaiah?
first verse of the 11th chapter of Isaiah,
that should come of the Stem of Jesse?
10th verse
of the 11th chapter?
Isaiah, 52d chapter, 1st
verse, which saith: Put on thy strength, O Zion—and
what people had Isaiah reference to?
2d verse?
6th,
7th, and 8th verses. The bands of her neck are the
curses of God upon her, or the remnants of Israel
in their scattered condition among the Gentiles.
1 Who is the Stem of Jesse spoken of in the
2 Verily thus saith the Lord: It is Christ
3 What is the rod spoken of in the
4 Behold, thus saith the Lord: It is a servant in
the hands of Christ, who is partly a descendant of
Jesse as well as of Ephraim, or of the house of
Joseph, on whom there is laid much power
5 What is the root of Jesse spoken of in the
6 Behold, thus saith the Lord, it is a descendant
of Jesse, as well as of Joseph, unto whom rightly
belongs the priesthood, and the keys of the
kingdom, for an ensign, and for the gathering of my
people in the last days
7 Questions by Elias Higbee: What is meant by the
command in
8 He had reference to those whom God should call
in the last days, who should hold the power of
priesthood to bring again Zion, and the redemption of
Israel; and to put on her strength is to put on
the authority of the priesthood, which she, Zion,
has a right to by lineage; also to return to that
power which she had lost
9 What are we to understand by Zion loosing
herself from the bands of her neck;
10 We are to understand that the scattered
remnants are exhorted to return to the Lord from whence
they have fallen; which if they do, the promise of
the Lord is that he will speak to them, or give
them revelation. See the