Section 128 An epistle from Joseph Smith the
Prophet to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day
Saints, containing further directions on baptism
for the dead, dated at Nauvoo, Illinois, September
6, 1842.
1–5, Local and general recorders must
certify to the fact of baptisms for the dead;
6–9, Their records are binding and recorded on
earth and in heaven;
10–14, The baptismal font is a
similitude of the grave;
15–17, Elijah restored
power relative to baptism for the dead;
18–21,
All of the keys, powers, and authorities of past
dispensations have been restored;
22–25, Glad and
glorious tidings are acclaimed for the living
and the dead.
Revelation 20:12—And I saw the dead,
small and great, stand before God; and the books
were opened; and another book was opened, which
is the book of life; and the dead were judged out
of those things which were written in the books,
according to their works.
Matthew 16:18, 19: And
I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and
upon this rock I will build my church; and the
gates of hell shall not prevail against it. And I
will give unto thee the keys of the kingdom of
heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt bind on earth shall
be bound in heaven; and whatsoever thou shalt
loose on earth shall be loosed in
heaven.
1 Corinthians 15:46, 47, and 48:
1 Corinthians 15:29: Else
what shall they do which are baptized for the
dead, if the dead rise not at all? Why are they
then baptized for the dead?
last chapter, verses 5th
and 6th: Behold, I will send you Elijah the
prophet before the coming of the great and dreadful
day of the Lord: And he shall turn the heart of
the fathers to the children, and the heart of the
children to their fathers, lest I come and smite the earth with a curse.
1 As I stated to you in my letter before I left
my place, that I would write to you from time to
time and give you information in relation to
many subjects, I now resume the subject of the
baptism for the dead, as that subject seems to
occupy my mind, and press itself upon my feelings
the strongest, since I have been pursued by my enemies.
2 I wrote a few words of revelation to you
concerning a recorder. I have had a few
additional views in relation to this
matter, which I now certify. That is, it was
declared in my former letter that there
should be a recorder, who should be
eye-witness, and also to hear with his ears, that he
might make a record of a truth before the Lord.
3 Now, in relation to this matter, it
would be very difficult for one recorder
to be present at all times, and to do all
the business. To obviate this
difficulty, there can be a recorder appointed in
each ward of the city, who is well
qualified for taking accurate minutes; and
let him be very particular and precise in
taking the whole proceedings, certifying
in his record that he saw with his
eyes, and heard with his ears, giving the
date, and names, and so forth, and the
history of the whole transaction; naming
also some three individuals that are
present, if there be any present, who can at
any time when called upon certify to the
same, that in the mouth of two or three
witnesses every word may be established.
4 Then, let there be a general
recorder, to whom these other records can be
handed, being attended with certificates
over their own signatures, certifying
that the record they have made is true.
Then the general church recorder can
enter the record on the general church
book, with the certificates and all the
attending witnesses, with his own
statement that he verily believes the above
statement and records to be true, from
his knowledge of the general character
and appointment of those men by the
church. And when this is done on the
general church book, the record shall be just
as holy, and shall answer the
ordinance just the same as if he had seen with
his eyes and heard with his ears, and
made a record of the same on the general church book.
5 You may think this order of
things to be very particular; but let me
tell you that it is only to answer
the will of God, by conforming to
the ordinance and preparation that
the Lord ordained and prepared
before the foundation of the world, for
the salvation of the dead who
should die without a knowledge of the gospel.
6 And further, I want you to
remember that John the Revelator was
contemplating this very subject in
relation to the dead, when he
declared, as you will find recorded in
7 You will discover in this
quotation that the books were
opened; and another book was opened,
which was the book of life; but
the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in
the books, according to their
works; consequently, the books
spoken of must be the books which
contained the record of their
works, and refer to the records which
are kept on the earth. And the
book which was the book of life
is the record which is kept in
heaven; the principle agreeing
precisely with the doctrine which
is commanded you in the
revelation contained in the letter which
I wrote to you previous to my
leaving my place—that in all your
recordings it may be recorded in heaven.
8 Now, the nature of this
ordinance consists in the power of
the priesthood, by the
revelation of Jesus Christ, wherein
it is granted that whatsoever
you bind on earth shall be
bound in heaven, and whatsoever
you loose on earth shall be
loosed in heaven. Or, in other
words, taking a different view
of the translation, whatsoever
you record on earth shall be
recorded in heaven, and
whatsoever you do not record on earth
shall not be recorded in
heaven; for out of the books shall
your dead be judged,
according to their own works, whether
they themselves have attended
to the ordinances in their own
propria persona, or by the
means of their own agents,
according to the ordinance which
God has prepared for their
salvation from before the
foundation of the world, according to
the records which they have kept concerning their dead.
9 It may seem to some to be a
very bold doctrine that we
talk of—a power which records
or binds on earth and binds
in heaven. Nevertheless, in
all ages of the world, whenever
the Lord has given a
dispensation of the priesthood to
any man by actual revelation,
or any set of men, this power
has always been given. Hence,
whatsoever those men did in
authority, in the name of the
Lord, and did it truly and
faithfully, and kept a proper
and faithful record of the
same, it became a law on earth
and in heaven, and could not
be annulled, according to the
decrees of the great
Jehovah. This is a faithful saying. Who can hear it?
10 And again,
for the precedent,
11 Now the
great and grand
secret of the
whole matter, and
the summum bonum
of the whole
subject that is
lying before
us, consists in
obtaining the
powers of the
Holy Priesthood.
For him to whom
these keys are
given there is
no difficulty
in obtaining a
knowledge of
facts in relation
to the
salvation of the
children of men, both
as well for
the dead as for the living.
12 Herein is
glory and
honor, and
immortality and
eternal life—The
ordinance of
baptism by water,
to be immersed
therein in
order to answer
to the
likeness of the dead,
that one
principle might
accord with the
other; to be
immersed in the
water and
come forth out of
the water is
in the
likeness of the
resurrection of the
dead in
coming forth out of
their graves;
hence, this
ordinance was
instituted to
form a
relationship with the
ordinance of
baptism for the
dead, being in likeness of the dead.
Consequently, the
baptismal font was
instituted
as a
similitude of the
grave, and was
commanded to be
in a place
underneath
where the living
are wont to
assemble, to
show forth
the living and
the dead, and
that all
things may have
their
likeness, and that
they may
accord one with
another—that
which is
earthly conforming
to that which
is heavenly, as Paul hath declared,
14 Howbeit
that was not
first which
is
spiritual, but that
which is
natural; and
afterward that
which is
spiritual. The
first man is
of the
earth, earthy;
the second
man is the
Lord from
heaven. As is the
earthy,
such are they
also that are
earthy; and
as is the
heavenly,
such are they
also that are
heavenly.
And as are
the records on
the earth
in relation
to your dead,
which are
truly made
out, so also
are the
records in
heaven. This,
therefore, is
the sealing
and binding
power, and, in
one sense
of the word,
the keys of
the kingdom, which consist in the key of knowledge.
15 And now,
my dearly
beloved
brethren and
sisters, let me
assure you
that these are
principles
in relation
to the dead
and the
living that
cannot be
lightly passed
over, as
pertaining to our
salvation.
For their
salvation is
necessary and
essential to
our
salvation, as Paul
says
concerning the
fathers—that
they without us
cannot be
made
perfect—neither can
we without
our dead be
made perfect.
16 And now,
in relation
to the
baptism for the
dead, I will
give you
another
quotation of Paul,
17 And
again, in
connection with
this
quotation I will
give you a
quotation
from one of
the
prophets, who had
his eye
fixed on the
restoration
of the
priesthood, the
glories to
be
revealed in the
last days,
and in an
especial
manner this most
glorious
of all
subjects
belonging to the
everlasting
gospel,
namely, the
baptism for the dead; for Malachi says,
18 I might
have
rendered a
plainer
translation to
this, but
it is
sufficiently
plain to
suit my
purpose as it
stands. It
is
sufficient to
know, in
this case,
that the
earth will be
smitten
with a
curse unless
there is a
welding
link of some
kind or
other
between the
fathers and
the
children, upon
some subject
or
other—and behold
what is
that
subject? It is
the baptism
for the
dead. For
we without
them
cannot be made
perfect;
neither can
they
without us be
made
perfect.
Neither can they
nor we be
made
perfect
without those
who have
died in the
gospel
also; for it
is
necessary in the
ushering in
of the
dispensation
fulness of
times,
which
dispensation is
now
beginning to usher
in, that
a whole
and complete
and
perfect union,
welding together
of
dispensations,
and keys,
and powers,
and
glories should
take
place, and be
revealed
from the
days of Adam
even to
the present
time. And
not only
this, but
those
things which
never have
been
revealed from
the
foundation of the
world, but
have been
kept hid
from the
wise and prudent, shall be revealed unto babes and sucklings in this, the dispensation of the fulness of times.
19 Now,
what do we
hear in
the
gospel which
we have
received? A
voice of
gladness! A voice
of mercy
from
heaven; and
a voice
of truth
out of the
earth;
glad
tidings for
the dead; a
voice of
gladness
for the
living
and the
dead; glad
tidings of
great
joy. How
beautiful
upon the
mountains
are the
feet of
those that
bring
glad tidings
of good
things,
and that
say unto
Zion:
Behold, thy
God
reigneth! As
the dews of
Carmel,
so shall the knowledge of God descend upon them!
20 And
again,
what do we
hear?
Glad
tidings from
Cumorah!
Moroni, an
angel from
heaven,
declaring the
fulfilment
of the
prophets—the
book to be
revealed. A
voice of the
Lord in
the
wilderness
of
Fayette,
Seneca
county,
declaring the
three
witnesses
to bear
record
of the
book! The
voice
of
Michael on the
banks
of the
Susquehanna,
detecting the
devil
when he
appeared
as an
angel of
light!
The voice
of
Peter, James,
and
John in the
wilderness
between
Harmony,
Susquehanna
county,
and
Colesville,
Broome
county,
on the
Susquehanna
river,
declaring
themselves
as
possessing the keys of the kingdom, and of the dispensation of the fulness of times!
21 And
again,
the
voice of
God in
the
chamber of
old
Father
Whitmer,
in
Fayette,
Seneca
county,
and at
sundry
times,
and in
divers
places
through
all the
travels
and
tribulations of
this
Church of
Jesus
Christ
of
Latter-day
Saints!
And
the voice
of
Michael,
the
archangel;
voice of
Gabriel,
and of
Raphael, and
of
divers
angels,
from
Michael or
Adam
down to
the
present
time, all
declaring their
dispensation,
their
rights,
keys,
their
honors,
majesty
and
glory, and
the
power of
their
priesthood;
giving line
upon
line,
precept
upon
precept;
here a
little,
and
there a
little; giving us consolation by holding forth that which is to come, confirming our hope!
Brethren,
shall we
not go
on in
so
great a
cause? Go
forward
and
not
backward.
Courage,
brethren; and
on, on
to the
victory! Let
your
hearts
rejoice,
and be
exceedingly
glad. Let
the
earth
break forth
into
singing.
Let
the dead
speak
forth
anthems
of
eternal
praise to
the King
Immanuel, who
hath
ordained,
before the
world
was, that
which
would
enable
us to
redeem
them out
of
their
prison; for
the
prisoners
shall
go free.
23 Let
the
mountains
shout for
joy,
and
all ye
valleys
cry
aloud;
and
all ye
seas
and dry
lands
tell
the
wonders
of your
Eternal
King! And
ye
rivers,
and
brooks,
rills,
flow
down
with
gladness.
Let
the
woods and
all
the
trees of
field
praise
the
Lord; and
ye
solid
rocks
weep for
joy!
And let
the
sun,
moon,
and the
morning
stars sing
together,
and let
all
the
sons of
God
shout for
joy!
And
let the
eternal
creations
declare his
name
forever
and
ever!
And
again I
say,
how
glorious
is the
voice
we
hear from
heaven,
proclaiming in
our
ears,
glory,
and salvation, and honor, and immortality, and eternal life; kingdoms, principalities, and powers!
Behold,
the
great
day
of
the
Lord is
at
hand;
and
who can
abide the
day
of
his
coming,
and
who
can
stand
when he
appeareth? For
he
is
like a
refiner’s
fire,
and
like
fuller’s
soap;
and he
shall sit
as a
refiner
and
purifier of
silver,
and he
shall
purify
the
sons of
Levi,
and
purge
them
as
gold
and
silver,
that
they
may
offer
unto
the
Lord
an
offering in
righteousness.
Let
us,
therefore,
as a
church
and
a
people,
and
as
Latter-day
Saints,
offer
unto the
Lord
an
offering in
righteousness;
and
let
us
present
in
his
holy
temple, when it is finished, a book containing the records of our dead, which shall be worthy of all acceptation.
Brethren,
I
have
many
things
to
say
you on
the
subject;
but
shall
now
close
for
the
present,
and
continue
the
subject
another
time. I
am,
as
ever,
your
humble
servant and never deviating friend,Joseph Smith.