Section 57 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, in Zion, Jackson County, Missouri,
July 20, 1831. In compliance with the Lord’s
command to travel to Missouri, where He would reveal
“the land of your inheritance” (
section 52), the
elders had journeyed from Ohio to Missouri’s
western border. Joseph Smith contemplated the state
of the Lamanites and wondered: “When will the
wilderness blossom as the rose? When will Zion be
built up in her glory, and where will Thy temple
stand, unto which all nations shall come in the last
days?” Subsequently he received this revelation.
1–3, Independence, Missouri, is the place for
the City of Zion and the temple;
4–7, The Saints
are to purchase lands and receive inheritances in
that area;
8–16, Sidney Gilbert is to establish
a store, William W. Phelps is to be a printer,
and Oliver Cowdery is to edit material for publication.
1 Hearken, O ye elders of my church, saith
the Lord your God, who have assembled
yourselves together, according to my commandments,
in this land, which is the land of Missouri,
which is the land which I have appointed
and consecrated for the gathering of the saints.
2 Wherefore, this is the land of
promise, and the place for the city of Zion.
3 And thus saith the Lord your
God, if you will receive wisdom here
is wisdom. Behold, the place which
is now called Independence is the
center place; and a spot for the
temple is lying westward, upon a
lot which is not far from the courthouse.
4 Wherefore, it is wisdom
that the land should be
purchased by the saints, and also
every tract lying westward,
even unto the line running
directly between Jew and Gentile;
5 And also every tract
bordering by the prairies,
inasmuch as my disciples
are enabled to buy lands.
Behold, this is wisdom,
that they may obtain it
for an everlasting inheritance.
6 And let my servant
Sidney Gilbert stand in
the office to which I
have appointed him,
to receive moneys, to
be an agent unto the
church, to buy land in
all the regions round
about, inasmuch as can
be done in
righteousness, and as wisdom shall direct.
7 And let my servant
Edward Partridge
stand in the office to
which I have appointed
him, and divide unto
the saints their
inheritance, even as I
have commanded; and
also those whom he has
appointed to assist him.
8 And again, verily
I say unto you, let
my servant Sidney
Gilbert plant himself
in this place, and
establish a store,
that he may sell goods
without fraud, that
he may obtain money
to buy lands for
the good of the
saints, and that he may
obtain whatsoever
things the disciples may
need to plant them
in their inheritance.
9 And also let my
servant Sidney
Gilbert obtain a
license—behold here is
wisdom, and whoso
readeth let him
understand—that he may
send goods also unto
the people, even by
whom he will as
clerks employed in his service;
10 And thus
provide for my
saints, that my
gospel may be
preached unto those who
sit in darkness
and in the
region and shadow of death.
11 And again,
verily I say unto
you, let my
servant William W.
Phelps be planted
in this place,
and be
established as a printer
unto the church.
12 And lo, if
the world
receive his
writings—behold here is
wisdom—let him
obtain
whatsoever he can
obtain in
righteousness, for the
good of the saints.
13 And let my
servant Oliver
Cowdery
assist him, even as
I have
commanded, in
whatsoever place I
shall appoint
unto him, to
copy, and to
correct, and
select, that all
things may be
right before
me, as it shall
be proved by
the Spirit through him.
14 And thus
let those of
whom I have
spoken be
planted in the
land of Zion, as
speedily as
can be, with
their
families, to do
those things even
as I have spoken.
15 And now
concerning
the
gathering—Let the
bishop and the
agent make
preparations
for those
families which
have been
commanded to
come to this
land, as
soon as
possible, and plant
them in their inheritance.
16 And unto
the
residue of both
elders and
members
further
directions shall
be given
hereafter.
Even so. Amen.