Section 7 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Oliver Cowdery, at Harmony,
Pennsylvania, April 1829, when they inquired through the
Urim and Thummim as to whether John, the beloved
disciple, tarried in the flesh or had died. The
revelation is a translated version of the record made
on parchment by John and hidden up by himself.
1–3, John the Beloved will live until the Lord
comes;
4–8, Peter, James, and John hold gospel keys.
1 And the Lord said unto me: John, my
beloved, what desirest thou? For if you shall ask
what you will, it shall be granted unto you.
2 And I said unto him: Lord, give
unto me power over death, that I
may live and bring souls unto thee.
3 And the Lord said unto me:
Verily, verily, I say unto thee,
because thou desirest this thou
shalt tarry until I come in my
glory, and shalt prophesy before
nations, kindreds, tongues and people.
4 And for this cause the Lord
said unto Peter: If I will
that he tarry till I come,
what is that to thee? For he
desired of me that he might
bring souls unto me, but thou
desiredst that thou mightest
speedily come unto me in my kingdom.
5 I say unto thee, Peter,
this was a good desire;
but my beloved has desired
that he might do more, or a
greater work yet among
men than what he has before done.
6 Yea, he has
undertaken a greater work;
therefore I will make him as
flaming fire and a
ministering angel; he
shall minister for those
who shall be heirs of
salvation who dwell on the earth.
7 And I will make thee
to minister for him
and for thy brother
James; and unto you three
I will give this
power and the keys of this
ministry until I come.
8 Verily I say unto
you, ye shall both
have according to
your desires, for
ye both joy in that
which ye have desired.