Section 59 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, in Zion, Jackson County, Missouri,
August 7, 1831. Preceding this revelation, the land
was consecrated, as the Lord had directed, and the
site for the future temple was dedicated. On the
day this revelation was received, Polly Knight, the
wife of Joseph Knight Sr., died, the first Church
member to die in Zion. Early members
characterized this revelation as “instructing the Saints how
to keep the sabbath and how to fast and pray.”
1–4, The faithful Saints in Zion will be blessed;
5–8, They are to love and serve the Lord and keep
His commandments;
9–19, By keeping the Lord’s day
holy, the Saints are blessed temporally and
spiritually;
20–24, The righteous are promised peace in
this world and eternal life in the world to come.
1 Behold, blessed, saith the Lord, are they
who have come up unto this land with an eye
single to my glory, according to my commandments.
2 For those that live shall inherit
the earth, and those that die shall
rest from all their labors, and their
works shall follow them; and they
shall receive a crown in the mansions of
my Father, which I have prepared for them.
3 Yea, blessed are they whose
feet stand upon the land of Zion,
who have obeyed my gospel; for they
shall receive for their reward
the good things of the earth, and
it shall bring forth in its strength.
4 And they shall also be
crowned with blessings from
above, yea, and with commandments
not a few, and with
revelations in their time—they that
are faithful and diligent before me.
5 Wherefore, I give unto
them a commandment,
saying thus: Thou shalt love
the Lord thy God with all
thy heart, with all thy
might, mind, and strength;
and in the name of Jesus
Christ thou shalt serve him.
6 Thou shalt love thy
neighbor as thyself.
Thou shalt not
steal; neither commit
adultery, nor kill, nor
do anything like unto it.
7 Thou shalt
thank the Lord thy
God in all things.
8 Thou shalt
offer a sacrifice
unto the Lord
thy God in
righteousness, even
that of a
broken heart and a
contrite spirit.
9 And that
thou mayest more
fully keep
thyself unspotted
from the
world, thou shalt
go to the
house of prayer
and offer up thy
sacraments
upon my holy day;
10 For verily
this is a
day appointed
unto you to
rest from your
labors, and
to pay thy
devotions unto
the Most High;
Nevertheless thy vows
shall be
offered up in
righteousness on
all days and
at all times;
12 But
remember that on
this, the
Lord’s day,
thou shalt
offer thine
oblations and
thy
sacraments unto the
Most High,
confessing thy
sins unto
thy brethren,
and before the Lord.
13 And on
this day
thou shalt do
none other
thing, only
let thy
food be
prepared with
singleness of
heart that
thy
fasting may be
perfect, or,
in other
words, that
thy joy may be full.
Verily, this is
fasting
and
prayer, or in
other
words,
rejoicing and prayer.
15 And
inasmuch
as ye do
these
things
with
thanksgiving,
cheerful
hearts
and
countenances,
not with
much
laughter,
for this
is sin,
but
with a glad
heart
and a cheerful countenance—
Verily I
say, that
inasmuch as
ye do
this, the
fulness of
the earth
is
yours, the
beasts
of the
field
and the
fowls
of the
air,
and that
which
climbeth
upon
the
trees and walketh upon the earth;
Yea, and
the
herb,
and the
good
things
which
come
of the
earth,
whether for
food
or for
raiment, or
for
houses,
or
for
barns, or
orchards, or
for gardens, or for vineyards;
Yea,
all
things
which
come
of
the
earth,
in the
season
thereof, are
made
for
the
benefit and
use
of
man,
both to
please the
eye and to gladden the heart;
Yea,
for
food
and
for
raiment,
taste
and
for
smell,
to
strengthen
the
body
and to enliven the soul.
And
it
pleaseth
God
that
he
hath
given
all
these
things
unto
man;
for
unto
this
end
were
they
made
to
be
used,
with
judgment, not to excess, neither by extortion.
And
in
nothing
doth
man
offend
God,
or
against
none
is
his
wrath
kindled,
save
those
who
confess
not
his hand in all things, and obey not his commandments.
22 Behold, this is according to the law and the prophets; wherefore, trouble me no more concerning this
Behold,
this
is
according
prophets; wherefore, trouble me no more concerning this matter.
23 But learn that he who doeth the works of righteousness shall receive his reward, even peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to
But
learn
that
he
who
doeth
the
works
of
righteousness
shall
receive
his
reward,
even
peace
in
this
world,
and
eternal
life
in
the
world
to
come.
24 I, the Lord, have spoken it, and the Spirit beareth record. Amen.
I,
the
Lord,
have
spoken
it,
and
the
Spirit
beareth
record.
Amen.