Section 123 Duty of the Saints in relation to
their persecutors, as written by Joseph Smith the
Prophet while a prisoner in the jail at Liberty,
Missouri. This section is an excerpt from an epistle to
the Church dated March 20, 1839 (see the
heading
to section 121).
1–6, The Saints should collect
and publish an account of their sufferings and
persecutions;
7–10, The same spirit that established
the false creeds also leads to persecution of the
Saints;
11–17, Many among all sects will yet
receive the truth.
1 And again, we would suggest for your
consideration the propriety of all the saints gathering up a
knowledge of all the facts, and sufferings and
abuses put upon them by the people of this State
2 And also of all the property and amount of
damages which they have sustained, both of character
and personal injuries, as well as real property
3 And also the names of all persons that have had
a hand in their oppressions, as far as they can
get hold of them and find them out
4 And perhaps a committee can be appointed to find
out these things, and to take statements and
affidavits; and also to gather up the libelous
publications that are afloat
5 And all that are in the magazines, and in the
encyclopedias, and all the libelous histories that
are published, and are writing, and by whom, and
present the whole concatenation of diabolical
rascality and nefarious and murderous impositions that
have been practiced upon this people
6 That we may not only publish to all the world,
but present them to the heads of government in all
their dark and hellish hue, as the last effort
which is enjoined on us by our Heavenly Father,
before we can fully and completely claim that promise
which shall call him forth from his hiding place;
and also that the whole nation may be left without
excuse before he can send forth the power of his
mighty arm
7 It is an imperative duty that we owe to God, to
angels, with whom we shall be brought to stand,
and also to ourselves, to our wives and children,
who have been made to bow down with grief, sorrow,
and care, under the most damning hand of murder,
tyranny, and oppression, supported and urged on and
upheld by the influence of that spirit which hath
so strongly riveted the creeds of the fathers, who
have inherited lies, upon the hearts of the
children, and filled the world with confusion, and has
been growing stronger and stronger, and is now the
very mainspring of all corruption, and the whole
earth groans under the weight of its iniquity
8 It is an iron yoke, it is a strong band; they
are the very handcuffs, and chains, and shackles,
and fetters of hell
9 Therefore it is an imperative duty that we owe,
not only to our own wives and children, but to the
widows and fatherless, whose husbands and fathers
have been murdered under its iron hand
10 Which dark and blackening deeds are enough to
make hell itself shudder, and to stand aghast and
pale, and the hands of the very devil to tremble
and palsy
11 And also it is an imperative duty that we owe
to all the rising generation, and to all the pure
in heart
12 For there are many yet on the earth among all
sects, parties, and denominations, who are blinded
by the subtle craftiness of men, whereby they lie
in wait to deceive, and who are only kept from the
truth because they know not where to find it
13 Therefore, that we should waste and wear out
our lives in bringing to light all the hidden things
of darkness, wherein we know them; and they are
truly manifest from heaven
14 These should then be attended to with great
earnestness
15 Let no man count them as small things; for
there is much which lieth in futurity, pertaining to
the saints, which depends upon these things
16 You know, brethren, that a very large ship is
benefited very much by a very small helm in the
time of a storm, by being kept workways with the wind
and the waves
17 Therefore, dearly beloved brethren, let us
cheerfully do all things that lie in our power; and
then may we stand still, with the utmost assurance,
to see the salvation of God, and for his arm to be
revealed.