Section 96 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, showing the order of the city or
stake of Zion at Kirtland, Ohio, June 4, 1833, as
an example to the Saints in Kirtland. The
occasion was a conference of high priests, and the
chief subject of consideration was the disposal
of certain lands, known as the French farm,
possessed by the Church near Kirtland. Since the
conference could not agree who should take charge
of the farm, all agreed to inquire of the Lord
concerning the matter.
1, The Kirtland Stake
of Zion is to be made strong;
2–5, The bishop
is to divide the inheritances for the Saints;
6–9, John Johnson is to be a member of the united order.
1 Behold, I say unto you, here is
wisdom, whereby ye may know how to act
concerning this matter, for it is expedient in
me that this stake that I have set for
the strength of Zion should be made strong.
2 Therefore, let my servant
Newel K. Whitney take charge of the place
which is named among you, upon
which I design to build mine holy house.
3 And again, let it be divided
into lots, according to wisdom,
for the benefit of those who
seek inheritances, as it shall
be determined in council among you.
4 Therefore, take heed that
ye see to this matter, and
that portion that is necessary
to benefit mine order, for the
purpose of bringing forth my
word to the children of men.
5 For behold, verily I say
unto you, this is the most
expedient in me, that my
word should go forth unto the
children of men, for the
purpose of subduing the
hearts of the children of men
for your good. Even so. Amen.
6 And again, verily I say
unto you, it is wisdom and
expedient in me, that my
servant John Johnson whose
offering I have accepted,
and whose prayers I have
heard, unto whom I give a
promise of eternal life
inasmuch as he keepeth my
commandments from henceforth—
7 For he is a descendant
of Joseph and a partaker of
the blessings of the
promise made unto his fathers—
8 Verily I say unto
you, it is expedient in me
that he should become
a member of the order,
that he may assist in
bringing forth my word
unto the children of men.
9 Therefore ye shall
ordain him unto this
blessing, and he
shall seek diligently to
take away
incumbrances that are upon the
house named among you,
that he may dwell
therein. Even so. Amen.