Section 20 Revelation on Church organization and
government, given through Joseph Smith the Prophet,
at or near Fayette, New York. Portions of this
revelation may have been given as early as summer
1829. The complete revelation, known at the time as
the Articles and Covenants, was likely recorded
soon after April 6, 1830 (the day the Church was
organized). The Prophet wrote, “We obtained of Him
[Jesus Christ] the following, by the spirit of
prophecy and revelation; which not only gave us much
information, but also pointed out to us the precise
day upon which, according to His will and
commandment, we should proceed to organize His Church once
more here upon the earth.”
1–16, The Book of
Mormon proves the divinity of the latter-day work;
17–28, The doctrines of creation, fall, atonement,
and baptism are affirmed;
29–37, Laws governing
repentance, justification, sanctification, and
baptism are set forth;
38–67, Duties of elders,
priests, teachers, and deacons are summarized;
68–74,
Duties of members, blessing of children, and the
mode of baptism are revealed;
75–84, Sacramental
prayers and regulations governing Church membership
are given.
1 The rise of the Church of Christ in these last
days, being one thousand eight hundred and thirty
years since the coming of our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ in the flesh, it being regularly organized
and established agreeable to the laws of our
country, by the will and commandments of God, in the
fourth month, and on the sixth day of the month
which is called April
2 Which commandments were given to Joseph Smith,
Jun., who was called of God, and ordained an
apostle of Jesus Christ, to be the first elder of this
church
3 And to Oliver Cowdery, who was also called of
God, an apostle of Jesus Christ, to be the second
elder of this church, and ordained under his hand
4 And this according to the grace of our Lord and
Savior Jesus Christ, to whom be all glory, both
now and forever. Amen
5 After it was truly manifested unto this first
elder that he had received a remission of his sins,
he was entangled again in the vanities of the
world
6 But after repenting, and humbling himself
sincerely, through faith, God ministered unto him by an
holy angel, whose countenance was as lightning,
and whose garments were pure and white above all
other whiteness
7 And gave unto him commandments which inspired
him
8 And gave him power from on high, by the means
which were before prepared, to translate the Book of
Mormon
9 Which contains a record of a fallen people, and
the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ to the
Gentiles and to the Jews also
10 Which was given by inspiration, and is
confirmed to others by the ministering of angels, and is
declared unto the world by them
11 Proving to the world that the holy scriptures
are true, and that God does inspire men and call
them to his holy work in this age and generation, as
well as in generations of old
12 Thereby showing that he is the same God
yesterday, today, and forever. Amen
13 Therefore, having so great witnesses, by them
shall the world be judged, even as many as shall
hereafter come to a knowledge of this work
14 And those who receive it in faith, and work
righteousness, shall receive a crown of eternal life
15 But those who harden their hearts in unbelief,
and reject it, it shall turn to their own
condemnation
16 For the Lord God has spoken it; and we, the
elders of the church, have heard and bear witness to
the words of the glorious Majesty on high, to whom
be glory forever and ever. Amen
17 By these things we know that there is a God in
heaven, who is infinite and eternal, from
everlasting to everlasting the same unchangeable God, the
framer of heaven and earth, and all things which
are in them
18 And that he created man, male and female, after
his own image and in his own likeness, created he
them
19 And gave unto them commandments that they
should love and serve him, the only living and true
God, and that he should be the only being whom they
should worship
20 But by the transgression of these holy laws man
became sensual and devilish, and became fallen
man
21 Wherefore, the Almighty God gave his Only
Begotten Son, as it is written in those scriptures
which have been given of him
22 He suffered temptations but gave no heed unto
them
23 He was crucified, died, and rose again the
third day
24 And ascended into heaven, to sit down on the
right hand of the Father, to reign with almighty
power according to the will of the Father
25 That as many as would believe and be baptized
in his holy name, and endure in faith to the end,
should be saved
26 Not only those who believed after he came in
the meridian of time, in the flesh, but all those
from the beginning, even as many as were before he
came, who believed in the words of the holy
prophets, who spake as they were inspired by the gift of
the Holy Ghost, who truly testified of him in all
things, should have eternal life
27 As well as those who should come after, who
should believe in the gifts and callings of God by
the Holy Ghost, which beareth record of the Father
and of the Son
28 Which Father, Son, and Holy Ghost are one God,
infinite and eternal, without end. Amen
29 And we know that all men must repent and
believe on the name of Jesus Christ, and worship the
Father in his name, and endure in faith on his name
to the end, or they cannot be saved in the kingdom
of God
30 And we know that justification through the
grace of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ is just and
true
31 And we know also, that sanctification through
the grace of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ is
just and true, to all those who love and serve God
with all their mights, minds, and strength
32 But there is a possibility that man may fall
from grace and depart from the living God
33 Therefore let the church take heed and pray
always, lest they fall into temptation
34 Yea, and even let those who are sanctified take
heed also
35 And we know that these things are true and
according to the revelations of John, neither adding
to, nor diminishing from the prophecy of his book,
the holy scriptures, or the revelations of God
which shall come hereafter by the gift and power of
the Holy Ghost, the voice of God, or the
ministering of angels
36 And the Lord God has spoken it; and honor,
power and glory be rendered to his holy name, both now
and ever. Amen
37 And again, by way of commandment to the church
concerning the manner of baptism—All those who
humble themselves before God, and desire to be
baptized, and come forth with broken hearts and contrite
spirits, and witness before the church that they
have truly repented of all their sins, and are
willing to take upon them the name of Jesus Christ,
having a determination to serve him to the end, and
truly manifest by their works that they have
received of the Spirit of Christ unto the remission of
their sins, shall be received by baptism into his
church
38 The duty of the elders, priests, teachers,
deacons, and members of the church of Christ—An
apostle is an elder, and it is his calling to baptize
39 And to ordain other elders, priests, teachers,
and deacons
40 And to administer bread and wine—the emblems of
the flesh and blood of Christ
41 And to confirm those who are baptized into the
church, by the laying on of hands for the baptism
of fire and the Holy Ghost, according to the
scriptures
42 And to teach, expound, exhort, baptize, and
watch over the church
43 And to confirm the church by the laying on of
the hands, and the giving of the Holy Ghost
44 And to take the lead of all meetings
45 The elders are to conduct the meetings as they
are led by the Holy Ghost, according to the
commandments and revelations of God
46 The priest’s duty is to preach, teach, expound,
exhort, and baptize, and administer the
sacrament
47 And visit the house of each member, and exhort
them to pray vocally and in secret and attend to
all family duties
48 And he may also ordain other priests, teachers,
and deacons
49 And he is to take the lead of meetings when
there is no elder present
50 But when there is an elder present, he is only
to preach, teach, expound, exhort, and baptize
51 And visit the house of each member, exhorting
them to pray vocally and in secret and attend to
all family duties
52 In all these duties the priest is to assist the
elder if occasion requires
53 The teacher’s duty is to watch over the church
always, and be with and strengthen them
54 And see that there is no iniquity in the
church, neither hardness with each other, neither lying,
backbiting, nor evil speaking
55 And see that the church meet together often,
and also see that all the members do their duty
56 And he is to take the lead of meetings in the
absence of the elder or priest
57 And is to be assisted always, in all his duties
in the church, by the deacons, if occasion
requires
58 But neither teachers nor deacons have authority
to baptize, administer the sacrament, or lay on
hands
59 They are, however, to warn, expound, exhort,
and teach, and invite all to come unto Christ
60 Every elder, priest, teacher, or deacon is to
be ordained according to the gifts and callings of
God unto him; and he is to be ordained by the
power of the Holy Ghost, which is in the one who
ordains him
61 The several elders composing this church of
Christ are to meet in conference once in three
months, or from time to time as said conferences shall
direct or appoint
62 And said conferences are to do whatever church
business is necessary to be done at the time
63 The elders are to receive their licenses from
other elders, by vote of the church to which they
belong, or from the conferences
64 Each priest, teacher, or deacon, who is
ordained by a priest, may take a certificate from him at
the time, which certificate, when presented to an
elder, shall entitle him to a license, which shall
authorize him to perform the duties of his
calling, or he may receive it from a conference
65 No person is to be ordained to any office in
this church, where there is a regularly organized
branch of the same, without the vote of that church
66 But the presiding elders, traveling bishops,
high councilors, high priests, and elders, may have
the privilege of ordaining, where there is no
branch of the church that a vote may be called
67 Every president of the high priesthood (or
presiding elder), bishop, high councilor, and high
priest, is to be ordained by the direction of a high
council or general conference
68 The duty of the members after they are received
by baptism—The elders or priests are to have a
sufficient time to expound all things concerning the
church of Christ to their understanding, previous
to their partaking of the sacrament and being
confirmed by the laying on of the hands of the
elders, so that all things may be done in order
69 And the members shall manifest before the
church, and also before the elders, by a godly walk and
conversation, that they are worthy of it, that
there may be works and faith agreeable to the holy
scriptures—walking in holiness before the Lord
70 Every member of the church of Christ having
children is to bring them unto the elders before the
church, who are to lay their hands upon them in
the name of Jesus Christ, and bless them in his
name
71 No one can be received into the church of
Christ unless he has arrived unto the years of
accountability before God, and is capable of repentance
72 Baptism is to be administered in the following
manner unto all those who repent
73 The person who is called of God and has
authority from Jesus Christ to baptize, shall go down
into the water with the person who has presented
himself or herself for baptism, and shall say, calling
him or her by name: Having been commissioned of
Jesus Christ, I baptize you in the name of the
Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost. Amen
74 Then shall he immerse him or her in the water,
and come forth again out of the water
75 It is expedient that the church meet together
often to partake of bread and wine in the
remembrance of the Lord Jesus
76 And the elder or priest shall administer it;
and after this manner shall he administer it—he
shall kneel with the church and call upon the Father
in solemn prayer, saying
77 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the
name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and
sanctify this bread to the souls of all those who partake
of it, that they may eat in remembrance of the
body of thy Son, and witness unto thee, O God, the
Eternal Father, that they are willing to take upon
them the name of thy Son, and always remember him
and keep his commandments which he has given them;
that they may always have his Spirit to be with
them. Amen
78 The manner of administering the wine—he shall
take the cup also, and say
79 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the
name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and
sanctify this wine to the souls of all those who drink of
it, that they may do it in remembrance of the
blood of thy Son, which was shed for them; that they
may witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father,
that they do always remember him, that they may
have his Spirit to be with them. Amen
80 Any member of the church of Christ
transgressing, or being overtaken in a fault, shall be dealt
with as the scriptures direct
81 It shall be the duty of the several churches,
composing the church of Christ, to send one or more
of their teachers to attend the several
conferences held by the elders of the church
82 With a list of the names of the several members
uniting themselves with the church since the last
conference; or send by the hand of some priest;
so that a regular list of all the names of the
whole church may be kept in a book by one of the
elders, whomsoever the other elders shall appoint from
time to time
83 And also, if any have been expelled from the
church, so that their names may be blotted out of
the general church record of names
84 All members removing from the church where they
reside, if going to a church where they are not
known, may take a letter certifying that they are
regular members and in good standing, which
certificate may be signed by any elder or priest if the
member receiving the letter is personally
acquainted with the elder or priest, or it may be signed by
the teachers or deacons of the church.