verses 60 through 100 incorporate a revelation
given through Joseph Smith on November 11, 1831. This
section was associated with the organization of
the Quorum of the Twelve in February and March
1835. The Prophet likely delivered it in the presence
of those who were preparing to depart May 3, 1835,
on their first quorum mission.
1–6, There are
two priesthoods: the Melchizedek and the Aaronic;
7–12, Those who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood
have power to officiate in all offices in the Church;
13–17, The bishopric presides over the Aaronic
Priesthood, which administers in outward
ordinances;
18–20, The Melchizedek Priesthood holds the
keys of all spiritual blessings; the Aaronic
Priesthood holds the keys of the ministering of angels;
21–38, The First Presidency, the Twelve, and the
Seventy constitute the presiding quorums, whose
decisions are to be made in unity and righteousness;
39–52, The patriarchal order is established from
Adam to Noah;
53–57, Ancient Saints assembled at
Adam-ondi-Ahman, and the Lord appeared to them;
58–67, The Twelve are to set the officers of the
Church in order;
68–76, Bishops serve as common
judges in Israel;
77–84, The First Presidency and the
Twelve constitute the highest court in the
Church;
85–100, Priesthood presidents govern their
respective quorums.
1 There are, in the church, two priesthoods,
namely, the Melchizedek and Aaronic, including the
Levitical Priesthood
2 Why the first is called the Melchizedek
Priesthood is because Melchizedek was such a great high
priest
3 Before his day it was called the Holy
Priesthood, after the Order of the Son of God
4 But out of respect or reverence to the name of
the Supreme Being, to avoid the too frequent
repetition of his name, they, the church, in ancient
days, called that priesthood after Melchizedek, or
the Melchizedek Priesthood
5 All other authorities or offices in the church
are appendages to this priesthood
6 But there are two divisions or grand heads—one
is the Melchizedek Priesthood, and the other is the
Aaronic or Levitical Priesthood
7 The office of an elder comes under the
priesthood of Melchizedek
8 The Melchizedek Priesthood holds the right of
presidency, and has power and authority over all the
offices in the church in all ages of the world,
to administer in spiritual things
9 The Presidency of the High Priesthood, after the
order of Melchizedek, have a right to officiate
in all the offices in the church
10 High priests after the order of the Melchizedek
Priesthood have a right to officiate in their own
standing, under the direction of the presidency,
in administering spiritual things, and also in the
office of an elder, priest (of the Levitical
order), teacher, deacon, and member
11 An elder has a right to officiate in his stead
when the high priest is not present
12 The high priest and elder are to administer in
spiritual things, agreeable to the covenants and
commandments of the church; and they have a right
to officiate in all these offices of the church
when there are no higher authorities present
13 The second priesthood is called the Priesthood
of Aaron, because it was conferred upon Aaron and
his seed, throughout all their generations
14 Why it is called the lesser priesthood is
because it is an appendage to the greater, or the
Melchizedek Priesthood, and has power in administering
outward ordinances
15 The bishopric is the presidency of this
priesthood, and holds the keys or authority of the same
16 No man has a legal right to this office, to
hold the keys of this priesthood, except he be a
literal descendant of Aaron
17 But as a high priest of the Melchizedek
Priesthood has authority to officiate in all the lesser
offices, he may officiate in the office of bishop
when no literal descendant of Aaron can be found,
provided he is called and set apart and ordained
unto this power by the hands of the Presidency of
the Melchizedek Priesthood
18 The power and authority of the higher, or
Melchizedek Priesthood, is to hold the keys of all the
spiritual blessings of the church
19 To have the privilege of receiving the
mysteries of the kingdom of heaven, to have the heavens
opened unto them, to commune with the general
assembly and church of the Firstborn, and to enjoy the
communion and presence of God the Father, and Jesus
the mediator of the new covenant
20 The power and authority of the lesser, or
Aaronic Priesthood, is to hold the keys of the
ministering of angels, and to administer in outward
ordinances, the letter of the gospel, the baptism of
repentance for the remission of sins, agreeable to
the covenants and commandments
21 Of necessity there are presidents, or presiding
officers growing out of, or appointed of or from
among those who are ordained to the several
offices in these two priesthoods
22 Of the Melchizedek Priesthood, three Presiding
High Priests, chosen by the body, appointed and
ordained to that office, and upheld by the
confidence, faith, and prayer of the church, form a quorum
of the Presidency of the Church
23 The twelve traveling councilors are called to
be the Twelve Apostles, or special witnesses of the
name of Christ in all the world—thus differing
from other officers in the church in the duties of
their calling
24 And they form a quorum, equal in authority and
power to the three presidents previously
mentioned
25 The Seventy are also called to preach the
gospel, and to be especial witnesses unto the Gentiles
and in all the world—thus differing from other
officers in the church in the duties of their
calling
26 And they form a quorum, equal in authority to
that of the Twelve special witnesses or Apostles
just named
27 And every decision made by either of these
quorums must be by the unanimous voice of the same;
that is, every member in each quorum must be agreed
to its decisions, in order to make their decisions
of the same power or validity one with the other
28 A majority may form a quorum when circumstances
render it impossible to be otherwise
29 Unless this is the case, their decisions are
not entitled to the same blessings which the
decisions of a quorum of three presidents were anciently,
who were ordained after the order of Melchizedek,
and were righteous and holy men
30 The decisions of these quorums, or either of
them, are to be made in all righteousness, in
holiness, and lowliness of heart, meekness and
long-suffering, and in faith, and virtue, and knowledge,
temperance, patience, godliness, brotherly kindness
and charity
31 Because the promise is, if these things abound
in them they shall not be unfruitful in the
knowledge of the Lord
32 And in case that any decision of these quorums
is made in unrighteousness, it may be brought
before a general assembly of the several quorums,
which constitute the spiritual authorities of the
church; otherwise there can be no appeal from their
decision
33 The Twelve are a Traveling Presiding High
Council, to officiate in the name of the Lord, under
the direction of the Presidency of the Church,
agreeable to the institution of heaven; to build up the
church, and regulate all the affairs of the same
in all nations, first unto the Gentiles and
secondly unto the Jews
34 The Seventy are to act in the name of the Lord,
under the direction of the Twelve or the
traveling high council, in building up the church and
regulating all the affairs of the same in all nations,
first unto the Gentiles and then to the Jews
35 The Twelve being sent out, holding the keys, to
open the door by the proclamation of the gospel
of Jesus Christ, and first unto the Gentiles and
then unto the Jews
36 The standing high councils, at the stakes of
Zion, form a quorum equal in authority in the
affairs of the church, in all their decisions, to the
quorum of the presidency, or to the traveling high
council
37 The high council in Zion form a quorum equal in
authority in the affairs of the church, in all
their decisions, to the councils of the Twelve at
the stakes of Zion
38 It is the duty of the traveling high council to
call upon the Seventy, when they need assistance,
to fill the several calls for preaching and
administering the gospel, instead of any others
39 It is the duty of the Twelve, in all large
branches of the church, to ordain evangelical
ministers, as they shall be designated unto them by
revelation
40 The order of this priesthood was confirmed to
be handed down from father to son, and rightly
belongs to the literal descendants of the chosen seed,
to whom the promises were made
41 This order was instituted in the days of Adam,
and came down by lineage in the following manner
42 From Adam to Seth, who was ordained by Adam at
the age of sixty-nine years, and was blessed by
him three years previous to his (Adam’s) death, and
received the promise of God by his father, that
his posterity should be the chosen of the Lord, and
that they should be preserved unto the end of the
earth
43 Because he (Seth) was a perfect man, and his
likeness was the express likeness of his father,
insomuch that he seemed to be like unto his father in
all things, and could be distinguished from him
only by his age
44 Enos was ordained at the age of one hundred and
thirty-four years and four months, by the hand of
Adam
45 God called upon Cainan in the wilderness in the
fortieth year of his age; and he met Adam in
journeying to the place Shedolamak. He was
eighty-seven years old when he received his ordination
46 Mahalaleel was four hundred and ninety-six
years and seven days old when he was ordained by the
hand of Adam, who also blessed him
47 Jared was two hundred years old when he was
ordained under the hand of Adam, who also blessed
him
48 Enoch was twenty-five years old when he was
ordained under the hand of Adam; and he was
sixty-five and Adam blessed him
49 And he saw the Lord, and he walked with him,
and was before his face continually; and he walked
with God three hundred and sixty-five years, making
him four hundred and thirty years old when he was
translated
50 Methuselah was one hundred years old when he
was ordained under the hand of Adam
51 Lamech was thirty-two years old when he was
ordained under the hand of Seth
52 Noah was ten years old when he was ordained
under the hand of Methuselah
53 Three years previous to the death of Adam, he
called Seth, Enos, Cainan, Mahalaleel, Jared,
Enoch, and Methuselah, who were all high priests, with
the residue of his posterity who were righteous,
into the valley of Adam-ondi-Ahman, and there
bestowed upon them his last blessing
54 And the Lord appeared unto them, and they rose
up and blessed Adam, and called him Michael, the
prince, the archangel
55 And the Lord administered comfort unto Adam,
and said unto him: I have set thee to be at the
head; a multitude of nations shall come of thee, and
thou art a prince over them forever
56 And Adam stood up in the midst of the
congregation; and, notwithstanding he was bowed down with
age, being full of the Holy Ghost, predicted
whatsoever should befall his posterity unto the latest
generation
57 These things were all written in the book of
Enoch, and are to be testified of in due time
58 It is the duty of the Twelve, also, to ordain
and set in order all the other officers of the
church, agreeable to the revelation which says
59 To the church of Christ in the land of Zion, in
addition to the church laws respecting church
business
60 Verily, I say unto you, saith the Lord of
Hosts, there must needs be presiding elders to preside
over those who are of the office of an elder
61 And also priests to preside over those who are
of the office of a priest
62 And also teachers to preside over those who are
of the office of a teacher, in like manner, and
also the deacons
63 Wherefore, from deacon to teacher, and from
teacher to priest, and from priest to elder,
severally as they are appointed, according to the
covenants and commandments of the church
64 Then comes the High Priesthood, which is the
greatest of all
65 Wherefore, it must needs be that one be
appointed of the High Priesthood to preside over the
priesthood, and he shall be called President of the
High Priesthood of the Church
66 Or, in other words, the Presiding High Priest
over the High Priesthood of the Church
67 From the same comes the administering of
ordinances and blessings upon the church, by the laying
on of the hands
68 Wherefore, the office of a bishop is not equal
unto it; for the office of a bishop is in
administering all temporal things
69 Nevertheless a bishop must be chosen from the
High Priesthood, unless he is a literal descendant
of Aaron
70 For unless he is a literal descendant of Aaron
he cannot hold the keys of that priesthood
71 Nevertheless, a high priest, that is, after the
order of Melchizedek, may be set apart unto the
ministering of temporal things, having a knowledge
of them by the Spirit of truth
72 And also to be a judge in Israel, to do the
business of the church, to sit in judgment upon
transgressors upon testimony as it shall be laid before
him according to the laws, by the assistance of
his counselors, whom he has chosen or will choose
among the elders of the church
73 This is the duty of a bishop who is not a
literal descendant of Aaron, but has been ordained to
the High Priesthood after the order of Melchizedek
74 Thus shall he be a judge, even a common judge
among the inhabitants of Zion, or in a stake of
Zion, or in any branch of the church where he shall
be set apart unto this ministry, until the borders
of Zion are enlarged and it becomes necessary to
have other bishops or judges in Zion or elsewhere
75 And inasmuch as there are other bishops
appointed they shall act in the same office
76 But a literal descendant of Aaron has a legal
right to the presidency of this priesthood, to the
keys of this ministry, to act in the office of
bishop independently, without counselors, except in a
case where a President of the High Priesthood,
after the order of Melchizedek, is tried, to sit as
a judge in Israel
77 And the decision of either of these councils,
agreeable to the commandment which says
78 Again, verily, I say unto you, the most
important business of the church, and the most difficult
cases of the church, inasmuch as there is not
satisfaction upon the decision of the bishop or
judges, it shall be handed over and carried up unto the
council of the church, before the Presidency of
the High Priesthood
79 And the Presidency of the council of the High
Priesthood shall have power to call other high
priests, even twelve, to assist as counselors; and
thus the Presidency of the High Priesthood and its
counselors shall have power to decide upon testimony
according to the laws of the church
80 And after this decision it shall be had in
remembrance no more before the Lord; for this is the
highest council of the church of God, and a final
decision upon controversies in spiritual matters
81 There is not any person belonging to the church
who is exempt from this council of the church
82 And inasmuch as a President of the High
Priesthood shall transgress, he shall be had in
remembrance before the common council of the church, who
shall be assisted by twelve counselors of the High
Priesthood
83 And their decision upon his head shall be an
end of controversy concerning him
84 Thus, none shall be exempted from the justice
and the laws of God, that all things may be done in
order and in solemnity before him, according to
truth and righteousness
85 And again, verily I say unto you, the duty of a
president over the office of a deacon is to
preside over twelve deacons, to sit in council with
them, and to teach them their duty, edifying one
another, as it is given according to the covenants
86 And also the duty of the president over the
office of the teachers is to preside over twenty-four
of the teachers, and to sit in council with them,
teaching them the duties of their office, as
given in the covenants
87 Also the duty of the president over the
Priesthood of Aaron is to preside over forty-eight
priests, and sit in council with them, to teach them the
duties of their office, as is given in the
covenants
88 This president is to be a bishop; for this is
one of the duties of this priesthood
89 Again, the duty of the president over the
office of elders is to preside over ninety-six elders,
and to sit in council with them, and to teach them
according to the covenants
90 This presidency is a distinct one from that of
the seventy, and is designed for those who do not
travel into all the world
91 And again, the duty of the President of the
office of the High Priesthood is to preside over the
whole church, and to be like unto Moses
92 Behold, here is wisdom; yea, to be a seer, a
revelator, a translator, and a prophet, having all
the gifts of God which he bestows upon the head of
the church
93 And it is according to the vision showing the
order of the Seventy, that they should have seven
presidents to preside over them, chosen out of the
number of the seventy
94 And the seventh president of these presidents
is to preside over the six
95 And these seven presidents are to choose other
seventy besides the first seventy to whom they
belong, and are to preside over them
96 And also other seventy, until seven times
seventy, if the labor in the vineyard of necessity
requires it
97 And these seventy are to be traveling
ministers, unto the Gentiles first and also unto the Jews
98 Whereas other officers of the church, who
belong not unto the Twelve, neither to the Seventy, are
not under the responsibility to travel among all
nations, but are to travel as their circumstances
shall allow, notwithstanding they may hold as high
and responsible offices in the church
99 Wherefore, now let every man learn his duty,
and to act in the office in which he is appointed,
in all diligence