Section 9 Revelation given through Joseph Smith the Prophet to
Oliver Cowdery, at Harmony, Pennsylvania, April 1829. Oliver is admonished
to be patient and is urged to be content to
write, for the time being, at the dictation of the
translator, rather than to attempt to translate.
1–6, Other ancient
records are yet to be translated;
7–14, The Book of
Mormon is translated by study and by spiritual confirmation.
1 Behold, I say unto you, my son, that because
you did not translate according to that which you desired
of me, and did commence again to write for my
servant, Joseph Smith, Jun., even so I would that ye
should continue until you have finished this record, which I
have entrusted unto him.
2 And then, behold, other records have I, that I
will give unto you power that you may assist to
translate.
3 Be patient, my son, for it is wisdom in
me, and it is not expedient that you should translate
at this present time.
4 Behold, the work which you are called to do
is to write for my servant Joseph.
5 And, behold, it is because that you did not
continue as you commenced, when you began to translate, that
I have taken away this privilege from you.
6 Do not murmur, my son, for it is wisdom
in me that I have dealt with you after this
manner.
7 Behold, you have not understood; you have supposed that
I would give it unto you, when you took no
thought save it was to ask me.
8 But, behold, I say unto you, that you must
study it out in your mind; then you must ask
me if it be right, and if it is right
I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you;
therefore, you shall feel that it is right.
9 But if it be not right you shall have
no such feelings, but you shall have a stupor of
thought that shall cause you to forget the thing which
is wrong; therefore, you cannot write that which is sacred
save it be given you from me.
10 Now, if you had known this you could have
translated; nevertheless, it is not expedient that you should translate
now.
11 Behold, it was expedient when you commenced; but you
feared, and the time is past, and it is not
expedient now;
12 For, do you not behold that I have given
unto my servant Joseph sufficient strength, whereby it is made
up? And neither of you have I condemned.
13 Do this thing which I have commanded you, and
you shall prosper. Be faithful, and yield to no temptation.
14 Stand fast in the work wherewith I have called
you, and a hair of your head shall not be
lost, and you shall be lifted up at the last
day. Amen.