Section 52 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to the elders of the Church, at
Kirtland, Ohio, June 6, 1831. A conference had been held
at Kirtland, beginning on the 3rd and closing on
the 6th of June. At this conference the first
distinctive ordinations to the office of high priest
were made, and certain manifestations of false and
deceiving spirits were discerned and rebuked.
1–2,
The next conference is designated to be held in
Missouri;
3–8, Appointments of certain elders to
travel together are made;
9–11, The elders are to
teach what the apostles and prophets have written;
12–21, Those enlightened by the Spirit bring
forth fruits of praise and wisdom;
22–44, Various
elders are appointed to go forth preaching the
gospel while traveling to Missouri for the conference.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto the elders whom
he hath called and chosen in these last days, by
the voice of his Spirit
2 Saying: I, the Lord, will make known unto you
what I will that ye shall do from this time until
the next conference, which shall be held in
Missouri, upon the land which I will consecrate unto my
people, which are a remnant of Jacob, and those who
are heirs according to the covenant
3 Wherefore, verily I say unto you, let my
servants Joseph Smith, Jun., and Sidney Rigdon take their
journey as soon as preparations can be made to
leave their homes, and journey to the land of
Missouri
4 And inasmuch as they are faithful unto me, it
shall be made known unto them what they shall do
5 And it shall also, inasmuch as they are
faithful, be made known unto them the land of your
inheritance
6 And inasmuch as they are not faithful, they
shall be cut off, even as I will, as seemeth me good
7 And again, verily I say unto you, let my servant
Lyman Wight and my servant John Corrill take
their journey speedily
8 And also my servant John Murdock, and my servant
Hyrum Smith, take their journey unto the same
place by the way of Detroit
9 And let them journey from thence preaching the
word by the way, saying none other things than that
which the prophets and apostles have written, and
that which is taught them by the Comforter
through the prayer of faith
10 Let them go two by two, and thus let them
preach by the way in every congregation, baptizing by
water, and the laying on of the hands by the
water’s side
11 For thus saith the Lord, I will cut my work
short in righteousness, for the days come that I will
send forth judgment unto victory
12 And let my servant Lyman Wight beware, for
Satan desireth to sift him as chaff
13 And behold, he that is faithful shall be made
ruler over many things
14 And again, I will give unto you a pattern in
all things, that ye may not be deceived; for Satan
is abroad in the land, and he goeth forth deceiving
the nations
15 Wherefore he that prayeth, whose spirit is
contrite, the same is accepted of me if he obey mine
ordinances
16 He that speaketh, whose spirit is contrite,
whose language is meek and edifieth, the same is of
God if he obey mine ordinances
17 And again, he that trembleth under my power
shall be made strong, and shall bring forth fruits of
praise and wisdom, according to the revelations
and truths which I have given you
18 And again, he that is overcome and bringeth not
forth fruits, even according to this pattern, is
not of me
19 Wherefore, by this pattern ye shall know the
spirits in all cases under the whole heavens
20 And the days have come; according to men’s
faith it shall be done unto them
21 Behold, this commandment is given unto all the
elders whom I have chosen
22 And again, verily I say unto you, let my
servant Thomas B. Marsh and my servant Ezra Thayre take
their journey also, preaching the word by the way
unto this same land
23 And again, let my servant Isaac Morley and my
servant Ezra Booth take their journey, also
preaching the word by the way unto this same land
24 And again, let my servants Edward Partridge and
Martin Harris take their journey with my servants
Sidney Rigdon and Joseph Smith, Jun
25 Let my servants David Whitmer and Harvey
Whitlock also take their journey, and preach by the way
unto this same land
26 And let my servants Parley P. Pratt and Orson
Pratt take their journey, and preach by the way,
even unto this same land
27 And let my servants Solomon Hancock and Simeon
Carter also take their journey unto this same
land, and preach by the way
28 Let my servants Edson Fuller and Jacob Scott
also take their journey
29 Let my servants Levi W. Hancock and Zebedee
Coltrin also take their journey
30 Let my servants Reynolds Cahoon and Samuel H.
Smith also take their journey
31 Let my servants Wheeler Baldwin and William
Carter also take their journey
32 And let my servants Newel Knight and Selah J.
Griffin both be ordained, and also take their
journey
33 Yea, verily I say, let all these take their
journey unto one place, in their several courses, and
one man shall not build upon another’s
foundation, neither journey in another’s track
34 He that is faithful, the same shall be kept and
blessed with much fruit
35 And again, I say unto you, let my servants
Joseph Wakefield and Solomon Humphrey take their
journey into the eastern lands
36 Let them labor with their families, declaring
none other things than the prophets and apostles,
that which they have seen and heard and most
assuredly believe, that the prophecies may be fulfilled
37 In consequence of transgression, let that which
was bestowed upon Heman Basset be taken from him,
and placed upon the head of Simonds Ryder
38 And again, verily I say unto you, let Jared
Carter be ordained a priest, and also George James be
ordained a priest
39 Let the residue of the elders watch over the
churches, and declare the word in the regions round
about them; and let them labor with their own
hands that there be no idolatry nor wickedness
practiced
40 And remember in all things the poor and the
needy, the sick and the afflicted, for he that doeth
not these things, the same is not my disciple
41 And again, let my servants Joseph Smith, Jun.,
and Sidney Rigdon and Edward Partridge take with
them a recommend from the church. And let there be
one obtained for my servant Oliver Cowdery also
42 And thus, even as I have said, if ye are
faithful ye shall assemble yourselves together to
rejoice upon the land of Missouri, which is the land of
your inheritance, which is now the land of your
enemies
43 But, behold, I, the Lord, will hasten the city
in its time, and will crown the faithful with joy
and with rejoicing
44 Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God, and
I will lift them up at the last day. Even so.
Amen.