Section 83 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Independence, Missouri, April
30, 1832. This revelation was received as the
Prophet sat in council with his brethren.
1–4,
Women and children have claim upon their husbands
and fathers for their support;
5–6, Widows and
orphans have claim upon the Church for their support.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord, in addition
to the laws of the church concerning women
and children, those who belong to the
church, who have lost their husbands or fathers:
2 Women have claim on their
husbands for their maintenance, until
their husbands are taken; and if
they are not found transgressors they
shall have fellowship in the church.
3 And if they are not faithful
they shall not have fellowship
in the church; yet they may
remain upon their inheritances
according to the laws of the land.
4 All children have claim
upon their parents for their
maintenance until they are of age.
5 And after that, they
have claim upon the church,
or in other words upon the
Lord’s storehouse, if
their parents have not
wherewith to give them inheritances.
6 And the storehouse
shall be kept by the
consecrations of the
church; and widows and
orphans shall be provided
for, as also the poor. Amen.