Section 68 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, November 1, 1831, in
response to prayer that the mind of the Lord be
made known concerning Orson Hyde, Luke S. Johnson,
Lyman E. Johnson, and William E. McLellin. Although
part of this revelation was directed toward these
four men, much of the content pertains to the
whole Church. This revelation was expanded under
Joseph Smith’s direction when it was published in the
1835 edition of the Doctrine and Covenants.
1–5,
The words of the elders when moved upon by the Holy
Ghost are scripture;
6–12, Elders are to preach
and baptize, and signs will follow true believers;
13–24, The firstborn among the sons of Aaron may
serve as the Presiding Bishop (that is, hold the
keys of presidency as a bishop) under the
direction of the First Presidency;
25–28, Parents are
commanded to teach the gospel to their children;
29–35, The Saints are to observe the Sabbath, labor
diligently, and pray.
1 My servant, Orson Hyde, was called by his
ordination to proclaim the everlasting gospel, by the
Spirit of the living God, from people to people, and
from land to land, in the congregations of the
wicked, in their synagogues, reasoning with and
expounding all scriptures unto them
2 And, behold, and lo, this is an ensample unto
all those who were ordained unto this priesthood,
whose mission is appointed unto them to go forth
3 And this is the ensample unto them, that they
shall speak as they are moved upon by the Holy
Ghost
4 And whatsoever they shall speak when moved upon
by the Holy Ghost shall be scripture, shall be the
will of the Lord, shall be the mind of the Lord,
shall be the word of the Lord, shall be the voice
of the Lord, and the power of God unto salvation
5 Behold, this is the promise of the Lord unto
you, O ye my servants
6 Wherefore, be of good cheer, and do not fear,
for I the Lord am with you, and will stand by you;
and ye shall bear record of me, even Jesus Christ,
that I am the Son of the living God, that I was,
that I am, and that I am to come
7 This is the word of the Lord unto you, my
servant Orson Hyde, and also unto my servant Luke
Johnson, and unto my servant Lyman Johnson, and unto my
servant William E. McLellin, and unto all the
faithful elders of my church
8 Go ye into all the world, preach the gospel to
every creature, acting in the authority which I
have given you, baptizing in the name of the Father,
and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost
9 And he that believeth and is baptized shall be
saved, and he that believeth not shall be damned
10 And he that believeth shall be blest with signs
following, even as it is written
11 And unto you it shall be given to know the
signs of the times, and the signs of the coming of the
Son of Man
12 And of as many as the Father shall bear record,
to you shall be given power to seal them up unto
eternal life. Amen
13 And now, concerning the items in addition to
the covenants and commandments, they are these
14 There remain hereafter, in the due time of the
Lord, other bishops to be set apart unto the
church, to minister even according to the first
15 Wherefore they shall be high priests who are
worthy, and they shall be appointed by the First
Presidency of the Melchizedek Priesthood, except they
be literal descendants of Aaron
16 And if they be literal descendants of Aaron
they have a legal right to the bishopric, if they are
the firstborn among the sons of Aaron
17 For the firstborn holds the right of the
presidency over this priesthood, and the keys or
authority of the same
18 No man has a legal right to this office, to
hold the keys of this priesthood, except he be a
literal descendant and the firstborn of Aaron
19 But, as a high priest of the Melchizedek
Priesthood has authority to officiate in all the lesser
offices he may officiate in the office of bishop
when no literal descendant of Aaron can be found,
provided he is called and set apart and ordained
unto this power, under the hands of the First
Presidency of the Melchizedek Priesthood
20 And a literal descendant of Aaron, also, must
be designated by this Presidency, and found worthy,
and anointed, and ordained under the hands of
this Presidency, otherwise they are not legally
authorized to officiate in their priesthood
21 But, by virtue of the decree concerning their
right of the priesthood descending from father to
son, they may claim their anointing if at any time
they can prove their lineage, or do ascertain it
by revelation from the Lord under the hands of the
above named Presidency
22 And again, no bishop or high priest who shall
be set apart for this ministry shall be tried or
condemned for any crime, save it be before the First
Presidency of the church
23 And inasmuch as he is found guilty before this
Presidency, by testimony that cannot be impeached,
he shall be condemned
24 And if he repent he shall be forgiven,
according to the covenants and commandments of the church
25 And again, inasmuch as parents have children in
Zion, or in any of her stakes which are
organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine
of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the
living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy
Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years
old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents
26 For this shall be a law unto the inhabitants of
Zion, or in any of her stakes which are
organized
27 And their children shall be baptized for the
remission of their sins when eight years old, and
receive the laying on of the hands
28 And they shall also teach their children to
pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord
29 And the inhabitants of Zion shall also observe
the Sabbath day to keep it holy
30 And the inhabitants of Zion also shall remember
their labors, inasmuch as they are appointed to
labor, in all faithfulness; for the idler shall be
had in remembrance before the Lord
31 Now, I, the Lord, am not well pleased with the
inhabitants of Zion, for there are idlers among
them; and their children are also growing up in
wickedness; they also seek not earnestly the riches of
eternity, but their eyes are full of greediness
32 These things ought not to be, and must be done
away from among them; wherefore, let my servant
Oliver Cowdery carry these sayings unto the land of
Zion
33 And a commandment I give unto them—that he that
observeth not his prayers before the Lord in the
season thereof, let him be had in remembrance
before the judge of my people
34 These sayings are true and faithful; wherefore,
transgress them not, neither take therefrom
35 Behold, I am Alpha and Omega, and I come
quickly. Amen.