Section 39 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to James Covel, at Fayette, New York,
January 5, 1831. James Covel, who had been a
Methodist minister for about forty years, covenanted
with the Lord that he would obey any command
that the Lord would give to him through Joseph the
Prophet.
1–4, The Saints have power to become the
sons of God;
5–6, To receive the gospel is to
receive Christ;
7–14, James Covel is commanded to
be baptized and labor in the Lord’s vineyard;
15–21, The Lord’s servants are to preach the
gospel before the Second Coming;
22–24, Those who
receive the gospel will be gathered in time and in eternity.
1 Hearken and listen to the voice of
him who is from all eternity to all
eternity, the Great I Am, even Jesus Christ—
2 The light and the life of the
world; a light which shineth in darkness
and the darkness comprehendeth it not;
3 The same which came in the
meridian of time unto mine own,
and mine own received me not;
4 But to as many as received
me, gave I power to become my
sons; and even so will I
give unto as many as will
receive me, power to become my sons.
5 And verily, verily, I
say unto you, he that
receiveth my gospel receiveth
me; and he that receiveth
not my gospel receiveth not me.
6 And this is my
gospel—repentance and baptism by
water, and then cometh the
baptism of fire and the
Holy Ghost, even the
Comforter, which showeth all
things, and teacheth the
peaceable things of the kingdom.
7 And now, behold, I say
unto you, my servant
James, I have looked upon
thy works and I know thee.
8 And verily I say unto
thee, thine heart is
now right before me at
this time; and, behold,
I have bestowed great
blessings upon thy head;
9 Nevertheless, thou
hast seen great
sorrow, for thou hast
rejected me many times
because of pride and
the cares of the world.
10 But, behold, the
days of thy
deliverance are come, if
thou wilt hearken to my
voice, which saith
unto thee: Arise and
be baptized, and
wash away your sins,
calling on my name,
and you shall receive
my Spirit, and a
blessing so great as
you never have known.
11 And if thou do
this, I have
prepared thee for a
greater work. Thou
shalt preach the
fulness of my gospel,
which I have sent
forth in these
last days, the
covenant which I have
sent forth to
recover my people,
which are of the house of Israel.
12 And it shall
come to pass that
power shall rest
upon thee; thou
shalt have great
faith, and I will
be with thee and
go before thy face.
13 Thou art
called to labor in
my vineyard, and
to build up my
church, and to
bring forth Zion,
that it may
rejoice upon the
hills and flourish.
14 Behold,
verily, verily, I
say unto thee,
thou art not
called to go into
the eastern
countries, but
thou art called to
go to the Ohio.
15 And
inasmuch as my people
shall
assemble themselves
at the Ohio, I
have kept in
store a
blessing such as is
not known among
the children
of men, and it
shall be
poured forth upon
their heads.
And from thence
men shall go
forth into all nations.
16 Behold,
verily, verily,
I say unto
you, that the
people in
Ohio call upon
me in much
faith, thinking
I will stay
my hand in
judgment upon
the nations,
but I cannot deny my word.
17 Wherefore
lay to with
your might
and call
faithful
laborers into my
vineyard,
that it may be
pruned for
the last time.
18 And
inasmuch as
they do repent
and
receive the
fulness of my
gospel, and
become
sanctified, I
will stay
mine hand in judgment.
Wherefore, go
forth, crying
with a
loud voice,
saying:
The kingdom
of heaven
is at
hand; crying:
Hosanna!
blessed be
the name
of the Most High God.
20 Go
forth
baptizing with
water,
preparing
the way
before my
face for
the time
of my coming;
21 For
the time
is at
hand; the
day or
the hour
no man
knoweth;
but it
surely shall come.
22 And
he that
receiveth
these
things
receiveth
me; and
they
shall be
gathered unto
me in
time and in eternity.
23 And
again, it
shall
come to
pass
that
on as
many as
ye
shall
baptize
with
water,
ye
shall lay
your
hands,
and
they
shall
receive
the
gift of
Holy
Ghost,
and
shall be
looking
forth
for
the
signs of my coming, and shall know me.
Behold, I
come
quickly.
Even so.
Amen.