headings to sections 78 and
82).
1–2, The Lord gives a commandment
relative to admission to the united order.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord, I
give unto the united order,
organized agreeable to the commandment
previously given, a revelation
and commandment concerning my
servant Frederick G. Williams, that
ye shall receive him into the
order. What I say unto one I say unto all.
2 And again, I say unto you my
servant Frederick G.
Williams, you shall be a lively member
in this order; and inasmuch
as you are faithful in keeping
all former commandments you
shall be blessed forever. Amen.
Section 92 Revelation given
to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, March
15, 1833. The revelation
instructs Frederick G.
Williams, who had recently been
appointed a counselor to
Joseph Smith, on his duties
in the United Firm (see the