Section 118 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Far West, Missouri, July 8, 1838,
in response to the supplication, “Show us thy
will, O Lord, concerning the Twelve.”
1–3, The Lord
will provide for the families of the Twelve;
4–6,
Vacancies in the Twelve are filled.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord: Let a conference be
held immediately; let the Twelve be organized;
and let men be appointed to supply the place of
those who are fallen
2 Let my servant Thomas remain for a season in the
land of Zion, to publish my word
3 Let the residue continue to preach from that
hour, and if they will do this in all lowliness of
heart, in meekness and humility, and long-suffering,
I, the Lord, give unto them a promise that I will
provide for their families; and an effectual door
shall be opened for them, from henceforth
4 And next spring let them depart to go over the
great waters, and there promulgate my gospel, the
fulness thereof, and bear record of my name
5 Let them take leave of my saints in the city of
Far West, on the twenty-sixth day of April next,
on the building-spot of my house, saith the Lord
6 Let my servant John Taylor, and also my servant
John E. Page, and also my servant Wilford
Woodruff, and also my servant Willard Richards, be
appointed to fill the places of those who have fallen,
and be officially notified of their appointment.