Section 91 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, March 9,
1833. The Prophet was at this time engaged in the
translation of the Old Testament. Having come to
that portion of the ancient writings called
the Apocrypha, he inquired of the Lord and
received this instruction.
1–3, The Apocrypha is
mostly translated correctly but contains many
interpolations by the hands of men that are not
true;
4–6, It benefits those enlightened by the Spirit.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you
concerning the Apocrypha—There are many
things contained therein that are
true, and it is mostly translated correctly;
2 There are many things contained
therein that are not true, which are
interpolations by the hands of men.
3 Verily, I say unto you,
that it is not needful that the
Apocrypha should be translated.
4 Therefore, whoso readeth
it, let him understand, for
the Spirit manifesteth truth;
5 And whoso is
enlightened by the Spirit shall
obtain benefit therefrom;
6 And whoso receiveth
not by the Spirit,
cannot be benefited.
Therefore it is not
needful that it should
be translated. Amen.