Section 70 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, November 12, 1831. The
Prophet’s history states that four special
conferences were held from the 1st to the 12th of
November, inclusive. In the last of these assemblies,
the great importance of the revelations that would
later be published as the Book of Commandments and
then the Doctrine and Covenants was considered.
This revelation was given after the conference voted
that the revelations were “worth to the Church
the riches of the whole Earth.” Joseph Smith’s
history refers to the revelations as “the foundation of
the Church in these last days, and a benefit to
the world, showing that the keys of the mysteries
of the kingdom of our Savior are again entrusted to
man.”
1–5, Stewards are appointed to publish the
revelations;
6–13, Those who labor in spiritual
things are worthy of their hire;
14–18, The
Saints should be equal in temporal things.
1 Behold, and hearken, O ye inhabitants of Zion,
and all ye people of my church who are afar off,
and hear the word of the Lord which I give unto my
servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and also unto my
servant Martin Harris, and also unto my servant Oliver
Cowdery, and also unto my servant John Whitmer, and
also unto my servant Sidney Rigdon, and also unto
my servant William W. Phelps, by the way of
commandment unto them
2 For I give unto them a commandment; wherefore
hearken and hear, for thus saith the Lord unto them
3 I, the Lord, have appointed them, and ordained
them to be stewards over the revelations and
commandments which I have given unto them, and which I
shall hereafter give unto them
4 And an account of this stewardship will I
require of them in the day of judgment
5 Wherefore, I have appointed unto them, and this
is their business in the church of God, to manage
them and the concerns thereof, yea, the benefits
thereof
6 Wherefore, a commandment I give unto them, that
they shall not give these things unto the church,
neither unto the world
7 Nevertheless, inasmuch as they receive more than
is needful for their necessities and their wants,
it shall be given into my storehouse
8 And the benefits shall be consecrated unto the
inhabitants of Zion, and unto their generations,
inasmuch as they become heirs according to the laws
of the kingdom
9 Behold, this is what the Lord requires of every
man in his stewardship, even as I, the Lord, have
appointed or shall hereafter appoint unto any man
10 And behold, none are exempt from this law who
belong to the church of the living God
11 Yea, neither the bishop, neither the agent who
keepeth the Lord’s storehouse, neither he who is
appointed in a stewardship over temporal things
12 He who is appointed to administer spiritual
things, the same is worthy of his hire, even as those
who are appointed to a stewardship to administer
in temporal things
13 Yea, even more abundantly, which abundance is
multiplied unto them through the manifestations of
the Spirit
14 Nevertheless, in your temporal things you shall
be equal, and this not grudgingly, otherwise the
abundance of the manifestations of the Spirit
shall be withheld
15 Now, this commandment I give unto my servants
for their benefit while they remain, for a
manifestation of my blessings upon their heads, and for a
reward of their diligence and for their security
16 For food and for raiment; for an inheritance;
for houses and for lands, in whatsoever
circumstances I, the Lord, shall place them, and
whithersoever I, the Lord, shall send them
17 For they have been faithful over many things,
and have done well inasmuch as they have not
sinned
18 Behold, I, the Lord, am merciful and will bless
them, and they shall enter into the joy of these
things. Even so. Amen.