Section 85 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, November
27, 1832. This section is an extract from a
letter of the Prophet to William W. Phelps, who
was living in Independence, Missouri. It answers
questions about those Saints who had moved to
Zion but who had not followed the commandment
to consecrate their properties and had thus
not received their inheritances according to
the established order in the Church.
1–5,
Inheritances in Zion are to be received through
consecration;
6–12, One mighty and strong will
give the Saints their inheritance in Zion.
second chapter and sixty-first and second verses of Ezra.
1 It is the duty of the Lord’s clerk,
whom he has appointed, to keep a
history, and a general church record of all
things that transpire in Zion, and of all
those who consecrate properties, and
receive inheritances legally from the bishop;
2 And also their manner of life,
their faith, and works; and also
of the apostates who apostatize
after receiving their inheritances.
3 It is contrary to the will
and commandment of God that
those who receive not their
inheritance by consecration,
agreeable to his law, which he has
given, that he may tithe his
people, to prepare them against
the day of vengeance and
burning, should have their names
enrolled with the people of God.
4 Neither is their
genealogy to be kept, or to
be had where it may be
found on any of the
records or history of the church.
5 Their names shall not
be found, neither the
names of the fathers,
nor the names of the
children written in the
book of the law of God,
saith the Lord of Hosts.
6 Yea, thus saith the
still small voice,
which whispereth
through and pierceth all
things, and often
times it maketh my bones
to quake while it
maketh manifest, saying:
7 And it shall come
to pass that I, the
Lord God, will send
one mighty and
strong, holding the
scepter of power in his
hand, clothed with
light for a covering,
whose mouth shall
utter words, eternal
words; while his
bowels shall be a
fountain of truth, to set
in order the house
of God, and to
arrange by lot the
inheritances of the saints
whose names are
found, and the names of
their fathers, and
of their children,
enrolled in the book of the law of God;
8 While that man,
who was called of
God and appointed,
that putteth
forth his hand to
steady the ark of God,
shall fall by the
shaft of death,
like as a tree that
is smitten by the
vivid shaft of lightning.
9 And all they
who are not found
written in the
book of remembrance
shall find none
inheritance in
that day, but they
shall be cut
asunder, and their
portion shall be
appointed them among
unbelievers,
where are wailing
and gnashing of teeth.
10 These things
I say not of
myself;
therefore, as the Lord
speaketh, he
will also fulfil.
11 And they
who are of the
High
Priesthood, whose names
are not found
written in the
book of the
law, or that
are found to
have apostatized,
or to have
been cut off
from the church,
as well as the
lesser
priesthood, or the
members, in
that day shall
not find an
inheritance among
the saints of the Most High;
12 Therefore,
it shall be
done unto
them as unto the
children of
the priest,
as will be
found recorded in the