Section 13 An extract from Joseph Smith’s
history recounting the ordination of the Prophet and
Oliver Cowdery to the Aaronic Priesthood near
Harmony, Pennsylvania, May 15, 1829. The ordination
was done by the hands of an angel who announced
himself as John, the same that is called John
the Baptist in the New Testament. The angel
explained that he was acting under the direction of
Peter, James, and John, the ancient Apostles, who
held the keys of the higher priesthood, which
was called the Priesthood of Melchizedek. The
promise was given to Joseph and Oliver that in due
time this higher priesthood would be conferred
upon them. (See
section 27:7–8, 12.) The keys
and powers of the Aaronic Priesthood are set forth.
1 Upon you my fellow servants, in the name of
Messiah I confer the Priesthood of Aaron,
which holds the keys of the ministering of
angels, and of the gospel of repentance, and of
baptism by immersion for the remission of
sins; and this shall never be taken again from
the earth, until the sons of Levi do offer
again an offering unto the Lord in righteousness.