Section 129 Instructions given by Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Nauvoo, Illinois,
February 9, 1843, making known three grand keys by
which the correct nature of ministering
angels and spirits may be distinguished.
1–3,
There are both resurrected and spirit bodies
in heaven;
4–9, Keys are given whereby
messengers from beyond the veil may be identified.
1 There are two kinds of beings in
heaven, namely: Angels, who are resurrected
personages, having bodies of flesh and bones—
2 For instance, Jesus said: Handle
me and see, for a spirit hath not
flesh and bones, as ye see me have.
3 Secondly: the spirits of
just men made perfect,
they who are not
resurrected, but inherit the same glory.
4 When a messenger
comes saying he has a
message from God, offer him
your hand and request
him to shake hands with you.
5 If he be an angel
he will do so, and
you will feel his hand.
6 If he be the
spirit of a just man
made perfect he will
come in his glory;
for that is the
only way he can appear—
7 Ask him to shake
hands with you,
but he will not
move, because it is
contrary to the
order of heaven for a
just man to
deceive; but he will
still deliver his message.
8 If it be the
devil as an angel
of light, when
you ask him to
shake hands he
will offer you his
hand, and you
will not feel
anything; you may
therefore detect him.
9 These are
three grand keys
whereby you may
know whether
any
administration is from God.