Section 60 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, in Independence, Jackson County,
Missouri, August 8, 1831. On this occasion the
elders who had traveled to Jackson County and
participated in the dedication of the land and
the temple site desired to know what they were
to do.
1–9, The elders are to preach the
gospel in the congregations of the wicked;
10–14,
They should not idle away their time, nor bury
their talents;
15–17, They may wash their feet
as a testimony against those who reject the gospel.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto the
elders of his church, who are to return speedily
to the land from whence they came: Behold,
it pleaseth me, that you have come up hither;
2 But with some I am not well pleased, for
they will not open their mouths, but they
hide the talent which I have given unto
them, because of the fear of man. Wo unto
such, for mine anger is kindled against them.
3 And it shall come to pass, if they
are not more faithful unto me, it shall
be taken away, even that which they have.
4 For I, the Lord, rule in the heavens
above, and among the armies of the
earth; and in the day when I shall make
up my jewels, all men shall know what
it is that bespeaketh the power of God.
5 But, verily, I will speak unto you
concerning your journey unto the
land from whence you came. Let there
be a craft made, or bought, as
seemeth you good, it mattereth not unto
me, and take your journey speedily for
the place which is called St. Louis.
6 And from thence let my
servants, Sidney Rigdon, Joseph
Smith, Jun., and Oliver Cowdery,
take their journey for Cincinnati;
7 And in this place let them
lift up their voice and declare
my word with loud voices,
without wrath or doubting,
lifting up holy hands upon them. For
I am able to make you holy,
and your sins are forgiven you.
8 And let the residue take
their journey from St. Louis,
two by two, and preach the
word, not in haste, among
the congregations of the
wicked, until they return to the
churches from whence they came.
9 And all this for the
good of the churches; for
this intent have I sent them.
10 And let my servant
Edward Partridge impart
of the money which I
have given him, a portion
unto mine elders who
are commanded to return;
11 And he that is
able, let him return it by
the way of the agent;
and he that is not,
of him it is not required.
12 And now I speak of
the residue who are
to come unto this land.
13 Behold, they
have been sent to
preach my gospel among
the congregations
of the wicked;
wherefore, I give unto
them a commandment,
thus: Thou shalt
not idle away thy
time, neither shalt
thou bury thy talent
that it may not be known.
14 And after thou
hast come up unto
the land of Zion,
and hast
proclaimed my word, thou
shalt speedily
return, proclaiming my
word among the
congregations of the
wicked, not in
haste, neither in
wrath nor with strife.
15 And shake off
the dust of thy
feet against those
who receive thee
not, not in
their presence, lest
thou provoke
them, but in secret;
and wash thy
feet, as a testimony
against them in
the day of judgment.
16 Behold, this
is sufficient
for you, and
the will of him
who hath sent you.
17 And by the
mouth of my
servant Joseph
Smith, Jun., it
shall be made
known
concerning Sidney
Rigdon and Oliver
Cowdery. The
residue
hereafter. Even so. Amen.