Section 36 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Edward Partridge, near Fayette, New
York, December 9, 1830 (see the
heading to
section 35). Joseph Smith’s history states that Edward
Partridge “was a pattern of piety, and one of the
Lord’s great men.”
1–3, The Lord lays His hand
upon Edward Partridge by the hand of Sidney Rigdon;
4–8, Every man who receives the gospel and the
priesthood is to be called to go forth and preach.
1 Thus saith the Lord God, the Mighty One of
Israel: Behold, I say unto you, my servant Edward, that
you are blessed, and your sins are forgiven you,
and you are called to preach my gospel as with the
voice of a trump
2 And I will lay my hand upon you by the hand of
my servant Sidney Rigdon, and you shall receive my
Spirit, the Holy Ghost, even the Comforter, which
shall teach you the peaceable things of the
kingdom
3 And you shall declare it with a loud voice,
saying: Hosanna, blessed be the name of the most high
God
4 And now this calling and commandment give I unto
you concerning all men
5 That as many as shall come before my servants
Sidney Rigdon and Joseph Smith, Jun., embracing this
calling and commandment, shall be ordained and
sent forth to preach the everlasting gospel among
the nations
6 Crying repentance, saying: Save yourselves from
this untoward generation, and come forth out of
the fire, hating even the garments spotted with the
flesh
7 And this commandment shall be given unto the
elders of my church, that every man which will
embrace it with singleness of heart may be ordained and
sent forth, even as I have spoken
8 I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God; wherefore,
gird up your loins and I will suddenly come to my
temple. Even so. Amen.