Section 24 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Oliver Cowdery, at Harmony,
Pennsylvania, July 1830. Though less than four months
had elapsed since the Church was organized,
persecution had become intense, and the leaders had to
seek safety in partial seclusion. The following
three revelations were given at this time to
strengthen, encourage, and instruct them.
1–9,
Joseph Smith is called to translate, preach, and
expound scriptures;
10–12, Oliver Cowdery is
called to preach the gospel;
13–19, The law is
revealed relative to miracles, cursings, casting
off the dust of one’s feet, and going without purse or scrip.
1 Behold, thou wast called and chosen to
write the Book of Mormon, and to my
ministry; and I have lifted thee up out of
thine afflictions, and have counseled thee,
that thou hast been delivered from all
thine enemies, and thou hast been delivered
from the powers of Satan and from darkness!
2 Nevertheless, thou art not
excusable in thy transgressions;
nevertheless, go thy way and sin no more.
3 Magnify thine office; and
after thou hast sowed thy
fields and secured them, go
speedily unto the church which is
in Colesville, Fayette, and
Manchester, and they shall
support thee; and I will bless
them both spiritually and temporally;
4 But if they receive thee
not, I will send upon them a
cursing instead of a blessing.
5 And thou shalt
continue in calling upon God in
my name, and writing
the things which shall be
given thee by the
Comforter, and expounding all
scriptures unto the church.
6 And it shall be given
thee in the very
moment what thou shalt speak
and write, and they
shall hear it, or I will
send unto them a
cursing instead of a blessing.
7 For thou shalt
devote all thy service in
Zion; and in this
thou shalt have strength.
8 Be patient in
afflictions, for
thou shalt have many;
but endure them,
for, lo, I am with
thee, even unto
the end of thy days.
9 And in temporal
labors thou
shalt not have
strength, for this is
not thy calling.
Attend to thy
calling and thou
shalt have wherewith
to magnify thine
office, and to
expound all
scriptures, and continue
in laying on of
the hands and
confirming the churches.
10 And thy
brother Oliver shall
continue in
bearing my name
before the world,
and also to the
church. And he
shall not suppose
that he can say
enough in my
cause; and lo, I am
with him to the end.
11 In me he
shall have glory,
and not of
himself, whether in
weakness or in
strength,
whether in bonds or free;
12 And at all
times, and in
all places, he
shall open
his mouth and
declare my
gospel as with the
voice of a
trump, both day
and night. And
I will give
unto him
strength such as is
not known among men.
13 Require
not miracles,
except I shall
command you,
except
casting out
devils, healing the
sick, and
against
poisonous serpents,
and against
deadly poisons;
14 And these
things ye
shall not do,
except it
be required
of you by
them who desire
it, that
the scriptures
might be
fulfilled; for
ye shall do
according
to that which is written.
15 And in
whatsoever
place ye
shall enter,
and they
receive you
not in my
name, ye shall
leave a
cursing
instead of a
blessing, by
casting off
the dust of
your feet
against
them as a
testimony, and
cleansing
your feet by the wayside.
16 And it
shall come
to pass
that
whosoever shall
lay their
hands upon
you by
violence, ye
shall
command to be
smitten
in my name;
and,
behold, I will
smite
them
according to your
words, in mine own due time.
17 And
whosoever
shall go to
law with
thee shall
be cursed
by the law.
18 And
thou shalt
take no
purse nor
scrip,
neither
staves,
neither two
coats, for
the
church shall
give unto
thee in
the very
hour what
thou
needest for
food and
for
raiment, and
for shoes
and for money, and for scrip.
19 For
thou art
called
to prune
my
vineyard with
a
mighty
pruning, yea,
even for
the
last time;
yea, and
also
all those
whom
thou hast
ordained,
and
they shall
do even
according to this pattern. Amen.