Section 88 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet at Kirtland, Ohio, December 27 and 28,
1832, and January 3, 1833. The Prophet designated
it as the “‘olive leaf’ … plucked from the Tree of
Paradise, the Lord’s message of peace to us.” The
revelation was given after high priests at a
conference prayed “separately and vocally to the Lord
to reveal his will unto us concerning the
upbuilding of Zion.”
1–5, Faithful Saints receive that
Comforter, which is the promise of eternal life;
6–13, All things are controlled and governed by the
Light of Christ;
14–16, The Resurrection comes
through the Redemption;
17–31, Obedience to
celestial, terrestrial, or telestial law prepares men for
those respective kingdoms and glories;
32–35,
Those who will to abide in sin remain filthy still;
36–41, All kingdoms are governed by law;
42–45,
God has given a law unto all things;
46–50, Man
will comprehend even God;
51–61, The parable of
the man sending his servants into the field and
visiting them in turn;
62–73, Draw near unto the
Lord, and ye will see His face;
74–80, Sanctify
yourselves and teach one another the doctrines of the
kingdom;
81–85, Every man who has been warned
should warn his neighbor;
86–94, Signs, upheavals of
the elements, and angels prepare the way for the
coming of the Lord;
95–102, Angelic trumps call
forth the dead in their order;
103–16, Angelic
trumps proclaim the restoration of the gospel, the
fall of Babylon, and the battle of the great God;
117–26, Seek learning, establish a house of God (a
temple), and clothe yourselves with the bond of
charity;
127–41, The order of the School of the
Prophets is set forth, including the ordinance of
washing of feet.
thirteenth chapter of John’s
testimony concerning me. Amen.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you who have
assembled yourselves together to receive his will
concerning you
2 Behold, this is pleasing unto your Lord, and the
angels rejoice over you; the alms of your prayers
have come up into the ears of the Lord of
Sabaoth, and are recorded in the book of the names of the
sanctified, even them of the celestial world
3 Wherefore, I now send upon you another
Comforter, even upon you my friends, that it may abide in
your hearts, even the Holy Spirit of promise; which
other Comforter is the same that I promised unto
my disciples, as is recorded in the testimony of
John
4 This Comforter is the promise which I give unto
you of eternal life, even the glory of the
celestial kingdom
5 Which glory is that of the church of the
Firstborn, even of God, the holiest of all, through Jesus
Christ his Son
6 He that ascended up on high, as also he
descended below all things, in that he comprehended all
things, that he might be in all and through all
things, the light of truth
7 Which truth shineth. This is the light of
Christ. As also he is in the sun, and the light of the
sun, and the power thereof by which it was made
8 As also he is in the moon, and is the light of
the moon, and the power thereof by which it was
made
9 As also the light of the stars, and the power
thereof by which they were made
10 And the earth also, and the power thereof, even
the earth upon which you stand
11 And the light which shineth, which giveth you
light, is through him who enlighteneth your eyes,
which is the same light that quickeneth your
understandings
12 Which light proceedeth forth from the presence
of God to fill the immensity of space
13 The light which is in all things, which giveth
life to all things, which is the law by which all
things are governed, even the power of God who
sitteth upon his throne, who is in the bosom of
eternity, who is in the midst of all things
14 Now, verily I say unto you, that through the
redemption which is made for you is brought to pass
the resurrection from the dead
15 And the spirit and the body are the soul of
man
16 And the resurrection from the dead is the
redemption of the soul
17 And the redemption of the soul is through him
that quickeneth all things, in whose bosom it is
decreed that the poor and the meek of the earth
shall inherit it
18 Therefore, it must needs be sanctified from all
unrighteousness, that it may be prepared for the
celestial glory
19 For after it hath filled the measure of its
creation, it shall be crowned with glory, even with
the presence of God the Father
20 That bodies who are of the celestial kingdom
may possess it forever and ever; for, for this
intent was it made and created, and for this intent are
they sanctified
21 And they who are not sanctified through the law
which I have given unto you, even the law of
Christ, must inherit another kingdom, even that of a
terrestrial kingdom, or that of a telestial
kingdom
22 For he who is not able to abide the law of a
celestial kingdom cannot abide a celestial glory
23 And he who cannot abide the law of a
terrestrial kingdom cannot abide a terrestrial glory
24 And he who cannot abide the law of a telestial
kingdom cannot abide a telestial glory; therefore
he is not meet for a kingdom of glory. Therefore
he must abide a kingdom which is not a kingdom of
glory
25 And again, verily I say unto you, the earth
abideth the law of a celestial kingdom, for it
filleth the measure of its creation, and transgresseth
not the law
26 Wherefore, it shall be sanctified; yea,
notwithstanding it shall die, it shall be quickened
again, and shall abide the power by which it is
quickened, and the righteous shall inherit it
27 For notwithstanding they die, they also shall
rise again, a spiritual body
28 They who are of a celestial spirit shall
receive the same body which was a natural body; even ye
shall receive your bodies, and your glory shall be
that glory by which your bodies are quickened
29 Ye who are quickened by a portion of the
celestial glory shall then receive of the same, even a
fulness
30 And they who are quickened by a portion of the
terrestrial glory shall then receive of the same,
even a fulness
31 And also they who are quickened by a portion of
the telestial glory shall then receive of the
same, even a fulness
32 And they who remain shall also be quickened;
nevertheless, they shall return again to their own
place, to enjoy that which they are willing to
receive, because they were not willing to enjoy that
which they might have received
33 For what doth it profit a man if a gift is
bestowed upon him, and he receive not the gift?
Behold, he rejoices not in that which is given unto him,
neither rejoices in him who is the giver of the
gift
34 And again, verily I say unto you, that which is
governed by law is also preserved by law and
perfected and sanctified by the same
35 That which breaketh a law, and abideth not by
law, but seeketh to become a law unto itself, and
willeth to abide in sin, and altogether abideth in
sin, cannot be sanctified by law, neither by
mercy, justice, nor judgment. Therefore, they must
remain filthy still
36 All kingdoms have a law given
37 And there are many kingdoms; for there is no
space in the which there is no kingdom; and there is
no kingdom in which there is no space, either a
greater or a lesser kingdom
38 And unto every kingdom is given a law; and unto
every law there are certain bounds also and
conditions
39 All beings who abide not in those conditions
are not justified
40 For intelligence cleaveth unto intelligence;
wisdom receiveth wisdom; truth embraceth truth;
virtue loveth virtue; light cleaveth unto light; mercy
hath compassion on mercy and claimeth her own;
justice continueth its course and claimeth its own;
judgment goeth before the face of him who sitteth
upon the throne and governeth and executeth all
things
41 He comprehendeth all things, and all things are
before him, and all things are round about him;
and he is above all things, and in all things, and
is through all things, and is round about all
things; and all things are by him, and of him, even
God, forever and ever
42 And again, verily I say unto you, he hath given
a law unto all things, by which they move in
their times and their seasons
43 And their courses are fixed, even the courses
of the heavens and the earth, which comprehend the
earth and all the planets
44 And they give light to each other in their
times and in their seasons, in their minutes, in their
hours, in their days, in their weeks, in their
months, in their years—all these are one year with
God, but not with man
45 The earth rolls upon her wings, and the sun
giveth his light by day, and the moon giveth her
light by night, and the stars also give their light,
as they roll upon their wings in their glory, in
the midst of the power of God
46 Unto what shall I liken these kingdoms, that ye
may understand
47 Behold, all these are kingdoms, and any man who
hath seen any or the least of these hath seen God
moving in his majesty and power
48 I say unto you, he hath seen him; nevertheless,
he who came unto his own was not comprehended
49 The light shineth in darkness, and the darkness
comprehendeth it not; nevertheless, the day shall
come when you shall comprehend even God, being
quickened in him and by him
50 Then shall ye know that ye have seen me, that I
am, and that I am the true light that is in you,
and that you are in me; otherwise ye could not
abound
51 Behold, I will liken these kingdoms unto a man
having a field, and he sent forth his servants
into the field to dig in the field
52 And he said unto the first: Go ye and labor in
the field, and in the first hour I will come unto
you, and ye shall behold the joy of my
countenance
53 And he said unto the second: Go ye also into
the field, and in the second hour I will visit you
with the joy of my countenance
54 And also unto the third, saying: I will visit
you
55 And unto the fourth, and so on unto the
twelfth
56 And the lord of the field went unto the first
in the first hour, and tarried with him all that
hour, and he was made glad with the light of the
countenance of his lord
57 And then he withdrew from the first that he
might visit the second also, and the third, and the
fourth, and so on unto the twelfth
58 And thus they all received the light of the
countenance of their lord, every man in his hour, and
in his time, and in his season
59 Beginning at the first, and so on unto the
last, and from the last unto the first, and from the
first unto the last
60 Every man in his own order, until his hour was
finished, even according as his lord had commanded
him, that his lord might be glorified in him, and
he in his lord, that they all might be glorified
61 Therefore, unto this parable I will liken all
these kingdoms, and the inhabitants thereof—every
kingdom in its hour, and in its time, and in its
season, even according to the decree which God hath
made
62 And again, verily I say unto you, my friends, I
leave these sayings with you to ponder in your
hearts, with this commandment which I give unto you,
that ye shall call upon me while I am near
63 Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto
you; seek me diligently and ye shall find me; ask,
and ye shall receive; knock, and it shall be opened
unto you
64 Whatsoever ye ask the Father in my name it
shall be given unto you, that is expedient for you
65 And if ye ask anything that is not expedient
for you, it shall turn unto your condemnation
66 Behold, that which you hear is as the voice of
one crying in the wilderness—in the wilderness,
because you cannot see him—my voice, because my
voice is Spirit; my Spirit is truth; truth abideth and
hath no end; and if it be in you it shall abound
67 And if your eye be single to my glory, your
whole bodies shall be filled with light, and there
shall be no darkness in you; and that body which is
filled with light comprehendeth all things
68 Therefore, sanctify yourselves that your minds
become single to God, and the days will come that
you shall see him; for he will unveil his face
unto you, and it shall be in his own time, and in his
own way, and according to his own will
69 Remember the great and last promise which I
have made unto you; cast away your idle thoughts and
your excess of laughter far from you
70 Tarry ye, tarry ye in this place, and call a
solemn assembly, even of those who are the first
laborers in this last kingdom
71 And let those whom they have warned in their
traveling call on the Lord, and ponder the warning
in their hearts which they have received, for a
little season
72 Behold, and lo, I will take care of your
flocks, and will raise up elders and send unto them
73 Behold, I will hasten my work in its time
74 And I give unto you, who are the first laborers
in this last kingdom, a commandment that you
assemble yourselves together, and organize yourselves,
and prepare yourselves, and sanctify yourselves;
yea, purify your hearts, and cleanse your hands
and your feet before me, that I may make you clean
75 That I may testify unto your Father, and your
God, and my God, that you are clean from the blood
of this wicked generation; that I may fulfil this
promise, this great and last promise, which I have
made unto you, when I will
76 Also, I give unto you a commandment that ye
shall continue in prayer and fasting from this time
forth
77 And I give unto you a commandment that you
shall teach one another the doctrine of the kingdom
78 Teach ye diligently and my grace shall attend
you, that you may be instructed more perfectly in
theory, in principle, in doctrine, in the law of
the gospel, in all things that pertain unto the
kingdom of God, that are expedient for you to
understand
79 Of things both in heaven and in the earth, and
under the earth; things which have been, things
which are, things which must shortly come to pass;
things which are at home, things which are abroad;
the wars and the perplexities of the nations, and
the judgments which are on the land; and a
knowledge also of countries and of kingdoms
80 That ye may be prepared in all things when I
shall send you again to magnify the calling
whereunto I have called you, and the mission with which I
have commissioned you
81 Behold, I sent you out to testify and warn the
people, and it becometh every man who hath been
warned to warn his neighbor
82 Therefore, they are left without excuse, and
their sins are upon their own heads
83 He that seeketh me early shall find me, and
shall not be forsaken
84 Therefore, tarry ye, and labor diligently, that
you may be perfected in your ministry to go forth
among the Gentiles for the last time, as many as
the mouth of the Lord shall name, to bind up the
law and seal up the testimony, and to prepare the
saints for the hour of judgment which is to come
85 That their souls may escape the wrath of God,
the desolation of abomination which awaits the
wicked, both in this world and in the world to come.
Verily, I say unto you, let those who are not the
first elders continue in the vineyard until the
mouth of the Lord shall call them, for their time is
not yet come; their garments are not clean from
the blood of this generation
86 Abide ye in the liberty wherewith ye are made
free; entangle not yourselves in sin, but let your
hands be clean, until the Lord comes
87 For not many days hence and the earth shall
tremble and reel to and fro as a drunken man; and the
sun shall hide his face, and shall refuse to give
light; and the moon shall be bathed in blood; and
the stars shall become exceedingly angry, and
shall cast themselves down as a fig that falleth from
off a fig tree
88 And after your testimony cometh wrath and
indignation upon the people
89 For after your testimony cometh the testimony
of earthquakes, that shall cause groanings in the
midst of her, and men shall fall upon the ground
and shall not be able to stand
90 And also cometh the testimony of the voice of
thunderings, and the voice of lightnings, and the
voice of tempests, and the voice of the waves of
the sea heaving themselves beyond their bounds
91 And all things shall be in commotion; and
surely, men’s hearts shall fail them; for fear shall
come upon all people
92 And angels shall fly through the midst of
heaven, crying with a loud voice, sounding the trump of
God, saying: Prepare ye, prepare ye, O
inhabitants of the earth; for the judgment of our God is
come. Behold, and lo, the Bridegroom cometh; go ye
out to meet him
93 And immediately there shall appear a great sign
in heaven, and all people shall see it together
94 And another angel shall sound his trump,
saying: That great church, the mother of abominations,
that made all nations drink of the wine of the
wrath of her fornication, that persecuteth the saints
of God, that shed their blood—she who sitteth upon
many waters, and upon the islands of the
sea—behold, she is the tares of the earth; she is bound in
bundles; her bands are made strong, no man can
loose them; therefore, she is ready to be burned.
And he shall sound his trump both long and loud, and
all nations shall hear it
95 And there shall be silence in heaven for the
space of half an hour; and immediately after shall
the curtain of heaven be unfolded, as a scroll is
unfolded after it is rolled up, and the face of the
Lord shall be unveiled
96 And the saints that are upon the earth, who are
alive, shall be quickened and be caught up to
meet him
97 And they who have slept in their graves shall
come forth, for their graves shall be opened; and
they also shall be caught up to meet him in the
midst of the pillar of heaven
98 They are Christ’s, the first fruits, they who
shall descend with him first, and they who are on
the earth and in their graves, who are first caught
up to meet him; and all this by the voice of the
sounding of the trump of the angel of God
99 And after this another angel shall sound, which
is the second trump; and then cometh the
redemption of those who are Christ’s at his coming; who
have received their part in that prison which is
prepared for them, that they might receive the
gospel, and be judged according to men in the flesh
100 And again, another trump shall sound, which is
the third trump; and then come the spirits of men
who are to be judged, and are found under
condemnation
101 And these are the rest of the dead; and they
live not again until the thousand years are ended,
neither again, until the end of the earth
102 And another trump shall sound, which is the
fourth trump, saying: There are found among those
who are to remain until that great and last day,
even the end, who shall remain filthy still
103 And another trump shall sound, which is the
fifth trump, which is the fifth angel who committeth
the everlasting gospel—flying through the midst
of heaven, unto all nations, kindreds, tongues, and
people
104 And this shall be the sound of his trump,
saying to all people, both in heaven and in earth, and
that are under the earth—for every ear shall hear
it, and every knee shall bow, and every tongue
shall confess, while they hear the sound of the
trump, saying: Fear God, and give glory to him who
sitteth upon the throne, forever and ever; for the
hour of his judgment is come
105 And again, another angel shall sound his
trump, which is the sixth angel, saying: She is fallen
who made all nations drink of the wine of the
wrath of her fornication; she is fallen, is fallen
106 And again, another angel shall sound his
trump, which is the seventh angel, saying: It is
finished; it is finished! The Lamb of God hath overcome
and trodden the wine-press alone, even the
wine-press of the fierceness of the wrath of Almighty
God
107 And then shall the angels be crowned with the
glory of his might, and the saints shall be filled
with his glory, and receive their inheritance and
be made equal with him
108 And then shall the first angel again sound his
trump in the ears of all living, and reveal the
secret acts of men, and the mighty works of God in
the first thousand years
109 And then shall the second angel sound his
trump, and reveal the secret acts of men, and the
thoughts and intents of their hearts, and the mighty
works of God in the second thousand years
110 And so on, until the seventh angel shall sound
his trump; and he shall stand forth upon the land
and upon the sea, and swear in the name of him
who sitteth upon the throne, that there shall be
time no longer; and Satan shall be bound, that old
serpent, who is called the devil, and shall not be
loosed for the space of a thousand years
111 And then he shall be loosed for a little
season, that he may gather together his armies
112 And Michael, the seventh angel, even the
archangel, shall gather together his armies, even the
hosts of heaven
113 And the devil shall gather together his
armies; even the hosts of hell, and shall come up to
battle against Michael and his armies
114 And then cometh the battle of the great God;
and the devil and his armies shall be cast away
into their own place, that they shall not have power
over the saints any more at all
115 For Michael shall fight their battles, and
shall overcome him who seeketh the throne of him who
sitteth upon the throne, even the Lamb
116 This is the glory of God, and the sanctified;
and they shall not any more see death
117 Therefore, verily I say unto you, my friends,
call your solemn assembly, as I have commanded
you
118 And as all have not faith, seek ye diligently
and teach one another words of wisdom; yea, seek
ye out of the best books words of wisdom; seek
learning, even by study and also by faith
119 Organize yourselves; prepare every needful
thing; and establish a house, even a house of prayer,
a house of fasting, a house of faith, a house of
learning, a house of glory, a house of order, a
house of God
120 That your incomings may be in the name of the
Lord; that your outgoings may be in the name of
the Lord; that all your salutations may be in the
name of the Lord, with uplifted hands unto the Most
High
121 Therefore, cease from all your light speeches,
from all laughter, from all your lustful desires,
from all your pride and light-mindedness, and
from all your wicked doings
122 Appoint among yourselves a teacher, and let
not all be spokesmen at once; but let one speak at a
time and let all listen unto his sayings, that
when all have spoken that all may be edified of all,
and that every man may have an equal privilege
123 See that ye love one another; cease to be
covetous; learn to impart one to another as the gospel
requires
124 Cease to be idle; cease to be unclean; cease
to find fault one with another; cease to sleep
longer than is needful; retire to thy bed early, that
ye may not be weary; arise early, that your bodies
and your minds may be invigorated
125 And above all things, clothe yourselves with
the bond of charity, as with a mantle, which is the
bond of perfectness and peace
126 Pray always, that ye may not faint, until I
come. Behold, and lo, I will come quickly, and
receive you unto myself. Amen
127 And again, the order of the house prepared for
the presidency of the school of the prophets,
established for their instruction in all things that
are expedient for them, even for all the officers
of the church, or in other words, those who are
called to the ministry in the church, beginning at
the high priests, even down to the deacons
128 And this shall be the order of the house of
the presidency of the school: He that is appointed
to be president, or teacher, shall be found
standing in his place, in the house which shall be
prepared for him
129 Therefore, he shall be first in the house of
God, in a place that the congregation in the house
may hear his words carefully and distinctly, not
with loud speech
130 And when he cometh into the house of God, for
he should be first in the house—behold, this is
beautiful, that he may be an example
131 Let him offer himself in prayer upon his knees
before God, in token or remembrance of the
everlasting covenant
132 And when any shall come in after him, let the
teacher arise, and, with uplifted hands to heaven,
yea, even directly, salute his brother or
brethren with these words
133 Art thou a brother or brethren? I salute you
in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, in token or
remembrance of the everlasting covenant, in which
covenant I receive you to fellowship, in a
determination that is fixed, immovable, and unchangeable,
to be your friend and brother through the grace of
God in the bonds of love, to walk in all the
commandments of God blameless, in thanksgiving,
forever and ever. Amen
134 And he that is found unworthy of this
salutation shall not have place among you; for ye shall
not suffer that mine house shall be polluted by him
135 And he that cometh in and is faithful before
me, and is a brother, or if they be brethren, they
shall salute the president or teacher with
uplifted hands to heaven, with this same prayer and
covenant, or by saying Amen, in token of the same
136 Behold, verily, I say unto you, this is an
ensample unto you for a salutation to one another in
the house of God, in the school of the prophets
137 And ye are called to do this by prayer and
thanksgiving, as the Spirit shall give utterance in
all your doings in the house of the Lord, in the
school of the prophets, that it may become a
sanctuary, a tabernacle of the Holy Spirit to your
edification
138 And ye shall not receive any among you into
this school save he is clean from the blood of this
generation
139 And he shall be received by the ordinance of
the washing of feet, for unto this end was the
ordinance of the washing of feet instituted
140 And again, the ordinance of washing feet is to
be administered by the president, or presiding
elder of the church
141 It is to be commenced with prayer; and after
partaking of bread and wine, he is to gird himself
according to the pattern given in the