Section 50 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, May 9, 1831. Joseph
Smith’s history states that some of the elders
did not understand the manifestations of different
spirits abroad in the earth and that this
revelation was given in response to his special inquiry on
the matter. So-called spiritual phenomena were not
uncommon among the members, some of whom claimed
to be receiving visions and revelations.
1–5,
Many false spirits are abroad in the earth;
6–9, Wo
unto the hypocrites and those who are cut off from
the Church;
10–14, Elders are to preach the
gospel by the Spirit;
15–22, Both preachers and
hearers need to be enlightened by the Spirit;
23–25,
That which doth not edify is not of God;
26–28,
The faithful are possessors of all things;
29–36,
The prayers of the purified are answered;
37–46,
Christ is the Good Shepherd and the Stone of
Israel.
1 Hearken, O ye elders of my church, and give ear
to the voice of the living God; and attend to the
words of wisdom which shall be given unto you,
according as ye have asked and are agreed as touching
the church, and the spirits which have gone
abroad in the earth
2 Behold, verily I say unto you, that there are
many spirits which are false spirits, which have
gone forth in the earth, deceiving the world
3 And also Satan hath sought to deceive you, that
he might overthrow you
4 Behold, I, the Lord, have looked upon you, and
have seen abominations in the church that profess
my name
5 But blessed are they who are faithful and
endure, whether in life or in death, for they shall
inherit eternal life
6 But wo unto them that are deceivers and
hypocrites, for, thus saith the Lord, I will bring them to
judgment
7 Behold, verily I say unto you, there are
hypocrites among you, who have deceived some, which has
given the adversary power; but behold such shall be
reclaimed
8 But the hypocrites shall be detected and shall
be cut off, either in life or in death, even as I
will; and wo unto them who are cut off from my
church, for the same are overcome of the world
9 Wherefore, let every man beware lest he do that
which is not in truth and righteousness before me
10 And now come, saith the Lord, by the Spirit,
unto the elders of his church, and let us reason
together, that ye may understand
11 Let us reason even as a man reasoneth one with
another face to face
12 Now, when a man reasoneth he is understood of
man, because he reasoneth as a man; even so will I,
the Lord, reason with you that you may
understand
13 Wherefore, I the Lord ask you this
question—unto what were ye ordained
14 To preach my gospel by the Spirit, even the
Comforter which was sent forth to teach the truth
15 And then received ye spirits which ye could not
understand, and received them to be of God; and
in this are ye justified
16 Behold ye shall answer this question
yourselves; nevertheless, I will be merciful unto you; he
that is weak among you hereafter shall be made
strong
17 Verily I say unto you, he that is ordained of
me and sent forth to preach the word of truth by
the Comforter, in the Spirit of truth, doth he
preach it by the Spirit of truth or some other way
18 And if it be by some other way it is not of
God
19 And again, he that receiveth the word of truth,
doth he receive it by the Spirit of truth or some
other way
20 If it be some other way it is not of God
21 Therefore, why is it that ye cannot understand
and know, that he that receiveth the word by the
Spirit of truth receiveth it as it is preached by
the Spirit of truth
22 Wherefore, he that preacheth and he that
receiveth, understand one another, and both are edified
and rejoice together
23 And that which doth not edify is not of God,
and is darkness
24 That which is of God is light; and he that
receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more
light; and that light groweth brighter and
brighter until the perfect day
25 And again, verily I say unto you, and I say it
that you may know the truth, that you may chase
darkness from among you
26 He that is ordained of God and sent forth, the
same is appointed to be the greatest,
notwithstanding he is the least and the servant of all
27 Wherefore, he is possessor of all things; for
all things are subject unto him, both in heaven and
on the earth, the life and the light, the Spirit
and the power, sent forth by the will of the
Father through Jesus Christ, his Son
28 But no man is possessor of all things except he
be purified and cleansed from all sin
29 And if ye are purified and cleansed from all
sin, ye shall ask whatsoever you will in the name of
Jesus and it shall be done
30 But know this, it shall be given you what you
shall ask; and as ye are appointed to the head, the
spirits shall be subject unto you
31 Wherefore, it shall come to pass, that if you
behold a spirit manifested that you cannot
understand, and you receive not that spirit, ye shall ask
of the Father in the name of Jesus; and if he give
not unto you that spirit, then you may know that
it is not of God
32 And it shall be given unto you, power over that
spirit; and you shall proclaim against that
spirit with a loud voice that it is not of God
33 Not with railing accusation, that ye be not
overcome, neither with boasting nor rejoicing, lest
you be seized therewith
34 He that receiveth of God, let him account it of
God; and let him rejoice that he is accounted of
God worthy to receive
35 And by giving heed and doing these things which
ye have received, and which ye shall hereafter
receive—and the kingdom is given you of the Father,
and power to overcome all things which are not
ordained of him
36 And behold, verily I say unto you, blessed are
you who are now hearing these words of mine from
the mouth of my servant, for your sins are forgiven
you
37 Let my servant Joseph Wakefield, in whom I am
well pleased, and my servant Parley P. Pratt go
forth among the churches and strengthen them by the
word of exhortation
38 And also my servant John Corrill, or as many of
my servants as are ordained unto this office, and
let them labor in the vineyard; and let no man
hinder them doing that which I have appointed unto
them
39 Wherefore, in this thing my servant Edward
Partridge is not justified; nevertheless let him
repent and he shall be forgiven
40 Behold, ye are little children and ye cannot
bear all things now; ye must grow in grace and in
the knowledge of the truth
41 Fear not, little children, for you are mine,
and I have overcome the world, and you are of them
that my Father hath given me
42 And none of them that my Father hath given me
shall be lost
43 And the Father and I are one. I am in the
Father and the Father in me; and inasmuch as ye have
received me, ye are in me and I in you
44 Wherefore, I am in your midst, and I am the
good shepherd, and the stone of Israel. He that
buildeth upon this rock shall never fall
45 And the day cometh that you shall hear my voice
and see me, and know that I am
46 Watch, therefore, that ye may be ready. Even
so. Amen.