Section 32 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Parley P. Pratt and Ziba
Peterson, in Manchester, New York, early October 1830.
Great interest and desires were felt by the
elders respecting the Lamanites, of whose predicted
blessings the Church had learned from the Book
of Mormon. In consequence, supplication was made
that the Lord would indicate His will as to
whether elders should be sent at that time to the
Indian tribes in the West. The revelation
followed.
1–3, Parley P. Pratt and Ziba Peterson are
called to preach to the Lamanites and to accompany
Oliver Cowdery and Peter Whitmer Jr.;
4–5,
They are to pray for an understanding of the scriptures.
1 And now concerning my servant Parley P.
Pratt, behold, I say unto him that as I live
I will that he shall declare my gospel and
learn of me, and be meek and lowly of heart.
2 And that which I have appointed unto
him is that he shall go with my servants,
Oliver Cowdery and Peter Whitmer, Jun.,
into the wilderness among the Lamanites.
3 And Ziba Peterson also shall go
with them; and I myself will go with
them and be in their midst; and I
am their advocate with the Father,
and nothing shall prevail against them.
4 And they shall give heed to
that which is written, and pretend
to no other revelation; and they
shall pray always that I may
unfold the same to their understanding.
5 And they shall give heed
unto these words and trifle
not, and I will bless them. Amen.