Section 21 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Fayette, New York, April 6, 1830. This
revelation was given at the organization of the
Church, on the date named, in the home of Peter
Whitmer Sr. Six men, who had previously been
baptized, participated. By unanimous vote these
persons expressed their desire and determination to
organize, according to the commandment of God (see
section 20). They also voted to accept and
sustain Joseph Smith Jr. and Oliver Cowdery as the
presiding officers of the Church. With the laying on
of hands, Joseph then ordained Oliver an elder of
the Church, and Oliver similarly ordained
Joseph. After administration of the sacrament, Joseph
and Oliver laid hands upon the participants
individually for the bestowal of the Holy Ghost and for
the confirmation of each as a member of the
Church.
1–3, Joseph Smith is called to be a seer,
translator, prophet, apostle, and elder;
4–8, His
word will guide the cause of Zion;
9–12, The
Saints will believe his words as he speaks by the Comforter.
1 Behold, there shall be a record kept among
you; and in it thou shalt be called a seer, a
translator, a prophet, an apostle of Jesus Christ, an
elder of the church through the will of God the
Father, and the grace of your Lord Jesus Christ,
2 Being inspired of the Holy Ghost
to lay the foundation thereof, and to
build it up unto the most holy faith.
3 Which church was organized and
established in the year of your Lord
eighteen hundred and thirty, in the
fourth month, and on the sixth day
of the month which is called April.
4 Wherefore, meaning the church,
thou shalt give heed unto all his
words and commandments which he shall
give unto you as he receiveth them,
walking in all holiness before me;
5 For his word ye shall
receive, as if from mine own
mouth, in all patience and faith.
6 For by doing these things
the gates of hell shall
not prevail against you; yea,
and the Lord God will
disperse the powers of darkness
from before you, and cause
the heavens to shake for
your good, and his name’s glory.
7 For thus saith the Lord
God: Him have I inspired
to move the cause of Zion
in mighty power for good,
and his diligence I know,
and his prayers I have heard.
8 Yea, his weeping for
Zion I have seen, and I
will cause that he shall
mourn for her no longer;
for his days of
rejoicing are come unto the
remission of his sins, and
the manifestations of my
blessings upon his works.
9 For, behold, I will
bless all those who labor
in my vineyard with a
mighty blessing, and they
shall believe on his
words, which are given him
through me by the
Comforter, which manifesteth
that Jesus was crucified
by sinful men for the
sins of the world, yea,
for the remission of sins
unto the contrite heart.
10 Wherefore it
behooveth me that he should be
ordained by you,
Oliver Cowdery mine apostle;
11 This being an
ordinance unto you, that
you are an elder
under his hand, he being
the first unto you,
that you might be an
elder unto this church
of Christ, bearing my name—
12 And the first
preacher of this
church unto the church,
and before the
world, yea, before the
Gentiles; yea, and
thus saith the
Lord God, lo, lo! to
the Jews also. Amen.