Section 114 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Far West, Missouri, April
11, 1838.
1–2, Church positions held by those
who are not faithful will be given to others.
1 Verily thus saith the Lord: It is wisdom
in my servant David W. Patten, that he
settle up all his business as soon as he
possibly can, and make a disposition of his
merchandise, that he may perform a mission unto
me next spring, in company with others,
even twelve including himself, to testify of
my name and bear glad tidings unto all the world.
2 For verily thus saith the Lord, that
inasmuch as there are those among you who
deny my name, others shall be planted in
their stead and receive their bishopric. Amen.