Section 110 Visions manifested to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Oliver Cowdery in the temple at
Kirtland, Ohio, April 3, 1836. The occasion was that of
a Sabbath day meeting. Joseph Smith’s history
states: “In the afternoon, I assisted the other
Presidents in distributing the Lord’s Supper to the
Church, receiving it from the Twelve, whose privilege
it was to officiate at the sacred desk this day.
After having performed this service to my
brethren, I retired to the pulpit, the veils being
dropped, and bowed myself, with Oliver Cowdery, in solemn
and silent prayer. After rising from prayer, the
following vision was opened to both of us.”
1–10,
The Lord Jehovah appears in glory and accepts the
Kirtland Temple as His house;
11–12, Moses and
Elias each appear and commit their keys and
dispensations;
13–16, Elijah returns and commits the
keys of his dispensation as promised by Malachi.
1 The veil was taken from our minds, and the eyes
of our understanding were opened
2 We saw the Lord standing upon the breastwork of
the pulpit, before us; and under his feet was a
paved work of pure gold, in color like amber
3 His eyes were as a flame of fire; the hair of
his head was white like the pure snow; his
countenance shone above the brightness of the sun; and his
voice was as the sound of the rushing of great
waters, even the voice of Jehovah, saying
4 I am the first and the last; I am he who liveth,
I am he who was slain; I am your advocate with
the Father
5 Behold, your sins are forgiven you; you are
clean before me; therefore, lift up your heads and
rejoice
6 Let the hearts of your brethren rejoice, and let
the hearts of all my people rejoice, who have,
with their might, built this house to my name
7 For behold, I have accepted this house, and my
name shall be here; and I will manifest myself to
my people in mercy in this house
8 Yea, I will appear unto my servants, and speak
unto them with mine own voice, if my people will
keep my commandments, and do not pollute this holy
house
9 Yea the hearts of thousands and tens of
thousands shall greatly rejoice in consequence of the
blessings which shall be poured out, and the endowment
with which my servants have been endowed in this
house
10 And the fame of this house shall spread to
foreign lands; and this is the beginning of the
blessing which shall be poured out upon the heads of my
people. Even so. Amen
11 After this vision closed, the heavens were
again opened unto us; and Moses appeared before us,
and committed unto us the keys of the gathering of
Israel from the four parts of the earth, and the
leading of the ten tribes from the land of the
north
12 After this, Elias appeared, and committed the
dispensation of the gospel of Abraham, saying that
in us and our seed all generations after us should
be blessed
13 After this vision had closed, another great and
glorious vision burst upon us; for Elijah the
prophet, who was taken to heaven without tasting
death, stood before us, and said
14 Behold, the time has fully come, which was
spoken of by the mouth of Malachi—testifying that he
[Elijah] should be sent, before the great and
dreadful day of the Lord come
15 To turn the hearts of the fathers to the
children, and the children to the fathers, lest the
whole earth be smitten with a curse
16 Therefore, the keys of this dispensation are
committed into your hands; and by this ye may know
that the great and dreadful day of the Lord is
near, even at the doors.