Section 98 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, August 6, 1833.
This revelation came in consequence of the
persecution upon the Saints in Missouri. Increased
settlement of Church members in Missouri troubled some
other settlers, who felt threatened by the Saints’
numbers, political and economic influence, and
cultural and religious differences. In July 1833, a mob
destroyed Church property, tarred and feathered
two Church members, and demanded that the Saints
leave Jackson County. Although some news of the
problems in Missouri had no doubt reached the Prophet
in Kirtland (nine hundred miles away), the
seriousness of the situation could have been known to him
at this date only by revelation.
1–3, The
afflictions of the Saints will be for their good;
4–8,
The Saints are to befriend the constitutional law
of the land;
9–10, Honest, wise, and good men
should be supported for secular government;
11–15,
Those who lay down their lives in the Lord’s cause
will have eternal life;
16–18, Renounce war and
proclaim peace;
19–22, The Saints in Kirtland are
reproved and commanded to repent;
23–32, The Lord
reveals His laws governing the persecutions and
afflictions imposed on His people;
33–38, War is
justified only when the Lord commands it;
39–48,
The Saints are to forgive their enemies, who, if
they repent, will also escape the Lord’s vengeance.
1 Verily I say unto you my friends, fear not, let
your hearts be comforted; yea, rejoice evermore,
and in everything give thanks
2 Waiting patiently on the Lord, for your prayers
have entered into the ears of the Lord of Sabaoth,
and are recorded with this seal and testament—the
Lord hath sworn and decreed that they shall be
granted
3 Therefore, he giveth this promise unto you, with
an immutable covenant that they shall be
fulfilled; and all things wherewith you have been
afflicted shall work together for your good, and to my
name’s glory, saith the Lord
4 And now, verily I say unto you concerning the
laws of the land, it is my will that my people
should observe to do all things whatsoever I command
them
5 And that law of the land which is
constitutional, supporting that principle of freedom in
maintaining rights and privileges, belongs to all mankind,
and is justifiable before me
6 Therefore, I, the Lord, justify you, and your
brethren of my church, in befriending that law which
is the constitutional law of the land
7 And as pertaining to law of man, whatsoever is
more or less than this, cometh of evil
8 I, the Lord God, make you free, therefore ye are
free indeed; and the law also maketh you free
9 Nevertheless, when the wicked rule the people
mourn
10 Wherefore, honest men and wise men should be
sought for diligently, and good men and wise men ye
should observe to uphold; otherwise whatsoever is
less than these cometh of evil
11 And I give unto you a commandment, that ye
shall forsake all evil and cleave unto all good, that
ye shall live by every word which proceedeth forth
out of the mouth of God
12 For he will give unto the faithful line upon
line, precept upon precept; and I will try you and
prove you herewith
13 And whoso layeth down his life in my cause, for
my name’s sake, shall find it again, even life
eternal
14 Therefore, be not afraid of your enemies, for I
have decreed in my heart, saith the Lord, that I
will prove you in all things, whether you will
abide in my covenant, even unto death, that you may
be found worthy
15 For if ye will not abide in my covenant ye are
not worthy of me
16 Therefore, renounce war and proclaim peace, and
seek diligently to turn the hearts of the
children to their fathers, and the hearts of the fathers
to the children
17 And again, the hearts of the Jews unto the
prophets, and the prophets unto the Jews; lest I come
and smite the whole earth with a curse, and all
flesh be consumed before me
18 Let not your hearts be troubled; for in my
Father’s house are many mansions, and I have prepared
a place for you; and where my Father and I am,
there ye shall be also
19 Behold, I, the Lord, am not well pleased with
many who are in the church at Kirtland
20 For they do not forsake their sins, and their
wicked ways, the pride of their hearts, and their
covetousness, and all their detestable things, and
observe the words of wisdom and eternal life which
I have given unto them
21 Verily I say unto you, that I, the Lord, will
chasten them and will do whatsoever I list, if they
do not repent and observe all things whatsoever I
have said unto them
22 And again I say unto you, if ye observe to do
whatsoever I command you, I, the Lord, will turn
away all wrath and indignation from you, and the
gates of hell shall not prevail against you
23 Now, I speak unto you concerning your
families—if men will smite you, or your families, once, and
ye bear it patiently and revile not against them,
neither seek revenge, ye shall be rewarded
24 But if ye bear it not patiently, it shall be
accounted unto you as being meted out as a just
measure unto you
25 And again, if your enemy shall smite you the
second time, and you revile not against your enemy,
and bear it patiently, your reward shall be an
hundred-fold
26 And again, if he shall smite you the third
time, and ye bear it patiently, your reward shall be
doubled unto you four-fold
27 And these three testimonies shall stand against
your enemy if he repent not, and shall not be
blotted out
28 And now, verily I say unto you, if that enemy
shall escape my vengeance, that he be not brought
into judgment before me, then ye shall see to it
that ye warn him in my name, that he come no more
upon you, neither upon your family, even your
children’s children unto the third and fourth
generation
29 And then, if he shall come upon you or your
children, or your children’s children unto the third
and fourth generation, I have delivered thine
enemy into thine hands
30 And then if thou wilt spare him, thou shalt be
rewarded for thy righteousness; and also thy
children and thy children’s children unto the third and
fourth generation
31 Nevertheless, thine enemy is in thine hands;
and if thou rewardest him according to his works
thou art justified; if he has sought thy life, and
thy life is endangered by him, thine enemy is in
thine hands and thou art justified
32 Behold, this is the law I gave unto my servant
Nephi, and thy fathers, Joseph, and Jacob, and
Isaac, and Abraham, and all mine ancient prophets and
apostles
33 And again, this is the law that I gave unto
mine ancients, that they should not go out unto
battle against any nation, kindred, tongue, or people,
save I, the Lord, commanded them
34 And if any nation, tongue, or people should
proclaim war against them, they should first lift a
standard of peace unto that people, nation, or
tongue
35 And if that people did not accept the offering
of peace, neither the second nor the third time,
they should bring these testimonies before the
Lord
36 Then I, the Lord, would give unto them a
commandment, and justify them in going out to battle
against that nation, tongue, or people
37 And I, the Lord, would fight their battles, and
their children’s battles, and their children’s
children’s, until they had avenged themselves on all
their enemies, to the third and fourth
generation
38 Behold, this is an ensample unto all people,
saith the Lord your God, for justification before
me
39 And again, verily I say unto you, if after
thine enemy has come upon thee the first time, he
repent and come unto thee praying thy forgiveness,
thou shalt forgive him, and shalt hold it no more as
a testimony against thine enemy
40 And so on unto the second and third time; and
as oft as thine enemy repenteth of the trespass
wherewith he has trespassed against thee, thou shalt
forgive him, until seventy times seven
41 And if he trespass against thee and repent not
the first time, nevertheless thou shalt forgive
him
42 And if he trespass against thee the second
time, and repent not, nevertheless thou shalt forgive
him
43 And if he trespass against thee the third time,
and repent not, thou shalt also forgive him
44 But if he trespass against thee the fourth time
thou shalt not forgive him, but shalt bring these
testimonies before the Lord; and they shall not
be blotted out until he repent and reward thee
four-fold in all things wherewith he has trespassed
against thee
45 And if he do this, thou shalt forgive him with
all thine heart; and if he do not this, I, the
Lord, will avenge thee of thine enemy an
hundred-fold
46 And upon his children, and upon his children’s
children of all them that hate me, unto the third
and fourth generation
47 But if the children shall repent, or the
children’s children, and turn to the Lord their God,
with all their hearts and with all their might, mind,
and strength, and restore four-fold for all their
trespasses wherewith they have trespassed, or
wherewith their fathers have trespassed, or their
fathers’ fathers, then thine indignation shall be
turned away
48 And vengeance shall no more come upon them,
saith the Lord thy God, and their trespasses shall
never be brought any more as a testimony before the
Lord against them. Amen.