Section 31 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Thomas B. Marsh, September 1830. The
occasion was immediately following a conference
of the Church (see the
heading to section 30).
Thomas B. Marsh had been baptized earlier in the
month and had been ordained an elder in the Church
before this revelation was given.
1–6, Thomas B.
Marsh is called to preach the gospel and is assured
of his family’s well-being;
7–13, He is counseled
to be patient, pray always, and follow the
Comforter.
1 Thomas, my son, blessed are you because of your
faith in my work
2 Behold, you have had many afflictions because of
your family; nevertheless, I will bless you and
your family, yea, your little ones; and the day
cometh that they will believe and know the truth and
be one with you in my church
3 Lift up your heart and rejoice, for the hour of
your mission is come; and your tongue shall be
loosed, and you shall declare glad tidings of great
joy unto this generation
4 You shall declare the things which have been
revealed to my servant, Joseph Smith, Jun. You shall
begin to preach from this time forth, yea, to reap
in the field which is white already to be burned
5 Therefore, thrust in your sickle with all your
soul, and your sins are forgiven you, and you shall
be laden with sheaves upon your back, for the
laborer is worthy of his hire. Wherefore, your family
shall live
6 Behold, verily I say unto you, go from them only
for a little time, and declare my word, and I
will prepare a place for them
7 Yea, I will open the hearts of the people, and
they will receive you. And I will establish a
church by your hand
8 And you shall strengthen them and prepare them
against the time when they shall be gathered
9 Be patient in afflictions, revile not against
those that revile. Govern your house in meekness,
and be steadfast
10 Behold, I say unto you that you shall be a
physician unto the church, but not unto the world, for
they will not receive you
11 Go your way whithersoever I will, and it shall
be given you by the Comforter what you shall do
and whither you shall go
12 Pray always, lest you enter into temptation and
lose your reward
13 Be faithful unto the end, and lo, I am with
you. These words are not of man nor of men, but of
me, even Jesus Christ, your Redeemer, by the will of
the Father. Amen.