Section 35 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at or near Fayette,
New York, December 7, 1830. At this time, the
Prophet was engaged almost daily in making a
translation of the Bible. The translation was begun as
early as June 1830, and both Oliver Cowdery and
John Whitmer had served as scribes. Since they
had now been called to other duties, Sidney
Rigdon was called by divine appointment to serve as
the Prophet’s scribe in this work (see
verse 20). As a preface to the record of this
revelation, Joseph Smith’s history states: “In December
Sidney Rigdon came [from Ohio] to inquire of the
Lord, and with him came Edward Partridge. …
Shortly after the arrival of these two brethren, thus
spake the Lord.”
1–2, How men may become the
sons of God;
3–7, Sidney Rigdon is called to
baptize and to confer the Holy Ghost;
8–12, Signs
and miracles are wrought by faith;
13–16, The
Lord’s servants will thresh the nations by the
power of the Spirit;
17–19, Joseph Smith holds
the keys of the mysteries;
20–21, The elect will
abide the day of the Lord’s coming;
22–27, Israel will be saved.
1 Listen to the voice of the Lord your
God, even Alpha and Omega, the beginning and
the end, whose course is one eternal
round, the same today as yesterday, and forever.
2 I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God, who
was crucified for the sins of the world,
even as many as will believe on my name,
that they may become the sons of God,
even one in me as I am one in the Father, as
the Father is one in me, that we may be one.
3 Behold, verily, verily, I say unto my
servant Sidney, I have looked upon
thee and thy works. I have heard thy
prayers, and prepared thee for a greater work.
4 Thou art blessed, for thou shalt do
great things. Behold thou wast sent
forth, even as John, to prepare the
way before me, and before Elijah which
should come, and thou knewest it not.
5 Thou didst baptize by
water unto repentance, but they
received not the Holy Ghost;
6 But now I give unto
thee a commandment, that
thou shalt baptize by
water, and they shall
receive the Holy Ghost by the
laying on of the hands,
even as the apostles of old.
7 And it shall come to
pass that there shall
be a great work in the
land, even among the
Gentiles, for their folly
and their abominations
shall be made manifest
in the eyes of all people.
8 For I am God, and
mine arm is not
shortened; and I will show
miracles, signs, and
wonders, unto all
those who believe on my name.
9 And whoso shall
ask it in my name in
faith, they shall
cast out devils;
they shall heal the
sick; they shall
cause the blind to
receive their sight,
and the deaf to
hear, and the dumb to
speak, and the lame to walk.
10 And the time
speedily cometh
that great
things are to be
shown forth unto the
children of men;
11 But without
faith shall not
anything be
shown forth
except desolations
upon Babylon,
the same which
has made all
nations drink of
the wine of the
wrath of her fornication.
12 And there
are none that
doeth good
except those who
are ready to
receive the
fulness of my
gospel, which I
have sent forth
unto this generation.
Wherefore, I call
upon the weak
things of the
world,
those who are
unlearned and
despised, to
thresh the
nations by
the power of my Spirit;
14 And
their arm shall
be my arm,
and I will
be their
shield and
their
buckler; and I
will gird up
their
loins, and they
shall fight
manfully
for me; and
their
enemies shall be
under
their feet; and
I will let
fall the
sword in
their behalf,
and by the
fire of
mine indignation will I preserve them.
15 And the
poor and
the meek
shall have
the gospel
preached
unto them,
and they
shall be
looking
forth for the
time of
my coming,
for it is nigh at hand—
16 And
they shall
learn the
parable
of the
fig tree,
for even
now
already summer is nigh.
17 And I
have
sent forth
the
fulness of
my
gospel by the
hand of
my
servant
Joseph; and
in
weakness have
I blessed him;
18 And
I have
given
unto him
the
keys of
mystery of
those
things
which
have been
sealed, even
things
which
were
from the
foundation of
the
world, and
things
which
shall come
from
this time
until
the
time of my
coming, if he
abide
in me,
and if
not, another will I plant in his stead.
Wherefore,
watch over
him
that
his
faith fail
not,
and it
shall
be
given by
the
Comforter,
the Holy
Ghost, that
knoweth all things.
And a
commandment
I
give
unto
thee—that
thou
shalt
write
for
him;
and
the
scriptures
shall
be
given,
even
as
they are
in
mine
own
bosom,
to
the salvation of mine own elect;
For
they
will
hear my
voice,
and
shall
see
me,
and
shall
not
be
asleep,
and
shall
abide
the
day
of my
coming;
for
they
shall be purified, even as I am pure.
And
now I
say
unto
you,
tarry
with
him,
and
he
shall
journey
with
you;
forsake
him
not,
and
surely these things shall be fulfilled.
And
inasmuch
as
ye
do
not
write,
behold,
it
shall
be
given
unto
him
to
prophesy;
and
thou
shalt
preach
my
gospel
and
call
on
the holy prophets to prove his words, as they shall be given him.
Keep
all
the
commandments
and
covenants
by
which
ye
are
bound;
and
I
will
cause
the
heavens
to
shake
for
your
good,
and
Satan
shall
tremble
and
Zion
shall
rejoice
upon
the
hills
and
flourish;
And
Israel
shall
be
saved
in
mine
own
due
time;
and
by
the
keys
which
I
have
given
shall
they
be
led,
and
no
more
be
confounded
at
all.
26 Lift up your hearts and be glad, your redemption draweth
Lift
up
your
hearts
and
be
glad, your redemption draweth nigh.
27 Fear not, little flock, the kingdom is yours until I come. Behold, I come quickly. Even so. Amen.
Fear
not,
little
flock,
the
kingdom
is
yours
until
I
come.
Behold,
I
come
quickly.
Even
so.
Amen.