Section 16 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Peter Whitmer Jr., at Fayette, New
York, June 1829 (see the
heading to section 14).
Peter Whitmer Jr. later became one of the Eight
Witnesses to the Book of Mormon.
1–2, The Lord’s arm
is over all the earth;
3–6, To preach the gospel
and save souls is the thing of most worth.
1 Hearken, my servant Peter, and listen to the
words of Jesus Christ, your Lord and your Redeemer
2 For behold, I speak unto you with sharpness and
with power, for mine arm is over all the earth
3 And I will tell you that which no man knoweth
save me and thee alone
4 For many times you have desired of me to know
that which would be of the most worth unto you
5 Behold, blessed are you for this thing, and for
speaking my words which I have given unto you
according to my commandments
6 And now, behold, I say unto you, that the thing
which will be of the most worth unto you will be
to declare repentance unto this people, that you
may bring souls unto me, that you may rest with them
in the kingdom of my Father. Amen.