Section 11 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to his brother Hyrum Smith, at
Harmony, Pennsylvania, May 1829. This revelation was
received through the Urim and Thummim in answer
to Joseph’s supplication and inquiry. Joseph
Smith’s history suggests that this revelation was
received after the restoration of the Aaronic
Priesthood.
1–6, Laborers in the vineyard will
gain salvation;
7–14, Seek wisdom, cry
repentance, trust in the Spirit;
15–22, Keep the
commandments, and study the Lord’s word;
23–27, Deny
not the spirit of revelation and of prophecy;
28–30, Those who receive Christ become the sons of God.
1 A great and marvelous work is about
to come forth among the children of men.
2 Behold, I am God; give heed to my
word, which is quick and powerful,
sharper than a two-edged sword, to the
dividing asunder of both joints and
marrow; therefore give heed unto my word.
3 Behold, the field is white
already to harvest; therefore, whoso
desireth to reap let him thrust in
his sickle with his might, and reap
while the day lasts, that he may
treasure up for his soul
everlasting salvation in the kingdom of God.
4 Yea, whosoever will
thrust in his sickle and reap,
the same is called of God.
5 Therefore, if you will
ask of me you shall
receive; if you will knock it
shall be opened unto you.
6 Now, as you have
asked, behold, I say
unto you, keep my
commandments, and seek to
bring forth and
establish the cause of Zion.
7 Seek not for
riches but for wisdom;
and, behold, the
mysteries of God
shall be unfolded unto
you, and then shall
you be made rich.
Behold, he that
hath eternal life is rich.
8 Verily, verily,
I say unto you,
even as you desire
of me so it shall
be done unto you;
and, if you desire,
you shall be the
means of doing
much good in this generation.
9 Say nothing
but repentance
unto this
generation. Keep my
commandments, and
assist to bring
forth my work,
according to my
commandments, and
you shall be blessed.
10 Behold,
thou hast a gift,
or thou shalt
have a gift
if thou wilt
desire of me in
faith, with an
honest heart,
believing in
the power of
Jesus Christ,
or in my power
which speaketh unto thee;
11 For,
behold, it is I
that speak;
behold, I am the
light which
shineth in
darkness, and
by my power I
give these
words unto thee.
12 And now,
verily,
verily, I say
unto thee, put
your trust
in that
Spirit which
leadeth to do
good—yea, to
do justly,
to walk
humbly, to judge
righteously;
and this is my Spirit.
13 Verily,
verily, I
say unto
you, I will
impart unto
you of my
Spirit, which
shall
enlighten your
mind, which
shall fill
your soul with joy;
14 And
then shall ye
know, or
by this
shall you
know, all
things
whatsoever you
desire of
me, which
are
pertaining unto
things of
righteousness, in
faith
believing in me
that you shall receive.
Behold, I
command you
that you
need not
suppose
that you are
called
to preach
until you
are called.
16 Wait
a little
longer,
until
you shall
have my
word,
my rock,
my
church, and
gospel, that
you may
know of a
surety my doctrine.
17 And
then,
behold,
according to
your
desires,
yea,
even
according to
your
faith
shall it
be done unto you.
Keep my
commandments;
hold
your
peace;
appeal
unto
my Spirit;
Yea,
cleave
unto
me
with
all
your
heart,
that
you
may
assist
in
bringing
to
light
those
things of
which has
been
spoken—yea,
the
translation
of my
work;
be
patient until you shall accomplish it.
Behold,
this
is
your
work, to
keep my
commandments,
yea,
with
all
your
might, mind and strength.
Seek
not
to
declare
my
word,
but
first
seek
to
obtain
my
word,
and
then
shall
your
tongue
be
loosed;
then, if
you
desire,
shall
have
my
Spirit
and my
word,
yea,
the
power of
God
unto
the
convincing
of
men.
But
now
hold
your
peace;
study
my
word
which
hath
gone
forth
among
the
children
of
men,
and
also
study
my
word
which
shall
come
forth
among
the
children
of
men,
or
that
which
is
now
translating,
yea,
until
you
have
obtained
all
which
I
shall
grant
unto the children of men in this generation, and then shall all things be added thereto.
Behold
thou
art
Hyrum,
my
son;
seek
the
kingdom
of
God,
and
all
things
shall
be added according to that which is just.
Build
upon
my
rock,
which
is
my
gospel;
Deny
not
the
spirit
of
revelation,
nor
the
spirit
of
prophecy,
for
wo
unto
him
that
denieth
these
things;
26 Therefore, treasure up in your heart until the time which is in my wisdom that you shall go
Therefore,
treasure
up
in
your
heart
until
the
time which is in my wisdom that you shall go forth.
27 Behold, I speak unto all who have good desires, and have thrust in their sickle to
Behold,
I
speak
unto
all
who
have
good
desires,
and
have
thrust
in
their
sickle
to
reap.
28 Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God. I am the life and the light of the
Behold,
I
am
Jesus
Christ,
the
Son
of
God.
I
am
the
life
and
the
light
of
the
world.
29 I am the same who came unto mine own and mine own received me
I
am
the
same
who
came
unto
mine
own
and
mine
own
received
me
not;
30 But verily, verily, I say unto you, that as many as receive me, to them will I give power to become the sons of God, even to them that believe on my name. Amen.
But
verily,
I
say
unto
you,
that
as
many
receive
me,
to
them
will
I
give
power
to
become
the
sons
of
God,
even
to
them
that
believe
on
my
name.
Amen.