Section 15 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to John Whitmer, at Fayette, New York,
June 1829 (see the
heading to section 14). The
message is intimately and impressively personal in
that the Lord tells of what was known only to John
Whitmer and Himself. John Whitmer later became one
of the Eight Witnesses to the Book of Mormon.
1–2, The Lord’s arm is over all the earth;
3–6, To
preach the gospel and save souls is the thing of
most worth.
1 Hearken, my servant John, and listen to the
words of Jesus Christ, your Lord and your Redeemer
2 For behold, I speak unto you with sharpness and
with power, for mine arm is over all the earth
3 And I will tell you that which no man knoweth
save me and thee alone
4 For many times you have desired of me to know
that which would be of the most worth unto you
5 Behold, blessed are you for this thing, and for
speaking my words which I have given you according
to my commandments
6 And now, behold, I say unto you, that the thing
which will be of the most worth unto you will be
to declare repentance unto this people, that you
may bring souls unto me, that you may rest with them
in the kingdom of my Father. Amen.