Section 84 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, September 22 and
23, 1832. During the month of September, elders had
begun to return from their missions in the eastern
states and to make reports of their labors. It
was while they were together in this season of joy
that the following communication was received. The
Prophet designated it a revelation on priesthood.
1–5, The New Jerusalem and the temple will be
built in Missouri;
6–17, The line of priesthood from
Moses to Adam is given;
18–25, The greater
priesthood holds the key of the knowledge of God;
26–32, The lesser priesthood holds the key of the
ministering of angels and of the preparatory gospel;
33–44, Men gain eternal life through the oath and
covenant of the priesthood;
45–53, The Spirit of
Christ enlightens men, and the world lies in sin;
54–61, The Saints must testify of those things
they have received;
62–76, They are to preach the
gospel, and signs will follow;
77–91, Elders are
to go forth without purse or scrip, and the Lord
will care for their needs;
92–97, Plagues and
cursings await those who reject the gospel;
98–102,
The new song of the redemption of Zion is given;
103–10, Let every man stand in his own office and
labor in his own calling;
111–20, The Lord’s
servants are to proclaim the abomination of desolation
of the last days.
1 A revelation of Jesus Christ unto his servant
Joseph Smith, Jun., and six elders, as they united
their hearts and lifted their voices on high
2 Yea, the word of the Lord concerning his church,
established in the last days for the restoration
of his people, as he has spoken by the mouth of
his prophets, and for the gathering of his saints to
stand upon Mount Zion, which shall be the city of
New Jerusalem
3 Which city shall be built, beginning at the
temple lot, which is appointed by the finger of the
Lord, in the western boundaries of the State of
Missouri, and dedicated by the hand of Joseph Smith,
Jun., and others with whom the Lord was well
pleased
4 Verily this is the word of the Lord, that the
city New Jerusalem shall be built by the gathering
of the saints, beginning at this place, even the
place of the temple, which temple shall be reared in
this generation
5 For verily this generation shall not all pass
away until an house shall be built unto the Lord,
and a cloud shall rest upon it, which cloud shall be
even the glory of the Lord, which shall fill the
house
6 And the sons of Moses, according to the Holy
Priesthood which he received under the hand of his
father-in-law, Jethro
7 And Jethro received it under the hand of Caleb
8 And Caleb received it under the hand of Elihu
9 And Elihu under the hand of Jeremy
10 And Jeremy under the hand of Gad
11 And Gad under the hand of Esaias
12 And Esaias received it under the hand of God
13 Esaias also lived in the days of Abraham, and
was blessed of him
14 Which Abraham received the priesthood from
Melchizedek, who received it through the lineage of
his fathers, even till Noah
15 And from Noah till Enoch, through the lineage
of their fathers
16 And from Enoch to Abel, who was slain by the
conspiracy of his brother, who received the
priesthood by the commandments of God, by the hand of his
father Adam, who was the first man
17 Which priesthood continueth in the church of
God in all generations, and is without beginning of
days or end of years
18 And the Lord confirmed a priesthood also upon
Aaron and his seed, throughout all their
generations, which priesthood also continueth and abideth
forever with the priesthood which is after the
holiest order of God
19 And this greater priesthood administereth the
gospel and holdeth the key of the mysteries of the
kingdom, even the key of the knowledge of God
20 Therefore, in the ordinances thereof, the power
of godliness is manifest
21 And without the ordinances thereof, and the
authority of the priesthood, the power of godliness
is not manifest unto men in the flesh
22 For without this no man can see the face of
God, even the Father, and live
23 Now this Moses plainly taught to the children
of Israel in the wilderness, and sought diligently
to sanctify his people that they might behold the
face of God
24 But they hardened their hearts and could not
endure his presence; therefore, the Lord in his
wrath, for his anger was kindled against them, swore
that they should not enter into his rest while in
the wilderness, which rest is the fulness of his
glory
25 Therefore, he took Moses out of their midst,
and the Holy Priesthood also
26 And the lesser priesthood continued, which
priesthood holdeth the key of the ministering of
angels and the preparatory gospel
27 Which gospel is the gospel of repentance and of
baptism, and the remission of sins, and the law
of carnal commandments, which the Lord in his wrath
caused to continue with the house of Aaron among
the children of Israel until John, whom God raised
up, being filled with the Holy Ghost from his
mother’s womb
28 For he was baptized while he was yet in his
childhood, and was ordained by the angel of God at
the time he was eight days old unto this power, to
overthrow the kingdom of the Jews, and to make
straight the way of the Lord before the face of his
people, to prepare them for the coming of the Lord,
in whose hand is given all power
29 And again, the offices of elder and bishop are
necessary appendages belonging unto the high
priesthood
30 And again, the offices of teacher and deacon
are necessary appendages belonging to the lesser
priesthood, which priesthood was confirmed upon Aaron
and his sons
31 Therefore, as I said concerning the sons of
Moses—for the sons of Moses and also the sons of
Aaron shall offer an acceptable offering and sacrifice
in the house of the Lord, which house shall be
built unto the Lord in this generation, upon the
consecrated spot as I have appointed
32 And the sons of Moses and of Aaron shall be
filled with the glory of the Lord, upon Mount Zion in
the Lord’s house, whose sons are ye; and also
many whom I have called and sent forth to build up my
church
33 For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these
two priesthoods of which I have spoken, and the
magnifying their calling, are sanctified by the
Spirit unto the renewing of their bodies
34 They become the sons of Moses and of Aaron and
the seed of Abraham, and the church and kingdom,
and the elect of God
35 And also all they who receive this priesthood
receive me, saith the Lord
36 For he that receiveth my servants receiveth me
37 And he that receiveth me receiveth my Father
38 And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my
Father’s kingdom; therefore all that my Father hath
shall be given unto him
39 And this is according to the oath and covenant
which belongeth to the priesthood
40 Therefore, all those who receive the
priesthood, receive this oath and covenant of my Father,
which he cannot break, neither can it be moved
41 But whoso breaketh this covenant after he hath
received it, and altogether turneth therefrom,
shall not have forgiveness of sins in this world nor
in the world to come
42 And wo unto all those who come not unto this
priesthood which ye have received, which I now
confirm upon you who are present this day, by mine own
voice out of the heavens; and even I have given
the heavenly hosts and mine angels charge concerning
you
43 And I now give unto you a commandment to beware
concerning yourselves, to give diligent heed to
the words of eternal life
44 For you shall live by every word that
proceedeth forth from the mouth of God
45 For the word of the Lord is truth, and
whatsoever is truth is light, and whatsoever is light is
Spirit, even the Spirit of Jesus Christ
46 And the Spirit giveth light to every man that
cometh into the world; and the Spirit enlighteneth
every man through the world, that hearkeneth to
the voice of the Spirit
47 And every one that hearkeneth to the voice of
the Spirit cometh unto God, even the Father
48 And the Father teacheth him of the covenant
which he has renewed and confirmed upon you, which is
confirmed upon you for your sakes, and not for
your sakes only, but for the sake of the whole
world
49 And the whole world lieth in sin, and groaneth
under darkness and under the bondage of sin
50 And by this you may know they are under the
bondage of sin, because they come not unto me
51 For whoso cometh not unto me is under the
bondage of sin
52 And whoso receiveth not my voice is not
acquainted with my voice, and is not of me
53 And by this you may know the righteous from the
wicked, and that the whole world groaneth under
sin and darkness even now
54 And your minds in times past have been darkened
because of unbelief, and because you have treated
lightly the things you have received
55 Which vanity and unbelief have brought the
whole church under condemnation
56 And this condemnation resteth upon the children
of Zion, even all
57 And they shall remain under this condemnation
until they repent and remember the new covenant,
even the Book of Mormon and the former commandments
which I have given them, not only to say, but to
do according to that which I have written
58 That they may bring forth fruit meet for their
Father’s kingdom; otherwise there remaineth a
scourge and judgment to be poured out upon the
children of Zion
59 For shall the children of the kingdom pollute
my holy land? Verily, I say unto you, Nay
60 Verily, verily, I say unto you who now hear my
words, which are my voice, blessed are ye inasmuch
as you receive these things
61 For I will forgive you of your sins with this
commandment—that you remain steadfast in your minds
in solemnity and the spirit of prayer, in bearing
testimony to all the world of those things which
are communicated unto you
62 Therefore, go ye into all the world; and unto
whatsoever place ye cannot go ye shall send, that
the testimony may go from you into all the world
unto every creature
63 And as I said unto mine apostles, even so I say
unto you, for you are mine apostles, even God’s
high priests; ye are they whom my Father hath given
me; ye are my friends
64 Therefore, as I said unto mine apostles I say
unto you again, that every soul who believeth on
your words, and is baptized by water for the
remission of sins, shall receive the Holy Ghost
65 And these signs shall follow them that believe
66 In my name they shall do many wonderful works
67 In my name they shall cast out devils
68 In my name they shall heal the sick
69 In my name they shall open the eyes of the
blind, and unstop the ears of the deaf
70 And the tongue of the dumb shall speak
71 And if any man shall administer poison unto
them it shall not hurt them
72 And the poison of a serpent shall not have
power to harm them
73 But a commandment I give unto them, that they
shall not boast themselves of these things, neither
speak them before the world; for these things are
given unto you for your profit and for salvation
74 Verily, verily, I say unto you, they who
believe not on your words, and are not baptized in water
in my name, for the remission of their sins, that
they may receive the Holy Ghost, shall be damned,
and shall not come into my Father’s kingdom where
my Father and I am
75 And this revelation unto you, and commandment,
is in force from this very hour upon all the
world, and the gospel is unto all who have not received
it
76 But, verily I say unto all those to whom the
kingdom has been given—from you it must be preached
unto them, that they shall repent of their former
evil works; for they are to be upbraided for their
evil hearts of unbelief, and your brethren in
Zion for their rebellion against you at the time I
sent you
77 And again I say unto you, my friends, for from
henceforth I shall call you friends, it is
expedient that I give unto you this commandment, that ye
become even as my friends in days when I was with
them, traveling to preach the gospel in my power
78 For I suffered them not to have purse or scrip,
neither two coats
79 Behold, I send you out to prove the world, and
the laborer is worthy of his hire
80 And any man that shall go and preach this
gospel of the kingdom, and fail not to continue
faithful in all things, shall not be weary in mind,
neither darkened, neither in body, limb, nor joint; and
a hair of his head shall not fall to the ground
unnoticed. And they shall not go hungry, neither
athirst
81 Therefore, take ye no thought for the morrow,
for what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink, or
wherewithal ye shall be clothed
82 For, consider the lilies of the field, how they
grow, they toil not, neither do they spin; and
the kingdoms of the world, in all their glory, are
not arrayed like one of these
83 For your Father, who is in heaven, knoweth that
you have need of all these things
84 Therefore, let the morrow take thought for the
things of itself
85 Neither take ye thought beforehand what ye
shall say; but treasure up in your minds continually
the words of life, and it shall be given you in the
very hour that portion that shall be meted unto
every man
86 Therefore, let no man among you, for this
commandment is unto all the faithful who are called of
God in the church unto the ministry, from this
hour take purse or scrip, that goeth forth to
proclaim this gospel of the kingdom
87 Behold, I send you out to reprove the world of
all their unrighteous deeds, and to teach them of
a judgment which is to come
88 And whoso receiveth you, there I will be also,
for I will go before your face. I will be on your
right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall
be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you,
to bear you up
89 Whoso receiveth you receiveth me; and the same
will feed you, and clothe you, and give you money
90 And he who feeds you, or clothes you, or gives
you money, shall in nowise lose his reward
91 And he that doeth not these things is not my
disciple; by this you may know my disciples
92 He that receiveth you not, go away from him
alone by yourselves, and cleanse your feet even with
water, pure water, whether in heat or in cold, and
bear testimony of it unto your Father which is in
heaven, and return not again unto that man
93 And in whatsoever village or city ye enter, do
likewise
94 Nevertheless, search diligently and spare not;
and wo unto that house, or that village or city
that rejecteth you, or your words, or your testimony
concerning me
95 Wo, I say again, unto that house, or that
village or city that rejecteth you, or your words, or
your testimony of me
96 For I, the Almighty, have laid my hands upon
the nations, to scourge them for their wickedness
97 And plagues shall go forth, and they shall not
be taken from the earth until I have completed my
work, which shall be cut short in righteousness
98 Until all shall know me, who remain, even from
the least unto the greatest, and shall be filled
with the knowledge of the Lord, and shall see eye
to eye, and shall lift up their voice, and with the
voice together sing this new song, saying
99 The Lord hath brought again Zion;The Lord hath
redeemed his people, Israel,According to the
election of grace,Which was brought to pass by the
faithAnd covenant of their fathers
100 The Lord hath redeemed his people;And Satan is
bound and time is no longer.The Lord hath
gathered all things in one.The Lord hath brought down
Zion from above.The Lord hath brought up Zion from
beneath
101 The earth hath travailed and brought forth her
strength;And truth is established in her
bowels;And the heavens have smiled upon her;And she is
clothed with the glory of her God;For he stands in
the midst of his people
102 Glory, and honor, and power, and might,Be
ascribed to our God; for he is full of mercy,Justice,
grace and truth, and peace,Forever and ever, Amen
103 And again, verily, verily, I say unto you, it
is expedient that every man who goes forth to
proclaim mine everlasting gospel, that inasmuch as
they have families, and receive money by gift, that
they should send it unto them or make use of it for
their benefit, as the Lord shall direct them, for
thus it seemeth me good
104 And let all those who have not families, who
receive money, send it up unto the bishop in Zion,
or unto the bishop in Ohio, that it may be
consecrated for the bringing forth of the revelations and
the printing thereof, and for establishing Zion
105 And if any man shall give unto any of you a
coat, or a suit, take the old and cast it unto the
poor, and go on your way rejoicing
106 And if any man among you be strong in the
Spirit, let him take with him him that is weak, that
he may be edified in all meekness, that he may
become strong also
107 Therefore, take with you those who are
ordained unto the lesser priesthood, and send them before
you to make appointments, and to prepare the way,
and to fill appointments that you yourselves are
not able to fill
108 Behold, this is the way that mine apostles, in
ancient days, built up my church unto me
109 Therefore, let every man stand in his own
office, and labor in his own calling; and let not the
head say unto the feet it hath no need of the
feet; for without the feet how shall the body be able
to stand
110 Also the body hath need of every member, that
all may be edified together, that the system may
be kept perfect
111 And behold, the high priests should travel,
and also the elders, and also the lesser priests;
but the deacons and teachers should be appointed to
watch over the church, to be standing ministers
unto the church
112 And the bishop, Newel K. Whitney, also should
travel round about and among all the churches,
searching after the poor to administer to their wants
by humbling the rich and the proud
113 He should also employ an agent to take charge
and to do his secular business as he shall direct
114 Nevertheless, let the bishop go unto the city
of New York, also to the city of Albany, and also
to the city of Boston, and warn the people of
those cities with the sound of the gospel, with a loud
voice, of the desolation and utter abolishment
which await them if they do reject these things
115 For if they do reject these things the hour of
their judgment is nigh, and their house shall be
left unto them desolate
116 Let him trust in me and he shall not be
confounded; and a hair of his head shall not fall to the
ground unnoticed
117 And verily I say unto you, the rest of my
servants, go ye forth as your circumstances shall
permit, in your several callings, unto the great and
notable cities and villages, reproving the world in
righteousness of all their unrighteous and
ungodly deeds, setting forth clearly and understandingly
the desolation of abomination in the last days
118 For, with you saith the Lord Almighty, I will
rend their kingdoms; I will not only shake the
earth, but the starry heavens shall tremble
119 For I, the Lord, have put forth my hand to
exert the powers of heaven; ye cannot see it now, yet
a little while and ye shall see it, and know that
I am, and that I will come and reign with my
people
120 I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the
end. Amen.