Section 62 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, on the bank of the Missouri River
at Chariton, Missouri, August 13, 1831. On this
day the Prophet and his group, who were on their
way from Independence to Kirtland, met several
elders who were on their way to the land of
Zion, and, after joyful salutations, received this
revelation.
1–3, Testimonies are recorded in
heaven;
4–9, The elders are to travel and preach
according to judgment and as directed by the Spirit.
1 Behold, and hearken, O ye elders of my
church, saith the Lord your God, even Jesus
Christ, your advocate, who knoweth the weakness
of man and how to succor them who are tempted.
2 And verily mine eyes are upon those who
have not as yet gone up unto the land of
Zion; wherefore your mission is not yet full.
3 Nevertheless, ye are blessed, for
the testimony which ye have borne
is recorded in heaven for the
angels to look upon; and they rejoice
over you, and your sins are forgiven you.
4 And now continue your
journey. Assemble yourselves upon the
land of Zion; and hold a
meeting and rejoice together, and
offer a sacrament unto the Most High.
5 And then you may return to
bear record, yea, even
altogether, or two by two, as seemeth
you good, it mattereth not
unto me; only be faithful, and
declare glad tidings unto the
inhabitants of the earth, or
among the congregations of the wicked.
6 Behold, I, the Lord, have
brought you together that
the promise might be
fulfilled, that the faithful among
you should be preserved and
rejoice together in the land
of Missouri. I, the Lord,
promise the faithful and cannot lie.
7 I, the Lord, am willing,
if any among you desire
to ride upon horses, or
upon mules, or in chariots,
he shall receive this
blessing, if he receive it from
the hand of the Lord,
with a thankful heart in all things.
8 These things remain
with you to do according
to judgment and the
directions of the Spirit.
9 Behold, the
kingdom is yours. And
behold, and lo, I am
with the faithful
always. Even so. Amen.