Section 77 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, about March 1832. Joseph
Smith’s history states, “In connection with the
translation of the Scriptures, I received the
following explanation of the
Revelation of
St. John.”
1–4, Beasts have spirits and will dwell in
eternal felicity;
8–10, Various angels restore the
gospel and minister on earth;
11, The sealing of
the 144,000;
12–14, Christ will come in the
beginning of the seventh thousand years;
15, Two
prophets will be raised up to the Jewish nation.
4th chapter, and 6th verse of the Revelation?A. It
is the earth, in its sanctified, immortal, and
eternal state.
same verse?A. They are figurative
expressions, used by the Revelator, John, in
describing heaven, the paradise of God, the happiness
of man, and of beasts, and of creeping things,
and of the fowls of the air; that which is
spiritual being in the likeness of that which is
temporal; and that which is temporal in the likeness of
that which is spiritual; the spirit of man in the
likeness of his person, as also the spirit of the
beast, and every other creature which God has
created.
7th chapter and 1st verse of Revelation?A.
We are to understand that they are four angels
sent forth from God, to whom is given power over
the four parts of the earth, to save life and to
destroy; these are they who have the everlasting
gospel to commit to every nation, kindred, tongue,
and people; having power to shut up the heavens,
to seal up unto life, or to cast down to the
regions of darkness.
Revelation 7th chapter and 2nd
verse?A. We are to understand that the angel
ascending from the east is he to whom is given the
seal of the living God over the twelve tribes of
Israel; wherefore, he crieth unto the four angels
having the everlasting gospel, saying: Hurt not
the earth, neither the sea, nor the trees, till we
have sealed the servants of our God in their
foreheads. And, if you will receive it, this is Elias
which was to come to gather together the tribes
of Israel and restore all things.
this chapter to
be accomplished?A. They are to be accomplished
in the sixth thousand years, or the opening of the
sixth seal.
8th chapter of Revelation?A. We are
to understand that as God made the world in six
days, and on the seventh day he finished his work,
and sanctified it, and also formed man out of
the dust of the earth, even so, in the beginning of
the seventh thousand years will the Lord God
sanctify the earth, and complete the salvation of
man, and judge all things, and shall redeem all
things, except that which he hath not put into his
power, when he shall have sealed all things, unto
the end of all things; and the sounding of the
trumpets of the seven angels are the preparing and
finishing of his work, in the beginning of the
seventh thousand years—the preparing of the way
before the time of his coming.
9th chapter of
Revelation?A. They are to be accomplished after the
opening of the seventh seal, before the coming of
Christ.
10th chapter of Revelation?A. We are to
understand that it was a mission, and an ordinance,
for him to gather the tribes of Israel; behold,
this is Elias, who, as it is written, must come
and restore all things.
eleventh chapter of
Revelation?A. They are two prophets that are to be
raised up to the Jewish nation in the last days, at
the time of the restoration, and to prophesy to the
Jews after they are gathered and have built the city of Jerusalem in the land of their fathers.
1 Q. What is the sea of glass spoken of by John,
2 Q. What are we to understand by
the four beasts, spoken of in the
3 Q. Are the four beasts limited
to individual beasts, or do they
represent classes or orders?A.
They are limited to four individual
beasts, which were shown to
John, to represent the glory of the
classes of beings in their
destined order or sphere of creation, in
the enjoyment of their eternal felicity.
4 Q. What are we to
understand by the eyes and wings,
which the beasts had?A. Their
eyes are a representation of
light and knowledge, that is,
they are full of knowledge; and
their wings are a
representation of power, to move, to act, etc.
5 Q. What are we to
understand by the four and twenty
elders, spoken of by John?A.
We are to understand that
these elders whom John saw,
were elders who had been
faithful in the work of the
ministry and were dead; who
belonged to the seven churches,
and were then in the paradise of God.
6 Q. What are we to
understand by the book which John
saw, which was sealed on
the back with seven seals?A.
We are to understand that
it contains the revealed
will, mysteries, and the works
of God; the hidden things
of his economy concerning
this earth during the seven
thousand years of its
continuance, or its temporal existence.
7 Q. What are we to
understand by the seven
seals with which it was
sealed?A. We are to
understand that the first seal
contains the things of
the first thousand years,
and the second also of
the second thousand
years, and so on until the seventh.
8 Q. What are we to
understand by the four
angels, spoken of in the
9 Q. What are we
to understand by
the angel
ascending from the east,
10 Q. What
time are the
things spoken of in
11 Q. What
are we to
understand by
sealing the one
hundred and
forty-four
thousand, out of
all the
tribes of
Israel—twelve
thousand out of
every tribe?A. We
are to
understand that
those who are
sealed are
high priests,
ordained unto
the holy order
of God, to
administer the
everlasting
gospel; for
they are they
who are
ordained out of
every nation,
kindred,
tongue, and
people, by the
angels to whom is
given power
over the
nations of the
earth, to bring
as many as
will come to the church of the Firstborn.
12 Q. What
are we to
understand
by the
sounding of the
trumpets,
mentioned in the
13 Q. When
are the
things to
be
accomplished,
which are
written in the
14 Q.
What are we
to
understand by
the little
book
which was
eaten by
John, as
mentioned in the
15 Q.
What is to
be
understood
by the
two
witnesses, in the
5–7,
This
earth has a
temporal
existence
of 7,000
years;