Section 122 The word of the Lord to Joseph Smith
the Prophet, while a prisoner in the jail at
Liberty, Missouri. This section is an excerpt from an
epistle to the Church dated March 20, 1839 (see the
heading to section 121).
1–4, The ends of the
earth will inquire after the name of Joseph Smith;
5–7, All his perils and travails will give him
experience and be for his good;
8–9, The Son of Man
has descended below them all.
1 The ends of the earth shall inquire after thy
name, and fools shall have thee in derision, and
hell shall rage against thee
2 While the pure in heart, and the wise, and the
noble, and the virtuous, shall seek counsel, and
authority, and blessings constantly from under thy
hand
3 And thy people shall never be turned against
thee by the testimony of traitors
4 And although their influence shall cast thee
into trouble, and into bars and walls, thou shalt be
had in honor; and but for a small moment and thy
voice shall be more terrible in the midst of thine
enemies than the fierce lion, because of thy
righteousness; and thy God shall stand by thee forever
and ever
5 If thou art called to pass through tribulation;
if thou art in perils among false brethren; if
thou art in perils among robbers; if thou art in
perils by land or by sea
6 If thou art accused with all manner of false
accusations; if thine enemies fall upon thee; if they
tear thee from the society of thy father and
mother and brethren and sisters; and if with a drawn
sword thine enemies tear thee from the bosom of thy
wife, and of thine offspring, and thine elder
son, although but six years of age, shall cling to
thy garments, and shall say, My father, my father,
why can’t you stay with us? O, my father, what are
the men going to do with you? and if then he shall
be thrust from thee by the sword, and thou be
dragged to prison, and thine enemies prowl around
thee like wolves for the blood of the lamb
7 And if thou shouldst be cast into the pit, or
into the hands of murderers, and the sentence of
death passed upon thee; if thou be cast into the
deep; if the billowing surge conspire against thee; if
fierce winds become thine enemy; if the heavens
gather blackness, and all the elements combine to
hedge up the way; and above all, if the very jaws
of hell shall gape open the mouth wide after thee,
know thou, my son, that all these things shall
give thee experience, and shall be for thy good
8 The Son of Man hath descended below them all.
Art thou greater than he
9 Therefore, hold on thy way, and the priesthood
shall remain with thee; for their bounds are set,
they cannot pass. Thy days are known, and thy years
shall not be numbered less; therefore, fear not
what man can do, for God shall be with you forever
and ever.