Section 69 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, November 11, 1831. The
compilation of revelations intended for early
publication had been passed upon at the special
conference of November 1–2. On November 3, the
revelation herein appearing as
section 133, later called
the Appendix, was added. Oliver Cowdery had
previously been appointed to carry the manuscript of the
compiled revelations and commandments to
Independence, Missouri, for printing. He was also to take
with him money that had been contributed for the
building up of the Church in Missouri. This
revelation instructs John Whitmer to accompany Oliver
Cowdery and also directs Whitmer to travel and
collect historical material in his calling as Church
historian and recorder.
1–2, John Whitmer is to
accompany Oliver Cowdery to Missouri;
3–8, He is also
to preach and to collect, record, and write
historical data.
1 Hearken unto me, saith the Lord your God, for my
servant Oliver Cowdery’s sake. It is not wisdom
in me that he should be entrusted with the
commandments and the moneys which he shall carry unto the
land of Zion, except one go with him who will be
true and faithful
2 Wherefore, I, the Lord, will that my servant,
John Whitmer, should go with my servant Oliver
Cowdery
3 And also that he shall continue in writing and
making a history of all the important things which
he shall observe and know concerning my church
4 And also that he receive counsel and assistance
from my servant Oliver Cowdery and others
5 And also, my servants who are abroad in the
earth should send forth the accounts of their
stewardships to the land of Zion
6 For the land of Zion shall be a seat and a place
to receive and do all these things
7 Nevertheless, let my servant John Whitmer travel
many times from place to place, and from church
to church, that he may the more easily obtain
knowledge
8 Preaching and expounding, writing, copying,
selecting, and obtaining all things which shall be for
the good of the church, and for the rising
generations that shall grow up on the land of Zion, to
possess it from generation to generation, forever
and ever. Amen.