Section 49 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Sidney Rigdon, Parley P. Pratt,
and Leman Copley, at Kirtland, Ohio, May 7, 1831.
Leman Copley had embraced the gospel but still
held to some of the teachings of the Shakers (United
Society of Believers in Christ’s Second
Appearing), to which he had formerly belonged. Some of
the beliefs of the Shakers were that Christ’s
Second Coming had already occurred and that He had
appeared in the form of a woman, Ann Lee. They did
not consider baptism by water essential. They
rejected marriage and believed in a life of total
celibacy. Some Shakers also forbade the eating of
meat. In prefacing this revelation, Joseph Smith’s
history states, “In order to have [a] more
perfect understanding on the subject, I inquired of the
Lord, and received the following.” The
revelation refutes some of the basic concepts of the
Shaker group. The aforementioned brethren took a copy
of the revelation to the Shaker community (near
Cleveland, Ohio) and read it to them in its
entirety, but it was rejected.
1–7, The day and hour
of Christ’s coming will remain unknown until He
comes;
8–14, Men must repent, believe the gospel,
and obey the ordinances to gain salvation;
15–16, Marriage is ordained of God;
17–21, The eating
of meat is approved;
22–28, Zion will flourish
and the Lamanites blossom as the rose before the Second Coming.
1 Hearken unto my word, my servants
Sidney, and Parley, and Leman; for behold,
verily I say unto you, that I give unto you
a commandment that you shall go and
preach my gospel which ye have received, even
as ye have received it, unto the Shakers.
2 Behold, I say unto you, that
they desire to know the truth in
part, but not all, for they are not
right before me and must needs repent.
3 Wherefore, I send you, my
servants Sidney and Parley, to
preach the gospel unto them.
4 And my servant Leman
shall be ordained unto this
work, that he may reason with
them, not according to that
which he has received of
them, but according to that
which shall be taught him
by you my servants; and by
so doing I will bless him,
otherwise he shall not prosper.
5 Thus saith the Lord;
for I am God, and have sent
mine Only Begotten Son
into the world for the
redemption of the world, and
have decreed that he
that receiveth him shall be
saved, and he that
receiveth him not shall be damned—
6 And they have done
unto the Son of Man even
as they listed; and he
has taken his power on
the right hand of his
glory, and now reigneth
in the heavens, and
will reign till he
descends on the earth to put
all enemies under his
feet, which time is nigh at hand—
7 I, the Lord God,
have spoken it; but
the hour and the day
no man knoweth,
neither the angels in
heaven, nor shall they
know until he comes.
8 Wherefore, I
will that all men
shall repent, for all
are under sin,
except those which I
have reserved
unto myself, holy men
that ye know not of.
9 Wherefore, I
say unto you that I
have sent unto
you mine
everlasting covenant, even
that which was
from the beginning.
10 And that
which I have
promised I have so
fulfilled, and the
nations of the
earth shall bow to
it; and, if not
of themselves,
they shall come
down, for that
which is now
exalted of itself
shall be laid low of power.
11 Wherefore,
I give unto
you a
commandment that ye go
among this
people, and say
unto them, like
unto mine
apostle of old,
whose name was Peter:
12 Believe on
the name of
the Lord
Jesus, who was on
the earth,
and is to
come, the
beginning and the end;
13 Repent
and be
baptized in the
name of Jesus
Christ,
according to the
holy
commandment, for
the remission of sins;
14 And
whoso doeth
this shall
receive the
gift of the
Holy Ghost,
by the
laying on of
the hands of
the elders
of the church.
15 And
again, verily
I say
unto you,
that whoso
forbiddeth
to marry is
not
ordained of
God, for
marriage is
ordained of
God unto man.
Wherefore, it
is lawful
that he
should
have one
wife, and
they twain
shall be
one
flesh, and all
this
that the
earth might
answer
the end of its creation;
17 And
that it
might be
filled with
the
measure of
man,
according to his
creation
before
the world
was made.
18 And
whoso
forbiddeth
to
abstain from
meats,
that man
should
not eat
the same,
is not
ordained of God;
19 For,
behold, the
beasts
of the
field
and the
fowls of
the
air, and
that
which
cometh of
the
earth, is
ordained for
the use
of man
for
food and
raiment,
and that
he might have in abundance.
20 But
it is
not
given
that
one man
should
possess
that
which is
above
another,
wherefore
the
world lieth in sin.
And wo
be
unto
man
that
sheddeth
blood or
that
wasteth
flesh
and hath no need.
And
again,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
that
the
Son of
Man
cometh
not
in
the
form
of a
woman,
neither
of a
man traveling on the earth.
Wherefore,
be
not
deceived,
but
continue
in
steadfastness,
looking
forth
for
the
heavens
to
be
shaken,
and
the
earth
to
tremble
and
to
reel
and
fro
as
a
drunken
man,
and
for
the
valleys
to
be
exalted,
and
for
the
mountains
to
be
made
low,
and
for
the rough places to become smooth—and all this when the angel shall sound his trumpet.
But
before
the
great
day
of
the
Lord
shall
come,
Jacob
shall
flourish
in
the
wilderness, and the Lamanites shall blossom as the rose.
Zion
shall
flourish
upon
the
hills
and
rejoice
upon
the
mountains,
and
shall
be
assembled
together
unto
the
place
which
I
have
appointed.
Behold,
I
say
unto
you,
go
forth
as
I
have
commanded
you;
repent
of
all
your
sins;
ask
and
ye
shall
receive;
knock
and
it
shall
be
opened
unto
you.
27 Behold, I will go before you and be your rearward; and I will be in your midst, and you shall not be
Behold,
I
will
go
before
you
and
be
your
rearward;
and
I will be in your midst, and you shall not be confounded.
28 Behold, I am Jesus Christ, and I come quickly. Even so. Amen.
Behold,
I
am
Jesus
Christ,
and
I
come
quickly.
Even
so.
Amen.