Section 137 A vision given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, in the temple at Kirtland, Ohio, January 21,
1836. The occasion was the administration of
ordinances in preparation for the dedication of the
temple.
1–6, The Prophet sees his brother Alvin in
the celestial kingdom;
7–9, The doctrine of
salvation for the dead is revealed;
10, All children
are saved in the celestial kingdom.
1 The heavens were opened upon us, and I beheld
the celestial kingdom of God, and the glory thereof,
whether in the body or out I cannot tell
2 I saw the transcendent beauty of the gate
through which the heirs of that kingdom will enter,
which was like unto circling flames of fire
3 Also the blazing throne of God, whereon was
seated the Father and the Son
4 I saw the beautiful streets of that kingdom,
which had the appearance of being paved with gold
5 I saw Father Adam and Abraham; and my father and
my mother; my brother Alvin, that has long since
slept
6 And marveled how it was that he had obtained an
inheritance in that kingdom, seeing that he had
departed this life before the Lord had set his hand
to gather Israel the second time, and had not been
baptized for the remission of sins
7 Thus came the voice of the Lord unto me, saying:
All who have died without a knowledge of this
gospel, who would have received it if they had been
permitted to tarry, shall be heirs of the celestial
kingdom of God
8 Also all that shall die henceforth without a
knowledge of it, who would have received it with all
their hearts, shall be heirs of that kingdom
9 For I, the Lord, will judge all men according to
their works, according to the desire of their
hearts
10 And I also beheld that all children who die
before they arrive at the years of accountability are
saved in the celestial kingdom of heaven.