Section 58 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, in Zion, Jackson County, Missouri,
August 1, 1831. Earlier, on the first Sabbath after
the arrival of the Prophet and his party in Jackson
County, Missouri, a religious service had been
held, and two members had been received by baptism.
During that week, some of the Colesville Saints
from the Thompson Branch and others arrived (see
section 54). Many were eager to learn the will of
the Lord concerning them in the new place of
gathering.
1–5, Those who endure tribulation will be
crowned with glory;
6–12, The Saints are to prepare
for the marriage of the Lamb and the supper of the
Lord;
13–18, Bishops are judges in Israel;
19–23, The Saints are to obey the laws of the land;
24–29, Men should use their agency to do good;
30–33, The Lord commands and revokes;
34–43, To
repent, men must confess and forsake their sins;
44–58, The Saints are to purchase their inheritance
and gather in Missouri;
59–65, The gospel must be
preached unto every creature.
1 Hearken, O ye elders of my church, and give ear
to my word, and learn of me what I will concerning
you, and also concerning this land unto which I
have sent you
2 For verily I say unto you, blessed is he that
keepeth my commandments, whether in life or in
death; and he that is faithful in tribulation, the
reward of the same is greater in the kingdom of
heaven
3 Ye cannot behold with your natural eyes, for the
present time, the design of your God concerning
those things which shall come hereafter, and the
glory which shall follow after much tribulation
4 For after much tribulation come the blessings.
Wherefore the day cometh that ye shall be crowned
with much glory; the hour is not yet, but is nigh
at hand
5 Remember this, which I tell you before, that you
may lay it to heart, and receive that which is to
follow
6 Behold, verily I say unto you, for this cause I
have sent you—that you might be obedient, and that
your hearts might be prepared to bear testimony
of the things which are to come
7 And also that you might be honored in laying the
foundation, and in bearing record of the land
upon which the Zion of God shall stand
8 And also that a feast of fat things might be
prepared for the poor; yea, a feast of fat things, of
wine on the lees well refined, that the earth may
know that the mouths of the prophets shall not
fail
9 Yea, a supper of the house of the Lord, well
prepared, unto which all nations shall be invited
10 First, the rich and the learned, the wise and
the noble
11 And after that cometh the day of my power; then
shall the poor, the lame, and the blind, and the
deaf, come in unto the marriage of the Lamb, and
partake of the supper of the Lord, prepared for the
great day to come
12 Behold, I, the Lord, have spoken it
13 And that the testimony might go forth from
Zion, yea, from the mouth of the city of the heritage
of God
14 Yea, for this cause I have sent you hither, and
have selected my servant Edward Partridge, and
have appointed unto him his mission in this land
15 But if he repent not of his sins, which are
unbelief and blindness of heart, let him take heed
lest he fall
16 Behold his mission is given unto him, and it
shall not be given again
17 And whoso standeth in this mission is appointed
to be a judge in Israel, like as it was in
ancient days, to divide the lands of the heritage of God
unto his children
18 And to judge his people by the testimony of the
just, and by the assistance of his counselors,
according to the laws of the kingdom which are given
by the prophets of God
19 For verily I say unto you, my law shall be kept
on this land
20 Let no man think he is ruler; but let God rule
him that judgeth, according to the counsel of his
own will, or, in other words, him that counseleth
or sitteth upon the judgment seat
21 Let no man break the laws of the land, for he
that keepeth the laws of God hath no need to break
the laws of the land
22 Wherefore, be subject to the powers that be,
until he reigns whose right it is to reign, and
subdues all enemies under his feet
23 Behold, the laws which ye have received from my
hand are the laws of the church, and in this
light ye shall hold them forth. Behold, here is
wisdom
24 And now, as I spake concerning my servant
Edward Partridge, this land is the land of his
residence, and those whom he has appointed for his
counselors; and also the land of the residence of him
whom I have appointed to keep my storehouse
25 Wherefore, let them bring their families to
this land, as they shall counsel between themselves
and me
26 For behold, it is not meet that I should
command in all things; for he that is compelled in all
things, the same is a slothful and not a wise
servant; wherefore he receiveth no reward
27 Verily I say, men should be anxiously engaged
in a good cause, and do many things of their own
free will, and bring to pass much righteousness
28 For the power is in them, wherein they are
agents unto themselves. And inasmuch as men do good
they shall in nowise lose their reward
29 But he that doeth not anything until he is
commanded, and receiveth a commandment with doubtful
heart, and keepeth it with slothfulness, the same
is damned
30 Who am I that made man, saith the Lord, that
will hold him guiltless that obeys not my
commandments
31 Who am I, saith the Lord, that have promised
and have not fulfilled
32 I command and men obey not; I revoke and they
receive not the blessing
33 Then they say in their hearts: This is not the
work of the Lord, for his promises are not
fulfilled. But wo unto such, for their reward lurketh
beneath, and not from above
34 And now I give unto you further directions
concerning this land
35 It is wisdom in me that my servant Martin
Harris should be an example unto the church, in laying
his moneys before the bishop of the church
36 And also, this is a law unto every man that
cometh unto this land to receive an inheritance; and
he shall do with his moneys according as the law
directs
37 And it is wisdom also that there should be
lands purchased in Independence, for the place of the
storehouse, and also for the house of the
printing
38 And other directions concerning my servant
Martin Harris shall be given him of the Spirit, that
he may receive his inheritance as seemeth him good
39 And let him repent of his sins, for he seeketh
the praise of the world
40 And also let my servant William W. Phelps stand
in the office to which I have appointed him, and
receive his inheritance in the land
41 And also he hath need to repent, for I, the
Lord, am not well pleased with him, for he seeketh to
excel, and he is not sufficiently meek before me
42 Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the
same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no
more
43 By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his
sins—behold, he will confess them and forsake them
44 And now, verily, I say concerning the residue
of the elders of my church, the time has not yet
come, for many years, for them to receive their
inheritance in this land, except they desire it
through the prayer of faith, only as it shall be
appointed unto them of the Lord
45 For, behold, they shall push the people
together from the ends of the earth
46 Wherefore, assemble yourselves together; and
they who are not appointed to stay in this land, let
them preach the gospel in the regions round
about; and after that let them return to their homes
47 Let them preach by the way, and bear testimony
of the truth in all places, and call upon the
rich, the high and the low, and the poor to repent
48 And let them build up churches, inasmuch as the
inhabitants of the earth will repent
49 And let there be an agent appointed by the
voice of the church, unto the church in Ohio, to
receive moneys to purchase lands in Zion
50 And I give unto my servant Sidney Rigdon a
commandment, that he shall write a description of the
land of Zion, and a statement of the will of God,
as it shall be made known by the Spirit unto him
51 And an epistle and subscription, to be
presented unto all the churches to obtain moneys, to be
put into the hands of the bishop, of himself or the
agent, as seemeth him good or as he shall direct,
to purchase lands for an inheritance for the
children of God
52 For, behold, verily I say unto you, the Lord
willeth that the disciples and the children of men
should open their hearts, even to purchase this
whole region of country, as soon as time will permit
53 Behold, here is wisdom. Let them do this lest
they receive none inheritance, save it be by the
shedding of blood
54 And again, inasmuch as there is land obtained,
let there be workmen sent forth of all kinds unto
this land, to labor for the saints of God
55 Let all these things be done in order; and let
the privileges of the lands be made known from
time to time, by the bishop or the agent of the
church
56 And let the work of the gathering be not in
haste, nor by flight; but let it be done as it shall
be counseled by the elders of the church at the
conferences, according to the knowledge which they
receive from time to time
57 And let my servant Sidney Rigdon consecrate and
dedicate this land, and the spot for the temple,
unto the Lord
58 And let a conference meeting be called; and
after that let my servants Sidney Rigdon and Joseph
Smith, Jun., return, and also Oliver Cowdery with
them, to accomplish the residue of the work which I
have appointed unto them in their own land, and
the residue as shall be ruled by the conferences
59 And let no man return from this land except he
bear record by the way, of that which he knows and
most assuredly believes
60 Let that which has been bestowed upon Ziba
Peterson be taken from him; and let him stand as a
member in the church, and labor with his own hands,
with the brethren, until he is sufficiently
chastened for all his sins; for he confesseth them not,
and he thinketh to hide them
61 Let the residue of the elders of this church,
who are coming to this land, some of whom are
exceedingly blessed even above measure, also hold a
conference upon this land
62 And let my servant Edward Partridge direct the
conference which shall be held by them
63 And let them also return, preaching the gospel
by the way, bearing record of the things which are
revealed unto them