Section 33 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to Ezra Thayre and Northrop
Sweet, at Fayette, New York, October 1830. In
introducing this revelation, Joseph Smith’s
history affirms that “the Lord … is ever ready to
instruct such as diligently seek in faith.”
1–4, Laborers are called to declare the gospel
in the eleventh hour;
5–6, The Church is
established, and the elect are to be gathered;
7–10, Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at
hand;
11–15, The Church is built upon the gospel
rock;
16–18, Prepare for the coming of the Bridegroom.
1 Behold, I say unto you, my servants Ezra
and Northrop, open ye your ears and hearken to
the voice of the Lord your God, whose word is
quick and powerful, sharper than a two-edged
sword, to the dividing asunder of the joints
and marrow, soul and spirit; and is a
discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart.
2 For verily, verily, I say unto you that
ye are called to lift up your voices as
with the sound of a trump, to declare my
gospel unto a crooked and perverse generation.
3 For behold, the field is white
already to harvest; and it is the
eleventh hour, and the last time that I
shall call laborers into my vineyard.
4 And my vineyard has become
corrupted every whit; and there
is none which doeth good save
it be a few; and they err in
many instances because of
priestcrafts, all having corrupt minds.
5 And verily, verily, I say
unto you, that this church
have I established and called
forth out of the wilderness.
6 And even so will I gather
mine elect from the four
quarters of the earth, even
as many as will believe in
me, and hearken unto my voice.
7 Yea, verily, verily,
I say unto you, that
the field is white
already to harvest;
wherefore, thrust in your
sickles, and reap with all
your might, mind, and strength.
8 Open your mouths and
they shall be filled,
and you shall become
even as Nephi of old,
who journeyed from
Jerusalem in the wilderness.
9 Yea, open your
mouths and spare not,
and you shall be
laden with sheaves
upon your backs, for
lo, I am with you.
10 Yea, open your
mouths and they
shall be filled,
saying: Repent,
repent, and
prepare ye the way of
the Lord, and make
his paths
straight; for the
kingdom of heaven is at hand;
11 Yea, repent
and be baptized,
every one of you,
for a remission of
your sins; yea,
be baptized even
by water, and
then cometh the
baptism of fire and
of the Holy Ghost.
12 Behold,
verily, verily, I
say unto you,
this is my
gospel; and remember
that they shall
have faith in
me or they can
in nowise be saved;
13 And upon
this rock I will
build my
church; yea, upon
this rock ye
are built, and
if ye
continue, the gates of
hell shall
not prevail against you.
14 And ye
shall remember
the church
articles and
covenants
to keep them.
15 And whoso
having
faith you shall
confirm in
my church, by
the laying
on of the
hands, and I
will bestow
the gift of
the Holy
Ghost upon them.
16 And the
Book of
Mormon and the
holy
scriptures are
given of me
for your
instruction;
and the
power of my
Spirit
quickeneth all things.
Wherefore, be
faithful,
praying always,
having your
lamps
trimmed and
burning, and
oil with you,
that you
may be ready
at the
coming of the
Bridegroom—
18 For
behold,
verily, verily,
I say
unto you,
that I come
quickly.
Even so. Amen.