Section 74 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Wayne County, New York, in 1830. Even
before the organization of the Church, questions had
arisen about the proper mode of baptism, leading
the Prophet to seek answers on the subject. Joseph
Smith’s history states that this revelation is an
explanation of
1 Corinthians 7:14, a scripture
that had often been used to justify infant baptism.
1–5, Paul counsels the Church of his day not to
keep the law of Moses;
6–7, Little children are
holy and are sanctified through the Atonement.
1 For the unbelieving husband is sanctified by the
wife, and the unbelieving wife is sanctified by
the husband; else were your children unclean, but
now are they holy
2 Now, in the days of the apostles the law of
circumcision was had among all the Jews who believed
not the gospel of Jesus Christ
3 And it came to pass that there arose a great
contention among the people concerning the law of
circumcision, for the unbelieving husband was
desirous that his children should be circumcised and
become subject to the law of Moses, which law was
fulfilled
4 And it came to pass that the children, being
brought up in subjection to the law of Moses, gave
heed to the traditions of their fathers and believed
not the gospel of Christ, wherein they became
unholy
5 Wherefore, for this cause the apostle wrote unto
the church, giving unto them a commandment, not
of the Lord, but of himself, that a believer should
not be united to an unbeliever; except the law of
Moses should be done away among them
6 That their children might remain without
circumcision; and that the tradition might be done away,
which saith that little children are unholy; for
it was had among the Jews
7 But little children are holy, being sanctified
through the atonement of Jesus Christ; and this is
what the scriptures mean.