Section 115 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Far West, Missouri, April 26,
1838, making known the will of God concerning the
building up of that place and of the Lord’s house.
This revelation is addressed to the presiding
officers and the members of the Church.
1–4, The Lord
names His church The Church of Jesus Christ of
Latter-day Saints;
5–6, Zion and her stakes are places
of defense and refuge for the Saints;
7–16, The
Saints are commanded to build a house of the Lord
at Far West;
17–19, Joseph Smith holds the keys
of the kingdom of God on earth.
1 Verily thus saith the Lord unto you, my servant
Joseph Smith, Jun., and also my servant Sidney
Rigdon, and also my servant Hyrum Smith, and your
counselors who are and shall be appointed hereafter
2 And also unto you, my servant Edward Partridge,
and his counselors
3 And also unto my faithful servants who are of
the high council of my church in Zion, for thus it
shall be called, and unto all the elders and people
of my Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day
Saints, scattered abroad in all the world
4 For thus shall my church be called in the last
days, even The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day
Saints
5 Verily I say unto you all: Arise and shine
forth, that thy light may be a standard for the
nations
6 And that the gathering together upon the land of
Zion, and upon her stakes, may be for a defense,
and for a refuge from the storm, and from wrath
when it shall be poured out without mixture upon the
whole earth
7 Let the city, Far West, be a holy and
consecrated land unto me; and it shall be called most holy,
for the ground upon which thou standest is holy
8 Therefore, I command you to build a house unto
me, for the gathering together of my saints, that
they may worship me
9 And let there be a beginning of this work, and a
foundation, and a preparatory work, this
following summer
10 And let the beginning be made on the fourth day
of July next; and from that time forth let my
people labor diligently to build a house unto my
name
11 And in one year from this day let them
re-commence laying the foundation of my house
12 Thus let them from that time forth labor
diligently until it shall be finished, from the
cornerstone thereof unto the top thereof, until there
shall not anything remain that is not finished
13 Verily I say unto you, let not my servant
Joseph, neither my servant Sidney, neither my servant
Hyrum, get in debt any more for the building of a
house unto my name
14 But let a house be built unto my name according
to the pattern which I will show unto them
15 And if my people build it not according to the
pattern which I shall show unto their presidency,
I will not accept it at their hands
16 But if my people do build it according to the
pattern which I shall show unto their presidency,
even my servant Joseph and his counselors, then I
will accept it at the hands of my people
17 And again, verily I say unto you, it is my will
that the city of Far West should be built up
speedily by the gathering of my saints
18 And also that other places should be appointed
for stakes in the regions round about, as they
shall be manifested unto my servant Joseph, from time
to time
19 For behold, I will be with him, and I will
sanctify him before the people; for unto him have I
given the keys of this kingdom and ministry. Even
so. Amen.