Section 127 An epistle from Joseph Smith
the Prophet to the Latter-day Saints at
Nauvoo, Illinois, containing directions on
baptism for the dead, dated at Nauvoo, September
1, 1842.
1–4, Joseph Smith glories in
persecution and tribulation;
5–12, Records
must be kept relative to baptisms for the dead.
1 Forasmuch as the Lord has revealed unto
me that my enemies, both in Missouri and
this State, were again in the pursuit of
me; and inasmuch as they pursue me without a
cause, and have not the least shadow or
coloring of justice or right on their side
in the getting up of their prosecutions
against me; and inasmuch as their
pretensions are all founded in falsehood of the
blackest dye, I have thought it expedient and
wisdom in me to leave the place for a
short season, for my own safety and the safety
of this people. I would say to all those
with whom I have business, that I have
left my affairs with agents and clerks who
will transact all business in a prompt and
proper manner, and will see that all my
debts are canceled in due time, by turning
out property, or otherwise, as the case may
require, or as the circumstances may admit
of. When I learn that the storm is fully
blown over, then I will return to you again.
2 And as for the perils which I am
called to pass through, they seem but a
small thing to me, as the envy and wrath
of man have been my common lot all the
days of my life; and for what cause it
seems mysterious, unless I was ordained
from before the foundation of the world
for some good end, or bad, as you may
choose to call it. Judge ye for
yourselves. God knoweth all these things,
whether it be good or bad. But
nevertheless, deep water is what I am wont to swim
in. It all has become a second nature
to me; and I feel, like Paul, to glory
in tribulation; for to this day has the
God of my fathers delivered me out of
them all, and will deliver me from
henceforth; for behold, and lo, I shall
triumph over all my enemies, for the Lord God hath spoken it.
3 Let all the saints rejoice,
therefore, and be exceedingly glad; for
Israel’s God is their God, and he will
mete out a just recompense of reward
upon the heads of all their oppressors.
4 And again, verily thus saith the
Lord: Let the work of my temple,
and all the works which I have
appointed unto you, be continued on
and not cease; and let your
diligence, and your perseverance, and
patience, and your works be
redoubled, and you shall in nowise lose
your reward, saith the Lord of Hosts.
And if they persecute you, so
persecuted they the prophets and
righteous men that were before you.
For all this there is a reward in heaven.
5 And again, I give unto
you a word in relation to
the baptism for your dead.
6 Verily, thus saith the
Lord unto you concerning
your dead: When any of
you are baptized for your
dead, let there be a
recorder, and let him be
eye-witness of your baptisms;
let him hear with his
ears, that he may testify of
a truth, saith the Lord;
7 That in all your
recordings it may be recorded
in heaven; whatsoever
you bind on earth, may be
bound in heaven;
whatsoever you loose on earth,
may be loosed in heaven;
8 For I am about to
restore many things to
the earth,
pertaining to the priesthood,
saith the Lord of Hosts.
9 And again, let all
the records be had
in order, that they
may be put in the
archives of my holy
temple, to be held in
remembrance from
generation to
generation, saith the Lord of Hosts.
10 I will say to
all the saints, that
I desired, with
exceedingly great
desire, to have
addressed them from the
stand on the subject
of baptism for the
dead, on the
following Sabbath. But
inasmuch as it is out
of my power to do
so, I will write
the word of the Lord
from time to time,
on that subject,
and send it to you by
mail, as well as many other things.
11 I now close my
letter for the
present, for the want
of more time; for
the enemy is on
the alert, and as
the Savior said,
the prince of this
world cometh, but
he hath nothing in me.
12 Behold, my
prayer to God is
that you all may be
saved. And I
subscribe myself your
servant in the
Lord, prophet and
seer of The
Church of Jesus Christ
of Latter-day
Saints.Joseph Smith.