Section 45 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to the Church, at Kirtland, Ohio, March
7, 1831. Prefacing the record of this revelation,
Joseph Smith’s history states that “at this age
of the Church … many false reports … and foolish
stories, were published … and circulated, … to
prevent people from investigating the work, or
embracing the faith. … But to the joy of the Saints, … I
received the following.”
1–5, Christ is our
advocate with the Father;
6–10, The gospel is a
messenger to prepare the way before the Lord;
11–15,
Enoch and his brethren were received by the Lord unto
Himself;
16–23, Christ revealed signs of His
coming as given on the Mount of Olives;
24–38, The
gospel will be restored, the times of the Gentiles
will be fulfilled, and a desolating sickness will
cover the land;
39–47, Signs, wonders, and the
Resurrection are to attend the Second Coming;
48–53, Christ will stand on the Mount of Olives, and
the Jews will see the wounds in His hands and feet;
54–59, The Lord will reign during the Millennium;
60–62, The Prophet is instructed to begin the
translation of the New Testament, through which
important information will be made known;
63–75, The
Saints are commanded to gather and build the New
Jerusalem, to which people from all nations will
come.
1 Hearken, O ye people of my church, to whom the
kingdom has been given; hearken ye and give ear to
him who laid the foundation of the earth, who made
the heavens and all the hosts thereof, and by
whom all things were made which live, and move, and
have a being
2 And again I say, hearken unto my voice, lest
death shall overtake you; in an hour when ye think
not the summer shall be past, and the harvest ended,
and your souls not saved
3 Listen to him who is the advocate with the
Father, who is pleading your cause before him
4 Saying: Father, behold the sufferings and death
of him who did no sin, in whom thou wast well
pleased; behold the blood of thy Son which was shed,
the blood of him whom thou gavest that thyself
might be glorified
5 Wherefore, Father, spare these my brethren that
believe on my name, that they may come unto me and
have everlasting life
6 Hearken, O ye people of my church, and ye elders
listen together, and hear my voice while it is
called today, and harden not your hearts
7 For verily I say unto you that I am Alpha and
Omega, the beginning and the end, the light and the
life of the world—a light that shineth in darkness
and the darkness comprehendeth it not
8 I came unto mine own, and mine own received me
not; but unto as many as received me gave I power
to do many miracles, and to become the sons of God;
and even unto them that believed on my name gave
I power to obtain eternal life
9 And even so I have sent mine everlasting
covenant into the world, to be a light to the world, and
to be a standard for my people, and for the
Gentiles to seek to it, and to be a messenger before my
face to prepare the way before me
10 Wherefore, come ye unto it, and with him that
cometh I will reason as with men in days of old,
and I will show unto you my strong reasoning
11 Wherefore, hearken ye together and let me show
unto you even my wisdom—the wisdom of him whom ye
say is the God of Enoch, and his brethren
12 Who were separated from the earth, and were
received unto myself—a city reserved until a day of
righteousness shall come—a day which was sought for
by all holy men, and they found it not because of
wickedness and abominations
13 And confessed they were strangers and pilgrims
on the earth
14 But obtained a promise that they should find it
and see it in their flesh
15 Wherefore, hearken and I will reason with you,
and I will speak unto you and prophesy, as unto
men in days of old
16 And I will show it plainly as I showed it unto
my disciples as I stood before them in the flesh,
and spake unto them, saying: As ye have asked of
me concerning the signs of my coming, in the day
when I shall come in my glory in the clouds of
heaven, to fulfil the promises that I have made unto
your fathers
17 For as ye have looked upon the long absence of
your spirits from your bodies to be a bondage, I
will show unto you how the day of redemption shall
come, and also the restoration of the scattered
Israel
18 And now ye behold this temple which is in
Jerusalem, which ye call the house of God, and your
enemies say that this house shall never fall
19 But, verily I say unto you, that desolation
shall come upon this generation as a thief in the
night, and this people shall be destroyed and
scattered among all nations
20 And this temple which ye now see shall be
thrown down that there shall not be left one stone upon
another
21 And it shall come to pass, that this generation
of Jews shall not pass away until every
desolation which I have told you concerning them shall come
to pass
22 Ye say that ye know that the end of the world
cometh; ye say also that ye know that the heavens
and the earth shall pass away
23 And in this ye say truly, for so it is; but
these things which I have told you shall not pass
away until all shall be fulfilled
24 And this I have told you concerning Jerusalem;
and when that day shall come, shall a remnant be
scattered among all nations
25 But they shall be gathered again; but they
shall remain until the times of the Gentiles be
fulfilled
26 And in that day shall be heard of wars and
rumors of wars, and the whole earth shall be in
commotion, and men’s hearts shall fail them, and they
shall say that Christ delayeth his coming until the
end of the earth
27 And the love of men shall wax cold, and
iniquity shall abound
28 And when the times of the Gentiles is come in,
a light shall break forth among them that sit in
darkness, and it shall be the fulness of my gospel
29 But they receive it not; for they perceive not
the light, and they turn their hearts from me
because of the precepts of men
30 And in that generation shall the times of the
Gentiles be fulfilled
31 And there shall be men standing in that
generation, that shall not pass until they shall see an
overflowing scourge; for a desolating sickness
shall cover the land
32 But my disciples shall stand in holy places,
and shall not be moved; but among the wicked, men
shall lift up their voices and curse God and die
33 And there shall be earthquakes also in divers
places, and many desolations; yet men will harden
their hearts against me, and they will take up the
sword, one against another, and they will kill one
another
34 And now, when I the Lord had spoken these words
unto my disciples, they were troubled
35 And I said unto them: Be not troubled, for,
when all these things shall come to pass, ye may know
that the promises which have been made unto you
shall be fulfilled
36 And when the light shall begin to break forth,
it shall be with them like unto a parable which I
will show you
37 Ye look and behold the fig trees, and ye see
them with your eyes, and ye say when they begin to
shoot forth, and their leaves are yet tender, that
summer is now nigh at hand
38 Even so it shall be in that day when they shall
see all these things, then shall they know that
the hour is nigh
39 And it shall come to pass that he that feareth
me shall be looking forth for the great day of the
Lord to come, even for the signs of the coming of
the Son of Man
40 And they shall see signs and wonders, for they
shall be shown forth in the heavens above, and in
the earth beneath
41 And they shall behold blood, and fire, and
vapors of smoke
42 And before the day of the Lord shall come, the
sun shall be darkened, and the moon be turned into
blood, and the stars fall from heaven
43 And the remnant shall be gathered unto this
place
44 And then they shall look for me, and, behold, I
will come; and they shall see me in the clouds of
heaven, clothed with power and great glory; with
all the holy angels; and he that watches not for
me shall be cut off
45 But before the arm of the Lord shall fall, an
angel shall sound his trump, and the saints that
have slept shall come forth to meet me in the cloud
46 Wherefore, if ye have slept in peace blessed
are you; for as you now behold me and know that I
am, even so shall ye come unto me and your souls
shall live, and your redemption shall be perfected;
and the saints shall come forth from the four
quarters of the earth
47 Then shall the arm of the Lord fall upon the
nations
48 And then shall the Lord set his foot upon this
mount, and it shall cleave in twain, and the earth
shall tremble, and reel to and fro, and the
heavens also shall shake
49 And the Lord shall utter his voice, and all the
ends of the earth shall hear it; and the nations
of the earth shall mourn, and they that have
laughed shall see their folly
50 And calamity shall cover the mocker, and the
scorner shall be consumed; and they that have
watched for iniquity shall be hewn down and cast into
the fire
51 And then shall the Jews look upon me and say:
What are these wounds in thine hands and in thy
feet
52 Then shall they know that I am the Lord; for I
will say unto them: These wounds are the wounds
with which I was wounded in the house of my friends.
I am he who was lifted up. I am Jesus that was
crucified. I am the Son of God
53 And then shall they weep because of their
iniquities; then shall they lament because they
persecuted their king
54 And then shall the heathen nations be redeemed,
and they that knew no law shall have part in the
first resurrection; and it shall be tolerable for
them
55 And Satan shall be bound, that he shall have no
place in the hearts of the children of men
56 And at that day, when I shall come in my glory,
shall the parable be fulfilled which I spake
concerning the ten virgins
57 For they that are wise and have received the
truth, and have taken the Holy Spirit for their
guide, and have not been deceived—verily I say unto
you, they shall not be hewn down and cast into the
fire, but shall abide the day
58 And the earth shall be given unto them for an
inheritance; and they shall multiply and wax
strong, and their children shall grow up without sin
unto salvation
59 For the Lord shall be in their midst, and his
glory shall be upon them, and he will be their king
and their lawgiver
60 And now, behold, I say unto you, it shall not
be given unto you to know any further concerning
this chapter, until the New Testament be translated,
and in it all these things shall be made known
61 Wherefore I give unto you that ye may now
translate it, that ye may be prepared for the things to
come
62 For verily I say unto you, that great things
await you
63 Ye hear of wars in foreign lands; but, behold,
I say unto you, they are nigh, even at your doors,
and not many years hence ye shall hear of wars in
your own lands
64 Wherefore I, the Lord, have said, gather ye out
from the eastern lands, assemble ye yourselves
together ye elders of my church; go ye forth into
the western countries, call upon the inhabitants to
repent, and inasmuch as they do repent, build up
churches unto me
65 And with one heart and with one mind, gather up
your riches that ye may purchase an inheritance
which shall hereafter be appointed unto you
66 And it shall be called the New Jerusalem, a
land of peace, a city of refuge, a place of safety
for the saints of the Most High God
67 And the glory of the Lord shall be there, and
the terror of the Lord also shall be there,
insomuch that the wicked will not come unto it, and it
shall be called Zion
68 And it shall come to pass among the wicked,
that every man that will not take his sword against
his neighbor must needs flee unto Zion for safety
69 And there shall be gathered unto it out of
every nation under heaven; and it shall be the only
people that shall not be at war one with another
70 And it shall be said among the wicked: Let us
not go up to battle against Zion, for the
inhabitants of Zion are terrible; wherefore we cannot
stand
71 And it shall come to pass that the righteous
shall be gathered out from among all nations, and
shall come to Zion, singing with songs of
everlasting joy
72 And now I say unto you, keep these things from
going abroad unto the world until it is expedient
in me, that ye may accomplish this work in the
eyes of the people, and in the eyes of your enemies,
that they may not know your works until ye have
accomplished the thing which I have commanded you
73 That when they shall know it, that they may
consider these things
74 For when the Lord shall appear he shall be
terrible unto them, that fear may seize upon them, and
they shall stand afar off and tremble
75 And all nations shall be afraid because of the
terror of the Lord, and the power of his might.
Even so. Amen.