Section 131 Instructions by Joseph Smith the
Prophet, given at Ramus, Illinois, May 16
and 17, 1843.
1–4, Celestial marriage is
essential to exaltation in the highest heaven;
5–6, How men are sealed up unto eternal
life is explained;
7–8, All spirit is matter.
1 In the celestial glory there
are three heavens or degrees;
2 And in order to obtain the
highest, a man must enter
into this order of the
priesthood [meaning the new and
everlasting covenant of marriage];
3 And if he does not,
he cannot obtain it.
4 He may enter
into the other, but
that is the end of
his kingdom; he
cannot have an increase.
5 (May 17th,
1843.) The more sure
word of prophecy
means a man’s
knowing that he is
sealed up unto
eternal life, by
revelation and the
spirit of
prophecy, through the
power of the Holy Priesthood.
6 It is
impossible for a
man to be
saved in ignorance.
7 There is
no such thing
as
immaterial matter.
All spirit is
matter, but
it is more
fine or
pure, and can
only be
discerned by purer eyes;
8 We cannot
see it;
but when our
bodies are
purified we
shall see
that it is
all matter.