Section 100 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at Perrysburg, New
York, October 12, 1833. The two brethren, having
been absent from their families for several
days, felt some concern about them.
1–4, Joseph and
Sidney to preach the gospel for the salvation
of souls;
5–8, It will be given them in the very
hour what they should say;
9–12, Sidney is to
be a spokesman and Joseph is to be a revelator
and mighty in testimony;
13–17, The Lord will
raise up a pure people, and the obedient will be saved.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you, my
friends Sidney and Joseph, your families are well;
they are in mine hands, and I will do with them
as seemeth me good; for in me there is all power.
2 Therefore, follow me, and listen to
the counsel which I shall give unto you.
3 Behold, and lo, I have much
people in this place, in the regions
round about; and an effectual
door shall be opened in the regions
round about in this eastern land.
4 Therefore, I, the Lord, have
suffered you to come unto this
place; for thus it was expedient
in me for the salvation of souls.
5 Therefore, verily I say
unto you, lift up your voices
unto this people; speak the
thoughts that I shall put
into your hearts, and you
shall not be confounded before men;
6 For it shall be
given you in the very
hour, yea, in the very
moment, what ye shall say.
7 But a commandment
I give unto you,
that ye shall declare
whatsoever thing ye
declare in my name,
in solemnity of
heart, in the spirit of
meekness, in all things.
8 And I give unto
you this promise,
that inasmuch as ye
do this the Holy
Ghost shall be shed
forth in bearing
record unto all things
whatsoever ye shall say.
9 And it is
expedient in me that
you, my servant
Sidney, should be a
spokesman unto
this people; yea,
verily, I will
ordain you unto
this calling, even
to be a spokesman
unto my servant Joseph.
10 And I will
give unto him
power to be
mighty in testimony.
11 And I will
give unto thee
power to be
mighty in
expounding all
scriptures, that
thou mayest be
a spokesman
unto him, and he
shall be a
revelator unto
thee, that thou
mayest know
the certainty
of all things
pertaining to
the things of
my kingdom on the earth.
12 Therefore,
continue
your journey and
let your
hearts rejoice;
for behold,
and lo, I am
with you even
unto the end.
13 And now I
give unto
you a word
concerning
Zion. Zion
shall be
redeemed, although
she is
chastened for a
little season.
14 Thy
brethren, my
servants
Orson Hyde and
John Gould,
are in my
hands; and
inasmuch as
they keep
my
commandments they
shall be saved.
Therefore, let
your hearts
be
comforted; for
all things
shall work
together
for good to
them that
walk
uprightly, and
to the
sanctification of the church.
16 For I
will
raise up unto
myself a
pure
people, that
will
serve me in
righteousness;
17 And
all that
call
upon the
name of
the Lord,
and keep
his
commandments, shall
be
saved. Even so. Amen.