Section 134 A declaration of belief regarding
governments and laws in general, adopted by unanimous
vote at a general assembly of the Church held at
Kirtland, Ohio, August 17, 1835. Many Saints
gathered together to consider the proposed contents of
the first edition of the Doctrine and Covenants. At
that time, this declaration was given the
following preamble: “That our belief with regard to
earthly governments and laws in general may not be
misinterpreted nor misunderstood, we have thought
proper to present, at the close of this volume, our
opinion concerning the same.”
1–4, Governments
should preserve freedom of conscience and worship;
5–8, All men should uphold their governments and owe
respect and deference to the law;
9–10,
Religious societies should not exercise civil powers;
11–12, Men are justified in defending themselves and
their property.
1 We believe that governments were instituted of
God for the benefit of man; and that he holds men
accountable for their acts in relation to them,
both in making laws and administering them, for the
good and safety of society
2 We believe that no government can exist in
peace, except such laws are framed and held inviolate
as will secure to each individual the free exercise
of conscience, the right and control of property,
and the protection of life
3 We believe that all governments necessarily
require civil officers and magistrates to enforce the
laws of the same; and that such as will administer
the law in equity and justice should be sought
for and upheld by the voice of the people if a
republic, or the will of the sovereign
4 We believe that religion is instituted of God;
and that men are amenable to him, and to him only,
for the exercise of it, unless their religious
opinions prompt them to infringe upon the rights and
liberties of others; but we do not believe that
human law has a right to interfere in prescribing
rules of worship to bind the consciences of men, nor
dictate forms for public or private devotion;
that the civil magistrate should restrain crime, but
never control conscience; should punish guilt, but
never suppress the freedom of the soul
5 We believe that all men are bound to sustain and
uphold the respective governments in which they
reside, while protected in their inherent and
inalienable rights by the laws of such governments; and
that sedition and rebellion are unbecoming every
citizen thus protected, and should be punished
accordingly; and that all governments have a right to
enact such laws as in their own judgments are
best calculated to secure the public interest; at the
same time, however, holding sacred the freedom of
conscience
6 We believe that every man should be honored in
his station, rulers and magistrates as such, being
placed for the protection of the innocent and the
punishment of the guilty; and that to the laws all
men owe respect and deference, as without them
peace and harmony would be supplanted by anarchy and
terror; human laws being instituted for the
express purpose of regulating our interests as
individuals and nations, between man and man; and divine
laws given of heaven, prescribing rules on
spiritual concerns, for faith and worship, both to be
answered by man to his Maker
7 We believe that rulers, states, and governments
have a right, and are bound to enact laws for the
protection of all citizens in the free exercise of
their religious belief; but we do not believe
that they have a right in justice to deprive citizens
of this privilege, or proscribe them in their
opinions, so long as a regard and reverence are shown
to the laws and such religious opinions do not
justify sedition nor conspiracy
8 We believe that the commission of crime should
be punished according to the nature of the offense;
that murder, treason, robbery, theft, and the
breach of the general peace, in all respects, should
be punished according to their criminality and
their tendency to evil among men, by the laws of that
government in which the offense is committed; and
for the public peace and tranquility all men
should step forward and use their ability in bringing
offenders against good laws to punishment
9 We do not believe it just to mingle religious
influence with civil government, whereby one
religious society is fostered and another proscribed in
its spiritual privileges, and the individual rights
of its members, as citizens, denied
10 We believe that all religious societies have a
right to deal with their members for disorderly
conduct, according to the rules and regulations of
such societies; provided that such dealings be for
fellowship and good standing; but we do not
believe that any religious society has authority to try
men on the right of property or life, to take from
them this world’s goods, or to put them in
jeopardy of either life or limb, or to inflict any
physical punishment upon them. They can only
excommunicate them from their society, and withdraw from
them their fellowship
11 We believe that men should appeal to the civil
law for redress of all wrongs and grievances,
where personal abuse is inflicted or the right of
property or character infringed, where such laws exist
as will protect the same; but we believe that all
men are justified in defending themselves, their
friends, and property, and the government, from
the unlawful assaults and encroachments of all
persons in times of exigency, where immediate appeal
cannot be made to the laws, and relief afforded
12 We believe it just to preach the gospel to the
nations of the earth, and warn the righteous to
save themselves from the corruption of the world;
but we do not believe it right to interfere with
bond-servants, neither preach the gospel to, nor
baptize them contrary to the will and wish of their
masters, nor to meddle with or influence them in the
least to cause them to be dissatisfied with their
situations in this life, thereby jeopardizing the
lives of men; such interference we believe to be
unlawful and unjust, and dangerous to the peace of
every government allowing human beings to be held
in servitude.