Section 103 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, February 24,
1834. This revelation was received after the arrival
in Kirtland, Ohio, of Parley P. Pratt and Lyman
Wight, who had come from Missouri to counsel with
the Prophet as to the relief and restoration of
the Saints to their lands in Jackson County.
1–4, Why the Lord permitted the Saints in Jackson
County to be persecuted;
5–10, The Saints will
prevail if they keep the commandments;
11–20, The
redemption of Zion will come by power, and the
Lord will go before His people;
21–28, The Saints
are to gather in Zion, and those who lay down
their lives will find them again;
29–40, Various
brethren are called to organize Zion’s Camp and go
to Zion; they are promised victory if they are faithful.
1 Verily I say unto you, my friends,
behold, I will give unto you a revelation and
commandment, that you may know how to act in
the discharge of your duties concerning the
salvation and redemption of your brethren,
who have been scattered on the land of Zion;
2 Being driven and smitten by the hands
of mine enemies, on whom I will pour out
my wrath without measure in mine own time.
3 For I have suffered them thus far, that
they might fill up the measure of their
iniquities, that their cup might be full;
4 And that those who call themselves
after my name might be chastened for
a little season with a sore and
grievous chastisement, because they did
not hearken altogether unto the
precepts and commandments which I gave unto them.
5 But verily I say unto you, that
I have decreed a decree which my
people shall realize, inasmuch
as they hearken from this very
hour unto the counsel which I, the
Lord their God, shall give unto them.
6 Behold they shall, for
I have decreed it, begin
to prevail against mine
enemies from this very hour.
7 And by hearkening to
observe all the words
which I, the Lord their
God, shall speak unto
them, they shall never
cease to prevail until
the kingdoms of the
world are subdued under my
feet, and the earth is
given unto the saints,
to possess it forever and ever.
8 But inasmuch as
they keep not my
commandments, and hearken
not to observe all
my words, the
kingdoms of the world
shall prevail against them.
9 For they were set
to be a light unto
the world, and to
be the saviors of men;
10 And inasmuch
as they are not
the saviors of men,
they are as salt
that has lost
its savor, and is
thenceforth good
for nothing but to
be cast out and
trodden under foot of men.
11 But verily I
say unto you, I
have decreed
that your brethren
which have been
scattered shall
return to the
lands of their
inheritances, and
shall build up
the waste places of Zion.
12 For after
much
tribulation, as I have
said unto you
in a former
commandment,
cometh the blessing.
13 Behold,
this is the
blessing which I
have
promised after your
tribulations,
and the
tribulations of
your
brethren—your
redemption, and the
redemption of
your
brethren, even their
restoration
to the land of
Zion, to be
established,
no more to be thrown down.
Nevertheless, if they
pollute
their
inheritances they
shall be thrown
down; for I
will not
spare them if
they pollute
their inheritances.
15 Behold,
I say
unto you, the
redemption of Zion
must needs
come by power;
Therefore, I
will raise
up unto
my people
a man,
who shall
lead them
like as
Moses led
the
children of Israel.
17 For
ye are
the
children of
Israel,
and of the
seed of
Abraham, and ye
must
needs be
led out
of
bondage by
power, and
with a
stretched-out arm.
18 And
as your
fathers were
led at
the
first,
even so
shall the
redemption of Zion be.
Therefore, let
not
your
hearts
faint,
for I
say not
unto
you as
I
said unto
your
fathers:
Mine
angel
shall go
up
before
you, but not my presence.
20 But
I say
unto
you:
Mine
angels
shall
go up
before
you,
and
also my
presence, and
in
time ye
shall
possess the
goodly
land.
Verily,
verily I
say
unto
you,
that
my
servant
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.,
is
the man
to
whom I
likened
the
servant
to
whom
the
Lord of
vineyard
spake
in
the
parable which I have given unto you.
Therefore
let my
servant
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.,
say
unto the
strength
of my
house, my
young men
and
the
middle
aged—Gather
yourselves
together
unto
the
land of
Zion,
upon
the
land
which
I
have
bought
with
money
that
has
been
consecrated
unto me.
And
let
all
the
churches
send
up
wise
men
with
their
moneys,
and
purchase
lands
even
as I have commanded them.
And
inasmuch
as
mine
enemies
come
against
you
to
drive
you
from
my
goodly
land,
which
I
have
consecrated
to
be
the
land
of
Zion,
even
from
your
own
lands
after
these
testimonies,
which
ye
have
brought
before
me
against
them,
ye
shall
curse
them;
And
whomsoever
ye
curse,
I
will
curse,
and
ye
shall
avenge me of mine enemies.
And
my
presence
shall
be
with
you
even
in
avenging
me
of
mine
enemies,
unto
the
third
and
fourth
generation
of
them
that
hate
afraid
to
lay
down
his
life
for
my
sake;
for
whoso
layeth
down
his life for my sake shall find it again.
And
whoso
is
not
willing
to
lay
down
his
life
for
my
sake
is
not
my
disciple.
It
is
my
will
that
my
servant
Sidney
Rigdon
shall
lift
up
his
voice
in
the
congregations
in
the
eastern
countries,
in
preparing
the
churches
to
keep
the
commandments
which
I
have
given
unto
them
concerning
the
restoration
and
redemption
of
Zion.
30 It is my will that my servant Parley P. Pratt and my servant Lyman Wight should not return to the land of their brethren, until they have obtained companies to go up unto the land of Zion, by tens, or by twenties, or by fifties, or by an hundred, until they have obtained to the number of five hundred of the strength of my
It
is
my
will
that
my
servant
Parley P.
Pratt
and
my
servant
Lyman
Wight
should
not
return
to
the
land
of
their
brethren,
until
they
have
obtained
companies
to
go
up unto the land of Zion, by tens, or by twenties, or by fifties, or by an hundred, until they have obtained to the number of five hundred of the strength of my house.
31 Behold this is my will; ask and ye shall receive; but men do not always do my
Behold
this
is
my
will;
ask
and
ye
shall
receive;
but
men
do
not
always
do
my
will.
32 Therefore, if you cannot obtain five hundred, seek diligently that peradventure you may obtain three
Therefore,
if
you
cannot
obtain
five
hundred,
seek
diligently
that
peradventure
you
may
obtain
three
hundred.
33 And if ye cannot obtain three hundred, seek diligently that peradventure ye may obtain one
And
if
ye
cannot
obtain
three
hundred,
seek
diligently
that
peradventure
ye
may
obtain
one
hundred.
34 But verily I say unto you, a commandment I give unto you, that ye shall not go up unto the land of Zion until you have obtained a hundred of the strength of my house, to go up with you unto the land of
But
verily
I
say
unto
you,
a
commandment
I
give
unto
you,
that
ye
shall
not
go
up
unto
the
land
of
Zion
until
you
have
obtained
a
hundred
of
the
strength
of
my
house,
to
go
up
with
you
unto
the
land
of
Zion.
35 Therefore, as I said unto you, ask and ye shall receive; pray earnestly that peradventure my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., may go with you, and preside in the midst of my people, and organize my kingdom upon the consecrated land, and establish the children of Zion upon the laws and commandments which have been and which shall be given unto
Therefore,
as
I
said
unto
you,
ask
and
ye
shall
receive;
pray
earnestly
that
peradventure
my
servant
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.,
may
go
with
you,
and
preside
in
the
midst
of
my
people,
and
organize
my
kingdom
upon
the
consecrated
land,
and
establish
the
children
of
Zion
upon
the
laws
and
commandments
which
have
been
and
which
shall
be
given
unto
you.
36 All victory and glory is brought to pass unto you through your diligence, faithfulness, and prayers of
All
victory
and
glory
is
brought
to
pass
unto
you
through
your
diligence,
faithfulness,
and
prayers
of
faith.
37 Let my servant Parley P. Pratt journey with my servant Joseph Smith,
Let
my
servant
Parley P.
Pratt
journey
with
my
servant
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.
38 Let my servant Lyman Wight journey with my servant Sidney
Let
my
servant
Lyman
Wight
journey
with
my
servant
Sidney
Rigdon.
39 Let my servant Hyrum Smith journey with my servant Frederick G.
Let
my
servant
Hyrum
Smith
journey
with
my
servant
Frederick G.
Williams.
40 Let my servant Orson Hyde journey with my servant Orson Pratt, whithersoever my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., shall counsel them, in obtaining the fulfilment of these commandments which I have given unto you, and leave the residue in my hands. Even so. Amen.
Let
my
servant
Orson
Hyde
journey
with
my
servant
Orson
Pratt,
whithersoever
my
servant
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.,
shall
counsel
them,
in
obtaining
the
fulfilment
of
these
commandments
which
I
have
given
unto
you,
and
leave
the
residue
in
my
hands.
Even
so.
Amen.