Section 112 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Thomas B. Marsh, at Kirtland,
Ohio, July 23, 1837, concerning the Twelve Apostles
of the Lamb. This revelation was received on the
day Elders Heber C. Kimball and Orson Hyde first
preached the gospel in England. Thomas B. Marsh
was at this time President of the Quorum of the
Twelve Apostles.
1–10, The Twelve are to send the
gospel and raise the warning voice to all nations
and people;
11–15, They are to take up their
cross, follow Jesus, and feed His sheep;
16–20,
Those who receive the First Presidency receive the
Lord;
21–29, Darkness covers the earth, and only
those who believe and are baptized will be
saved;
30–34, The First Presidency and the Twelve
hold the keys of the dispensation of the fulness of times.
1 Verily thus saith the Lord unto you my servant
Thomas: I have heard thy prayers; and thine alms
have come up as a memorial before me, in behalf
of those, thy brethren, who were chosen to bear
testimony of my name and to send it abroad among
all nations, kindreds, tongues, and people, and
ordained through the instrumentality of my servants.
2 Verily I say unto you, there have been
some few things in thine heart and with thee
with which I, the Lord, was not well pleased.
3 Nevertheless, inasmuch as thou hast
abased thyself thou shalt be exalted;
therefore, all thy sins are forgiven thee.
4 Let thy heart be of good cheer
before my face; and thou shalt
bear record of my name, not only
unto the Gentiles, but also unto
the Jews; and thou shalt send forth
my word unto the ends of the earth.
5 Contend thou, therefore,
morning by morning; and day after
day let thy warning voice go
forth; and when the night cometh
let not the inhabitants of the
earth slumber, because of thy speech.
6 Let thy habitation be
known in Zion, and remove not
thy house; for I, the Lord,
have a great work for thee
to do, in publishing my
name among the children of men.
7 Therefore, gird up thy
loins for the work. Let thy
feet be shod also, for
thou art chosen, and thy
path lieth among the
mountains, and among many nations.
8 And by thy word many
high ones shall be brought
low, and by thy word many
low ones shall be exalted.
9 Thy voice shall be
a rebuke unto the
transgressor; and at thy
rebuke let the
tongue of the slanderer
cease its perverseness.
10 Be thou humble;
and the Lord thy God
shall lead thee by the
hand, and give thee
answer to thy prayers.
11 I know thy heart,
and have heard thy
prayers concerning
thy brethren. Be not
partial towards them
in love above many
others, but let thy
love be for them as
for thyself; and let
thy love abound
unto all men, and unto
all who love my name.
12 And pray for thy
brethren of the
Twelve. Admonish them
sharply for my
name’s sake, and let
them be admonished
for all their sins,
and be ye faithful
before me unto my name.
13 And after their
temptations, and
much tribulation,
behold, I, the
Lord, will feel after
them, and if they
harden not their
hearts, and
stiffen not their necks
against me, they
shall be converted,
and I will heal them.
14 Now, I say
unto you, and what I
say unto you, I
say unto all the
Twelve: Arise and
gird up your
loins, take up your
cross, follow me,
and feed my sheep.
15 Exalt not
yourselves; rebel not
against my
servant Joseph; for
verily I say unto
you, I am with
him, and my hand
shall be over him;
and the keys which
I have given
unto him, and also
to youward, shall
not be taken from
him till I come.
16 Verily I say
unto you, my
servant Thomas,
thou art the man
whom I have chosen
to hold the
keys of my kingdom,
as pertaining
to the Twelve,
abroad among all nations—
17 That thou
mayest be my
servant to
unlock the door of
the kingdom in
all places
where my servant
Joseph, and
my servant
Sidney, and my
servant Hyrum, cannot come;
18 For on
them have I laid
the burden
of all the
churches for a
little season.
Wherefore,
whithersoever they
shall send you,
go ye, and
I will be
with you; and
in
whatsoever place ye
shall
proclaim my name an
effectual
door shall be
opened unto
you, that
they may receive my word.
Whosoever receiveth
my word
receiveth me,
and
whosoever
receiveth me,
receiveth
those, the First
Presidency, whom I
have sent,
whom I have
made
counselors for my
name’s sake unto you.
21 And
again, I say
unto you,
that
whosoever ye
shall send
in my name,
by the
voice of
your
brethren, the
Twelve, duly
recommended
and
authorized by
you, shall
have power
to open
the door of
my
kingdom unto any
nation
whithersoever ye shall send them—
Inasmuch as
they shall
humble
themselves
before me,
and
abide in my
word, and
hearken
to the
voice of my Spirit.
Verily,
verily, I say
unto
you,
darkness
covereth the
earth,
and
gross
darkness the
minds of
the
people, and
all
flesh has
become
corrupt before my face.
Behold,
vengeance
cometh
speedily upon
the
inhabitants of
earth, a day
of
wrath, a
day of
burning,
a day
of
desolation,
weeping,
of
mourning,
and of
lamentation; and
as a
whirlwind it
shall
come upon
all the
face of the earth, saith the Lord.
25 And
upon
my
house
shall it
begin,
and
from my
house
shall
it go
forth, saith the Lord;
First
among
those
you,
saith
the
Lord,
who
have
professed to
know
my
name
and
have not
known me,
and
have
blasphemed
against
me in
the
midst of my house, saith the Lord.
Therefore,
see to
it
that
ye
trouble
not
yourselves
concerning
the
affairs of
my
church
in
this place, saith the Lord.
But
purify
your
hearts
before
me;
and
then
go
ye
into
all
the
world,
and
preach
my
gospel
unto
every creature who has not received it;
And
he
that
believeth
and
is
baptized
shall
be
saved,
and
he
that
believeth
not, and is not baptized, shall be damned.
For
unto
you,
the
Twelve,
and
those,
the
First
Presidency,
who
are
appointed
with
you
to
be
your
counselors
and
your
leaders,
is
the
power
of
this
priesthood
given,
for
the
last
days
and
for
the
last
time,
in
the
which
is
the
dispensation
of
the
fulness
of
times,
Which
power
you
hold,
in
connection
with
all
those
who
have
received
a
dispensation
at
any
time
from
the
beginning
of
the
creation;
32 For verily I say unto you, the keys of the dispensation, which ye have received, have come down from the fathers, and last of all, being sent down from heaven unto
For
verily
I
say
unto
you,
the
keys
of
the
dispensation,
which
ye
have
received,
have come down from the fathers, and last of all, being sent down from heaven unto you.
33 Verily I say unto you, behold how great is your calling. Cleanse your hearts and your garments, lest the blood of this generation be required at your
Verily
I
say
unto
you,
behold
how
great
is
your
calling.
Cleanse
your
hearts
and
your
garments,
lest
the
blood
of
this
generation
be
required
at
your
hands.
34 Be faithful until I come, for I come quickly; and my reward is with me to recompense every man according as his work shall be. I am Alpha and Omega. Amen.
Be
faithful
until
I
come,
for
I
come
quickly;
and
my
reward
is
with
me
to
recompense
every
man
according
as
his
work
shall
be.
I
am
Alpha
and
Omega.
Amen.