Section 8 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Oliver Cowdery, at Harmony,
Pennsylvania, April 1829. In the course of the translation
of the Book of Mormon, Oliver, who continued to
serve as scribe, writing at the Prophet’s dictation,
desired to be endowed with the gift of
translation. The Lord responded to his supplication by
granting this revelation.
1–5, Revelation comes by the
power of the Holy Ghost;
6–12, Knowledge of the
mysteries of God and the power to translate
ancient records come by faith.
1 Oliver Cowdery, verily, verily, I say unto you,
that assuredly as the Lord liveth, who is your God
and your Redeemer, even so surely shall you
receive a knowledge of whatsoever things you shall ask
in faith, with an honest heart, believing that you
shall receive a knowledge concerning the
engravings of old records, which are ancient, which
contain those parts of my scripture of which has been
spoken by the manifestation of my Spirit
2 Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in
your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come
upon you and which shall dwell in your heart
3 Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation;
behold, this is the spirit by which Moses brought
the children of Israel through the Red Sea on dry
ground
4 Therefore this is thy gift; apply unto it, and
blessed art thou, for it shall deliver you out of
the hands of your enemies, when, if it were not so,
they would slay you and bring your soul to
destruction
5 Oh, remember these words, and keep my
commandments. Remember, this is your gift
6 Now this is not all thy gift; for you have
another gift, which is the gift of Aaron; behold, it
has told you many things
7 Behold, there is no other power, save the power
of God, that can cause this gift of Aaron to be
with you
8 Therefore, doubt not, for it is the gift of God;
and you shall hold it in your hands, and do
marvelous works; and no power shall be able to take it
away out of your hands, for it is the work of God
9 And, therefore, whatsoever you shall ask me to
tell you by that means, that will I grant unto you,
and you shall have knowledge concerning it
10 Remember that without faith you can do nothing;
therefore ask in faith. Trifle not with these
things; do not ask for that which you ought not
11 Ask that you may know the mysteries of God, and
that you may translate and receive knowledge from
all those ancient records which have been hid up,
that are sacred; and according to your faith
shall it be done unto you
12 Behold, it is I that have spoken it; and I am
the same that spake unto you from the beginning.
Amen.