Section 97 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, August 2, 1833.
This revelation deals particularly with the
affairs of the Saints in Zion, Jackson County,
Missouri, in response to the Prophet’s inquiry of the
Lord for information. Members of the Church in
Missouri were at this time subjected to severe
persecution and, on July 23, 1833, had been forced to
sign an agreement to leave Jackson County.
1–2,
Many of the Saints in Zion (Jackson County,
Missouri) are blessed for their faithfulness;
3–5,
Parley P. Pratt is commended for his labors in the
school in Zion;
6–9, Those who observe their
covenants are accepted by the Lord;
10–17, A house is
to be built in Zion in which the pure in heart
will see God;
18–21, Zion is the pure in heart;
22–28, Zion will escape the Lord’s scourge if she is faithful.
1 Verily I say unto you my friends, I speak
unto you with my voice, even the voice of my
Spirit, that I may show unto you my will
concerning your brethren in the land of Zion,
many of whom are truly humble and are
seeking diligently to learn wisdom and to find truth.
2 Verily, verily I say unto you, blessed
are such, for they shall obtain; for I, the
Lord, show mercy unto all the meek, and upon
all whomsoever I will, that I may be
justified when I shall bring them unto judgment.
3 Behold, I say unto you, concerning
the school in Zion, I, the Lord, am
well pleased that there should be a
school in Zion, and also with my
servant Parley P. Pratt, for he abideth in me.
4 And inasmuch as he continueth
to abide in me he shall
continue to preside over the school
in the land of Zion until I
shall give unto him other commandments.
5 And I will bless him
with a multiplicity of
blessings, in expounding all
scriptures and mysteries to
the edification of the
school, and of the church in Zion.
6 And to the residue of
the school, I, the Lord,
am willing to show
mercy; nevertheless, there
are those that must needs
be chastened, and their
works shall be made known.
7 The ax is laid at the
root of the trees; and
every tree that
bringeth not forth good fruit
shall be hewn down and
cast into the fire. I,
the Lord, have spoken it.
8 Verily I say unto
you, all among them who
know their hearts are
honest, and are
broken, and their spirits
contrite, and are
willing to observe their
covenants by
sacrifice—yea, every sacrifice
which I, the Lord, shall
command—they are accepted of me.
9 For I, the Lord,
will cause them to
bring forth as a very
fruitful tree which
is planted in a
goodly land, by a pure
stream, that yieldeth
much precious fruit.
10 Verily I say
unto you, that it is
my will that a
house should be
built unto me in the
land of Zion, like
unto the pattern
which I have given you.
11 Yea, let it
be built
speedily, by the
tithing of my people.
12 Behold,
this is the
tithing and the
sacrifice which
I, the Lord,
require at their
hands, that
there may be a
house built
unto me for the
salvation of Zion—
13 For a
place of
thanksgiving for all
saints, and
for a place of
instruction
for all those
who are
called to the
work of the
ministry in all
their several
callings and offices;
14 That they
may be
perfected in the
understanding of their
ministry, in
theory, in
principle,
and in
doctrine, in all
things
pertaining to the
kingdom of
God on the
earth, the
keys of which
kingdom have
been conferred upon you.
15 And
inasmuch as my
people
build a house
unto me in
the name of
the Lord,
and do not
suffer any
unclean
thing to come
into it,
that it be not
defiled,
my glory
shall rest upon it;
16 Yea,
and my
presence shall
be there,
for I will
come into
it, and
all the
pure in heart
that
shall come
into it shall see God.
17 But if
it be
defiled I
will not
come into
it, and
my glory
shall not
be there;
for I
will not
come into
unholy temples.
18 And,
now,
behold, if
Zion do
these
things she
shall
prosper,
and
spread
herself and
become
very
glorious,
very great,
and very terrible.
19 And
the
nations of
the earth
shall
honor her,
and
shall say:
Surely
Zion is
the city
of our
God, and
surely
Zion
cannot fall,
neither
be
moved out of
her
place, for
God is
there,
and the
hand of
the Lord
is there;
20 And
he hath
sworn
by the
power
of his
might to
be her
salvation and
her high tower.
Therefore,
verily,
thus
saith the
Lord,
let
Zion
rejoice,
for
this is
Zion—the
pure in
heart;
therefore,
let
Zion
rejoice,
while
all the wicked shall mourn.
22 For
behold, and
lo,
vengeance
cometh
speedily
upon
the
ungodly
as the
whirlwind;
and
who
shall
escape it?
The
Lord’s
scourge
shall
pass
over by
night and
by
day,
and
the
report
thereof
shall
vex all
people;
yea,
it
shall
not be
stayed until the Lord come;
For the
indignation of
the
Lord
is
kindled
against
their
abominations
and all
their
wicked
works.
Nevertheless,
Zion
shall
escape
if
she
observe to
do
all
things
whatsoever I have commanded her.
But
if
she
observe
not
to
do
whatsoever
I
have
commanded
her, I
will
visit
her
according
to
all
her
works,
with
sore
affliction,
with
pestilence,
plague, with sword, with vengeance, with devouring fire.
Nevertheless,
let
it
be
read
this
once
to
her
ears,
that
I,
the
Lord,
have
accepted
of
her
offering;
more
none
of
these
things
shall
come
upon
her;
And
I
will
bless
her
with
blessings,
and
multiply a
multiplicity
of
blessings
upon
her,
and
upon
her
generations
forever
and
ever,
saith
the
Lord
your
God.
Amen.