Section 71 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at Hiram, Ohio, December
1, 1831. The Prophet had continued to translate
the Bible with Sidney Rigdon as his scribe until
this revelation was received, at which time it was
temporarily laid aside so as to enable them to
fulfill the instruction given herein. The brethren were
to go forth to preach in order to allay the
unfriendly feelings that had developed against the
Church as a result of the publication of letters
written by Ezra Booth, who had apostatized.
1–4,
Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon are sent forth to
proclaim the gospel;
5–11, Enemies of the Saints will
be confounded.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto you my servants
Joseph Smith, Jun., and Sidney Rigdon, that the
time has verily come that it is necessary and
expedient in me that you should open your mouths in
proclaiming my gospel, the things of the kingdom,
expounding the mysteries thereof out of the
scriptures, according to that portion of Spirit and power
which shall be given unto you, even as I will
2 Verily I say unto you, proclaim unto the world
in the regions round about, and in the church also,
for the space of a season, even until it shall be
made known unto you
3 Verily this is a mission for a season, which I
give unto you
4 Wherefore, labor ye in my vineyard. Call upon
the inhabitants of the earth, and bear record, and
prepare the way for the commandments and
revelations which are to come
5 Now, behold this is wisdom; whoso readeth, let
him understand and receive also
6 For unto him that receiveth it shall be given
more abundantly, even power
7 Wherefore, confound your enemies; call upon them
to meet you both in public and in private; and
inasmuch as ye are faithful their shame shall be
made manifest
8 Wherefore, let them bring forth their strong
reasons against the Lord
9 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you—there is no
weapon that is formed against you shall prosper
10 And if any man lift his voice against you he
shall be confounded in mine own due time
11 Wherefore, keep my commandments; they are true
and faithful. Even so. Amen.