verses 73 through 93. The Prophet specifies this
revelation as “embracing the law of the Church.”
1–10, The elders are called to preach the gospel,
baptize converts, and build up the Church;
11–12,
They must be called and ordained and are to teach
the principles of the gospel found in the
scriptures;
13–17, They are to teach and prophesy by the
power of the Spirit;
18–29, The Saints are
commanded not to kill, steal, lie, lust, commit
adultery, or speak evil against others;
30–39, Laws
governing the consecration of properties are set forth;
40–42, Pride and idleness are condemned;
43–52,
The sick are to be healed through administrations
and by faith;
53–60, The scriptures govern the
Church and are to be proclaimed to the world;
61–69, The site of the New Jerusalem and the mysteries
of the kingdom will be revealed;
70–73,
Consecrated properties are to be used to support Church
officers;
74–93, Laws governing fornication,
adultery, killing, stealing, and confession of sins are
set forth.
1 Hearken, O ye elders of my church, who have
assembled yourselves together in my name, even Jesus
Christ the Son of the living God, the Savior of the
world; inasmuch as ye believe on my name and keep
my commandments
2 Again I say unto you, hearken and hear and obey
the law which I shall give unto you
3 For verily I say, as ye have assembled
yourselves together according to the commandment wherewith
I commanded you, and are agreed as touching this
one thing, and have asked the Father in my name,
even so ye shall receive
4 Behold, verily I say unto you, I give unto you
this first commandment, that ye shall go forth in
my name, every one of you, excepting my servants
Joseph Smith, Jun., and Sidney Rigdon
5 And I give unto them a commandment that they
shall go forth for a little season, and it shall be
given by the power of the Spirit when they shall
return
6 And ye shall go forth in the power of my Spirit,
preaching my gospel, two by two, in my name,
lifting up your voices as with the sound of a trump,
declaring my word like unto angels of God
7 And ye shall go forth baptizing with water,
saying: Repent ye, repent ye, for the kingdom of
heaven is at hand
8 And from this place ye shall go forth into the
regions westward; and inasmuch as ye shall find
them that will receive you ye shall build up my
church in every region
9 Until the time shall come when it shall be
revealed unto you from on high, when the city of the
New Jerusalem shall be prepared, that ye may be
gathered in one, that ye may be my people and I will
be your God
10 And again, I say unto you, that my servant
Edward Partridge shall stand in the office whereunto I
have appointed him. And it shall come to pass,
that if he transgress another shall be appointed in
his stead. Even so. Amen
11 Again I say unto you, that it shall not be
given to any one to go forth to preach my gospel, or
to build up my church, except he be ordained by
some one who has authority, and it is known to the
church that he has authority and has been regularly
ordained by the heads of the church
12 And again, the elders, priests and teachers of
this church shall teach the principles of my
gospel, which are in the Bible and the Book of Mormon,
in the which is the fulness of the gospel
13 And they shall observe the covenants and church
articles to do them, and these shall be their
teachings, as they shall be directed by the Spirit
14 And the Spirit shall be given unto you by the
prayer of faith; and if ye receive not the Spirit
ye shall not teach
15 And all this ye shall observe to do as I have
commanded concerning your teaching, until the
fulness of my scriptures is given
16 And as ye shall lift up your voices by the
Comforter, ye shall speak and prophesy as seemeth me
good
17 For, behold, the Comforter knoweth all things,
and beareth record of the Father and of the Son
18 And now, behold, I speak unto the church. Thou
shalt not kill; and he that kills shall not have
forgiveness in this world, nor in the world to
come
19 And again, I say, thou shalt not kill; but he
that killeth shall die
20 Thou shalt not steal; and he that stealeth and
will not repent shall be cast out
21 Thou shalt not lie; he that lieth and will not
repent shall be cast out
22 Thou shalt love thy wife with all thy heart,
and shalt cleave unto her and none else
23 And he that looketh upon a woman to lust after
her shall deny the faith, and shall not have the
Spirit; and if he repents not he shall be cast out
24 Thou shalt not commit adultery; and he that
committeth adultery, and repenteth not, shall be cast
out
25 But he that has committed adultery and repents
with all his heart, and forsaketh it, and doeth it
no more, thou shalt forgive
26 But if he doeth it again, he shall not be
forgiven, but shall be cast out
27 Thou shalt not speak evil of thy neighbor, nor
do him any harm
28 Thou knowest my laws concerning these things
are given in my scriptures; he that sinneth and
repenteth not shall be cast out
29 If thou lovest me thou shalt serve me and keep
all my commandments
30 And behold, thou wilt remember the poor, and
consecrate of thy properties for their support that
which thou hast to impart unto them, with a
covenant and a deed which cannot be broken
31 And inasmuch as ye impart of your substance
unto the poor, ye will do it unto me; and they shall
be laid before the bishop of my church and his
counselors, two of the elders, or high priests, such
as he shall appoint or has appointed and set apart
for that purpose
32 And it shall come to pass, that after they are
laid before the bishop of my church, and after
that he has received these testimonies concerning the
consecration of the properties of my church, that
they cannot be taken from the church, agreeable
to my commandments, every man shall be made
accountable unto me, a steward over his own property, or
that which he has received by consecration, as
much as is sufficient for himself and family
33 And again, if there shall be properties in the
hands of the church, or any individuals of it,
more than is necessary for their support after this
first consecration, which is a residue to be
consecrated unto the bishop, it shall be kept to
administer to those who have not, from time to time, that
every man who has need may be amply supplied and
receive according to his wants
34 Therefore, the residue shall be kept in my
storehouse, to administer to the poor and the needy,
as shall be appointed by the high council of the
church, and the bishop and his council
35 And for the purpose of purchasing lands for the
public benefit of the church, and building houses
of worship, and building up of the New Jerusalem
which is hereafter to be revealed
36 That my covenant people may be gathered in one
in that day when I shall come to my temple. And
this I do for the salvation of my people
37 And it shall come to pass, that he that sinneth
and repenteth not shall be cast out of the
church, and shall not receive again that which he has
consecrated unto the poor and the needy of my
church, or in other words, unto me
38 For inasmuch as ye do it unto the least of
these, ye do it unto me
39 For it shall come to pass, that which I spake
by the mouths of my prophets shall be fulfilled;
for I will consecrate of the riches of those who
embrace my gospel among the Gentiles unto the poor of
my people who are of the house of Israel
40 And again, thou shalt not be proud in thy
heart; let all thy garments be plain, and their beauty
the beauty of the work of thine own hands
41 And let all things be done in cleanliness
before me
42 Thou shalt not be idle; for he that is idle
shall not eat the bread nor wear the garments of the
laborer
43 And whosoever among you are sick, and have not
faith to be healed, but believe, shall be
nourished with all tenderness, with herbs and mild food,
and that not by the hand of an enemy
44 And the elders of the church, two or more,
shall be called, and shall pray for and lay their
hands upon them in my name; and if they die they shall
die unto me, and if they live they shall live
unto me
45 Thou shalt live together in love, insomuch that
thou shalt weep for the loss of them that die,
and more especially for those that have not hope of
a glorious resurrection
46 And it shall come to pass that those that die
in me shall not taste of death, for it shall be
sweet unto them
47 And they that die not in me, wo unto them, for
their death is bitter
48 And again, it shall come to pass that he that
hath faith in me to be healed, and is not appointed
unto death, shall be healed
49 He who hath faith to see shall see
50 He who hath faith to hear shall hear
51 The lame who hath faith to leap shall leap
52 And they who have not faith to do these things,
but believe in me, have power to become my sons;
and inasmuch as they break not my laws thou shalt
bear their infirmities
53 Thou shalt stand in the place of thy
stewardship
54 Thou shalt not take thy brother’s garment; thou
shalt pay for that which thou shalt receive of
thy brother
55 And if thou obtainest more than that which
would be for thy support, thou shalt give it into my
storehouse, that all things may be done according
to that which I have said
56 Thou shalt ask, and my scriptures shall be
given as I have appointed, and they shall be preserved
in safety
57 And it is expedient that thou shouldst hold thy
peace concerning them, and not teach them until
ye have received them in full
58 And I give unto you a commandment that then ye
shall teach them unto all men; for they shall be
taught unto all nations, kindreds, tongues and
people
59 Thou shalt take the things which thou hast
received, which have been given unto thee in my
scriptures for a law, to be my law to govern my church
60 And he that doeth according to these things
shall be saved, and he that doeth them not shall be
damned if he so continue
61 If thou shalt ask, thou shalt receive
revelation upon revelation, knowledge upon knowledge, that
thou mayest know the mysteries and peaceable
things—that which bringeth joy, that which bringeth
life eternal
62 Thou shalt ask, and it shall be revealed unto
you in mine own due time where the New Jerusalem
shall be built
63 And behold, it shall come to pass that my
servants shall be sent forth to the east and to the
west, to the north and to the south
64 And even now, let him that goeth to the east
teach them that shall be converted to flee to the
west, and this in consequence of that which is
coming on the earth, and of secret combinations
65 Behold, thou shalt observe all these things,
and great shall be thy reward; for unto you it is
given to know the mysteries of the kingdom, but unto
the world it is not given to know them
66 Ye shall observe the laws which ye have
received and be faithful
67 And ye shall hereafter receive church
covenants, such as shall be sufficient to establish you,
both here and in the New Jerusalem
68 Therefore, he that lacketh wisdom, let him ask
of me, and I will give him liberally and upbraid
him not
69 Lift up your hearts and rejoice, for unto you
the kingdom, or in other words, the keys of the
church have been given. Even so. Amen
70 The priests and teachers shall have their
stewardships, even as the members
71 And the elders or high priests who are
appointed to assist the bishop as counselors in all
things, are to have their families supported out of the
property which is consecrated to the bishop, for
the good of the poor, and for other purposes, as
before mentioned
72 Or they are to receive a just remuneration for
all their services, either a stewardship or
otherwise, as may be thought best or decided by the
counselors and bishop
73 And the bishop, also, shall receive his
support, or a just remuneration for all his services in
the church
74 Behold, verily I say unto you, that whatever
persons among you, having put away their companions
for the cause of fornication, or in other words,
if they shall testify before you in all lowliness
of heart that this is the case, ye shall not cast
them out from among you
75 But if ye shall find that any persons have left
their companions for the sake of adultery, and
they themselves are the offenders, and their
companions are living, they shall be cast out from among
you
76 And again, I say unto you, that ye shall be
watchful and careful, with all inquiry, that ye
receive none such among you if they are married
77 And if they are not married, they shall repent
of all their sins or ye shall not receive them
78 And again, every person who belongeth to this
church of Christ, shall observe to keep all the
commandments and covenants of the church
79 And it shall come to pass, that if any persons
among you shall kill they shall be delivered up
and dealt with according to the laws of the land;
for remember that he hath no forgiveness; and it
shall be proved according to the laws of the land
80 And if any man or woman shall commit adultery,
he or she shall be tried before two elders of the
church, or more, and every word shall be
established against him or her by two witnesses of the
church, and not of the enemy; but if there are more
than two witnesses it is better
81 But he or she shall be condemned by the mouth
of two witnesses; and the elders shall lay the case
before the church, and the church shall lift up
their hands against him or her, that they may be
dealt with according to the law of God
82 And if it can be, it is necessary that the
bishop be present also
83 And thus ye shall do in all cases which shall
come before you
84 And if a man or woman shall rob, he or she
shall be delivered up unto the law of the land
85 And if he or she shall steal, he or she shall
be delivered up unto the law of the land
86 And if he or she shall lie, he or she shall be
delivered up unto the law of the land
87 And if he or she do any manner of iniquity, he
or she shall be delivered up unto the law, even
that of God
88 And if thy brother or sister offend thee, thou
shalt take him or her between him or her and thee
alone; and if he or she confess thou shalt be
reconciled
89 And if he or she confess not thou shalt deliver
him or her up unto the church, not to the
members, but to the elders. And it shall be done in a
meeting, and that not before the world
90 And if thy brother or sister offend many, he or
she shall be chastened before many
91 And if any one offend openly, he or she shall
be rebuked openly, that he or she may be ashamed.
And if he or she confess not, he or she shall be
delivered up unto the law of God
92 If any shall offend in secret, he or she shall
be rebuked in secret, that he or she may have
opportunity to confess in secret to him or her whom he
or she has offended, and to God, that the church
may not speak reproachfully of him or her
verses 1 through 72, was received in the presence
of twelve elders and in fulfillment of the Lord’s
promise previously made that the “law” would be
given in Ohio (see
section 38:32). The second
portion consists of
Section 42 Revelation given in two parts through
Joseph Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio,
February 9 and 23, 1831. The first part, consisting of