Section 90 Revelation to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, given at Kirtland, Ohio, March 8, 1833. This
revelation is a continuing step in the
establishment of the First Presidency (see the
heading
to section 81); as a consequence thereof, the
counselors mentioned were ordained on March 18,
1833.
1–5, The keys of the kingdom are committed
to Joseph Smith and through him to the Church;
6–7, Sidney Rigdon and Frederick G. Williams are
to serve in the First Presidency;
8–11, The
gospel is to be preached to the nations of Israel,
to the Gentiles, and to the Jews, every man
hearing in his own tongue;
12–18, Joseph Smith and
his counselors are to set the Church in order;
19–37, Various individuals are counseled by the
Lord to walk uprightly and serve in His kingdom.
1 Thus saith the Lord, verily, verily I say
unto you my son, thy sins are forgiven thee,
according to thy petition, for thy prayers and the
prayers of thy brethren have come up into my ears.
2 Therefore, thou art blessed from
henceforth that bear the keys of the
kingdom given unto you; which
kingdom is coming forth for the last time.
3 Verily I say unto you, the keys
of this kingdom shall never be
taken from you, while thou art in the
world, neither in the world to come;
4 Nevertheless, through you
shall the oracles be given to
another, yea, even unto the church.
5 And all they who receive
the oracles of God, let them
beware how they hold them
lest they are accounted as a
light thing, and are brought
under condemnation thereby,
and stumble and fall when
the storms descend, and the
winds blow, and the rains
descend, and beat upon their house.
6 And again, verily I say
unto thy brethren,
Sidney Rigdon and Frederick G.
Williams, their sins are
forgiven them also, and
they are accounted as
equal with thee in holding
the keys of this last kingdom;
7 As also through your
administration the keys
of the school of the
prophets, which I have
commanded to be organized;
8 That thereby they
may be perfected in
their ministry for the
salvation of Zion, and of
the nations of
Israel, and of the Gentiles,
as many as will believe;
9 That through your
administration they
may receive the
word, and through their
administration the
word may go forth
unto the ends of the
earth, unto the
Gentiles first, and then,
behold, and lo, they
shall turn unto the Jews.
10 And then cometh
the day when the
arm of the Lord
shall be revealed in
power in
convincing the nations,
the heathen nations,
the house of
Joseph, of the gospel
of their salvation.
11 For it shall
come to pass in
that day, that
every man shall hear
the fulness of
the gospel in his
own tongue, and in
his own
language, through those
who are ordained
unto this power,
by the
administration of the
Comforter, shed forth
upon them for the
revelation of Jesus Christ.
12 And now,
verily I say unto
you, I give unto
you a commandment
that you
continue in the
ministry and presidency.
13 And when you
have finished
the translation of
the prophets,
you shall from
thenceforth
preside over the
affairs of the church
and the school;
14 And from
time to time, as
shall be
manifested by the
Comforter, receive
revelations to
unfold the
mysteries of the kingdom;
15 And set in
order the
churches, and
study and
learn, and become
acquainted
with all good
books, and
with languages,
tongues, and people.
16 And this
shall be
your business
and mission
in all your
lives, to
preside in
council, and set
in order
all the
affairs of this
church and kingdom.
17 Be not
ashamed,
neither
confounded; but
be
admonished in all
your
high-mindedness and
pride, for
it
bringeth a snare
upon your souls.
18 Set in
order your
houses;
keep
slothfulness and
uncleanness far from you.
19 Now,
verily I say
unto you,
let there
be a
place
provided, as soon
as it is
possible,
for the
family of thy
counselor
and
scribe, even
Frederick G.
Williams.
20 And
let mine
aged
servant, Joseph
Smith,
Sen.,
continue with
his
family upon
the place
where he
now
lives; and let
it not
be sold
until the
mouth of
the Lord shall name.
21 And
let my
counselor,
even
Sidney
Rigdon,
remain
where he now
resides
until
the mouth
of the
Lord shall name.
22 And
let the
bishop
search
diligently to
obtain
an
agent, and
let
him be a
man who
has
got
riches in
store—a
man of
God, and of strong faith—
That
thereby he
may
be
enabled to
discharge
every
debt;
that
the
storehouse
of
the Lord
may
not be
brought into
disrepute
before
the eyes of the people.
Search
diligently,
pray
always,
and
be
believing,
and all
things
shall
work
together
for
your
good, if
ye
walk
uprightly
and
remember the
covenant
wherewith
ye have covenanted one with another.
Let
your
families
be
small,
especially
mine
aged
servant
Joseph
Smith’s,
Sen., as
pertaining
to
those
who
do not
belong to
your
families;
That
those
things
that
are
provided
for
you, to
bring to
pass
my
work,
be not
taken
from you
and
given
to
those
that
are
not
worthy—
And
thereby
you
be
hindered
in
accomplishing
those
things
which I
have commanded you.
And
again,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
it
is
my
will
that
my
handmaid
Vienna
Jaques
should
receive
money
to
bear
her
expenses, and go up unto the land of Zion;
And
the
residue
of
the
money
may
be
consecrated
unto
me,
and
she be rewarded in mine own due time.
30 Verily I say unto you, that it is meet in mine eyes that she should go up unto the land of Zion, and receive an inheritance from the hand of the
Verily
I
say
unto
you,
that
it
is
meet
in
mine
eyes
that
she
should
go
up
unto the land of Zion, and receive an inheritance from the hand of the bishop;
31 That she may settle down in peace inasmuch as she is faithful, and not be idle in her days from
That
she
may
settle
down
in
peace
inasmuch
as
she
is
faithful,
and
not
be
idle
in
her
days
from
thenceforth.
32 And behold, verily I say unto you, that ye shall write this commandment, and say unto your brethren in Zion, in love greeting, that I have called you also to preside over Zion in mine own due
And
behold,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
that
ye
shall
write
this
commandment,
and
say
unto
your
brethren
in
Zion,
love
greeting,
that
I
have
called
you
also
to
preside
over
Zion
in
mine
own
due
time.
33 Therefore, let them cease wearying me concerning this
Therefore,
let
them
cease
wearying
me
concerning
this
matter.
34 Behold, I say unto you that your brethren in Zion begin to repent, and the angels rejoice over
Behold,
I
say
unto
you
that
your
brethren
in
Zion
begin
to
repent,
and
the
angels
rejoice
over
them.
35 Nevertheless, I am not well pleased with many things; and I am not well pleased with my servant William E. McLellin, neither with my servant Sidney Gilbert; and the bishop also, and others have many things to repent
Nevertheless,
I
am
not
well
pleased
with
many
things;
and
I
am
not
well
pleased
with
my
servant
William E.
McLellin,
neither
with
my
servant
Sidney
Gilbert;
and
the
bishop
also,
and
others
have
many
things
to
repent
of.
36 But verily I say unto you, that I, the Lord, will contend with Zion, and plead with her strong ones, and chasten her until she overcomes and is clean before
But
verily
I
say
unto
you,
that
I,
the
Lord,
will
contend
with
Zion,
and
plead
with
her
strong
ones,
and
chasten
her
until
she
overcomes
and
is
clean
before
me.
37 For she shall not be removed out of her place. I, the Lord, have spoken it. Amen.
For
she
shall
not
be
removed
out
of
her
place.
I,
the
Lord,
have
spoken
it.
Amen.