Section 138 A vision given to President Joseph F.
Smith in Salt Lake City, Utah, on October 3, 1918.
In his opening address at the 89th Semiannual
General Conference of the Church, on October 4, 1918,
President Smith declared that he had received
several divine communications during the previous
months. One of these, concerning the Savior’s visit
to the spirits of the dead while His body was in
the tomb, President Smith had received the previous
day. It was written immediately following the
close of the conference. On October 31, 1918, it was
submitted to the counselors in the First
Presidency, the Council of the Twelve, and the Patriarch,
and it was unanimously accepted by them.
1–10,
President Joseph F. Smith ponders upon the writings of
Peter and our Lord’s visit to the spirit world;
11–24, President Smith sees the righteous dead
assembled in paradise and Christ’s ministry among
them;
25–37, He sees how the preaching of the gospel
was organized among the spirits;
38–52, He sees
Adam, Eve, and many of the holy prophets in the
spirit world who considered their spirit state
before their resurrection as a bondage;
53–60, The
righteous dead of this day continue their labors in
the world of spirits.
1 Peter 3:18–20.)
1 Peter
4:6.
1 On the third of October, in the year nineteen
hundred and eighteen, I sat in my room pondering
over the scriptures
2 And reflecting upon the great atoning sacrifice
that was made by the Son of God, for the
redemption of the world
3 And the great and wonderful love made manifest
by the Father and the Son in the coming of the
Redeemer into the world
4 That through his atonement, and by obedience to
the principles of the gospel, mankind might be
saved
5 While I was thus engaged, my mind reverted to
the writings of the apostle Peter, to the primitive
saints scattered abroad throughout Pontus,
Galatia, Cappadocia, and other parts of Asia, where the
gospel had been preached after the crucifixion of
the Lord
6 I opened the Bible and read the third and fourth
chapters of the first epistle of Peter, and as I
read I was greatly impressed, more than I had ever
been before, with the following passages
7 “For Christ also hath once suffered for sins,
the just for the unjust, that he might bring us to
God, being put to death in the flesh, but quickened
by the Spirit
8 “By which also he went and preached unto the
spirits in prison
9 “Which sometime were disobedient, when once the
longsuffering of God waited in the days of Noah,
while the ark was a preparing, wherein few, that
is, eight souls were saved by water.”
10 “For for this cause was the gospel preached
also to them that are dead, that they might be judged
according to men in the flesh, but live according
to God in the spirit.”
11 As I pondered over these things which are
written, the eyes of my understanding were opened, and
the Spirit of the Lord rested upon me, and I saw
the hosts of the dead, both small and great
12 And there were gathered together in one place
an innumerable company of the spirits of the just,
who had been faithful in the testimony of Jesus
while they lived in mortality
13 And who had offered sacrifice in the similitude
of the great sacrifice of the Son of God, and had
suffered tribulation in their Redeemer’s name
14 All these had departed the mortal life, firm in
the hope of a glorious resurrection, through the
grace of God the Father and his Only Begotten Son,
Jesus Christ
15 I beheld that they were filled with joy and
gladness, and were rejoicing together because the day
of their deliverance was at hand
16 They were assembled awaiting the advent of the
Son of God into the spirit world, to declare their
redemption from the bands of death
17 Their sleeping dust was to be restored unto its
perfect frame, bone to his bone, and the sinews
and the flesh upon them, the spirit and the body to
be united never again to be divided, that they
might receive a fulness of joy
18 While this vast multitude waited and conversed,
rejoicing in the hour of their deliverance from
the chains of death, the Son of God appeared,
declaring liberty to the captives who had been
faithful
19 And there he preached to them the everlasting
gospel, the doctrine of the resurrection and the
redemption of mankind from the fall, and from
individual sins on conditions of repentance
20 But unto the wicked he did not go, and among
the ungodly and the unrepentant who had defiled
themselves while in the flesh, his voice was not
raised
21 Neither did the rebellious who rejected the
testimonies and the warnings of the ancient prophets
behold his presence, nor look upon his face
22 Where these were, darkness reigned, but among
the righteous there was peace
23 And the saints rejoiced in their redemption,
and bowed the knee and acknowledged the Son of God
as their Redeemer and Deliverer from death and the
chains of hell
24 Their countenances shone, and the radiance from
the presence of the Lord rested upon them, and
they sang praises unto his holy name
25 I marveled, for I understood that the Savior
spent about three years in his ministry among the
Jews and those of the house of Israel, endeavoring
to teach them the everlasting gospel and call them
unto repentance
26 And yet, notwithstanding his mighty works, and
miracles, and proclamation of the truth, in great
power and authority, there were but few who
hearkened to his voice, and rejoiced in his presence,
and received salvation at his hands
27 But his ministry among those who were dead was
limited to the brief time intervening between the
crucifixion and his resurrection
28 And I wondered at the words of Peter—wherein he
said that the Son of God preached unto the
spirits in prison, who sometime were disobedient, when
once the long-suffering of God waited in the days
of Noah—and how it was possible for him to preach
to those spirits and perform the necessary labor
among them in so short a time
29 And as I wondered, my eyes were opened, and my
understanding quickened, and I perceived that the
Lord went not in person among the wicked and the
disobedient who had rejected the truth, to teach
them
30 But behold, from among the righteous, he
organized his forces and appointed messengers, clothed
with power and authority, and commissioned them to
go forth and carry the light of the gospel to them
that were in darkness, even to all the spirits of
men; and thus was the gospel preached to the
dead
31 And the chosen messengers went forth to declare
the acceptable day of the Lord and proclaim
liberty to the captives who were bound, even unto all
who would repent of their sins and receive the
gospel
32 Thus was the gospel preached to those who had
died in their sins, without a knowledge of the
truth, or in transgression, having rejected the
prophets
33 These were taught faith in God, repentance from
sin, vicarious baptism for the remission of sins,
the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of
hands
34 And all other principles of the gospel that
were necessary for them to know in order to qualify
themselves that they might be judged according to
men in the flesh, but live according to God in the
spirit
35 And so it was made known among the dead, both
small and great, the unrighteous as well as the
faithful, that redemption had been wrought through
the sacrifice of the Son of God upon the cross
36 Thus was it made known that our Redeemer spent
his time during his sojourn in the world of
spirits, instructing and preparing the faithful spirits
of the prophets who had testified of him in the
flesh
37 That they might carry the message of redemption
unto all the dead, unto whom he could not go
personally, because of their rebellion and
transgression, that they through the ministration of his
servants might also hear his words
38 Among the great and mighty ones who were
assembled in this vast congregation of the righteous
were Father Adam, the Ancient of Days and father of
all
39 And our glorious Mother Eve, with many of her
faithful daughters who had lived through the ages
and worshiped the true and living God
40 Abel, the first martyr, was there, and his
brother Seth, one of the mighty ones, who was in the
express image of his father, Adam
41 Noah, who gave warning of the flood; Shem, the
great high priest; Abraham, the father of the
faithful; Isaac, Jacob, and Moses, the great law-giver
of Israel
42 And Isaiah, who declared by prophecy that the
Redeemer was anointed to bind up the
broken-hearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the
opening of the prison to them that were bound, were
also there
43 Moreover, Ezekiel, who was shown in vision the
great valley of dry bones, which were to be
clothed upon with flesh, to come forth again in the
resurrection of the dead, living souls
44 Daniel, who foresaw and foretold the
establishment of the kingdom of God in the latter days,
never again to be destroyed nor given to other people
45 Elias, who was with Moses on the Mount of
Transfiguration
46 And Malachi, the prophet who testified of the
coming of Elijah—of whom also Moroni spake to the
Prophet Joseph Smith, declaring that he should come
before the ushering in of the great and dreadful
day of the Lord—were also there
47 The Prophet Elijah was to plant in the hearts
of the children the promises made to their fathers
48 Foreshadowing the great work to be done in the
temples of the Lord in the dispensation of the
fulness of times, for the redemption of the dead, and
the sealing of the children to their parents,
lest the whole earth be smitten with a curse and
utterly wasted at his coming
49 All these and many more, even the prophets who
dwelt among the Nephites and testified of the
coming of the Son of God, mingled in the vast assembly
and waited for their deliverance
50 For the dead had looked upon the long absence
of their spirits from their bodies as a bondage
51 These the Lord taught, and gave them power to
come forth, after his resurrection from the dead,
to enter into his Father’s kingdom, there to be
crowned with immortality and eternal life
52 And continue thenceforth their labor as had
been promised by the Lord, and be partakers of all
blessings which were held in reserve for them that
love him
53 The Prophet Joseph Smith, and my father, Hyrum
Smith, Brigham Young, John Taylor, Wilford
Woodruff, and other choice spirits who were reserved to
come forth in the fulness of times to take part in
laying the foundations of the great latter-day
work
54 Including the building of the temples and the
performance of ordinances therein for the
redemption of the dead, were also in the spirit world
55 I observed that they were also among the noble
and great ones who were chosen in the beginning to
be rulers in the Church of God
56 Even before they were born, they, with many
others, received their first lessons in the world of
spirits and were prepared to come forth in the due
time of the Lord to labor in his vineyard for the
salvation of the souls of men
57 I beheld that the faithful elders of this
dispensation, when they depart from mortal life,
continue their labors in the preaching of the gospel of
repentance and redemption, through the sacrifice
of the Only Begotten Son of God, among those who
are in darkness and under the bondage of sin in the
great world of the spirits of the dead
58 The dead who repent will be redeemed, through
obedience to the ordinances of the house of God
59 And after they have paid the penalty of their
transgressions, and are washed clean, shall receive
a reward according to their works, for they are
heirs of salvation
60 Thus was the vision of the redemption of the
dead revealed to me, and I bear record, and I know
that this record is true, through the blessing of
our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, even so. Amen.