Section 135 Announcement of the martyrdom of
Joseph Smith the Prophet and his brother, Hyrum Smith
the Patriarch, at Carthage, Illinois, June 27,
1844. This document was included at the end of the
1844 edition of the Doctrine and Covenants,
which was nearly ready for publication when Joseph
and Hyrum Smith were murdered.
1–2, Joseph and
Hyrum martyred in Carthage Jail;
3, The preeminent
position of the Prophet is acclaimed;
4–7, Their
innocent blood testifies of the truth and
divinity of the work.
twelfth chapter of Ether, in the
Book of Mormon, and turned down the leaf upon it:
1 To seal the testimony of this book and the
Book of Mormon, we announce the martyrdom of
Joseph Smith the Prophet, and Hyrum Smith the
Patriarch. They were shot in Carthage jail,
on the 27th of June, 1844, about five o’clock
p.m., by an armed mob—painted black—of from
150 to 200 persons. Hyrum was shot first and
fell calmly, exclaiming: I am a dead man!
Joseph leaped from the window, and was shot dead
in the attempt, exclaiming: O Lord my God!
They were both shot after they were dead, in a
brutal manner, and both received four balls.
2 John Taylor and Willard Richards, two of
the Twelve, were the only persons in the room
at the time; the former was wounded in a
savage manner with four balls, but has since
recovered; the latter, through the providence of
God, escaped, without even a hole in his robe.
3 Joseph Smith, the Prophet and Seer of the
Lord, has done more, save Jesus only, for
the salvation of men in this world, than
any other man that ever lived in it. In the
short space of twenty years, he has brought
forth the Book of Mormon, which he
translated by the gift and power of God, and has
been the means of publishing it on two
continents; has sent the fulness of the
everlasting gospel, which it contained, to the four
quarters of the earth; has brought forth
the revelations and commandments which
compose this book of Doctrine and Covenants, and
many other wise documents and instructions
for the benefit of the children of men;
gathered many thousands of the Latter-day
Saints, founded a great city, and left a fame
and name that cannot be slain. He lived
great, and he died great in the eyes of God and
his people; and like most of the Lord’s
anointed in ancient times, has sealed his
mission and his works with his own blood; and
so has his brother Hyrum. In life they were
not divided, and in death they were not separated!
4 When Joseph went to Carthage to deliver
himself up to the pretended requirements
of the law, two or three days previous to
his assassination, he said: “I am going
like a lamb to the slaughter; but I am calm
as a summer’s morning; I have a conscience
void of offense towards God, and towards
all men. I shall die innocent, and it shall
yet be said of me—he was murdered in cold
blood.”—The same morning, after Hyrum had
made ready to go—shall it be said to the
slaughter? yes, for so it was—he read the
following paragraph, near the close of the
5 And it came to pass that I prayed unto
the Lord that he would give unto the
Gentiles grace, that they might have
charity. And it came to pass that the Lord
said unto me: If they have not charity it
mattereth not unto thee, thou hast been
faithful; wherefore thy garments shall
be made clean. And because thou hast seen
thy weakness, thou shalt be made
strong, even unto the sitting down in the
place which I have prepared in the mansions
of my Father. And now I … bid farewell
unto the Gentiles; yea, and also unto my
brethren whom I love, until we shall
meet before the judgment-seat of Christ,
where all men shall know that my garments
are not spotted with your blood. The
testators are now dead, and their testament is in force.
6 Hyrum Smith was forty-four years old
in February, 1844, and Joseph Smith
was thirty-eight in December, 1843; and
henceforward their names will be
classed among the martyrs of religion; and
the reader in every nation will be
reminded that the Book of Mormon, and
this book of Doctrine and Covenants of
the church, cost the best blood of the
nineteenth century to bring them forth
for the salvation of a ruined world;
and that if the fire can scathe a
green tree for the glory of God, how easy
it will burn up the dry trees to
purify the vineyard of corruption. They
lived for glory; they died for glory; and
glory is their eternal reward. From
age to age shall their names go down to
posterity as gems for the sanctified.
7 They were innocent of any crime, as
they had often been proved before,
and were only confined in jail by the
conspiracy of traitors and wicked
men; and their innocent blood on the
floor of Carthage jail is a broad seal
affixed to “Mormonism” that cannot be
rejected by any court on earth, and
their innocent blood on the escutcheon
of the State of Illinois, with the
broken faith of the State as pledged
by the governor, is a witness to the
truth of the everlasting gospel that
all the world cannot impeach; and
their innocent blood on the banner of
liberty, and on the magna charta of the
United States, is an ambassador for
the religion of Jesus Christ, that
will touch the hearts of honest men
among all nations; and their innocent
blood, with the innocent blood of all
the martyrs under the altar that John
saw, will cry unto the Lord of Hosts
till he avenges that blood on the earth. Amen.