Section 95 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, June 1, 1833. This
revelation is a continuation of divine directions
to build a house for worship and instruction, the
house of the Lord (see
section 88:119–36).
1–6,
The Saints are chastened for their failure to
build the house of the Lord;
7–10, The Lord desires
to use His house to endow His people with power
from on high;
11–17, The house is to be dedicated as
a place of worship and for the school of the
Apostles.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you whom I
love, and whom I love I also chasten that their sins
may be forgiven, for with the chastisement I
prepare a way for their deliverance in all things out of
temptation, and I have loved you
2 Wherefore, ye must needs be chastened and stand
rebuked before my face
3 For ye have sinned against me a very grievous
sin, in that ye have not considered the great
commandment in all things, that I have given unto you
concerning the building of mine house
4 For the preparation wherewith I design to
prepare mine apostles to prune my vineyard for the last
time, that I may bring to pass my strange act,
that I may pour out my Spirit upon all flesh
5 But behold, verily I say unto you, that there
are many who have been ordained among you, whom I
have called but few of them are chosen
6 They who are not chosen have sinned a very
grievous sin, in that they are walking in darkness at
noon-day
7 And for this cause I gave unto you a commandment
that you should call your solemn assembly, that
your fastings and your mourning might come up into
the ears of the Lord of Sabaoth, which is by
interpretation, the creator of the first day, the
beginning and the end
8 Yea, verily I say unto you, I gave unto you a
commandment that you should build a house, in the
which house I design to endow those whom I have
chosen with power from on high
9 For this is the promise of the Father unto you;
therefore I command you to tarry, even as mine
apostles at Jerusalem
10 Nevertheless, my servants sinned a very
grievous sin; and contentions arose in the school of the
prophets; which was very grievous unto me, saith
your Lord; therefore I sent them forth to be
chastened
11 Verily I say unto you, it is my will that you
should build a house. If you keep my commandments
you shall have power to build it
12 If you keep not my commandments, the love of
the Father shall not continue with you, therefore
you shall walk in darkness
13 Now here is wisdom, and the mind of the
Lord—let the house be built, not after the manner of the
world, for I give not unto you that ye shall live
after the manner of the world
14 Therefore, let it be built after the manner
which I shall show unto three of you, whom ye shall
appoint and ordain unto this power
15 And the size thereof shall be fifty and five
feet in width, and let it be sixty-five feet in
length, in the inner court thereof
16 And let the lower part of the inner court be
dedicated unto me for your sacrament offering, and
for your preaching, and your fasting, and your
praying, and the offering up of your most holy desires
unto me, saith your Lord
17 And let the higher part of the inner court be
dedicated unto me for the school of mine apostles,
saith Son Ahman; or, in other words, Alphus; or,
in other words, Omegus; even Jesus Christ your
Lord. Amen.