Section 26 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, Oliver Cowdery, and John Whitmer, at
Harmony, Pennsylvania, July 1830 (see the
heading to
section 24).
1, They are instructed to study the
scriptures and to preach;
2, The law of common
consent is affirmed.
1 Behold, I say unto you that you shall let your
time be devoted to the studying of the scriptures,
and to preaching, and to confirming the church at
Colesville, and to performing your labors on the
land, such as is required, until after you shall go
to the west to hold the next conference; and then
it shall be made known what you shall do
2 And all things shall be done by common consent
in the church, by much prayer and faith, for all
things you shall receive by faith. Amen.