Section 53 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to Algernon Sidney Gilbert, at
Kirtland, Ohio, June 8, 1831. At Sidney Gilbert’s
request, the Prophet inquired of the Lord as
to Brother Gilbert’s work and appointment in the
Church.
1–3, Sidney Gilbert’s calling and
election in the Church is to be ordained an elder;
4–7, He is also to serve as a bishop’s agent.
1 Behold, I say unto you, my servant Sidney
Gilbert, that I have heard your prayers; and you
have called upon me that it should be made
known unto you, of the Lord your God, concerning
your calling and election in the church,
which I, the Lord, have raised up in these last days.
2 Behold, I, the Lord, who was crucified
for the sins of the world, give unto you a
commandment that you shall forsake the world.
3 Take upon you mine ordination, even
that of an elder, to preach faith and
repentance and remission of sins,
according to my word, and the reception of the
Holy Spirit by the laying on of hands;
4 And also to be an agent unto this
church in the place which shall be
appointed by the bishop, according to
commandments which shall be given hereafter.
5 And again, verily I say
unto you, you shall take your
journey with my servants Joseph
Smith, Jun., and Sidney Rigdon.
6 Behold, these are the
first ordinances which you
shall receive; and the
residue shall be made known in
a time to come, according
to your labor in my vineyard.
7 And again, I would
that ye should learn
that he only is saved
who endureth unto
the end. Even so. Amen.