Section 6 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Oliver Cowdery, at Harmony, Pennsylvania,
April 1829. Oliver Cowdery began his labors as
scribe in the translation of the Book of Mormon,
April 7, 1829. He had already received a divine
manifestation of the truth of the Prophet’s testimony
respecting the plates on which was engraved the
Book of Mormon record. The Prophet inquired of the
Lord through the Urim and Thummim and received this
response.
1–6, Laborers in the Lord’s field gain
salvation;
7–13, There is no gift greater than
the gift of salvation;
14–27, A witness of the
truth comes by the power of the Spirit;
28–37, Look
unto Christ, and do good continually.
1 A great and marvelous work is about to come
forth unto the children of men
2 Behold, I am God; give heed unto my word, which
is quick and powerful, sharper than a two-edged
sword, to the dividing asunder of both joints and
marrow; therefore give heed unto my words
3 Behold, the field is white already to harvest;
therefore, whoso desireth to reap, let him thrust
in his sickle with his might, and reap while the
day lasts, that he may treasure up for his soul
everlasting salvation in the kingdom of God
4 Yea, whosoever will thrust in his sickle and
reap, the same is called of God
5 Therefore, if you will ask of me you shall
receive; if you will knock it shall be opened unto you
6 Now, as you have asked, behold, I say unto you,
keep my commandments, and seek to bring forth and
establish the cause of Zion
7 Seek not for riches but for wisdom, and behold,
the mysteries of God shall be unfolded unto you,
and then shall you be made rich. Behold, he that
hath eternal life is rich
8 Verily, verily, I say unto you, even as you
desire of me so it shall be unto you; and if you
desire, you shall be the means of doing much good in
this generation
9 Say nothing but repentance unto this generation;
keep my commandments, and assist to bring forth
my work, according to my commandments, and you
shall be blessed
10 Behold thou hast a gift, and blessed art thou
because of thy gift. Remember it is sacred and
cometh from above
11 And if thou wilt inquire, thou shalt know
mysteries which are great and marvelous; therefore thou
shalt exercise thy gift, that thou mayest find
out mysteries, that thou mayest bring many to the
knowledge of the truth, yea, convince them of the
error of their ways
12 Make not thy gift known unto any save it be
those who are of thy faith. Trifle not with sacred
things
13 If thou wilt do good, yea, and hold out
faithful to the end, thou shalt be saved in the kingdom
of God, which is the greatest of all the gifts of
God; for there is no gift greater than the gift of
salvation
14 Verily, verily, I say unto thee, blessed art
thou for what thou hast done; for thou hast inquired
of me, and behold, as often as thou hast inquired
thou hast received instruction of my Spirit. If
it had not been so, thou wouldst not have come to
the place where thou art at this time
15 Behold, thou knowest that thou hast inquired of
me and I did enlighten thy mind; and now I tell
thee these things that thou mayest know that thou
hast been enlightened by the Spirit of truth
16 Yea, I tell thee, that thou mayest know that
there is none else save God that knowest thy
thoughts and the intents of thy heart
17 I tell thee these things as a witness unto
thee—that the words or the work which thou hast been
writing are true
18 Therefore be diligent; stand by my servant
Joseph, faithfully, in whatsoever difficult
circumstances he may be for the word’s sake
19 Admonish him in his faults, and also receive
admonition of him. Be patient; be sober; be
temperate; have patience, faith, hope and charity
20 Behold, thou art Oliver, and I have spoken unto
thee because of thy desires; therefore treasure
up these words in thy heart. Be faithful and
diligent in keeping the commandments of God, and I will
encircle thee in the arms of my love
21 Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God. I am
the same that came unto mine own, and mine own
received me not. I am the light which shineth in
darkness, and the darkness comprehendeth it not
22 Verily, verily, I say unto you, if you desire a
further witness, cast your mind upon the night
that you cried unto me in your heart, that you might
know concerning the truth of these things
23 Did I not speak peace to your mind concerning
the matter? What greater witness can you have than
from God
24 And now, behold, you have received a witness;
for if I have told you things which no man knoweth
have you not received a witness
25 And, behold, I grant unto you a gift, if you
desire of me, to translate, even as my servant
Joseph
26 Verily, verily, I say unto you, that there are
records which contain much of my gospel, which
have been kept back because of the wickedness of the
people
27 And now I command you, that if you have good
desires—a desire to lay up treasures for yourself in
heaven—then shall you assist in bringing to
light, with your gift, those parts of my scriptures
which have been hidden because of iniquity
28 And now, behold, I give unto you, and also unto
my servant Joseph, the keys of this gift, which
shall bring to light this ministry; and in the
mouth of two or three witnesses shall every word be
established
29 Verily, verily, I say unto you, if they reject
my words, and this part of my gospel and ministry,
blessed are ye, for they can do no more unto you
than unto me
30 And even if they do unto you even as they have
done unto me, blessed are ye, for you shall dwell
with me in glory
31 But if they reject not my words, which shall be
established by the testimony which shall be
given, blessed are they, and then shall ye have joy in
the fruit of your labors
32 Verily, verily, I say unto you, as I said unto
my disciples, where two or three are gathered
together in my name, as touching one thing, behold,
there will I be in the midst of them—even so am I in
the midst of you
33 Fear not to do good, my sons, for whatsoever ye
sow, that shall ye also reap; therefore, if ye
sow good ye shall also reap good for your reward
34 Therefore, fear not, little flock; do good; let
earth and hell combine against you, for if ye are
built upon my rock, they cannot prevail
35 Behold, I do not condemn you; go your ways and
sin no more; perform with soberness the work which
I have commanded you
36 Look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear
not
37 Behold the wounds which pierced my side, and
also the prints of the nails in my hands and feet;
be faithful, keep my commandments, and ye shall
inherit the kingdom of heaven. Amen.