Section 46 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to the Church, at Kirtland, Ohio,
March 8, 1831. In this early time of the Church,
a unified pattern for the conducting of Church
services had not yet developed. However, a custom
of admitting only members and earnest
investigators to the sacrament meetings and other
assemblies of the Church had become somewhat general.
This revelation expresses the will of the Lord
relative to governing and conducting meetings and
His direction on seeking and discerning the
gifts of the Spirit.
1–2, Elders are to conduct
meetings as guided by the Holy Spirit;
3–6, Truth
seekers should not be excluded from sacramental
services;
7–12, Ask of God and seek the gifts
of the Spirit;
13–26, An enumeration of some of
these gifts is given;
27–33, Church leaders are
given power to discern the gifts of the Spirit.
1 Hearken, O ye people of my church; for
verily I say unto you that these things were
spoken unto you for your profit and learning.
2 But notwithstanding those things
which are written, it always has been
given to the elders of my church
from the beginning, and ever shall be,
to conduct all meetings as they are
directed and guided by the Holy Spirit.
3 Nevertheless ye are
commanded never to cast any one out
from your public meetings,
which are held before the world.
4 Ye are also commanded not
to cast any one who
belongeth to the church out of
your sacrament meetings;
nevertheless, if any have
trespassed, let him not partake
until he makes reconciliation.
5 And again I say unto
you, ye shall not cast any
out of your sacrament
meetings who are earnestly
seeking the kingdom—I
speak this concerning those
who are not of the church.
6 And again I say unto
you, concerning your
confirmation meetings,
that if there be any that
are not of the church,
that are earnestly
seeking after the kingdom,
ye shall not cast them out.
7 But ye are commanded
in all things to ask
of God, who giveth
liberally; and that which
the Spirit testifies
unto you even so I
would that ye should do
in all holiness of
heart, walking uprightly
before me, considering
the end of your
salvation, doing all things
with prayer and
thanksgiving, that ye may
not be seduced by evil
spirits, or doctrines
of devils, or the
commandments of men; for
some are of men, and others of devils.
8 Wherefore, beware
lest ye are deceived;
and that ye may not
be deceived seek ye
earnestly the best
gifts, always remembering
for what they are given;
9 For verily I say
unto you, they are
given for the benefit
of those who love me
and keep all my
commandments, and him
that seeketh so to
do; that all may be
benefited that seek or
that ask of me,
that ask and not for a
sign that they may
consume it upon their lusts.
10 And again,
verily I say unto you,
I would that ye
should always
remember, and always
retain in your minds
what those gifts
are, that are
given unto the church.
11 For all have
not every gift
given unto them;
for there are
many gifts, and to
every man is
given a gift by
the Spirit of God.
12 To some is
given one, and
to some is
given another,
that all may be
profited thereby.
13 To some it
is given by
the Holy
Ghost to know
that Jesus
Christ is the Son
of God, and
that he was
crucified for
the sins of the world.
14 To others
it is given
to believe on
their words,
that they
also might have
eternal life
if they
continue faithful.
15 And
again, to some it
is given by
the Holy
Ghost to know
the
differences of
administration,
as it will be
pleasing
unto the same
Lord,
according as the
Lord will,
suiting his
mercies
according to the
conditions of
the children of men.
16 And
again, it is
given by the
Holy Ghost
to some to
know the
diversities
of
operations, whether
they be of
God, that
the
manifestations of
the Spirit
may be given
to every
man to profit withal.
17 And
again, verily
I say
unto you, to
some is
given, by
the Spirit
of God, the
word of wisdom.
18 To
another is
given the
word of
knowledge,
that all
may be
taught to
be wise
and to
have knowledge.
19 And
again, to
some it
is
given to
have faith
to be healed;
20 And
to
others it
is given
to
have faith
to heal.
21 And
again, to
some is
given
the
working
of miracles;
And to
others it
is
given
to prophesy;
And
to
others
the
discerning
of spirits.
And
again, it
is
given to
some to
speak
with
tongues;
And
to
another
is
given
the
interpretation of tongues.
And
all
these
gifts
come
from
God,
for
the
benefit of the children of God.
And
unto
the
bishop
of
the
church,
and
unto
such
as
God
shall
appoint
and
ordain
to
watch
over
the
church
and
to
be
elders
unto
the
church,
are
to
have
it
given
unto
them
to
discern
all
those
gifts
lest
there
shall
be
any
among
you
professing
God.
28 And it shall come to pass that he that asketh in Spirit shall receive in
And
it
shall
come
to
pass
that
he
asketh in Spirit shall receive in Spirit;
29 That unto some it may be given to have all those gifts, that there may be a head, in order that every member may be profited
That
unto
some
it
may
be
given
to
have
all
those
gifts,
that
there
may
be
a
head,
in
order
that
every
member
may
be
profited
thereby.
30 He that asketh in the Spirit asketh according to the will of God; wherefore it is done even as he
He
that
asketh
in
the
Spirit
asketh
according
to
the
will
of
God;
wherefore
it
is
done
even
as
he
asketh.
31 And again, I say unto you, all things must be done in the name of Christ, whatsoever you do in the
And
again,
I
say
unto
you,
all
things
must
be
done
in
the
name
of
Christ,
whatsoever
you
do
in
the
Spirit;
32 And ye must give thanks unto God in the Spirit for whatsoever blessing ye are blessed
And
ye
must
give
thanks
unto
God
in
the
Spirit
for
whatsoever
blessing
ye
are
blessed
with.
33 And ye must practice virtue and holiness before me continually. Even so. Amen.
And
ye
must
practice
virtue
and
holiness
before
me
continually.
Even
so.
Amen.