Section 101 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, December 16 and 17,
1833. At this time the Saints who had gathered in
Missouri were suffering great persecution. Mobs had
driven them from their homes in Jackson County; and
some of the Saints had tried to establish
themselves in Van Buren, Lafayette, and Ray Counties, but
persecution followed them. The main body of the
Saints was at that time in Clay County, Missouri.
Threats of death against individuals of the Church
were many. The Saints in Jackson County had lost
household furniture, clothing, livestock, and other
personal property; and many of their crops had
been destroyed.
1–8, The Saints are chastened and
afflicted because of their transgressions;
9–15,
The Lord’s indignation will fall upon the nations,
but His people will be gathered and comforted;
16–21, Zion and her stakes will be established;
22–31, The nature of life during the Millennium is
set forth;
32–42, The Saints will be blessed and
rewarded then;
43–62, The parable of the nobleman
and the olive trees signifies the troubles and
eventual redemption of Zion;
63–75, The Saints are to
continue gathering together;
76–80, The Lord
established the Constitution of the United States;
81–101, The Saints are to importune for the redress
of grievances, according to the parable of the
woman and the unjust judge.
1 Verily I say unto you, concerning your brethren
who have been afflicted, and persecuted, and cast
out from the land of their inheritance
2 I, the Lord, have suffered the affliction to
come upon them, wherewith they have been afflicted,
in consequence of their transgressions
3 Yet I will own them, and they shall be mine in
that day when I shall come to make up my jewels
4 Therefore, they must needs be chastened and
tried, even as Abraham, who was commanded to offer up
his only son
5 For all those who will not endure chastening,
but deny me, cannot be sanctified
6 Behold, I say unto you, there were jarrings, and
contentions, and envyings, and strifes, and
lustful and covetous desires among them; therefore by
these things they polluted their inheritances
7 They were slow to hearken unto the voice of the
Lord their God; therefore, the Lord their God is
slow to hearken unto their prayers, to answer them
in the day of their trouble
8 In the day of their peace they esteemed lightly
my counsel; but, in the day of their trouble, of
necessity they feel after me
9 Verily I say unto you, notwithstanding their
sins, my bowels are filled with compassion towards
them. I will not utterly cast them off; and in the
day of wrath I will remember mercy
10 I have sworn, and the decree hath gone forth by
a former commandment which I have given unto you,
that I would let fall the sword of mine
indignation in behalf of my people; and even as I have
said, it shall come to pass
11 Mine indignation is soon to be poured out
without measure upon all nations; and this will I do
when the cup of their iniquity is full
12 And in that day all who are found upon the
watch-tower, or in other words, all mine Israel, shall
be saved
13 And they that have been scattered shall be
gathered
14 And all they who have mourned shall be
comforted
15 And all they who have given their lives for my
name shall be crowned
16 Therefore, let your hearts be comforted
concerning Zion; for all flesh is in mine hands; be still
and know that I am God
17 Zion shall not be moved out of her place,
notwithstanding her children are scattered
18 They that remain, and are pure in heart, shall
return, and come to their inheritances, they and
their children, with songs of everlasting joy, to
build up the waste places of Zion
19 And all these things that the prophets might be
fulfilled
20 And, behold, there is none other place
appointed than that which I have appointed; neither shall
there be any other place appointed than that which
I have appointed, for the work of the gathering
of my saints
21 Until the day cometh when there is found no
more room for them; and then I have other places
which I will appoint unto them, and they shall be
called stakes, for the curtains or the strength of
Zion
22 Behold, it is my will, that all they who call
on my name, and worship me according to mine
everlasting gospel, should gather together, and stand in
holy places
23 And prepare for the revelation which is to
come, when the veil of the covering of my temple, in
my tabernacle, which hideth the earth, shall be
taken off, and all flesh shall see me together
24 And every corruptible thing, both of man, or of
the beasts of the field, or of the fowls of the
heavens, or of the fish of the sea, that dwells
upon all the face of the earth, shall be consumed
25 And also that of element shall melt with
fervent heat; and all things shall become new, that my
knowledge and glory may dwell upon all the earth
26 And in that day the enmity of man, and the
enmity of beasts, yea, the enmity of all flesh, shall
cease from before my face
27 And in that day whatsoever any man shall ask,
it shall be given unto him
28 And in that day Satan shall not have power to
tempt any man
29 And there shall be no sorrow because there is
no death
30 In that day an infant shall not die until he is
old; and his life shall be as the age of a tree
31 And when he dies he shall not sleep, that is to
say in the earth, but shall be changed in the
twinkling of an eye, and shall be caught up, and his
rest shall be glorious
32 Yea, verily I say unto you, in that day when
the Lord shall come, he shall reveal all things
33 Things which have passed, and hidden things
which no man knew, things of the earth, by which it
was made, and the purpose and the end thereof
34 Things most precious, things that are above,
and things that are beneath, things that are in the
earth, and upon the earth, and in heaven
35 And all they who suffer persecution for my
name, and endure in faith, though they are called to
lay down their lives for my sake yet shall they
partake of all this glory
36 Wherefore, fear not even unto death; for in
this world your joy is not full, but in me your joy
is full
37 Therefore, care not for the body, neither the
life of the body; but care for the soul, and for
the life of the soul
38 And seek the face of the Lord always, that in
patience ye may possess your souls, and ye shall
have eternal life
39 When men are called unto mine everlasting
gospel, and covenant with an everlasting covenant, they
are accounted as the salt of the earth and the
savor of men
40 They are called to be the savor of men;
therefore, if that salt of the earth lose its savor,
behold, it is thenceforth good for nothing only to be
cast out and trodden under the feet of men
41 Behold, here is wisdom concerning the children
of Zion, even many, but not all; they were found
transgressors, therefore they must needs be
chastened
42 He that exalteth himself shall be abased, and
he that abaseth himself shall be exalted
43 And now, I will show unto you a parable, that
you may know my will concerning the redemption of
Zion
44 A certain nobleman had a spot of land, very
choice; and he said unto his servants: Go ye unto my
vineyard, even upon this very choice piece of
land, and plant twelve olive trees
45 And set watchmen round about them, and build a
tower, that one may overlook the land round about,
to be a watchman upon the tower, that mine olive
trees may not be broken down when the enemy shall
come to spoil and take upon themselves the fruit
of my vineyard
46 Now, the servants of the nobleman went and did
as their lord commanded them, and planted the
olive trees, and built a hedge round about, and set
watchmen, and began to build a tower
47 And while they were yet laying the foundation
thereof, they began to say among themselves: And
what need hath my lord of this tower
48 And consulted for a long time, saying among
themselves: What need hath my lord of this tower,
seeing this is a time of peace
49 Might not this money be given to the
exchangers? For there is no need of these things
50 And while they were at variance one with
another they became very slothful, and they hearkened
not unto the commandments of their lord
51 And the enemy came by night, and broke down the
hedge; and the servants of the nobleman arose and
were affrighted, and fled; and the enemy
destroyed their works, and broke down the olive trees
52 Now, behold, the nobleman, the lord of the
vineyard, called upon his servants, and said unto
them, Why! what is the cause of this great evil
53 Ought ye not to have done even as I commanded
you, and—after ye had planted the vineyard, and
built the hedge round about, and set watchmen upon
the walls thereof—built the tower also, and set a
watchman upon the tower, and watched for my
vineyard, and not have fallen asleep, lest the enemy
should come upon you
54 And behold, the watchman upon the tower would
have seen the enemy while he was yet afar off; and
then ye could have made ready and kept the enemy
from breaking down the hedge thereof, and saved my
vineyard from the hands of the destroyer
55 And the lord of the vineyard said unto one of
his servants: Go and gather together the residue of
my servants, and take all the strength of mine
house, which are my warriors, my young men, and they
that are of middle age also among all my
servants, who are the strength of mine house, save those
only whom I have appointed to tarry
56 And go ye straightway unto the land of my
vineyard, and redeem my vineyard; for it is mine; I
have bought it with money
57 Therefore, get ye straightway unto my land;
break down the walls of mine enemies; throw down
their tower, and scatter their watchmen
58 And inasmuch as they gather together against
you, avenge me of mine enemies, that by and by I may
come with the residue of mine house and possess
the land
59 And the servant said unto his lord: When shall
these things be
60 And he said unto his servant: When I will; go
ye straightway, and do all things whatsoever I have
commanded you
61 And this shall be my seal and blessing upon
you—a faithful and wise steward in the midst of mine
house, a ruler in my kingdom
62 And his servant went straightway, and did all
things whatsoever his lord commanded him; and after
many days all things were fulfilled
63 Again, verily I say unto you, I will show unto
you wisdom in me concerning all the churches,
inasmuch as they are willing to be guided in a right
and proper way for their salvation
64 That the work of the gathering together of my
saints may continue, that I may build them up unto
my name upon holy places; for the time of harvest
is come, and my word must needs be fulfilled
65 Therefore, I must gather together my people,
according to the parable of the wheat and the tares,
that the wheat may be secured in the garners to
possess eternal life, and be crowned with celestial
glory, when I shall come in the kingdom of my
Father to reward every man according as his work
shall be
66 While the tares shall be bound in bundles, and
their bands made strong, that they may be burned
with unquenchable fire
67 Therefore, a commandment I give unto all the
churches, that they shall continue to gather
together unto the places which I have appointed
68 Nevertheless, as I have said unto you in a
former commandment, let not your gathering be in
haste, nor by flight; but let all things be prepared
before you
69 And in order that all things be prepared before
you, observe the commandment which I have given
concerning these things
70 Which saith, or teacheth, to purchase all the
lands with money, which can be purchased for money,
in the region round about the land which I have
appointed to be the land of Zion, for the beginning
of the gathering of my saints
71 All the land which can be purchased in Jackson
county, and the counties round about, and leave
the residue in mine hand
72 Now, verily I say unto you, let all the
churches gather together all their moneys; let these
things be done in their time, but not in haste; and
observe to have all things prepared before you
73 And let honorable men be appointed, even wise
men, and send them to purchase these lands
74 And the churches in the eastern countries, when
they are built up, if they will hearken unto this
counsel they may buy lands and gather together
upon them; and in this way they may establish Zion
75 There is even now already in store sufficient,
yea, even an abundance, to redeem Zion, and
establish her waste places, no more to be thrown down,
were the churches, who call themselves after my
name, willing to hearken to my voice
76 And again I say unto you, those who have been
scattered by their enemies, it is my will that they
should continue to importune for redress, and
redemption, by the hands of those who are placed as
rulers and are in authority over you
77 According to the laws and constitution of the
people, which I have suffered to be established,
and should be maintained for the rights and
protection of all flesh, according to just and holy
principles
78 That every man may act in doctrine and
principle pertaining to futurity, according to the moral
agency which I have given unto him, that every man
may be accountable for his own sins in the day of
judgment
79 Therefore, it is not right that any man should
be in bondage one to another
80 And for this purpose have I established the
Constitution of this land, by the hands of wise men
whom I raised up unto this very purpose, and
redeemed the land by the shedding of blood
81 Now, unto what shall I liken the children of
Zion? I will liken them unto the parable of the
woman and the unjust judge, for men ought always to
pray and not to faint, which saith
82 There was in a city a judge which feared not
God, neither regarded man
83 And there was a widow in that city, and she
came unto him, saying: Avenge me of mine adversary
84 And he would not for a while, but afterward he
said within himself: Though I fear not God, nor
regard man, yet because this widow troubleth me I
will avenge her, lest by her continual coming she
weary me
85 Thus will I liken the children of Zion
86 Let them importune at the feet of the judge
87 And if he heed them not, let them importune at
the feet of the governor
88 And if the governor heed them not, let them
importune at the feet of the president
89 And if the president heed them not, then will
the Lord arise and come forth out of his hiding
place, and in his fury vex the nation
90 And in his hot displeasure, and in his fierce
anger, in his time, will cut off those wicked,
unfaithful, and unjust stewards, and appoint them
their portion among hypocrites, and unbelievers
91 Even in outer darkness, where there is weeping,
and wailing, and gnashing of teeth
92 Pray ye, therefore, that their ears may be
opened unto your cries, that I may be merciful unto
them, that these things may not come upon them
93 What I have said unto you must needs be, that
all men may be left without excuse
94 That wise men and rulers may hear and know that
which they have never considered
95 That I may proceed to bring to pass my act, my
strange act, and perform my work, my strange work,
that men may discern between the righteous and
the wicked, saith your God
96 And again, I say unto you, it is contrary to my
commandment and my will that my servant Sidney
Gilbert should sell my storehouse, which I have
appointed unto my people, into the hands of mine
enemies
97 Let not that which I have appointed be polluted
by mine enemies, by the consent of those who call
themselves after my name
98 For this is a very sore and grievous sin
against me, and against my people, in consequence of
those things which I have decreed and which are soon
to befall the nations
99 Therefore, it is my will that my people should
claim, and hold claim upon that which I have
appointed unto them, though they should not be
permitted to dwell thereon
100 Nevertheless, I do not say they shall not
dwell thereon; for inasmuch as they bring forth fruit
and works meet for my kingdom they shall dwell
thereon
101 They shall build, and another shall not
inherit it; they shall plant vineyards, and they shall
eat the fruit thereof. Even so. Amen.