Section 66 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, October 29, 1831.
William E. McLellin had petitioned the Lord in secret
to make known through the Prophet the answer to
five questions, which were unknown to Joseph Smith.
At McLellin’s request, the Prophet inquired of the
Lord and received this revelation.
1–4, The
everlasting covenant is the fulness of the gospel;
5–8, Elders are to preach, testify, and reason with
the people;
9–13, Faithful ministerial service
ensures an inheritance of eternal life.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto my servant
William E. McLellin—Blessed are you, inasmuch as you
have turned away from your iniquities, and have
received my truths, saith the Lord your Redeemer, the
Savior of the world, even of as many as believe
on my name
2 Verily I say unto you, blessed are you for
receiving mine everlasting covenant, even the fulness
of my gospel, sent forth unto the children of men,
that they might have life and be made partakers of
the glories which are to be revealed in the last
days, as it was written by the prophets and
apostles in days of old
3 Verily I say unto you, my servant William, that
you are clean, but not all; repent, therefore, of
those things which are not pleasing in my sight,
saith the Lord, for the Lord will show them unto
you
4 And now, verily, I, the Lord, will show unto you
what I will concerning you, or what is my will
concerning you
5 Behold, verily I say unto you, that it is my
will that you should proclaim my gospel from land to
land, and from city to city, yea, in those regions
round about where it has not been proclaimed
6 Tarry not many days in this place; go not up
unto the land of Zion as yet; but inasmuch as you can
send, send; otherwise, think not of thy property
7 Go unto the eastern lands, bear testimony in
every place, unto every people and in their
synagogues, reasoning with the people
8 Let my servant Samuel H. Smith go with you, and
forsake him not, and give him thine instructions;
and he that is faithful shall be made strong in
every place; and I, the Lord, will go with you
9 Lay your hands upon the sick, and they shall
recover. Return not till I, the Lord, shall send you.
Be patient in affliction. Ask, and ye shall
receive; knock, and it shall be opened unto you
10 Seek not to be cumbered. Forsake all
unrighteousness. Commit not adultery—a temptation with which
thou hast been troubled
11 Keep these sayings, for they are true and
faithful; and thou shalt magnify thine office, and push
many people to Zion with songs of everlasting joy
upon their heads
12 Continue in these things even unto the end, and
you shall have a crown of eternal life at the
right hand of my Father, who is full of grace and
truth
13 Verily, thus saith the Lord your God, your
Redeemer, even Jesus Christ. Amen.