Section 78 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, March 1, 1832. On
that day, the Prophet and other leaders had
assembled to discuss Church business. This revelation
originally instructed the Prophet, Sidney Rigdon, and
Newel K. Whitney to travel to Missouri and
organize the Church’s mercantile and publishing
endeavors by creating a “firm” that would oversee these
efforts, generating funds for the establishment of
Zion and for the benefit of the poor. This firm,
known as the United Firm, was organized in April
1832 and disbanded in 1834 (see
section 82).
Sometime after its dissolution, under the direction of
Joseph Smith, the phrase “the affairs of the
storehouse for the poor” replaced “mercantile and
publishing establishments” in the revelation, and the
word “order” replaced the word “firm.”
1–4, The
Saints should organize and establish a storehouse;
5–12, Wise use of their properties will lead to
salvation;
13–14, The Church should be independent of
earthly powers;
15–16, Michael (Adam) serves
under the direction of the Holy One (Christ);
17–22,
Blessed are the faithful, for they will inherit
all things.
1 The Lord spake unto Joseph Smith, Jun., saying:
Hearken unto me, saith the Lord your God, who are
ordained unto the high priesthood of my church,
who have assembled yourselves together
2 And listen to the counsel of him who has
ordained you from on high, who shall speak in your ears
the words of wisdom, that salvation may be unto you
in that thing which you have presented before me,
saith the Lord God
3 For verily I say unto you, the time has come,
and is now at hand; and behold, and lo, it must
needs be that there be an organization of my people,
in regulating and establishing the affairs of the
storehouse for the poor of my people, both in this
place and in the land of Zion
4 For a permanent and everlasting establishment
and order unto my church, to advance the cause,
which ye have espoused, to the salvation of man, and
to the glory of your Father who is in heaven
5 That you may be equal in the bonds of heavenly
things, yea, and earthly things also, for the
obtaining of heavenly things
6 For if ye are not equal in earthly things ye
cannot be equal in obtaining heavenly things
7 For if you will that I give unto you a place in
the celestial world, you must prepare yourselves
by doing the things which I have commanded you and
required of you
8 And now, verily thus saith the Lord, it is
expedient that all things be done unto my glory, by you
who are joined together in this order
9 Or, in other words, let my servant Newel K.
Whitney and my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and my
servant Sidney Rigdon sit in council with the saints
which are in Zion
10 Otherwise Satan seeketh to turn their hearts
away from the truth, that they become blinded and
understand not the things which are prepared for
them
11 Wherefore, a commandment I give unto you, to
prepare and organize yourselves by a bond or
everlasting covenant that cannot be broken
12 And he who breaketh it shall lose his office
and standing in the church, and shall be delivered
over to the buffetings of Satan until the day of
redemption
13 Behold, this is the preparation wherewith I
prepare you, and the foundation, and the ensample
which I give unto you, whereby you may accomplish the
commandments which are given you
14 That through my providence, notwithstanding the
tribulation which shall descend upon you, that
the church may stand independent above all other
creatures beneath the celestial world
15 That you may come up unto the crown prepared
for you, and be made rulers over many kingdoms,
saith the Lord God, the Holy One of Zion, who hath
established the foundations of Adam-ondi-Ahman
16 Who hath appointed Michael your prince, and
established his feet, and set him upon high, and
given unto him the keys of salvation under the counsel
and direction of the Holy One, who is without
beginning of days or end of life
17 Verily, verily, I say unto you, ye are little
children, and ye have not as yet understood how
great blessings the Father hath in his own hands and
prepared for you
18 And ye cannot bear all things now;
nevertheless, be of good cheer, for I will lead you along. The
kingdom is yours and the blessings thereof are
yours, and the riches of eternity are yours
19 And he who receiveth all things with
thankfulness shall be made glorious; and the things of this
earth shall be added unto him, even an hundred
fold, yea, more
20 Wherefore, do the things which I have commanded
you, saith your Redeemer, even the Son Ahman, who
prepareth all things before he taketh you
21 For ye are the church of the Firstborn, and he
will take you up in a cloud, and appoint every man
his portion
22 And he that is a faithful and wise steward
shall inherit all things. Amen.