Section 133 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, November 3, 1831.
Prefacing this revelation, Joseph Smith’s history
states, “At this time there were many things which
the Elders desired to know relative to preaching the
Gospel to the inhabitants of the earth, and
concerning the gathering; and in order to walk by the
true light, and be instructed from on high, on the
3rd of November, 1831, I inquired of the Lord and
received the following important revelation.” This
section was first added to the book of Doctrine
and Covenants as an appendix and was subsequently
assigned a section number.
1–6, The Saints are
commanded to prepare for the Second Coming;
7–16,
All men are commanded to flee from Babylon, come to
Zion, and prepare for the great day of the Lord;
17–35, He will stand on Mount Zion, the continents
will become one land, and the lost tribes of
Israel will return;
36–40, The gospel was restored
through Joseph Smith to be preached in all the
world;
41–51, The Lord will come down in vengeance
upon the wicked;
52–56, It will be the year of His
redeemed;
57–74, The gospel is to be sent forth to
save the Saints and for the destruction of the
wicked.
1 Hearken, O ye people of my church, saith the
Lord your God, and hear the word of the Lord
concerning you
2 The Lord who shall suddenly come to his temple;
the Lord who shall come down upon the world with a
curse to judgment; yea, upon all the nations that
forget God, and upon all the ungodly among you
3 For he shall make bare his holy arm in the eyes
of all the nations, and all the ends of the earth
shall see the salvation of their God
4 Wherefore, prepare ye, prepare ye, O my people;
sanctify yourselves; gather ye together, O ye
people of my church, upon the land of Zion, all you
that have not been commanded to tarry
5 Go ye out from Babylon. Be ye clean that bear
the vessels of the Lord
6 Call your solemn assemblies, and speak often one
to another. And let every man call upon the name
of the Lord
7 Yea, verily I say unto you again, the time has
come when the voice of the Lord is unto you: Go ye
out of Babylon; gather ye out from among the
nations, from the four winds, from one end of heaven to
the other
8 Send forth the elders of my church unto the
nations which are afar off; unto the islands of the
sea; send forth unto foreign lands; call upon all
nations, first upon the Gentiles, and then upon the
Jews
9 And behold, and lo, this shall be their cry, and
the voice of the Lord unto all people: Go ye
forth unto the land of Zion, that the borders of my
people may be enlarged, and that her stakes may be
strengthened, and that Zion may go forth unto the
regions round about
10 Yea, let the cry go forth among all people:
Awake and arise and go forth to meet the Bridegroom;
behold and lo, the Bridegroom cometh; go ye out to
meet him. Prepare yourselves for the great day of
the Lord
11 Watch, therefore, for ye know neither the day
nor the hour
12 Let them, therefore, who are among the Gentiles
flee unto Zion
13 And let them who be of Judah flee unto
Jerusalem, unto the mountains of the Lord’s house
14 Go ye out from among the nations, even from
Babylon, from the midst of wickedness, which is
spiritual Babylon
15 But verily, thus saith the Lord, let not your
flight be in haste, but let all things be prepared
before you; and he that goeth, let him not look
back lest sudden destruction shall come upon him
16 Hearken and hear, O ye inhabitants of the
earth. Listen, ye elders of my church together, and
hear the voice of the Lord; for he calleth upon all
men, and he commandeth all men everywhere to
repent
17 For behold, the Lord God hath sent forth the
angel crying through the midst of heaven, saying:
Prepare ye the way of the Lord, and make his paths
straight, for the hour of his coming is nigh
18 When the Lamb shall stand upon Mount Zion, and
with him a hundred and forty-four thousand, having
his Father’s name written on their foreheads
19 Wherefore, prepare ye for the coming of the
Bridegroom; go ye, go ye out to meet him
20 For behold, he shall stand upon the mount of
Olivet, and upon the mighty ocean, even the great
deep, and upon the islands of the sea, and upon the
land of Zion
21 And he shall utter his voice out of Zion, and
he shall speak from Jerusalem, and his voice shall
be heard among all people
22 And it shall be a voice as the voice of many
waters, and as the voice of a great thunder, which
shall break down the mountains, and the valleys
shall not be found
23 He shall command the great deep, and it shall
be driven back into the north countries, and the
islands shall become one land
24 And the land of Jerusalem and the land of Zion
shall be turned back into their own place, and the
earth shall be like as it was in the days before
it was divided
25 And the Lord, even the Savior, shall stand in
the midst of his people, and shall reign over all
flesh
26 And they who are in the north countries shall
come in remembrance before the Lord; and their
prophets shall hear his voice, and shall no longer
stay themselves; and they shall smite the rocks, and
the ice shall flow down at their presence
27 And an highway shall be cast up in the midst of
the great deep
28 Their enemies shall become a prey unto them
29 And in the barren deserts there shall come
forth pools of living water; and the parched ground
shall no longer be a thirsty land
30 And they shall bring forth their rich treasures
unto the children of Ephraim, my servants
31 And the boundaries of the everlasting hills
shall tremble at their presence
32 And there shall they fall down and be crowned
with glory, even in Zion, by the hands of the
servants of the Lord, even the children of Ephraim
33 And they shall be filled with songs of
everlasting joy
34 Behold, this is the blessing of the everlasting
God upon the tribes of Israel, and the richer
blessing upon the head of Ephraim and his fellows
35 And they also of the tribe of Judah, after
their pain, shall be sanctified in holiness before the
Lord, to dwell in his presence day and night,
forever and ever
36 And now, verily saith the Lord, that these
things might be known among you, O inhabitants of the
earth, I have sent forth mine angel flying through
the midst of heaven, having the everlasting
gospel, who hath appeared unto some and hath committed
it unto man, who shall appear unto many that dwell
on the earth
37 And this gospel shall be preached unto every
nation, and kindred, and tongue, and people
38 And the servants of God shall go forth, saying
with a loud voice: Fear God and give glory to him,
for the hour of his judgment is come
39 And worship him that made heaven, and earth,
and the sea, and the fountains of waters
40 Calling upon the name of the Lord day and
night, saying: O that thou wouldst rend the heavens,
that thou wouldst come down, that the mountains
might flow down at thy presence
41 And it shall be answered upon their heads; for
the presence of the Lord shall be as the melting
fire that burneth, and as the fire which causeth
the waters to boil
42 O Lord, thou shalt come down to make thy name
known to thine adversaries, and all nations shall
tremble at thy presence
43 When thou doest terrible things, things they
look not for
44 Yea, when thou comest down, and the mountains
flow down at thy presence, thou shalt meet him who
rejoiceth and worketh righteousness, who
remembereth thee in thy ways
45 For since the beginning of the world have not
men heard nor perceived by the ear, neither hath
any eye seen, O God, besides thee, how great things
thou hast prepared for him that waiteth for thee
46 And it shall be said: Who is this that cometh
down from God in heaven with dyed garments; yea,
from the regions which are not known, clothed in his
glorious apparel, traveling in the greatness of
his strength
47 And he shall say: I am he who spake in
righteousness, mighty to save
48 And the Lord shall be red in his apparel, and
his garments like him that treadeth in the
wine-vat
49 And so great shall be the glory of his presence
that the sun shall hide his face in shame, and
the moon shall withhold its light, and the stars
shall be hurled from their places
50 And his voice shall be heard: I have trodden
the wine-press alone, and have brought judgment upon
all people; and none were with me
51 And I have trampled them in my fury, and I did
tread upon them in mine anger, and their blood
have I sprinkled upon my garments, and stained all my
raiment; for this was the day of vengeance which
was in my heart
52 And now the year of my redeemed is come; and
they shall mention the loving kindness of their
Lord, and all that he has bestowed upon them according
to his goodness, and according to his loving
kindness, forever and ever
53 In all their afflictions he was afflicted. And
the angel of his presence saved them; and in his
love, and in his pity, he redeemed them, and bore
them, and carried them all the days of old
54 Yea, and Enoch also, and they who were with
him; the prophets who were before him; and Noah also,
and they who were before him; and Moses also, and
they who were before him
55 And from Moses to Elijah, and from Elijah to
John, who were with Christ in his resurrection, and
the holy apostles, with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob,
shall be in the presence of the Lamb
56 And the graves of the saints shall be opened;
and they shall come forth and stand on the right
hand of the Lamb, when he shall stand upon Mount
Zion, and upon the holy city, the New Jerusalem; and
they shall sing the song of the Lamb, day and
night forever and ever
57 And for this cause, that men might be made
partakers of the glories which were to be revealed,
the Lord sent forth the fulness of his gospel, his
everlasting covenant, reasoning in plainness and
simplicity
58 To prepare the weak for those things which are
coming on the earth, and for the Lord’s errand in
the day when the weak shall confound the wise, and
the little one become a strong nation, and two
shall put their tens of thousands to flight
59 And by the weak things of the earth the Lord
shall thresh the nations by the power of his Spirit
60 And for this cause these commandments were
given; they were commanded to be kept from the world
in the day that they were given, but now are to go
forth unto all flesh
61 And this according to the mind and will of the
Lord, who ruleth over all flesh
62 And unto him that repenteth and sanctifieth
himself before the Lord shall be given eternal life
63 And upon them that hearken not to the voice of
the Lord shall be fulfilled that which was written
by the prophet Moses, that they should be cut off
from among the people
64 And also that which was written by the prophet
Malachi: For, behold, the day cometh that shall
burn as an oven, and all the proud, yea, and all
that do wickedly, shall be stubble; and the day that
cometh shall burn them up, saith the Lord of
hosts, that it shall leave them neither root nor
branch
65 Wherefore, this shall be the answer of the Lord
unto them
66 In that day when I came unto mine own, no man
among you received me, and you were driven out
67 When I called again there was none of you to
answer; yet my arm was not shortened at all that I
could not redeem, neither my power to deliver
68 Behold, at my rebuke I dry up the sea. I make
the rivers a wilderness; their fish stink, and die
for thirst
69 I clothe the heavens with blackness, and make
sackcloth their covering
70 And this shall ye have of my hand—ye shall lie
down in sorrow
71 Behold, and lo, there are none to deliver you;
for ye obeyed not my voice when I called to you
out of the heavens; ye believed not my servants, and
when they were sent unto you ye received them
not
72 Wherefore, they sealed up the testimony and
bound up the law, and ye were delivered over unto
darkness
73 These shall go away into outer darkness, where
there is weeping, and wailing, and gnashing of
teeth
74 Behold the Lord your God hath spoken it. Amen.