Section 27 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Harmony, Pennsylvania, August 1830. In
preparation for a religious service at which the
sacrament of bread and wine was to be administered,
Joseph set out to procure wine. He was met by a
heavenly messenger and received this revelation, a
portion of which was written at the time and the
remainder in the September following. Water is now
used instead of wine in the sacramental services of
the Church.
1–4, The emblems to be used in
partaking of the sacrament are set forth;
5–14, Christ
and His servants from all dispensations are to
partake of the sacrament;
15–18, Put on the whole
armor of God.
1 Listen to the voice of Jesus Christ, your Lord,
your God, and your Redeemer, whose word is quick
and powerful
2 For, behold, I say unto you, that it mattereth
not what ye shall eat or what ye shall drink when
ye partake of the sacrament, if it so be that ye do
it with an eye single to my glory—remembering
unto the Father my body which was laid down for you,
and my blood which was shed for the remission of
your sins
3 Wherefore, a commandment I give unto you, that
you shall not purchase wine neither strong drink of
your enemies
4 Wherefore, you shall partake of none except it
is made new among you; yea, in this my Father’s
kingdom which shall be built up on the earth
5 Behold, this is wisdom in me; wherefore, marvel
not, for the hour cometh that I will drink of the
fruit of the vine with you on the earth, and with
Moroni, whom I have sent unto you to reveal the
Book of Mormon, containing the fulness of my
everlasting gospel, to whom I have committed the keys of
the record of the stick of Ephraim
6 And also with Elias, to whom I have committed
the keys of bringing to pass the restoration of all
things spoken by the mouth of all the holy
prophets since the world began, concerning the last days
7 And also John the son of Zacharias, which
Zacharias he (Elias) visited and gave promise that he
should have a son, and his name should be John, and
he should be filled with the spirit of Elias
8 Which John I have sent unto you, my servants,
Joseph Smith, Jun., and Oliver Cowdery, to ordain
you unto the first priesthood which you have
received, that you might be called and ordained even as
Aaron
9 And also Elijah, unto whom I have committed the
keys of the power of turning the hearts of the
fathers to the children, and the hearts of the
children to the fathers, that the whole earth may not be
smitten with a curse
10 And also with Joseph and Jacob, and Isaac, and
Abraham, your fathers, by whom the promises
remain
11 And also with Michael, or Adam, the father of
all, the prince of all, the ancient of days
12 And also with Peter, and James, and John, whom
I have sent unto you, by whom I have ordained you
and confirmed you to be apostles, and especial
witnesses of my name, and bear the keys of your
ministry and of the same things which I revealed unto
them
13 Unto whom I have committed the keys of my
kingdom, and a dispensation of the gospel for the last
times; and for the fulness of times, in the which
I will gather together in one all things, both
which are in heaven, and which are on earth
14 And also with all those whom my Father hath
given me out of the world
15 Wherefore, lift up your hearts and rejoice, and
gird up your loins, and take upon you my whole
armor, that ye may be able to withstand the evil
day, having done all, that ye may be able to stand
16 Stand, therefore, having your loins girt about
with truth, having on the breastplate of
righteousness, and your feet shod with the preparation of
the gospel of peace, which I have sent mine angels
to commit unto you
17 Taking the shield of faith wherewith ye shall
be able to quench all the fiery darts of the
wicked
18 And take the helmet of salvation, and the sword
of my Spirit, which I will pour out upon you, and
my word which I reveal unto you, and be agreed as
touching all things whatsoever ye ask of me, and
be faithful until I come, and ye shall be caught
up, that where I am ye shall be also. Amen.