Section 94 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, August 2,
1833. Hyrum Smith, Reynolds Cahoon, and Jared
Carter are appointed as a Church building
committee.
1–9, The Lord gives a commandment relative
to the erection of a house for the work of the
Presidency;
10–12, A printing house is to be
built;
13–17, Certain inheritances are assigned.
1 And again, verily I say unto you, my
friends, a commandment I give unto you,
that ye shall commence a work of laying out
and preparing a beginning and foundation
of the city of the stake of Zion, here in
the land of Kirtland, beginning at my house.
2 And behold, it must be
done according to the pattern
which I have given unto you.
3 And let the first lot on
the south be consecrated
unto me for the building
of a house for the
presidency, for the work of the
presidency, in obtaining
revelations; and for the work
of the ministry of the
presidency, in all things
pertaining to the church and kingdom.
4 Verily I say unto you,
that it shall be built
fifty-five by sixty-five
feet in the width
thereof and in the length
thereof, in the inner court.
5 And there shall be a
lower court and a higher
court, according to the
pattern which shall be
given unto you hereafter.
6 And it shall be
dedicated unto the Lord
from the foundation
thereof, according to the
order of the
priesthood, according to the
pattern which shall be
given unto you hereafter.
7 And it shall be
wholly dedicated unto
the Lord for the
work of the presidency.
8 And ye shall
not suffer any
unclean thing to come
in unto it; and
my glory shall be
there, and my
presence shall be there.
9 But if there
shall come into
it any unclean
thing, my
glory shall not be
there; and my
presence shall
not come into it.
10 And again,
verily I say
unto you, the
second lot on
the south shall
be dedicated
unto me for
the building of
a house unto
me, for the
work of the
printing of the
translation of my
scriptures,
and all things
whatsoever I
shall command you.
11 And it
shall be
fifty-five by
sixty-five feet in
the width
thereof and the
length
thereof, in the
inner court; and
there shall
be a lower
and a higher court.
12 And this
house shall
be wholly
dedicated unto
the Lord
from the
foundation
thereof, for the
work of the
printing, in
all things
whatsoever I
shall
command you, to be
holy,
undefiled,
according to the
pattern in
all things as
it shall be given unto you.
13 And on
the third
lot shall my
servant
Hyrum Smith
receive his
inheritance.
14 And on
the first
and second
lots on
the north
shall my
servants
Reynolds
Cahoon and
Jared Carter
receive
their inheritances—
15 That
they may
do the
work which I
have
appointed
unto them,
to be a
committee
to build
mine
houses,
according to
the
commandment,
which I,
the Lord
God, have given unto you.
16 These
two
houses are
not to
be built
until I
give
unto you a
commandment
concerning them.
17 And
now I
give
unto you
no more
at this
time. Amen.