Section 125 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Nauvoo, Illinois, March 1841,
concerning the Saints in the territory of Iowa.
1–4,
The Saints are to build cities and to gather to
the stakes of Zion.
1 What is the will of the Lord concerning the
saints in the Territory of Iowa
2 Verily, thus saith the Lord, I say unto you, if
those who call themselves by my name and are
essaying to be my saints, if they will do my will and
keep my commandments concerning them, let them
gather themselves together unto the places which I
shall appoint unto them by my servant Joseph, and
build up cities unto my name, that they may be
prepared for that which is in store for a time to come
3 Let them build up a city unto my name upon the
land opposite the city of Nauvoo, and let the name
of Zarahemla be named upon it
4 And let all those who come from the east, and
the west, and the north, and the south, that have
desires to dwell therein, take up their inheritance
in the same, as well as in the city of Nashville,
or in the city of Nauvoo, and in all the stakes
which I have appointed, saith the Lord.