Section 81 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, March 15, 1832.
Frederick G. Williams is called to be a high
priest and a counselor in the Presidency of the High
Priesthood. The historical records show that
when this revelation was received in March 1832, it
called Jesse Gause to the office of counselor
to Joseph Smith in the Presidency. However, when
he failed to continue in a manner consistent
with this appointment, the call was subsequently
transferred to Frederick G. Williams. The
revelation (dated March 1832) should be regarded as a
step toward the formal organization of the First
Presidency, specifically calling for the office
of counselor in that body and explaining the
dignity of the appointment. Brother Gause served for
a time but was excommunicated from the Church
in December 1832. Brother Williams was ordained
to the specified office on March 18, 1833.
1–2,
The keys of the kingdom are always held by the
First Presidency;
3–7, If Frederick G. Williams
is faithful in his ministry, he will have eternal life.
1 Verily, verily, I say unto you my servant
Frederick G. Williams: Listen to the voice of him
who speaketh, to the word of the Lord your God,
and hearken to the calling wherewith you are
called, even to be a high priest in my church,
and a counselor unto my servant Joseph Smith, Jun.;
2 Unto whom I have given the keys of
the kingdom, which belong always unto
the Presidency of the High Priesthood:
3 Therefore, verily I acknowledge
him and will bless him, and also thee,
inasmuch as thou art faithful in
counsel, in the office which I have
appointed unto you, in prayer always,
vocally and in thy heart, in public
and in private, also in thy ministry
in proclaiming the gospel in the
land of the living, and among thy brethren.
4 And in doing these things thou
wilt do the greatest good unto
thy fellow beings, and wilt promote
the glory of him who is your Lord.
5 Wherefore, be faithful; stand
in the office which I have
appointed unto you; succor the weak,
lift up the hands which hang
down, and strengthen the feeble knees.
6 And if thou art faithful
unto the end thou shalt
have a crown of
immortality, and eternal life in the
mansions which I have
prepared in the house of my Father.
7 Behold, and lo,
these are the words of
Alpha and Omega,
even Jesus Christ. Amen.