headings to sections 78 and
1–10, Saints who
transgress against the united order will be cursed;
11–16, The Lord provides for His Saints in His own
way;
17–18, Gospel law governs the care of the
poor;
19–46, The stewardships and blessings of
various brethren are designated;
47–53, The united
order in Kirtland and the order in Zion are to
operate separately;
54–66, The sacred treasury of the
Lord is set up for the printing of the scriptures;
67–77, The general treasury of the united order
is to operate on the basis of common consent;
78–86, Those in the united order are to pay all their
debts, and the Lord will deliver them from
financial bondage.
1 Verily I say unto you, my friends, I give unto
you counsel, and a commandment, concerning all the
properties which belong to the order which I
commanded to be organized and established, to be a
united order, and an everlasting order for the benefit
of my church, and for the salvation of men until
I come
2 With promise immutable and unchangeable, that
inasmuch as those whom I commanded were faithful
they should be blessed with a multiplicity of
blessings
3 But inasmuch as they were not faithful they were
nigh unto cursing
4 Therefore, inasmuch as some of my servants have
not kept the commandment, but have broken the
covenant through covetousness, and with feigned words,
I have cursed them with a very sore and grievous
curse
5 For I, the Lord, have decreed in my heart, that
inasmuch as any man belonging to the order shall
be found a transgressor, or, in other words, shall
break the covenant with which ye are bound, he
shall be cursed in his life, and shall be trodden
down by whom I will
6 For I, the Lord, am not to be mocked in these
things
7 And all this that the innocent among you may not
be condemned with the unjust; and that the guilty
among you may not escape; because I, the Lord,
have promised unto you a crown of glory at my right
hand
8 Therefore, inasmuch as you are found
transgressors, you cannot escape my wrath in your lives
9 Inasmuch as ye are cut off for transgression, ye
cannot escape the buffetings of Satan until the
day of redemption
10 And I now give unto you power from this very
hour, that if any man among you, of the order, is
found a transgressor and repenteth not of the evil,
that ye shall deliver him over unto the buffetings
of Satan; and he shall not have power to bring
evil upon you
11 It is wisdom in me; therefore, a commandment I
give unto you, that ye shall organize yourselves
and appoint every man his stewardship
12 That every man may give an account unto me of
the stewardship which is appointed unto him
13 For it is expedient that I, the Lord, should
make every man accountable, as a steward over
earthly blessings, which I have made and prepared for my
creatures
14 I, the Lord, stretched out the heavens, and
built the earth, my very handiwork; and all things
therein are mine
15 And it is my purpose to provide for my saints,
for all things are mine
16 But it must needs be done in mine own way; and
behold this is the way that I, the Lord, have
decreed to provide for my saints, that the poor shall
be exalted, in that the rich are made low
17 For the earth is full, and there is enough and
to spare; yea, I prepared all things, and have
given unto the children of men to be agents unto
themselves
18 Therefore, if any man shall take of the
abundance which I have made, and impart not his portion,
according to the law of my gospel, unto the poor
and the needy, he shall, with the wicked, lift up
his eyes in hell, being in torment
19 And now, verily I say unto you, concerning the
properties of the order
20 Let my servant Sidney Rigdon have appointed
unto him the place where he now resides, and the lot
of the tannery for his stewardship, for his
support while he is laboring in my vineyard, even as I
will, when I shall command him
21 And let all things be done according to the
counsel of the order, and united consent or voice of
the order, which dwell in the land of Kirtland
22 And this stewardship and blessing, I, the Lord,
confer upon my servant Sidney Rigdon for a
blessing upon him, and his seed after him
23 And I will multiply blessings upon him,
inasmuch as he will be humble before me
24 And again, let my servant Martin Harris have
appointed unto him, for his stewardship, the lot of
land which my servant John Johnson obtained in
exchange for his former inheritance, for him and his
seed after him
25 And inasmuch as he is faithful, I will multiply
blessings upon him and his seed after him
26 And let my servant Martin Harris devote his
moneys for the proclaiming of my words, according as
my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., shall direct
27 And again, let my servant Frederick G. Williams
have the place upon which he now dwells
28 And let my servant Oliver Cowdery have the lot
which is set off joining the house, which is to be
for the printing office, which is lot number one,
and also the lot upon which his father resides
29 And let my servants Frederick G. Williams and
Oliver Cowdery have the printing office and all
things that pertain unto it
30 And this shall be their stewardship which shall
be appointed unto them
31 And inasmuch as they are faithful, behold I
will bless, and multiply blessings upon them
32 And this is the beginning of the stewardship
which I have appointed them, for them and their seed
after them
33 And, inasmuch as they are faithful, I will
multiply blessings upon them and their seed after
them, even a multiplicity of blessings
34 And again, let my servant John Johnson have the
house in which he lives, and the inheritance, all
save the ground which has been reserved for the
building of my houses, which pertains to that
inheritance, and those lots which have been named for
my servant Oliver Cowdery
35 And inasmuch as he is faithful, I will multiply
blessings upon him
36 And it is my will that he should sell the lots
that are laid off for the building up of the city
of my saints, inasmuch as it shall be made known
to him by the voice of the Spirit, and according to
the counsel of the order, and by the voice of the
order
37 And this is the beginning of the stewardship
which I have appointed unto him, for a blessing unto
him and his seed after him
38 And inasmuch as he is faithful, I will multiply
a multiplicity of blessings upon him
39 And again, let my servant Newel K. Whitney have
appointed unto him the houses and lot where he
now resides, and the lot and building on which the
mercantile establishment stands, and also the lot
which is on the corner south of the mercantile
establishment, and also the lot on which the ashery is
situated
40 And all this I have appointed unto my servant
Newel K. Whitney for his stewardship, for a
blessing upon him and his seed after him, for the benefit
of the mercantile establishment of my order which
I have established for my stake in the land of
Kirtland
41 Yea, verily, this is the stewardship which I
have appointed unto my servant N. K. Whitney, even
this whole mercantile establishment, him and his
agent, and his seed after him
42 And inasmuch as he is faithful in keeping my
commandments, which I have given unto him, I will
multiply blessings upon him and his seed after him,
even a multiplicity of blessings
43 And again, let my servant Joseph Smith, Jun.,
have appointed unto him the lot which is laid off
for the building of my house, which is forty rods
long and twelve wide, and also the inheritance upon
which his father now resides
44 And this is the beginning of the stewardship
which I have appointed unto him, for a blessing upon
him, and upon his father
45 For behold, I have reserved an inheritance for
his father, for his support; therefore he shall be
reckoned in the house of my servant Joseph Smith,
Jun
46 And I will multiply blessings upon the house of
my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., inasmuch as he is
faithful, even a multiplicity of blessings
47 And now, a commandment I give unto you
concerning Zion, that you shall no longer be bound as a
united order to your brethren of Zion, only on this
wise
48 After you are organized, you shall be called
the United Order of the Stake of Zion, the City of
Kirtland. And your brethren, after they are
organized, shall be called the United Order of the City
of Zion
49 And they shall be organized in their own names,
and in their own name; and they shall do their
business in their own name, and in their own names
50 And you shall do your business in your own
name, and in your own names
51 And this I have commanded to be done for your
salvation, and also for their salvation, in
consequence of their being driven out and that which is
to come
52 The covenants being broken through
transgression, by covetousness and feigned words
53 Therefore, you are dissolved as a united order
with your brethren, that you are not bound only up
to this hour unto them, only on this wise, as I
said, by loan as shall be agreed by this order in
council, as your circumstances will admit and the
voice of the council direct
54 And again, a commandment I give unto you
concerning your stewardship which I have appointed unto
you
55 Behold, all these properties are mine, or else
your faith is vain, and ye are found hypocrites,
and the covenants which ye have made unto me are
broken
56 And if the properties are mine, then ye are
stewards; otherwise ye are no stewards
57 But, verily I say unto you, I have appointed
unto you to be stewards over mine house, even
stewards indeed
58 And for this purpose I have commanded you to
organize yourselves, even to print my words, the
fulness of my scriptures, the revelations which I
have given unto you, and which I shall, hereafter,
from time to time give unto you
59 For the purpose of building up my church and
kingdom on the earth, and to prepare my people for
the time when I shall dwell with them, which is
nigh at hand
60 And ye shall prepare for yourselves a place for
a treasury, and consecrate it unto my name
61 And ye shall appoint one among you to keep the
treasury, and he shall be ordained unto this
blessing
62 And there shall be a seal upon the treasury,
and all the sacred things shall be delivered into
the treasury; and no man among you shall call it his
own, or any part of it, for it shall belong to
you all with one accord
63 And I give it unto you from this very hour; and
now see to it, that ye go to and make use of the
stewardship which I have appointed unto you,
exclusive of the sacred things, for the purpose of
printing these sacred things as I have said
64 And the avails of the sacred things shall be
had in the treasury, and a seal shall be upon it;
and it shall not be used or taken out of the
treasury by any one, neither shall the seal be loosed
which shall be placed upon it, only by the voice of
the order, or by commandment
65 And thus shall ye preserve the avails of the
sacred things in the treasury, for sacred and holy
purposes
66 And this shall be called the sacred treasury of
the Lord; and a seal shall be kept upon it that
it may be holy and consecrated unto the Lord
67 And again, there shall be another treasury
prepared, and a treasurer appointed to keep the
treasury, and a seal shall be placed upon it
68 And all moneys that you receive in your
stewardships, by improving upon the properties which I
have appointed unto you, in houses, or in lands, or
in cattle, or in all things save it be the holy
and sacred writings, which I have reserved unto
myself for holy and sacred purposes, shall be cast
into the treasury as fast as you receive moneys, by
hundreds, or by fifties, or by twenties, or by
tens, or by fives
69 Or in other words, if any man among you obtain
five dollars let him cast them into the treasury;
or if he obtain ten, or twenty, or fifty, or an
hundred, let him do likewise
70 And let not any among you say that it is his
own; for it shall not be called his, nor any part of
it
71 And there shall not any part of it be used, or
taken out of the treasury, only by the voice and
common consent of the order
72 And this shall be the voice and common consent
of the order—that any man among you say to the
treasurer: I have need of this to help me in my
stewardship
73 If it be five dollars, or if it be ten dollars,
or twenty, or fifty, or a hundred, the treasurer
shall give unto him the sum which he requires to
help him in his stewardship
74 Until he be found a transgressor, and it is
manifest before the council of the order plainly that
he is an unfaithful and an unwise steward
75 But so long as he is in full fellowship, and is
faithful and wise in his stewardship, this shall
be his token unto the treasurer that the treasurer
shall not withhold
76 But in case of transgression, the treasurer
shall be subject unto the council and voice of the
order
77 And in case the treasurer is found an
unfaithful and an unwise steward, he shall be subject to
the council and voice of the order, and shall be
removed out of his place, and another shall be
appointed in his stead
78 And again, verily I say unto you, concerning
your debts—behold it is my will that you shall pay
all your debts
79 And it is my will that you shall humble
yourselves before me, and obtain this blessing by your
diligence and humility and the prayer of faith
80 And inasmuch as you are diligent and humble,
and exercise the prayer of faith, behold, I will
soften the hearts of those to whom you are in debt,
until I shall send means unto you for your
deliverance
81 Therefore write speedily to New York and write
according to that which shall be dictated by my
Spirit; and I will soften the hearts of those to
whom you are in debt, that it shall be taken away out
of their minds to bring affliction upon you
82 And inasmuch as ye are humble and faithful and
call upon my name, behold, I will give you the
victory
83 I give unto you a promise, that you shall be
delivered this once out of your bondage
84 Inasmuch as you obtain a chance to loan money
by hundreds, or thousands, even until you shall
loan enough to deliver yourself from bondage, it is
your privilege
85 And pledge the properties which I have put into
your hands, this once, by giving your names by
common consent or otherwise, as it shall seem good
unto you
Section 104 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at or near Kirtland, Ohio, April 23, 1834,
concerning the United Firm (see the
82). The occasion was likely that of a council
meeting of members of the United Firm, which
discussed the pressing temporal needs of the Church. An
earlier meeting of the firm on April 10 had resolved
that the organization be dissolved. This
revelation directs that the firm instead be reorganized;
its properties were to be divided among members of
the firm as their stewardships. Under Joseph
Smith’s direction, the phrase “United Firm” was later
replaced with “United Order” in the revelation.