Section 86 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, December 6,
1832. This revelation was received while the
Prophet was reviewing and editing the manuscript of
the translation of the Bible.
1–7, The Lord gives
the meaning of the parable of the wheat and
tares;
8–11, He explains priesthood blessings to
those who are lawful heirs according to the flesh.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto
you my servants, concerning the
parable of the wheat and of the tares:
2 Behold, verily I say, the
field was the world, and the
apostles were the sowers of the seed;
3 And after they have fallen
asleep the great persecutor
of the church, the
apostate, the whore, even Babylon,
that maketh all nations to
drink of her cup, in whose
hearts the enemy, even Satan,
sitteth to reign—behold he
soweth the tares; wherefore,
the tares choke the wheat and
drive the church into the wilderness.
4 But behold, in the
last days, even now while
the Lord is beginning
to bring forth the
word, and the blade is
springing up and is yet tender—
5 Behold, verily I
say unto you, the
angels are crying unto the
Lord day and night,
who are ready and
waiting to be sent forth
to reap down the fields;
6 But the Lord
saith unto them,
pluck not up the tares
while the blade
is yet tender (for
verily your faith
is weak), lest you
destroy the wheat also.
7 Therefore, let
the wheat and the
tares grow
together until the
harvest is fully
ripe; then ye shall
first gather out
the wheat from
among the tares,
and after the
gathering of the
wheat, behold and lo,
the tares are
bound in bundles,
and the field
remaineth to be burned.
8 Therefore, thus
saith the Lord
unto you, with
whom the priesthood
hath continued
through the lineage
of your fathers—
9 For ye are
lawful heirs,
according to
the flesh, and
have been hid
from the world
with Christ in God—
10 Therefore
your life and
the
priesthood have
remained, and must
needs remain
through you
and your
lineage until the
restoration
of all things
spoken by
the mouths of
all the holy
prophets since
the world began.
Therefore, blessed
are ye if ye
continue in
my goodness,
a light unto
the
Gentiles, and
through this
priesthood, a
savior unto my
people
Israel. The Lord
hath said it. Amen.