Section 124 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Nauvoo, Illinois, January 19, 1841.
Because of increasing persecutions and illegal
procedures against them by public officers, the Saints
had been compelled to leave Missouri. The
exterminating order issued by Lilburn W. Boggs, governor of
Missouri, dated October 27, 1838, had left them
no alternative. In 1841, when this revelation was
given, the city of Nauvoo, occupying the site of
the former village of Commerce, Illinois, had been
built up by the Saints, and here the headquarters
of the Church had been established.
1–14, Joseph
Smith is commanded to make a solemn proclamation of
the gospel to the president of the United States,
the governors, and the rulers of all nations;
15–21, Hyrum Smith, David W. Patten, Joseph Smith
Sr., and others among the living and the dead are
blessed for their integrity and virtues;
22–28, The
Saints are commanded to build both a house for
the entertainment of strangers and a temple in
Nauvoo;
29–36, Baptisms for the dead are to be
performed in temples;
37–44, The Lord’s people always
build temples for the performance of holy
ordinances;
45–55, The Saints are excused from building the
temple in Jackson County because of the
oppression of their enemies;
56–83, Directions are given
for the building of the Nauvoo House;
84–96, Hyrum
Smith is called to be a patriarch, to receive the
keys, and to stand in the place of Oliver
Cowdery;
97–122, William Law and others are counseled in
their labors;
123–45, General and local officers
are named, along with their duties and quorum
affiliations.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you, my servant
Joseph Smith, I am well pleased with your
offering and acknowledgments, which you have made; for
unto this end have I raised you up, that I might
show forth my wisdom through the weak things of the
earth
2 Your prayers are acceptable before me; and in
answer to them I say unto you, that you are now
called immediately to make a solemn proclamation of my
gospel, and of this stake which I have planted to
be a cornerstone of Zion, which shall be polished
with the refinement which is after the similitude
of a palace
3 This proclamation shall be made to all the kings
of the world, to the four corners thereof, to the
honorable president-elect, and the high-minded
governors of the nation in which you live, and to
all the nations of the earth scattered abroad
4 Let it be written in the spirit of meekness and
by the power of the Holy Ghost, which shall be in
you at the time of the writing of the same
5 For it shall be given you by the Holy Ghost to
know my will concerning those kings and
authorities, even what shall befall them in a time to come
6 For, behold, I am about to call upon them to
give heed to the light and glory of Zion, for the set
time has come to favor her
7 Call ye, therefore, upon them with loud
proclamation, and with your testimony, fearing them not,
for they are as grass, and all their glory as the
flower thereof which soon falleth, that they may be
left also without excuse
8 And that I may visit them in the day of
visitation, when I shall unveil the face of my covering,
to appoint the portion of the oppressor among
hypocrites, where there is gnashing of teeth, if they
reject my servants and my testimony which I have
revealed unto them
9 And again, I will visit and soften their hearts,
many of them for your good, that ye may find
grace in their eyes, that they may come to the light
of truth, and the Gentiles to the exaltation or
lifting up of Zion
10 For the day of my visitation cometh speedily,
in an hour when ye think not of; and where shall be
the safety of my people, and refuge for those who
shall be left of them
11 Awake, O kings of the earth! Come ye, O, come
ye, with your gold and your silver, to the help of
my people, to the house of the daughters of Zion
12 And again, verily I say unto you, let my
servant Robert B. Thompson help you to write this
proclamation, for I am well pleased with him, and that
he should be with you
13 Let him, therefore, hearken to your counsel,
and I will bless him with a multiplicity of
blessings; let him be faithful and true in all things from
henceforth, and he shall be great in mine eyes
14 But let him remember that his stewardship will
I require at his hands
15 And again, verily I say unto you, blessed is my
servant Hyrum Smith; for I, the Lord, love him
because of the integrity of his heart, and because
he loveth that which is right before me, saith the
Lord
16 Again, let my servant John C. Bennett help you
in your labor in sending my word to the kings and
people of the earth, and stand by you, even you my
servant Joseph Smith, in the hour of affliction;
and his reward shall not fail if he receive
counsel
17 And for his love he shall be great, for he
shall be mine if he do this, saith the Lord. I have
seen the work which he hath done, which I accept if
he continue, and will crown him with blessings and
great glory
18 And again, I say unto you that it is my will
that my servant Lyman Wight should continue in
preaching for Zion, in the spirit of meekness,
confessing me before the world; and I will bear him up as
on eagles’ wings; and he shall beget glory and
honor to himself and unto my name
19 That when he shall finish his work I may
receive him unto myself, even as I did my servant David
Patten, who is with me at this time, and also my
servant Edward Partridge, and also my aged servant
Joseph Smith, Sen., who sitteth with Abraham at
his right hand, and blessed and holy is he, for he
is mine
20 And again, verily I say unto you, my servant
George Miller is without guile; he may be trusted
because of the integrity of his heart; and for the
love which he has to my testimony I, the Lord, love
him
21 I therefore say unto you, I seal upon his head
the office of a bishopric, like unto my servant
Edward Partridge, that he may receive the
consecrations of mine house, that he may administer
blessings upon the heads of the poor of my people, saith
the Lord. Let no man despise my servant George, for
he shall honor me
22 Let my servant George, and my servant Lyman,
and my servant John Snider, and others, build a
house unto my name, such a one as my servant Joseph
shall show unto them, upon the place which he shall
show unto them also
23 And it shall be for a house for boarding, a
house that strangers may come from afar to lodge
therein; therefore let it be a good house, worthy of
all acceptation, that the weary traveler may find
health and safety while he shall contemplate the
word of the Lord; and the cornerstone I have
appointed for Zion
24 This house shall be a healthful habitation if
it be built unto my name, and if the governor which
shall be appointed unto it shall not suffer any
pollution to come upon it. It shall be holy, or the
Lord your God will not dwell therein
25 And again, verily I say unto you, let all my
saints come from afar
26 And send ye swift messengers, yea, chosen
messengers, and say unto them: Come ye, with all your
gold, and your silver, and your precious stones,
and with all your antiquities; and with all who have
knowledge of antiquities, that will come, may
come, and bring the box tree, and the fir tree, and
the pine tree, together with all the precious trees
of the earth
27 And with iron, with copper, and with brass, and
with zinc, and with all your precious things of
the earth; and build a house to my name, for the
Most High to dwell therein
28 For there is not a place found on earth that he
may come to and restore again that which was lost
unto you, or which he hath taken away, even the
fulness of the priesthood
29 For a baptismal font there is not upon the
earth, that they, my saints, may be baptized for those
who are dead
30 For this ordinance belongeth to my house, and
cannot be acceptable to me, only in the days of
your poverty, wherein ye are not able to build a
house unto me
31 But I command you, all ye my saints, to build a
house unto me; and I grant unto you a sufficient
time to build a house unto me; and during this
time your baptisms shall be acceptable unto me
32 But behold, at the end of this appointment your
baptisms for your dead shall not be acceptable
unto me; and if you do not these things at the end
of the appointment ye shall be rejected as a
church, with your dead, saith the Lord your God
33 For verily I say unto you, that after you have
had sufficient time to build a house to me,
wherein the ordinance of baptizing for the dead
belongeth, and for which the same was instituted from
before the foundation of the world, your baptisms for
your dead cannot be acceptable unto me
34 For therein are the keys of the holy priesthood
ordained, that you may receive honor and glory
35 And after this time, your baptisms for the
dead, by those who are scattered abroad, are not
acceptable unto me, saith the Lord
36 For it is ordained that in Zion, and in her
stakes, and in Jerusalem, those places which I have
appointed for refuge, shall be the places for your
baptisms for your dead
37 And again, verily I say unto you, how shall
your washings be acceptable unto me, except ye
perform them in a house which you have built to my name
38 For, for this cause I commanded Moses that he
should build a tabernacle, that they should bear it
with them in the wilderness, and to build a house
in the land of promise, that those ordinances
might be revealed which had been hid from before the
world was
39 Therefore, verily I say unto you, that your
anointings, and your washings, and your baptisms for
the dead, and your solemn assemblies, and your
memorials for your sacrifices by the sons of Levi,
and for your oracles in your most holy places
wherein you receive conversations, and your statutes and
judgments, for the beginning of the revelations
and foundation of Zion, and for the glory, honor,
and endowment of all her municipals, are ordained
by the ordinance of my holy house, which my people
are always commanded to build unto my holy name
40 And verily I say unto you, let this house be
built unto my name, that I may reveal mine
ordinances therein unto my people
41 For I deign to reveal unto my church things
which have been kept hid from before the foundation
of the world, things that pertain to the
dispensation of the fulness of times
42 And I will show unto my servant Joseph all
things pertaining to this house, and the priesthood
thereof, and the place whereon it shall be built
43 And ye shall build it on the place where you
have contemplated building it, for that is the spot
which I have chosen for you to build it
44 If ye labor with all your might, I will
consecrate that spot that it shall be made holy
45 And if my people will hearken unto my voice,
and unto the voice of my servants whom I have
appointed to lead my people, behold, verily I say unto
you, they shall not be moved out of their place
46 But if they will not hearken to my voice, nor
unto the voice of these men whom I have appointed,
they shall not be blest, because they pollute mine
holy grounds, and mine holy ordinances, and
charters, and my holy words which I give unto them
47 And it shall come to pass that if you build a
house unto my name, and do not do the things that I
say, I will not perform the oath which I make
unto you, neither fulfil the promises which ye expect
at my hands, saith the Lord
48 For instead of blessings, ye, by your own
works, bring cursings, wrath, indignation, and
judgments upon your own heads, by your follies, and by all
your abominations, which you practice before me,
saith the Lord
49 Verily, verily, I say unto you, that when I
give a commandment to any of the sons of men to do a
work unto my name, and those sons of men go with
all their might and with all they have to perform
that work, and cease not their diligence, and their
enemies come upon them and hinder them from
performing that work, behold, it behooveth me to
require that work no more at the hands of those sons of
men, but to accept of their offerings
50 And the iniquity and transgression of my holy
laws and commandments I will visit upon the heads
of those who hindered my work, unto the third and
fourth generation, so long as they repent not, and
hate me, saith the Lord God
51 Therefore, for this cause have I accepted the
offerings of those whom I commanded to build up a
city and a house unto my name, in Jackson county,
Missouri, and were hindered by their enemies, saith
the Lord your God
52 And I will answer judgment, wrath, and
indignation, wailing, and anguish, and gnashing of teeth
upon their heads, unto the third and fourth
generation, so long as they repent not, and hate me,
saith the Lord your God
53 And this I make an example unto you, for your
consolation concerning all those who have been
commanded to do a work and have been hindered by the
hands of their enemies, and by oppression, saith
the Lord your God
54 For I am the Lord your God, and will save all
those of your brethren who have been pure in heart,
and have been slain in the land of Missouri,
saith the Lord
55 And again, verily I say unto you, I command you
again to build a house to my name, even in this
place, that you may prove yourselves unto me that
ye are faithful in all things whatsoever I command
you, that I may bless you, and crown you with
honor, immortality, and eternal life
56 And now I say unto you, as pertaining to my
boarding house which I have commanded you to build
for the boarding of strangers, let it be built unto
my name, and let my name be named upon it, and let
my servant Joseph and his house have place
therein, from generation to generation
57 For this anointing have I put upon his head,
that his blessing shall also be put upon the head of
his posterity after him
58 And as I said unto Abraham concerning the
kindreds of the earth, even so I say unto my servant
Joseph: In thee and in thy seed shall the kindred of
the earth be blessed
59 Therefore, let my servant Joseph and his seed
after him have place in that house, from generation
to generation, forever and ever, saith the Lord
60 And let the name of that house be called Nauvoo
House; and let it be a delightful habitation for
man, and a resting-place for the weary traveler,
that he may contemplate the glory of Zion, and the
glory of this, the cornerstone thereof
61 That he may receive also the counsel from those
whom I have set to be as plants of renown, and as
watchmen upon her walls
62 Behold, verily I say unto you, let my servant
George Miller, and my servant Lyman Wight, and my
servant John Snider, and my servant Peter Haws,
organize themselves, and appoint one of them to be a
president over their quorum for the purpose of
building that house
63 And they shall form a constitution, whereby
they may receive stock for the building of that
house
64 And they shall not receive less than fifty
dollars for a share of stock in that house, and they
shall be permitted to receive fifteen thousand
dollars from any one man for stock in that house
65 But they shall not be permitted to receive over
fifteen thousand dollars stock from any one man
66 And they shall not be permitted to receive
under fifty dollars for a share of stock from any one
man in that house
67 And they shall not be permitted to receive any
man, as a stockholder in this house, except the
same shall pay his stock into their hands at the
time he receives stock
68 And in proportion to the amount of stock he
pays into their hands he shall receive stock in that
house; but if he pays nothing into their hands he
shall not receive any stock in that house
69 And if any pay stock into their hands it shall
be for stock in that house, for himself, and for
his generation after him, from generation to
generation, so long as he and his heirs shall hold that
stock, and do not sell or convey the stock away
out of their hands by their own free will and act,
if you will do my will, saith the Lord your God
70 And again, verily I say unto you, if my servant
George Miller, and my servant Lyman Wight, and my
servant John Snider, and my servant Peter Haws,
receive any stock into their hands, in moneys, or
in properties wherein they receive the real value
of moneys, they shall not appropriate any portion
of that stock to any other purpose, only in that
house
71 And if they do appropriate any portion of that
stock anywhere else, only in that house, without
the consent of the stockholder, and do not repay
four-fold for the stock which they appropriate
anywhere else, only in that house, they shall be
accursed, and shall be moved out of their place, saith
the Lord God; for I, the Lord, am God, and cannot
be mocked in any of these things
72 Verily I say unto you, let my servant Joseph
pay stock into their hands for the building of that
house, as seemeth him good; but my servant Joseph
cannot pay over fifteen thousand dollars stock in
that house, nor under fifty dollars; neither can
any other man, saith the Lord
73 And there are others also who wish to know my
will concerning them, for they have asked it at my
hands
74 Therefore, I say unto you concerning my servant
Vinson Knight, if he will do my will let him put
stock into that house for himself, and for his
generation after him, from generation to generation
75 And let him lift up his voice long and loud, in
the midst of the people, to plead the cause of
the poor and the needy; and let him not fail,
neither let his heart faint; and I will accept of his
offerings, for they shall not be unto me as the
offerings of Cain, for he shall be mine, saith the
Lord
76 Let his family rejoice and turn away their
hearts from affliction; for I have chosen him and
anointed him, and he shall be honored in the midst of
his house, for I will forgive all his sins, saith
the Lord. Amen
77 Verily I say unto you, let my servant Hyrum put
stock into that house as seemeth him good, for
himself and his generation after him, from
generation to generation
78 Let my servant Isaac Galland put stock into
that house; for I, the Lord, love him for the work he
hath done, and will forgive all his sins;
therefore, let him be remembered for an interest in that
house from generation to generation
79 Let my servant Isaac Galland be appointed among
you, and be ordained by my servant William Marks,
and be blessed of him, to go with my servant
Hyrum to accomplish the work that my servant Joseph
shall point out to them, and they shall be greatly
blessed
80 Let my servant William Marks pay stock into
that house, as seemeth him good, for himself and his
generation, from generation to generation
81 Let my servant Henry G. Sherwood pay stock into
that house, as seemeth him good, for himself and
his seed after him, from generation to generation
82 Let my servant William Law pay stock into that
house, for himself and his seed after him, from
generation to generation
83 If he will do my will let him not take his
family unto the eastern lands, even unto Kirtland;
nevertheless, I, the Lord, will build up Kirtland,
but I, the Lord, have a scourge prepared for the
inhabitants thereof
84 And with my servant Almon Babbitt, there are
many things with which I am not pleased; behold, he
aspireth to establish his counsel instead of the
counsel which I have ordained, even that of the
Presidency of my Church; and he setteth up a golden
calf for the worship of my people
85 Let no man go from this place who has come here
essaying to keep my commandments
86 If they live here let them live unto me; and if
they die let them die unto me; for they shall
rest from all their labors here, and shall continue
their works
87 Therefore, let my servant William put his trust
in me, and cease to fear concerning his family,
because of the sickness of the land. If ye love me,
keep my commandments; and the sickness of the
land shall redound to your glory
88 Let my servant William go and proclaim my
everlasting gospel with a loud voice, and with great
joy, as he shall be moved upon by my Spirit, unto
the inhabitants of Warsaw, and also unto the
inhabitants of Carthage, and also unto the inhabitants of
Burlington, and also unto the inhabitants of
Madison, and await patiently and diligently for
further instructions at my general conference, saith the
Lord
89 If he will do my will let him from henceforth
hearken to the counsel of my servant Joseph, and
with his interest support the cause of the poor, and
publish the new translation of my holy word unto
the inhabitants of the earth
90 And if he will do this I will bless him with a
multiplicity of blessings, that he shall not be
forsaken, nor his seed be found begging bread
91 And again, verily I say unto you, let my
servant William be appointed, ordained, and anointed, as
counselor unto my servant Joseph, in the room of
my servant Hyrum, that my servant Hyrum may take
the office of Priesthood and Patriarch, which was
appointed unto him by his father, by blessing and
also by right
92 That from henceforth he shall hold the keys of
the patriarchal blessings upon the heads of all my
people
93 That whoever he blesses shall be blessed, and
whoever he curses shall be cursed; that whatsoever
he shall bind on earth shall be bound in heaven;
and whatsoever he shall loose on earth shall be
loosed in heaven
94 And from this time forth I appoint unto him
that he may be a prophet, and a seer, and a revelator
unto my church, as well as my servant Joseph
95 That he may act in concert also with my servant
Joseph; and that he shall receive counsel from my
servant Joseph, who shall show unto him the keys
whereby he may ask and receive, and be crowned
with the same blessing, and glory, and honor, and
priesthood, and gifts of the priesthood, that once
were put upon him that was my servant Oliver
Cowdery
96 That my servant Hyrum may bear record of the
things which I shall show unto him, that his name
may be had in honorable remembrance from generation
to generation, forever and ever
97 Let my servant William Law also receive the
keys by which he may ask and receive blessings; let
him be humble before me, and be without guile, and
he shall receive of my Spirit, even the Comforter,
which shall manifest unto him the truth of all
things, and shall give him, in the very hour, what
he shall say
98 And these signs shall follow him—he shall heal
the sick, he shall cast out devils, and shall be
delivered from those who would administer unto him
deadly poison
99 And he shall be led in paths where the
poisonous serpent cannot lay hold upon his heel, and he
shall mount up in the imagination of his thoughts as
upon eagles’ wings
100 And what if I will that he should raise the
dead, let him not withhold his voice
101 Therefore, let my servant William cry aloud
and spare not, with joy and rejoicing, and with
hosannas to him that sitteth upon the throne forever
and ever, saith the Lord your God
102 Behold, I say unto you, I have a mission in
store for my servant William, and my servant Hyrum,
and for them alone; and let my servant Joseph
tarry at home, for he is needed. The remainder I will
show unto you hereafter. Even so. Amen
103 And again, verily I say unto you, if my
servant Sidney will serve me and be counselor unto my
servant Joseph, let him arise and come up and stand
in the office of his calling, and humble himself
before me
104 And if he will offer unto me an acceptable
offering, and acknowledgments, and remain with my
people, behold, I, the Lord your God, will heal him
that he shall be healed; and he shall lift up his
voice again on the mountains, and be a spokesman
before my face
105 Let him come and locate his family in the
neighborhood in which my servant Joseph resides
106 And in all his journeyings let him lift up his
voice as with the sound of a trump, and warn the
inhabitants of the earth to flee the wrath to
come
107 Let him assist my servant Joseph, and also let
my servant William Law assist my servant Joseph,
in making a solemn proclamation unto the kings of
the earth, even as I have before said unto you
108 If my servant Sidney will do my will, let him
not remove his family unto the eastern lands, but
let him change their habitation, even as I have
said
109 Behold, it is not my will that he shall seek
to find safety and refuge out of the city which I
have appointed unto you, even the city of Nauvoo
110 Verily I say unto you, even now, if he will
hearken unto my voice, it shall be well with him.
Even so. Amen
111 And again, verily I say unto you, let my
servant Amos Davies pay stock into the hands of those
whom I have appointed to build a house for
boarding, even the Nauvoo House
112 This let him do if he will have an interest;
and let him hearken unto the counsel of my servant
Joseph, and labor with his own hands that he may
obtain the confidence of men
113 And when he shall prove himself faithful in
all things that shall be entrusted unto his care,
yea, even a few things, he shall be made ruler over
many
114 Let him therefore abase himself that he may be
exalted. Even so. Amen
115 And again, verily I say unto you, if my
servant Robert D. Foster will obey my voice, let him
build a house for my servant Joseph, according to the
contract which he has made with him, as the door
shall be open to him from time to time
116 And let him repent of all his folly, and
clothe himself with charity; and cease to do evil, and
lay aside all his hard speeches
117 And pay stock also into the hands of the
quorum of the Nauvoo House, for himself and for his
generation after him, from generation to generation
118 And hearken unto the counsel of my servants
Joseph, and Hyrum, and William Law, and unto the
authorities which I have called to lay the foundation
of Zion; and it shall be well with him forever
and ever. Even so. Amen
119 And again, verily I say unto you, let no man
pay stock to the quorum of the Nauvoo House unless
he shall be a believer in the Book of Mormon, and
the revelations I have given unto you, saith the
Lord your God
120 For that which is more or less than this
cometh of evil, and shall be attended with cursings and
not blessings, saith the Lord your God. Even so.
Amen
121 And again, verily I say unto you, let the
quorum of the Nauvoo House have a just recompense of
wages for all their labors which they do in
building the Nauvoo House; and let their wages be as
shall be agreed among themselves, as pertaining to the
price thereof
122 And let every man who pays stock bear his
proportion of their wages, if it must needs be, for
their support, saith the Lord; otherwise, their
labors shall be accounted unto them for stock in that
house. Even so. Amen
123 Verily I say unto you, I now give unto you the
officers belonging to my Priesthood, that ye may
hold the keys thereof, even the Priesthood which
is after the order of Melchizedek, which is after
the order of mine Only Begotten Son
124 First, I give unto you Hyrum Smith to be a
patriarch unto you, to hold the sealing blessings of
my church, even the Holy Spirit of promise,
whereby ye are sealed up unto the day of redemption,
that ye may not fall notwithstanding the hour of
temptation that may come upon you
125 I give unto you my servant Joseph to be a
presiding elder over all my church, to be a
translator, a revelator, a seer, and prophet
126 I give unto him for counselors my servant
Sidney Rigdon and my servant William Law, that these
may constitute a quorum and First Presidency, to
receive the oracles for the whole church
127 I give unto you my servant Brigham Young to be
a president over the Twelve traveling council
128 Which Twelve hold the keys to open up the
authority of my kingdom upon the four corners of the
earth, and after that to send my word to every
creature
129 They are Heber C. Kimball, Parley P. Pratt,
Orson Pratt, Orson Hyde, William Smith, John Taylor,
John E. Page, Wilford Woodruff, Willard Richards,
George A. Smith
130 David Patten I have taken unto myself; behold,
his priesthood no man taketh from him; but,
verily I say unto you, another may be appointed unto
the same calling
131 And again, I say unto you, I give unto you a
high council, for the cornerstone of Zion
132 Namely, Samuel Bent, Henry G. Sherwood,
George W. Harris, Charles C. Rich, Thomas Grover, Newel
Knight, David Dort, Dunbar Wilson—Seymour Brunson
I have taken unto myself; no man taketh his
priesthood, but another may be appointed unto the same
priesthood in his stead; and verily I say unto you,
let my servant Aaron Johnson be ordained unto
this calling in his stead—David Fullmer, Alpheus
Cutler, William Huntington
133 And again, I give unto you Don C. Smith to be
a president over a quorum of high priests
134 Which ordinance is instituted for the purpose
of qualifying those who shall be appointed
standing presidents or servants over different stakes
scattered abroad
135 And they may travel also if they choose, but
rather be ordained for standing presidents; this is
the office of their calling, saith the Lord your
God
136 I give unto him Amasa Lyman and Noah Packard
for counselors, that they may preside over the
quorum of high priests of my church, saith the Lord
137 And again, I say unto you, I give unto you
John A. Hicks, Samuel Williams, and Jesse Baker,
which priesthood is to preside over the quorum of
elders, which quorum is instituted for standing
ministers; nevertheless they may travel, yet they are
ordained to be standing ministers to my church,
saith the Lord
138 And again, I give unto you Joseph Young,
Josiah Butterfield, Daniel Miles, Henry Herriman, Zera
Pulsipher, Levi Hancock, James Foster, to preside
over the quorum of seventies
139 Which quorum is instituted for traveling
elders to bear record of my name in all the world,
wherever the traveling high council, mine apostles,
shall send them to prepare a way before my face
140 The difference between this quorum and the
quorum of elders is that one is to travel
continually, and the other is to preside over the churches
from time to time; the one has the responsibility of
presiding from time to time, and the other has no
responsibility of presiding, saith the Lord your
God
141 And again, I say unto you, I give unto you
Vinson Knight, Samuel H. Smith, and Shadrach Roundy,
if he will receive it, to preside over the
bishopric; a knowledge of said bishopric is given unto
you in the book of Doctrine and Covenants
142 And again, I say unto you, Samuel Rolfe and
his counselors for priests, and the president of the
teachers and his counselors, and also the
president of the deacons and his counselors, and also the
president of the stake and his counselors
143 The above offices I have given unto you, and
the keys thereof, for helps and for governments,
for the work of the ministry and the perfecting of
my saints
144 And a commandment I give unto you, that you
should fill all these offices and approve of those
names which I have mentioned, or else disapprove of
them at my general conference
145 And that ye should prepare rooms for all these
offices in my house when you build it unto my
name, saith the Lord your God. Even so. Amen.