Section 22 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Manchester, New York, April 16,
1830. This revelation was given to the Church
in consequence of some who had previously been
baptized desiring to unite with the Church without
rebaptism.
1, Baptism is a new and everlasting
covenant;
2–4, Authoritative baptism is required.
1 Behold, I say unto you that all old
covenants have I caused to be done away in this
thing; and this is a new and an everlasting
covenant, even that which was from the beginning.
2 Wherefore, although a man should
be baptized an hundred times it
availeth him nothing, for you cannot
enter in at the strait gate by the law
of Moses, neither by your dead works.
3 For it is because of your dead
works that I have caused this last
covenant and this church to be built
up unto me, even as in days of old.
4 Wherefore, enter ye in at the
gate, as I have commanded, and
seek not to counsel your God. Amen.