Section 54 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Newel Knight, at Kirtland, Ohio,
June 10, 1831. Members of the Church living in
Thompson, Ohio, were divided on questions having to do
with the consecration of properties. Selfishness
and greed were manifest. Following his mission to
the Shakers (see the
heading to section 49), Leman
Copley had broken his covenant to consecrate his
large farm as a place of inheritance for the Saints
arriving from Colesville, New York. As a
consequence, Newel Knight (leader of the members living in
Thompson) and other elders had come to the
Prophet asking how to proceed. The Prophet inquired of
the Lord and received this revelation, which
commands the members in Thompson to leave Leman Copley’s
farm and journey to Missouri.
1–6, The Saints
must keep the gospel covenant to gain mercy;
7–10,
They must be patient in tribulation.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord, even Alpha and
Omega, the beginning and the end, even he who was
crucified for the sins of the world
2 Behold, verily, verily, I say unto you, my
servant Newel Knight, you shall stand fast in the
office whereunto I have appointed you
3 And if your brethren desire to escape their
enemies, let them repent of all their sins, and become
truly humble before me and contrite
4 And as the covenant which they made unto me has
been broken, even so it has become void and of
none effect
5 And wo to him by whom this offense cometh, for
it had been better for him that he had been drowned
in the depth of the sea
6 But blessed are they who have kept the covenant
and observed the commandment, for they shall
obtain mercy
7 Wherefore, go to now and flee the land, lest
your enemies come upon you; and take your journey,
and appoint whom you will to be your leader, and to
pay moneys for you
8 And thus you shall take your journey into the
regions westward, unto the land of Missouri, unto
the borders of the Lamanites
9 And after you have done journeying, behold, I
say unto you, seek ye a living like unto men, until
I prepare a place for you
10 And again, be patient in tribulation until I
come; and, behold, I come quickly, and my reward is
with me, and they who have sought me early shall
find rest to their souls. Even so. Amen.