Section 117 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Far West, Missouri, July 8,
1838, concerning the immediate duties of William
Marks, Newel K. Whitney, and Oliver Granger.
1–9, The Lord’s servants should not covet temporal
things, for “what is property unto the Lord?”;
10–16, They are to forsake littleness of soul,
and their sacrifices will be sacred unto the Lord.
1 Verily thus saith the Lord unto my
servant William Marks, and also unto my
servant Newel K. Whitney, let them settle
up their business speedily and journey
from the land of Kirtland, before I, the
Lord, send again the snows upon the earth.
2 Let them awake, and arise,
and come forth, and not
tarry, for I, the Lord, command it.
3 Therefore, if they tarry it
shall not be well with them.
4 Let them repent of all
their sins, and of all their
covetous desires, before me,
saith the Lord; for what is
property unto me? saith the Lord.
5 Let the properties of
Kirtland be turned out
for debts, saith the
Lord. Let them go, saith the
Lord, and whatsoever
remaineth, let it remain
in your hands, saith the Lord.
6 For have I not the
fowls of heaven, and
also the fish of the
sea, and the beasts of
the mountains? Have I
not made the earth? Do I
not hold the
destinies of all the armies of
the nations of the earth?
7 Therefore, will I
not make solitary
places to bud and
to blossom, and to
bring forth in
abundance? saith the Lord.
8 Is there not
room enough on the
mountains of
Adam-ondi-Ahman, and on
the plains of Olaha
Shinehah, or the
land where Adam
dwelt, that you
should covet that
which is but the drop,
and neglect the
more weighty matters?
9 Therefore,
come up hither unto
the land of my
people, even Zion.
10 Let my
servant William
Marks be faithful
over a few
things, and he shall
be a ruler
over many. Let him
preside in the
midst of my
people in the
city of Far West,
and let him be
blessed with
the blessings of my people.
11 Let my
servant Newel K.
Whitney be
ashamed of the
Nicolaitane band
and of all
their secret
abominations, and
of all his
littleness of
soul before me,
saith the Lord,
and come up
to the land of
Adam-ondi-Ahman, and be a
bishop unto my
people, saith
the Lord, not
in name but in
deed, saith the Lord.
12 And again,
I say unto
you, I
remember my servant
Oliver
Granger; behold,
verily I say
unto him that
his name shall
be had in
sacred
remembrance from
generation to
generation,
forever and ever,
saith the Lord.
Therefore, let him
contend
earnestly for the
redemption
of the First
Presidency
of my Church,
saith the
Lord; and
when he falls
he shall rise
again, for
his
sacrifice shall be
more sacred
unto me than
his increase, saith the Lord.
Therefore, let him
come up
hither
speedily, unto the
land of
Zion; and in
the due
time he shall
be made a
merchant
unto my name,
saith the
Lord, for
the benefit of my people.
Therefore let no
man despise
my servant
Oliver
Granger, but let
the
blessings of my
people be on
him
forever and ever.
16 And
again, verily
I say
unto you, let
all my
servants in
the land
of Kirtland
remember
the Lord
their God,
and mine
house also,
to keep
and
preserve it holy,
and to
overthrow
the
moneychangers in
mine own
due time,
saith the Lord. Even so. Amen.