Section 99 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to John Murdock, August 29, 1832, at
Hiram, Ohio. For over a year, John Murdock had been
preaching the gospel while his children—motherless
after the death of his wife, Julia Clapp, in
April 1831—resided with other families in Ohio.
1–8,
John Murdock is called to proclaim the gospel, and
those who receive him receive the Lord and will
obtain mercy.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto my servant John
Murdock—thou art called to go into the eastern
countries from house to house, from village to
village, and from city to city, to proclaim mine
everlasting gospel unto the inhabitants thereof, in the
midst of persecution and wickedness
2 And who receiveth you receiveth me; and you
shall have power to declare my word in the
demonstration of my Holy Spirit
3 And who receiveth you as a little child,
receiveth my kingdom; and blessed are they, for they
shall obtain mercy
4 And whoso rejecteth you shall be rejected of my
Father and his house; and you shall cleanse your
feet in the secret places by the way for a
testimony against them
5 And behold, and lo, I come quickly to judgment,
to convince all of their ungodly deeds which they
have committed against me, as it is written of me
in the volume of the book
6 And now, verily I say unto you, that it is not
expedient that you should go until your children
are provided for, and sent up kindly unto the bishop
of Zion
7 And after a few years, if thou desirest of me,
thou mayest go up also unto the goodly land, to
possess thine inheritance
8 Otherwise thou shalt continue proclaiming my
gospel until thou be taken. Amen.