Section 87 Revelation and prophecy on war, given
through Joseph Smith the Prophet, at or near
Kirtland, Ohio, December 25, 1832. At this time disputes
in the United States over slavery and South
Carolina’s nullification of federal tariffs were
prevalent. Joseph Smith’s history states that
“appearances of troubles among the nations” were becoming
“more visible” to the Prophet “than they had
previously been since the Church began her journey out of
the wilderness.”
1–4, War is foretold between
the Northern States and the Southern States;
5–8,
Great calamities will fall upon all the inhabitants
of the earth.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord concerning the wars
that will shortly come to pass, beginning at the
rebellion of South Carolina, which will eventually
terminate in the death and misery of many souls
2 And the time will come that war will be poured
out upon all nations, beginning at this place
3 For behold, the Southern States shall be divided
against the Northern States, and the Southern
States will call on other nations, even the nation of
Great Britain, as it is called, and they shall
also call upon other nations, in order to defend
themselves against other nations; and then war shall
be poured out upon all nations
4 And it shall come to pass, after many days,
slaves shall rise up against their masters, who shall
be marshaled and disciplined for war
5 And it shall come to pass also that the remnants
who are left of the land will marshal themselves,
and shall become exceedingly angry, and shall vex
the Gentiles with a sore vexation
6 And thus, with the sword and by bloodshed the
inhabitants of the earth shall mourn; and with
famine, and plague, and earthquake, and the thunder of
heaven, and the fierce and vivid lightning also,
shall the inhabitants of the earth be made to feel
the wrath, and indignation, and chastening hand of
an Almighty God, until the consumption decreed
hath made a full end of all nations
7 That the cry of the saints, and of the blood of
the saints, shall cease to come up into the ears
of the Lord of Sabaoth, from the earth, to be
avenged of their enemies
8 Wherefore, stand ye in holy places, and be not
moved, until the day of the Lord come; for behold,
it cometh quickly, saith the Lord. Amen.