Section 40 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at Fayette, New York,
January 6, 1831. Preceding the record of this
revelation, the Prophet’s history states, “As James
[Covel] rejected the word of the Lord, and
returned to his former principles and people, the Lord
gave unto me and Sidney Rigdon the following
revelation” (see
section 39).
1–3, Fear of
persecution and cares of the world cause rejection of the gospel.
1 Behold, verily I say unto you, that
the heart of my servant James Covel
was right before me, for he
covenanted with me that he would obey my word.
2 And he received the word with
gladness, but straightway Satan
tempted him; and the fear of
persecution and the cares of the
world caused him to reject the word.
3 Wherefore he broke my
covenant, and it remaineth
with me to do with him
as seemeth me good. Amen.