Section 73 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at Hiram, Ohio, January
10, 1832. Since the early part of the preceding
December, the Prophet and Sidney had been engaged in
preaching, and by this means much was accomplished
in diminishing the unfavorable feelings that had
arisen against the Church (see the
heading to
section 71).
1–2, Elders are to continue to preach;
3–6, Joseph Smith and Sidney Rigdon are to
continue to translate the Bible until it is finished.
1 For verily, thus saith the Lord, it is expedient
in me that they should continue preaching the
gospel, and in exhortation to the churches in the
regions round about, until conference
2 And then, behold, it shall be made known unto
them, by the voice of the conference, their several
missions
3 Now, verily I say unto you my servants, Joseph
Smith, Jun., and Sidney Rigdon, saith the Lord, it
is expedient to translate again
4 And, inasmuch as it is practicable, to preach in
the regions round about until conference; and
after that it is expedient to continue the work of
translation until it be finished
5 And let this be a pattern unto the elders until
further knowledge, even as it is written
6 Now I give no more unto you at this time. Gird
up your loins and be sober. Even so. Amen.