Verses 30 through 32, having to do with the
Council of the Twelve Apostles, were added in 1835
under Joseph Smith’s direction when this section was
prepared for publication in the Doctrine and
Covenants.
1–8, A high council is appointed to
settle important difficulties that arise in the
Church;
9–18, Procedures are given for hearing cases;
19–23, The president of the council renders the
decision;
24–34, Appellate procedure is set forth.
1 This day a general council of twenty-four
high priests assembled at the house of Joseph
Smith, Jun., by revelation, and proceeded to
organize the high council of the church of Christ,
which was to consist of twelve high priests, and
one or three presidents as the case might require.
2 The high council was appointed by revelation
for the purpose of settling important
difficulties which might arise in the church, which
could not be settled by the church or the
bishop’s council to the satisfaction of the parties.
3 Joseph Smith, Jun., Sidney Rigdon and
Frederick G. Williams were acknowledged presidents
by the voice of the council; and Joseph
Smith, Sen., John Smith, Joseph Coe, John
Johnson, Martin Harris, John S. Carter, Jared
Carter, Oliver Cowdery, Samuel H. Smith, Orson
Hyde, Sylvester Smith, and Luke Johnson, high
priests, were chosen to be a standing council
for the church, by the unanimous voice of the council.
4 The above-named councilors were then
asked whether they accepted their appointments,
and whether they would act in that office
according to the law of heaven, to which
they all answered that they accepted their
appointments, and would fill their offices
according to the grace of God bestowed upon them.
5 The number composing the council,
who voted in the name and for the
church in appointing the above-named
councilors were forty-three, as
follows: nine high priests, seventeen
elders, four priests, and thirteen members.
6 Voted: that the high council
cannot have power to act
without seven of the above-named
councilors, or their regularly
appointed successors are present.
7 These seven shall have
power to appoint other high
priests, whom they may consider
worthy and capable to act in
the place of absent councilors.
8 Voted: that whenever any
vacancy shall occur by the
death, removal from office
for transgression, or
removal from the bounds of this
church government, of any
one of the above-named
councilors, it shall be filled
by the nomination of the
president or presidents, and
sanctioned by the voice of a
general council of high
priests, convened for that
purpose, to act in the name of the church.
9 The president of the
church, who is also the
president of the
council, is appointed by
revelation, and
acknowledged in his
administration by the voice of the church.
10 And it is
according to the dignity of
his office that he
should preside over the
council of the
church; and it is his
privilege to be assisted
by two other
presidents, appointed after
the same manner that he
himself was appointed.
11 And in case of
the absence of one or
both of those who
are appointed to
assist him, he has power
to preside over the
council without an
assistant; and in
case he himself is
absent, the other
presidents have power to
preside in his stead,
both or either of them.
12 Whenever a high
council of the
church of Christ is
regularly organized,
according to the
foregoing pattern, it
shall be the duty
of the twelve
councilors to cast lots
by numbers, and
thereby ascertain who
of the twelve shall
speak first,
commencing with number
one and so in
succession to number twelve.
13 Whenever this
council convenes
to act upon any
case, the twelve
councilors shall
consider whether
it is a difficult
one or not; if it
is not, two only
of the
councilors shall speak
upon it, according
to the form above written.
14 But if it is
thought to be
difficult, four
shall be
appointed; and if more
difficult, six;
but in no case
shall more than six
be appointed to speak.
15 The
accused, in all
cases, has a right
to one-half of
the council,
to prevent
insult or injustice.
16 And the
councilors
appointed to
speak before the
council are
to present the
case, after
the evidence
is examined,
in its true
light before
the council;
and every man
is to speak
according to
equity and justice.
17 Those
councilors who
draw even
numbers, that
is, 2, 4, 6,
8, 10, and
12, are the
individuals
who are to
stand up in
behalf of the
accused,
and prevent
insult and injustice.
18 In all
cases the
accuser and
the accused
shall have
a privilege
of
speaking for
themselves
before the
council, after
the
evidences are heard
and the
councilors
who are
appointed to
speak on the
case have
finished their remarks.
19 After
the
evidences are
heard, the
councilors,
accuser
and accused
have
spoken, the
president
shall give a
decision
according
to the
understanding
which he
shall have
of the
case, and
call upon the
twelve
councilors
to sanction
the same by their vote.
20 But
should the
remaining
councilors, who
have not
spoken, or
any one
of them,
after
hearing the
evidences
and
pleadings
impartially,
discover
an error
in the
decision
of the
president,
they can
manifest
it, and
the case shall have a re-hearing.
21 And
if, after a
careful
re-hearing, any
additional
light is
shown
upon the
case, the
decision
shall be
altered
accordingly.
22 But
in case
no
additional
light is
given, the
first
decision
shall
stand, the
majority of the
council
having
power to
determine the same.
23 In
case of
difficulty
respecting
doctrine or
principle, if
there is
not a
sufficiency
written
to make
the
case clear
to the
minds
of the
council, the
president may
inquire
and
obtain the
mind of the Lord by revelation.
24 The
high
priests,
when
abroad,
have
power to
call
and
organize
a
council
after
the
manner of
foregoing, to
settle
difficulties,
when the
parties or
either of them shall request it.
And the
said
council
of
high
priests
shall
have
power to
appoint
one of
their
own
number to
preside
over
such
council for the time being.
It
shall
be
the
duty
of
said
council
to
transmit,
immediately, a
copy
of
their
proceedings,
with
a
full
statement
of
the
testimony
accompanying
their
decision,
to
the
high
council
of the seat of the First Presidency of the Church.
Should
the
parties or
either
of
them
be
dissatisfied
with
the
decision of
said
council,
they
may
appeal
to
the
high
council
of
the
seat
of
the
First
Presidency
of
the
Church,
and
have a
re-hearing,
which
case
shall
there
be
conducted,
according
to
the
former
pattern
written,
as
though
no
such
decision
had
been
made.
This
council
of
high
priests
abroad
is
only
to
be
called
on
the
most
difficult
cases
of
church
matters;
and
no
common
or
ordinary
case is to be sufficient to call such council.
The
traveling
or
located
high
priests
abroad
have
power
to
say
whether
it
is
necessary
to
call
such
a
council
or
not.
There
is
a
distinction
between
the
high
council
or
traveling
high
priests
abroad,
and
the
traveling
high
council
composed
of
the
twelve
apostles,
in
their
decisions.
From
the
decision
of
the
former
there
can
be
an
appeal;
but
from
the
decision
of
the
latter
there
cannot.
The
latter
can
only
be
called
in
question
by
the
general
authorities
of
the
church
in
case
of
transgression.
Resolved:
that
the
president
or
presidents
of
the
seat
of
the
First
Presidency
of
the
Church
shall
have
power
to
determine
whether
any
such
case,
as
may
be
appealed,
is
justly
entitled to a re-hearing, after examining the appeal and the evidences and statements accompanying it.
34 The twelve councilors then proceeded to cast lots or ballot, to ascertain who should speak first, and the following was the result, namely: 1, Oliver Cowdery; 2, Joseph Coe; 3, Samuel H. Smith; 4, Luke Johnson; 5, John S. Carter; 6, Sylvester Smith; 7, John Johnson; 8, Orson Hyde; 9, Jared Carter; 10, Joseph Smith, Sen.; 11, John Smith; 12, Martin Harris.After prayer the conference adjourned.Oliver Cowdery,Orson Hyde,Clerks
The
twelve
councilors
then
proceeded
to
cast
lots
or
ballot,
to
ascertain
who
should
speak
first,
and
the
following
was
the
result,
namely:
1,
Oliver
Cowdery;
2,
Joseph
Coe;
3,
Samuel H.
Smith;
4,
Luke
Johnson;
5, John S. Carter; 6, Sylvester Smith; 7, John Johnson; 8, Orson Hyde; 9, Jared Carter; 10, Joseph Smith, Sen.; 11, John Smith; 12, Martin Harris.After prayer the conference adjourned.Oliver Cowdery,Orson Hyde,Clerks
Section 102 Minutes of the organization of the first high council of the Church, at Kirtland, Ohio, February 17, 1834. The original minutes were recorded by Elders Oliver Cowdery and Orson Hyde. The Prophet revised the minutes the following day, and the next day the corrected minutes were unanimously accepted by the high council as “a form and constitution of the high council” of the Church.
Minutes
of
the
organization
of
the
first
high
council
of
the
Church,
at
Kirtland,
Ohio,
February
17,
1834.
The
original
minutes
were
recorded
by
Elders
Oliver
Cowdery
and
Orson
Hyde.
The
Prophet
revised
the
minutes
following
day,
and
the
next
day
the
corrected
minutes
were
unanimously
accepted
by
the
high
council
as
“a
form
and
constitution
of
the
high
council”
of
the
Church.