Section 119 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Far West, Missouri, July 8,
1838, in answer to his supplication: “O Lord! Show
unto thy servants how much thou requirest of
the properties of thy people for a tithing.” The
law of tithing, as understood today, had not been
given to the Church previous to this
revelation. The term tithing in the prayer just quoted and
in previous revelations (
64:23;
85:3;
97:11)
had meant not just one-tenth, but all free-will
offerings, or contributions, to the Church
funds. The Lord had previously given to the Church
the law of consecration and stewardship of
property, which members (chiefly the leading elders)
entered into by a covenant that was to be
everlasting. Because of failure on the part of many to
abide by this covenant, the Lord withdrew it for
a time and gave instead the law of tithing to
the whole Church. The Prophet asked the Lord how
much of their property He required for sacred
purposes. The answer was this revelation.
1–5,
The Saints are to pay their surplus property and
then give, as tithing, one-tenth of their
interest annually;
6–7, Such a course will sanctify the land of Zion.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord, I require
all their surplus property to be put into
the hands of the bishop of my church in Zion,
2 For the building of mine house, and
for the laying of the foundation of
Zion and for the priesthood, and for the
debts of the Presidency of my Church.
3 And this shall be the
beginning of the tithing of my people.
4 And after that, those who
have thus been tithed
shall pay one-tenth of all
their interest annually; and
this shall be a standing law
unto them forever, for my
holy priesthood, saith the Lord.
5 Verily I say unto you,
it shall come to pass
that all those who gather
unto the land of Zion
shall be tithed of their
surplus properties, and
shall observe this law,
or they shall not be
found worthy to abide among you.
6 And I say unto you,
if my people observe not
this law, to keep it
holy, and by this law
sanctify the land of Zion
unto me, that my
statutes and my judgments
may be kept thereon, that
it may be most holy,
behold, verily I say
unto you, it shall not be
a land of Zion unto you.
7 And this shall be
an ensample unto
all the stakes of
Zion. Even so. Amen.