Section 56 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, June 15,
1831. This revelation chastises Ezra Thayre for not
obeying a former revelation (the “commandment”
referred to in
verse 8), which Joseph Smith
had received for him, instructing Thayre
concerning his duties on Frederick G. Williams’ farm,
where he lived. The following revelation also
revokes Thayre’s call to travel to Missouri with
Thomas B. Marsh (see
section 52:22).
1–2,
The Saints must take up their cross and follow
the Lord to gain salvation;
3–13, The Lord
commands and revokes, and the disobedient are cast
off;
14–17, Wo unto the rich who will not help
the poor, and wo unto the poor whose hearts are
not broken;
18–20, Blessed are the poor who
are pure in heart, for they will inherit the earth.
1 Hearken, O ye people who profess my name,
saith the Lord your God; for behold, mine anger
is kindled against the rebellious, and they
shall know mine arm and mine indignation, in the
day of visitation and of wrath upon the nations.
2 And he that will not take up his
cross and follow me, and keep my
commandments, the same shall not be saved.
3 Behold, I, the Lord,
command; and he that will not obey
shall be cut off in mine own due
time, after I have commanded
and the commandment is broken.
4 Wherefore I, the Lord,
command and revoke, as it seemeth
me good; and all this to be
answered upon the heads of
the rebellious, saith the Lord.
5 Wherefore, I revoke the
commandment which was given
unto my servants Thomas B.
Marsh and Ezra Thayre, and
give a new commandment unto
my servant Thomas, that he
shall take up his journey
speedily to the land of
Missouri, and my servant
Selah J. Griffin shall also go with him.
6 For behold, I revoke
the commandment which was
given unto my servants
Selah J. Griffin and Newel
Knight, in consequence of
the stiffneckedness of my
people which are in
Thompson, and their rebellions.
7 Wherefore, let my
servant Newel Knight remain
with them; and as many
as will go may go, that
are contrite before me,
and be led by him to the
land which I have appointed.
8 And again, verily I
say unto you, that my
servant Ezra Thayre must
repent of his pride,
and of his selfishness,
and obey the former
commandment which I have
given him concerning the
place upon which he lives.
9 And if he will do
this, as there shall be
no divisions made upon
the land, he shall be
appointed still to go
to the land of Missouri;
10 Otherwise he shall
receive the money
which he has paid, and
shall leave the
place, and shall be cut
off out of my church,
saith the Lord God of hosts;
11 And though the
heaven and the
earth pass away,
these words shall
not pass away,
but shall be fulfilled.
12 And if my
servant Joseph
Smith, Jun., must
needs pay the
money, behold, I,
the Lord, will pay
it unto him
again in the land
of Missouri, that
those of whom
he shall receive
may be rewarded
again according
to that which they do;
13 For
according to that which
they do they
shall receive,
even in lands
for their inheritance.
14 Behold,
thus saith the
Lord unto my
people—you have
many things to
do and to
repent of; for
behold, your sins
have come up
unto me, and
are not
pardoned, because you
seek to
counsel in your own ways.
15 And your
hearts are
not
satisfied. And ye
obey not the
truth, but
have pleasure
in unrighteousness.
16 Wo unto
you rich
men, that
will not give
your
substance to the
poor, for
your riches
will canker
your
souls; and this
shall be
your
lamentation in the
day of
visitation, and
of
judgment, and of
indignation:
The
harvest is past,
the summer
is ended,
and my soul is not saved!
17 Wo unto
you poor
men, whose
hearts
are not
broken, whose
spirits
are not
contrite, and
whose
bellies are
not
satisfied, and
whose hands
are not
stayed from
laying hold
upon
other men’s
goods, whose
eyes are
full of
greediness,
and who
will not labor with your own hands!
18 But
blessed are
the poor
who are
pure in
heart,
whose hearts
are
broken, and
whose
spirits are
contrite,
for they
shall see
the
kingdom of
God coming
in power
and great
glory
unto their
deliverance; for
the
fatness of the earth shall be theirs.
19 For
behold,
the Lord
shall
come, and
his
recompense
shall be
with
him, and he
shall
reward
every man,
and the
poor shall rejoice;
20 And
their
generations
shall
inherit the
earth
from
generation to
generation,
forever and
ever.
And now
I make
an end
of
speaking
unto you. Even so. Amen.