Section 48 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, March 10, 1831. The
Prophet had inquired of the Lord as to the mode
of procedure in procuring lands for the settlement
of the Saints. This was an important matter in
view of the migration of members of the Church from
the eastern United States, in obedience to the
Lord’s command that they should assemble in Ohio (see
sections 37:1–3;
45:64).
1–3, The Saints in
Ohio are to share their lands with their brethren;
4–6, The Saints are to purchase lands, build a
city, and follow the counsel of their presiding
officers.
1 It is necessary that ye should remain for the
present time in your places of abode, as it shall be
suitable to your circumstances
2 And inasmuch as ye have lands, ye shall impart
to the eastern brethren
3 And inasmuch as ye have not lands, let them buy
for the present time in those regions round about,
as seemeth them good, for it must needs be
necessary that they have places to live for the present
time
4 It must needs be necessary that ye save all the
money that ye can, and that ye obtain all that ye
can in righteousness, that in time ye may be
enabled to purchase land for an inheritance, even the
city
5 The place is not yet to be revealed; but after
your brethren come from the east there are to be
certain men appointed, and to them it shall be given
to know the place, or to them it shall be
revealed
6 And they shall be appointed to purchase the
lands, and to make a commencement to lay the
foundation of the city; and then shall ye begin to be
gathered with your families, every man according to his
family, according to his circumstances, and as is
appointed to him by the presidency and the bishop
of the church, according to the laws and
commandments which ye have received, and which ye shall
hereafter receive. Even so. Amen.