Section 132 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Nauvoo, Illinois, recorded July
12, 1843, relating to the new and everlasting
covenant, including the eternity of the marriage
covenant and the principle of plural marriage. Although
the revelation was recorded in 1843, evidence
indicates that some of the principles involved in this
revelation were known by the Prophet as early as
1831. See
Official Declaration 1.
1–6, Exaltation
is gained through the new and everlasting
covenant;
7–14, The terms and conditions of that
covenant are set forth;
15–20, Celestial marriage and a
continuation of the family unit enable men to
become gods;
21–25, The strait and narrow way leads
to eternal lives;
26–27, The law is given relative
to blasphemy against the Holy Ghost;
28–39,
Promises of eternal increase and exaltation are made
to prophets and Saints in all ages;
40–47, Joseph
Smith is given the power to bind and seal on earth
and in heaven;
48–50, The Lord seals upon him
his exaltation;
51–57, Emma Smith is counseled to
be faithful and true;
58–66, Laws governing plural
marriage are set forth.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you my servant
Joseph, that inasmuch as you have inquired of my
hand to know and understand wherein I, the Lord,
justified my servants Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, as
also Moses, David and Solomon, my servants, as
touching the principle and doctrine of their having
many wives and concubines
2 Behold, and lo, I am the Lord thy God, and will
answer thee as touching this matter
3 Therefore, prepare thy heart to receive and obey
the instructions which I am about to give unto
you; for all those who have this law revealed unto
them must obey the same
4 For behold, I reveal unto you a new and an
everlasting covenant; and if ye abide not that
covenant, then are ye damned; for no one can reject this
covenant and be permitted to enter into my glory
5 For all who will have a blessing at my hands
shall abide the law which was appointed for that
blessing, and the conditions thereof, as were
instituted from before the foundation of the world
6 And as pertaining to the new and everlasting
covenant, it was instituted for the fulness of my
glory; and he that receiveth a fulness thereof must
and shall abide the law, or he shall be damned,
saith the Lord God
7 And verily I say unto you, that the conditions
of this law are these: All covenants, contracts,
bonds, obligations, oaths, vows, performances,
connections, associations, or expectations, that are
not made and entered into and sealed by the Holy
Spirit of promise, of him who is anointed, both as
well for time and for all eternity, and that too
most holy, by revelation and commandment through the
medium of mine anointed, whom I have appointed on
the earth to hold this power (and I have appointed
unto my servant Joseph to hold this power in the
last days, and there is never but one on the earth
at a time on whom this power and the keys of this
priesthood are conferred), are of no efficacy,
virtue, or force in and after the resurrection from
the dead; for all contracts that are not made unto
this end have an end when men are dead
8 Behold, mine house is a house of order, saith
the Lord God, and not a house of confusion
9 Will I accept of an offering, saith the Lord,
that is not made in my name
10 Or will I receive at your hands that which I
have not appointed
11 And will I appoint unto you, saith the Lord,
except it be by law, even as I and my Father
ordained unto you, before the world was
12 I am the Lord thy God; and I give unto you this
commandment—that no man shall come unto the
Father but by me or by my word, which is my law, saith
the Lord
13 And everything that is in the world, whether it
be ordained of men, by thrones, or
principalities, or powers, or things of name, whatsoever they
may be, that are not by me or by my word, saith the
Lord, shall be thrown down, and shall not remain
after men are dead, neither in nor after the
resurrection, saith the Lord your God
14 For whatsoever things remain are by me; and
whatsoever things are not by me shall be shaken and
destroyed
15 Therefore, if a man marry him a wife in the
world, and he marry her not by me nor by my word, and
he covenant with her so long as he is in the
world and she with him, their covenant and marriage
are not of force when they are dead, and when they
are out of the world; therefore, they are not bound
by any law when they are out of the world
16 Therefore, when they are out of the world they
neither marry nor are given in marriage; but are
appointed angels in heaven, which angels are
ministering servants, to minister for those who are
worthy of a far more, and an exceeding, and an eternal
weight of glory
17 For these angels did not abide my law;
therefore, they cannot be enlarged, but remain separately
and singly, without exaltation, in their saved
condition, to all eternity; and from henceforth are
not gods, but are angels of God forever and ever
18 And again, verily I say unto you, if a man
marry a wife, and make a covenant with her for time
and for all eternity, if that covenant is not by me
or by my word, which is my law, and is not sealed
by the Holy Spirit of promise, through him whom I
have anointed and appointed unto this power, then
it is not valid neither of force when they are out
of the world, because they are not joined by me,
saith the Lord, neither by my word; when they are
out of the world it cannot be received there,
because the angels and the gods are appointed there,
by whom they cannot pass; they cannot, therefore,
inherit my glory; for my house is a house of order,
saith the Lord God
19 And again, verily I say unto you, if a man
marry a wife by my word, which is my law, and by the
new and everlasting covenant, and it is sealed unto
them by the Holy Spirit of promise, by him who is
anointed, unto whom I have appointed this power
and the keys of this priesthood; and it shall be
said unto them—Ye shall come forth in the first
resurrection; and if it be after the first
resurrection, in the next resurrection; and shall inherit
thrones, kingdoms, principalities, and powers,
dominions, all heights and depths—then shall it be
written in the Lamb’s Book of Life, that he shall
commit no murder whereby to shed innocent blood, and if
ye abide in my covenant, and commit no murder
whereby to shed innocent blood, it shall be done unto
them in all things whatsoever my servant hath put
upon them, in time, and through all eternity; and
shall be of full force when they are out of the
world; and they shall pass by the angels, and the
gods, which are set there, to their exaltation and
glory in all things, as hath been sealed upon
their heads, which glory shall be a fulness and a
continuation of the seeds forever and ever
20 Then shall they be gods, because they have no
end; therefore shall they be from everlasting to
everlasting, because they continue; then shall they
be above all, because all things are subject unto
them. Then shall they be gods, because they have
all power, and the angels are subject unto them
21 Verily, verily, I say unto you, except ye abide
my law ye cannot attain to this glory
22 For strait is the gate, and narrow the way that
leadeth unto the exaltation and continuation of
the lives, and few there be that find it, because
ye receive me not in the world neither do ye know
me
23 But if ye receive me in the world, then shall
ye know me, and shall receive your exaltation; that
where I am ye shall be also
24 This is eternal lives—to know the only wise and
true God, and Jesus Christ, whom he hath sent. I
am he. Receive ye, therefore, my law
25 Broad is the gate, and wide the way that
leadeth to the deaths; and many there are that go in
thereat, because they receive me not, neither do they
abide in my law
26 Verily, verily, I say unto you, if a man marry
a wife according to my word, and they are sealed
by the Holy Spirit of promise, according to mine
appointment, and he or she shall commit any sin or
transgression of the new and everlasting covenant
whatever, and all manner of blasphemies, and if
they commit no murder wherein they shed innocent
blood, yet they shall come forth in the first
resurrection, and enter into their exaltation; but they
shall be destroyed in the flesh, and shall be
delivered unto the buffetings of Satan unto the day of
redemption, saith the Lord God
27 The blasphemy against the Holy Ghost, which
shall not be forgiven in the world nor out of the
world, is in that ye commit murder wherein ye shed
innocent blood, and assent unto my death, after ye
have received my new and everlasting covenant,
saith the Lord God; and he that abideth not this law
can in nowise enter into my glory, but shall be
damned, saith the Lord
28 I am the Lord thy God, and will give unto thee
the law of my Holy Priesthood, as was ordained by
me and my Father before the world was
29 Abraham received all things, whatsoever he
received, by revelation and commandment, by my word,
saith the Lord, and hath entered into his
exaltation and sitteth upon his throne
30 Abraham received promises concerning his seed,
and of the fruit of his loins—from whose loins ye
are, namely, my servant Joseph—which were to
continue so long as they were in the world; and as
touching Abraham and his seed, out of the world they
should continue; both in the world and out of the
world should they continue as innumerable as the
stars; or, if ye were to count the sand upon the
seashore ye could not number them
31 This promise is yours also, because ye are of
Abraham, and the promise was made unto Abraham; and
by this law is the continuation of the works of
my Father, wherein he glorifieth himself
32 Go ye, therefore, and do the works of Abraham;
enter ye into my law and ye shall be saved
33 But if ye enter not into my law ye cannot
receive the promise of my Father, which he made unto
Abraham
34 God commanded Abraham, and Sarah gave Hagar to
Abraham to wife. And why did she do it? Because
this was the law; and from Hagar sprang many people.
This, therefore, was fulfilling, among other
things, the promises
35 Was Abraham, therefore, under condemnation?
Verily I say unto you, Nay; for I, the Lord,
commanded it
36 Abraham was commanded to offer his son Isaac;
nevertheless, it was written: Thou shalt not kill.
Abraham, however, did not refuse, and it was
accounted unto him for righteousness
37 Abraham received concubines, and they bore him
children; and it was accounted unto him for
righteousness, because they were given unto him, and he
abode in my law; as Isaac also and Jacob did none
other things than that which they were commanded;
and because they did none other things than that
which they were commanded, they have entered into
their exaltation, according to the promises, and
sit upon thrones, and are not angels but are gods
38 David also received many wives and concubines,
and also Solomon and Moses my servants, as also
many others of my servants, from the beginning of
creation until this time; and in nothing did they
sin save in those things which they received not of
me
39 David’s wives and concubines were given unto
him of me, by the hand of Nathan, my servant, and
others of the prophets who had the keys of this
power; and in none of these things did he sin against
me save in the case of Uriah and his wife; and,
therefore he hath fallen from his exaltation, and
received his portion; and he shall not inherit them
out of the world, for I gave them unto another,
saith the Lord
40 I am the Lord thy God, and I gave unto thee, my
servant Joseph, an appointment, and restore all
things. Ask what ye will, and it shall be given
unto you according to my word
41 And as ye have asked concerning adultery,
verily, verily, I say unto you, if a man receiveth a
wife in the new and everlasting covenant, and if she
be with another man, and I have not appointed
unto her by the holy anointing, she hath committed
adultery and shall be destroyed
42 If she be not in the new and everlasting
covenant, and she be with another man, she has committed
adultery
43 And if her husband be with another woman, and
he was under a vow, he hath broken his vow and hath
committed adultery
44 And if she hath not committed adultery, but is
innocent and hath not broken her vow, and she
knoweth it, and I reveal it unto you, my servant
Joseph, then shall you have power, by the power of my
Holy Priesthood, to take her and give her unto him
that hath not committed adultery but hath been
faithful; for he shall be made ruler over many
45 For I have conferred upon you the keys and
power of the priesthood, wherein I restore all things,
and make known unto you all things in due time
46 And verily, verily, I say unto you, that
whatsoever you seal on earth shall be sealed in heaven;
and whatsoever you bind on earth, in my name and
by my word, saith the Lord, it shall be eternally
bound in the heavens; and whosesoever sins you
remit on earth shall be remitted eternally in the
heavens; and whosesoever sins you retain on earth
shall be retained in heaven
47 And again, verily I say, whomsoever you bless I
will bless, and whomsoever you curse I will
curse, saith the Lord; for I, the Lord, am thy God
48 And again, verily I say unto you, my servant
Joseph, that whatsoever you give on earth, and to
whomsoever you give any one on earth, by my word and
according to my law, it shall be visited with
blessings and not cursings, and with my power, saith
the Lord, and shall be without condemnation on
earth and in heaven
49 For I am the Lord thy God, and will be with
thee even unto the end of the world, and through all
eternity; for verily I seal upon you your
exaltation, and prepare a throne for you in the kingdom of
my Father, with Abraham your father
50 Behold, I have seen your sacrifices, and will
forgive all your sins; I have seen your sacrifices
in obedience to that which I have told you. Go,
therefore, and I make a way for your escape, as I
accepted the offering of Abraham of his son Isaac
51 Verily, I say unto you: A commandment I give
unto mine handmaid, Emma Smith, your wife, whom I
have given unto you, that she stay herself and
partake not of that which I commanded you to offer unto
her; for I did it, saith the Lord, to prove you
all, as I did Abraham, and that I might require an
offering at your hand, by covenant and sacrifice
52 And let mine handmaid, Emma Smith, receive all
those that have been given unto my servant Joseph,
and who are virtuous and pure before me; and
those who are not pure, and have said they were pure,
shall be destroyed, saith the Lord God
53 For I am the Lord thy God, and ye shall obey my
voice; and I give unto my servant Joseph that he
shall be made ruler over many things; for he hath
been faithful over a few things, and from
henceforth I will strengthen him
54 And I command mine handmaid, Emma Smith, to
abide and cleave unto my servant Joseph, and to none
else. But if she will not abide this commandment
she shall be destroyed, saith the Lord; for I am
the Lord thy God, and will destroy her if she abide
not in my law
55 But if she will not abide this commandment,
then shall my servant Joseph do all things for her,
even as he hath said; and I will bless him and
multiply him and give unto him an hundred-fold in this
world, of fathers and mothers, brothers and
sisters, houses and lands, wives and children, and
crowns of eternal lives in the eternal worlds
56 And again, verily I say, let mine handmaid
forgive my servant Joseph his trespasses; and then
shall she be forgiven her trespasses, wherein she has
trespassed against me; and I, the Lord thy God,
will bless her, and multiply her, and make her
heart to rejoice
57 And again, I say, let not my servant Joseph put
his property out of his hands, lest an enemy come
and destroy him; for Satan seeketh to destroy;
for I am the Lord thy God, and he is my servant; and
behold, and lo, I am with him, as I was with
Abraham, thy father, even unto his exaltation and
glory
58 Now, as touching the law of the priesthood,
there are many things pertaining thereunto
59 Verily, if a man be called of my Father, as was
Aaron, by mine own voice, and by the voice of him
that sent me, and I have endowed him with the
keys of the power of this priesthood, if he do
anything in my name, and according to my law and by my
word, he will not commit sin, and I will justify
him
60 Let no one, therefore, set on my servant
Joseph; for I will justify him; for he shall do the
sacrifice which I require at his hands for his
transgressions, saith the Lord your God
61 And again, as pertaining to the law of the
priesthood—if any man espouse a virgin, and desire to
espouse another, and the first give her consent,
and if he espouse the second, and they are virgins,
and have vowed to no other man, then is he
justified; he cannot commit adultery for they are given
unto him; for he cannot commit adultery with that
that belongeth unto him and to no one else
62 And if he have ten virgins given unto him by
this law, he cannot commit adultery, for they belong
to him, and they are given unto him; therefore is
he justified
63 But if one or either of the ten virgins, after
she is espoused, shall be with another man, she
has committed adultery, and shall be destroyed; for
they are given unto him to multiply and replenish
the earth, according to my commandment, and to
fulfil the promise which was given by my Father
before the foundation of the world, and for their
exaltation in the eternal worlds, that they may bear
the souls of men; for herein is the work of my
Father continued, that he may be glorified
64 And again, verily, verily, I say unto you, if
any man have a wife, who holds the keys of this
power, and he teaches unto her the law of my
priesthood, as pertaining to these things, then shall she
believe and administer unto him, or she shall be
destroyed, saith the Lord your God; for I will
destroy her; for I will magnify my name upon all those
who receive and abide in my law
65 Therefore, it shall be lawful in me, if she
receive not this law, for him to receive all things
whatsoever I, the Lord his God, will give unto him,
because she did not believe and administer unto
him according to my word; and she then becomes the
transgressor; and he is exempt from the law of
Sarah, who administered unto Abraham according to the
law when I commanded Abraham to take Hagar to
wife
66 And now, as pertaining to this law, verily,
verily, I say unto you, I will reveal more unto you,
hereafter; therefore, let this suffice for the
present. Behold, I am Alpha and Omega. Amen.