Words of Mormon 1:3–7).
1–26, Satan stirs up wicked men
to oppose the Lord’s work;
27–33, He seeks to destroy
the souls of men;
34–52, The gospel is to go
to the Lamanites and all nations through the Book of
Mormon;
53–63, The Lord will establish His Church and His
gospel among men;
64–70, He will gather the repentant into
His Church and will save the obedient.
1 Now, behold, I say unto you, that because you
delivered up those writings which you had power given unto
you to translate by the means of the Urim and
Thummim, into the hands of a wicked man, you have
lost them.
2 And you also lost your gift at the same
time, and your mind became darkened.
3 Nevertheless, it is now restored unto you again; therefore
see that you are faithful and continue on unto the
finishing of the remainder of the work of translation as
you have begun.
4 Do not run faster or labor more than you
have strength and means provided to enable you to translate;
but be diligent unto the end.
5 Pray always, that you may come off conqueror; yea,
that you may conquer Satan, and that you may escape
the hands of the servants of Satan that do uphold
his work.
6 Behold, they have sought to destroy you; yea, even
the man in whom you have trusted has sought to
destroy you.
7 And for this cause I said that he is
a wicked man, for he has sought to take away
the things wherewith you have been entrusted; and he has
also sought to destroy your gift.
8 And because you have delivered the writings into his
hands, behold, wicked men have taken them from you.
9 Therefore, you have delivered them up, yea, that which
was sacred, unto wickedness.
10 And, behold, Satan hath put it into their hearts
to alter the words which you have caused to be
written, or which you have translated, which have gone out
of your hands.
11 And behold, I say unto you, that because they
have altered the words, they read contrary from that which
you translated and caused to be written;
12 And, on this wise, the devil has sought to
lay a cunning plan, that he may destroy this work;
13 For he hath put into their hearts to do
this, that by lying they may say they have caught
you in the words which you have pretended to translate.
14 Verily, I say unto you, that I will not
suffer that Satan shall accomplish his evil design in this
thing.
15 For behold, he has put it into their hearts
to get thee to tempt the Lord thy God, in
asking to translate it over again.
16 And then, behold, they say and think in their
hearts—We will see if God has given him power to
translate; if so, he will also give him power again;
17 And if God giveth him power again, or if
he translates again, or, in other words, if he bringeth
forth the same words, behold, we have the same with
us, and we have altered them;
18 Therefore they will not agree, and we will say
that he has lied in his words, and that he
has no gift, and that he has no power;
19 Therefore we will destroy him, and also the work;
and we will do this that we may not be
ashamed in the end, and that we may get glory
of the world.
20 Verily, verily, I say unto you, that Satan has
great hold upon their hearts; he stirreth them up to
iniquity against that which is good;
21 And their hearts are corrupt, and full of wickedness
and abominations; and they love darkness rather than light, because
their deeds are evil; therefore they will not ask of
me.
22 Satan stirreth them up, that he may lead their
souls to destruction.
23 And thus he has laid a cunning plan, thinking
to destroy the work of God; but I will require
this at their hands, and it shall turn to their
shame and condemnation in the day of judgment.
24 Yea, he stirreth up their hearts to anger against
this work.
25 Yea, he saith unto them: Deceive and lie in
wait to catch, that ye may destroy; behold, this is
no harm. And thus he flattereth them, and telleth them
that it is no sin to lie that they may
catch a man in a lie, that they may destroy
him.
26 And thus he flattereth them, and leadeth them along
until he draggeth their souls down to hell; and thus
he causeth them to catch themselves in their own snare.
27 And thus he goeth up and down, to and
fro in the earth, seeking to destroy the souls of
men.
28 Verily, verily, I say unto you, wo be unto
him that lieth to deceive because he supposeth that another
lieth to deceive, for such are not exempt from the
justice of God.
29 Now, behold, they have altered these words, because Satan
saith unto them: He hath deceived you—and thus he flattereth
them away to do iniquity, to get thee to tempt
the Lord thy God.
30 Behold, I say unto you, that you shall not
translate again those words which have gone forth out of
your hands;
31 For, behold, they shall not accomplish their evil designs
in lying against those words. For, behold, if you should
bring forth the same words they will say that you
have lied and that you have pretended to translate, but
that you have contradicted yourself.
32 And, behold, they will publish this, and Satan will
harden the hearts of the people to stir them up
to anger against you, that they will not believe my
words.
33 Thus Satan thinketh to overpower your testimony in this
generation, that the work may not come forth in this
generation.
34 But behold, here is wisdom, and because I show
unto you wisdom, and give you commandments concerning these things,
what you shall do, show it not unto the world
until you have accomplished the work of translation.
35 Marvel not that I said unto you: Here is
wisdom, show it not unto the world—for I said, show
it not unto the world, that you may be preserved.
36 Behold, I do not say that you shall not
show it unto the righteous;
37 But as you cannot always judge the righteous, or
as you cannot always tell the wicked from the righteous,
therefore I say unto you, hold your peace until I
shall see fit to make all things known unto the
world concerning the matter.
38 And now, verily I say unto you, that an
account of those things that you have written, which have
gone out of your hands, is engraven upon the plates
of Nephi;
39 Yea, and you remember it was said in those
writings that a more particular account was given of these
things upon the plates of Nephi.
40 And now, because the account which is engraven upon
the plates of Nephi is more particular concerning the things
which, in my wisdom, I would bring to the knowledge
of the people in this account—
41 Therefore, you shall translate the engravings which are on
the plates of Nephi, down even till you come to
the reign of king Benjamin, or until you come to
that which you have translated, which you have retained;
42 And behold, you shall publish it as the record
of Nephi; and thus I will confound those who have
altered my words.
43 I will not suffer that they shall destroy my
work; yea, I will show unto them that my wisdom
is greater than the cunning of the devil.
44 Behold, they have only got a part, or an
abridgment of the account of Nephi.
45 Behold, there are many things engraven upon the plates
of Nephi which do throw greater views upon my gospel;
therefore, it is wisdom in me that you should translate
this first part of the engravings of Nephi, and send
forth in this work.
46 And, behold, all the remainder of this work does
contain all those parts of my gospel which my holy
prophets, yea, and also my disciples, desired in their prayers
should come forth unto this people.
47 And I said unto them, that it should be
granted unto them according to their faith in their prayers;
48 Yea, and this was their faith—that my gospel, which
I gave unto them that they might preach in their
days, might come unto their brethren the Lamanites, and also
all that had become Lamanites because of their dissensions.
49 Now, this is not all—their faith in their prayers
was that this gospel should be made known also, if
it were possible that other nations should possess this land;
50 And thus they did leave a blessing upon this
land in their prayers, that whosoever should believe in this
gospel in this land might have eternal life;
51 Yea, that it might be free unto all of
whatsoever nation, kindred, tongue, or people they may be.
52 And now, behold, according to their faith in their
prayers will I bring this part of my gospel to
the knowledge of my people. Behold, I do not bring
it to destroy that which they have received, but to
build it up.
53 And for this cause have I said: If this
generation harden not their hearts, I will establish my church
among them.
54 Now I do not say this to destroy my
church, but I say this to build up my church;
55 Therefore, whosoever belongeth to my church need not fear,
for such shall inherit the kingdom of heaven.
56 But it is they who do not fear me,
neither keep my commandments but build up churches unto themselves
to get gain, yea, and all those that do wickedly
and build up the kingdom of the devil—yea, verily, verily,
I say unto you, that it is they that I
will disturb, and cause to tremble and shake to the
center.
57 Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Son of God.
I came unto mine own, and mine own received me
not.
58 I am the light which shineth in darkness, and
the darkness comprehendeth it not.
59 I am he who said—Other sheep have I which
are not of this fold—unto my disciples, and many there
were that understood me not.
60 And I will show unto this people that I
had other sheep, and that they were a branch of
the house of Jacob;
61 And I will bring to light their marvelous works,
which they did in my name;
62 Yea, and I will also bring to light my
gospel which was ministered unto them, and, behold, they shall
not deny that which you have received, but they shall
build it up, and shall bring to light the true
points of my doctrine, yea, and the only doctrine which
is in me.
63 And this I do that I may establish my
gospel, that there may not be so much contention; yea,
Satan doth stir up the hearts of the people to
contention concerning the points of my doctrine; and in these
things they do err, for they do wrest the scriptures
and do not understand them.
64 Therefore, I will unfold unto them this great mystery;
65 For, behold, I will gather them as a hen
gathereth her chickens under her wings, if they will not
harden their hearts;
66 Yea, if they will come, they may, and partake
of the waters of life freely.
67 Behold, this is my doctrine—whosoever repenteth and cometh unto
me, the same is my church.
68 Whosoever declareth more or less than this, the same
is not of me, but is against me; therefore he
is not of my church.
69 And now, behold, whosoever is of my church, and
endureth of my church to the end, him will I
establish upon my rock, and the gates of hell shall
not prevail against them.
heading to section 3.) The evil design was to await the
expected retranslation of the matter covered by the stolen pages
and then to discredit the translator by showing discrepancies created
by the alterations. That this wicked purpose had been conceived
by the evil one and was known to the Lord
even while Mormon, the ancient Nephite historian, was making his
abridgment of the accumulated plates, is shown in the Book
of Mormon (see
Section 10 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the Prophet, at
Harmony, Pennsylvania, likely around April 1829, though portions may have
been received as early as the summer of 1828. Herein
the Lord informs Joseph of alterations made by wicked men
in the 116 manuscript pages from the translation of the
book of Lehi, in the Book of Mormon. These manuscript
pages had been lost from the possession of Martin Harris,
to whom the sheets had been temporarily entrusted. (See the