section 1 had been received, some conversation was
had concerning the language used in the
revelations. The present revelation followed.
1–3, The
Lord hears the prayers of and watches over His
elders;
4–9, He challenges the wisest person to
duplicate the least of His revelations;
10–14, Faithful
elders will be quickened by the Spirit and see the
face of God.
1 Behold and hearken, O ye elders of my church,
who have assembled yourselves together, whose
prayers I have heard, and whose hearts I know, and whose
desires have come up before me
2 Behold and lo, mine eyes are upon you, and the
heavens and the earth are in mine hands, and the
riches of eternity are mine to give
3 Ye endeavored to believe that ye should receive
the blessing which was offered unto you; but
behold, verily I say unto you there were fears in your
hearts, and verily this is the reason that ye did
not receive
4 And now I, the Lord, give unto you a testimony
of the truth of these commandments which are lying
before you
5 Your eyes have been upon my servant Joseph
Smith, Jun., and his language you have known, and his
imperfections you have known; and you have sought
in your hearts knowledge that you might express
beyond his language; this you also know
6 Now, seek ye out of the Book of Commandments,
even the least that is among them, and appoint him
that is the most wise among you
7 Or, if there be any among you that shall make
one like unto it, then ye are justified in saying
that ye do not know that they are true
8 But if ye cannot make one like unto it, ye are
under condemnation if ye do not bear record that
they are true
9 For ye know that there is no unrighteousness in
them, and that which is righteous cometh down from
above, from the Father of lights
10 And again, verily I say unto you that it is
your privilege, and a promise I give unto you that
have been ordained unto this ministry, that inasmuch
as you strip yourselves from jealousies and
fears, and humble yourselves before me, for ye are not
sufficiently humble, the veil shall be rent and
you shall see me and know that I am—not with the
carnal neither natural mind, but with the spiritual
11 For no man has seen God at any time in the
flesh, except quickened by the Spirit of God
12 Neither can any natural man abide the presence
of God, neither after the carnal mind
13 Ye are not able to abide the presence of God
now, neither the ministering of angels; wherefore,
continue in patience until ye are perfected
heading to section 1). William W. Phelps had
recently established the Church printing press in
Independence, Missouri. The conference decided to
publish the revelations in the Book of Commandments and
to print 10,000 copies (which because of
unforeseen difficulties was later reduced to 3,000
copies). Many of the brethren bore solemn testimony that
the revelations then compiled for publication were
verily true, as was witnessed by the Holy Ghost
shed forth upon them. Joseph Smith’s history
records that after the revelation known as
Section 67 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, early November 1831.
The occasion was that of a special conference, and
the publication of the revelations already
received from the Lord through the Prophet was considered
and acted upon (see the