Section 82 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, in Independence, Jackson County,
Missouri, April 26, 1832. The occasion was a council of
high priests and elders of the Church. At the
council, Joseph Smith was sustained as the President
of the High Priesthood, to which office he had
previously been ordained at a conference of high
priests, elders, and members, at Amherst, Ohio,
January 25, 1832 (see the
heading to section 75).
This revelation reiterates instructions given in
an earlier revelation (
section 78) to establish a
firm—known as the United Firm (under Joseph
Smith’s direction, the term “order” later replaced
“firm”)—to govern the Church’s mercantile and
publishing endeavors.
1–4, Where much is given, much
is required;
5–7, Darkness reigns in the world;
8–13, The Lord is bound when we do what He says;
14–18, Zion must increase in beauty and
holiness;
19–24, Every man should seek the interest of his neighbor.
1 Verily, verily, I say unto you, my servants,
that inasmuch as you have forgiven one another
your trespasses, even so I, the Lord, forgive you.
2 Nevertheless, there are those among you
who have sinned exceedingly; yea, even all
of you have sinned; but verily I say unto
you, beware from henceforth, and refrain from
sin, lest sore judgments fall upon your heads.
3 For of him unto whom much is
given much is required; and he who
sins against the greater light shall
receive the greater condemnation.
4 Ye call upon my name for
revelations, and I give them unto
you; and inasmuch as ye keep not my
sayings, which I give unto you,
ye become transgressors; and
justice and judgment are the
penalty which is affixed unto my law.
5 Therefore, what I say unto
one I say unto all: Watch, for
the adversary spreadeth his
dominions, and darkness reigneth;
6 And the anger of God
kindleth against the
inhabitants of the earth;
and none doeth good, for
all have gone out of the way.
7 And now, verily I
say unto you, I, the
Lord, will not lay any
sin to your charge; go
your ways and sin no
more; but unto that soul
who sinneth shall the
former sins return,
saith the Lord your God.
8 And again, I say
unto you, I give
unto you a new
commandment, that you
may understand my
will concerning you;
9 Or, in other
words, I give unto
you directions
how you may act
before me, that it
may turn to you
for your salvation.
10 I, the Lord,
am bound when ye
do what I say;
but when ye do
not what I say,
ye have no promise.
11 Therefore,
verily I say
unto you, that it
is expedient
for my servants
Edward Partridge
and Newel K.
Whitney,
A. Sidney Gilbert and
Sidney Rigdon,
and my servant
Joseph Smith,
and John Whitmer
and Oliver
Cowdery, and W. W.
Phelps and
Martin Harris to
be bound
together by a bond and
covenant that
cannot be
broken by
transgression, except
judgment shall
immediately
follow, in your several stewardships—
12 To manage
the affairs of
the poor, and
all things
pertaining to the
bishopric
both in the land
of Zion and in
the land of Kirtland;
13 For I have
consecrated
the land of
Kirtland in mine
own due time
for the benefit
of the saints
of the Most
High, and for a
stake to Zion.
14 For Zion
must increase
in beauty,
and in
holiness; her borders
must be
enlarged; her
stakes must be
strengthened;
yea, verily I
say unto
you, Zion must
arise and put
on her beautiful garments.
Therefore, I give
unto you this
commandment,
that ye bind
yourselves
by this
covenant, and it
shall be
done according
to the laws
of the Lord.
16 Behold,
here is
wisdom also
in me for
your good.
17 And
you are to
be equal,
or in
other
words, you are
to have
equal
claims on
the
properties, for
benefit of
managing the
concerns
of your
stewardships,
every man
according to
his
wants and his
needs,
inasmuch as his wants are just—
18 And
all this
for the
benefit
of the
church of
the
living God,
that
every man
may
improve upon
his
talent,
that every
man may
gain
other
talents, yea,
even an
hundred
fold,
to be
cast into
the
Lord’s
storehouse, to
become
the
common property of the whole church—
Every man
seeking
the
interest
of his
neighbor, and
doing
all
things with
an eye
single
to the glory of God.
This
order I
have
appointed
to be
an
everlasting
order
unto
you, and
your
successors,
inasmuch as you sin not.
And the
soul
that
sins
against
this
covenant,
and
hardeneth
his
heart
against
it,
shall
be
dealt
with
according
to
the
laws of
my
church,
and
shall
be
delivered
over
to the
buffetings of Satan until the day of redemption.
And
now,
verily I
say
unto
you,
and
this
is
wisdom,
make
unto
yourselves
friends
with
the
mammon
of
unrighteousness,
and
they
will
not
destroy
you.
Leave
judgment
alone
with
me,
for
it
is
mine
and
I
will
repay.
Peace
be
with
you;
my
blessings continue with you.
For
even
yet
the
kingdom
is
yours,
and
shall
be
forever,
if
you
fall
not
from
your
steadfastness.
Even
so.
Amen.