Section 80 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Stephen Burnett, at Hiram, Ohio,
March 7, 1832.
1–5, Stephen Burnett and Eden Smith
are called to preach in whatever place they choose.
1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you my servant
Stephen Burnett: Go ye, go ye into the world and
preach the gospel to every creature that cometh
under the sound of your voice
2 And inasmuch as you desire a companion, I will
give unto you my servant Eden Smith
3 Wherefore, go ye and preach my gospel, whether
to the north or to the south, to the east or to the
west, it mattereth not, for ye cannot go amiss
4 Therefore, declare the things which ye have
heard, and verily believe, and know to be true
5 Behold, this is the will of him who hath called
you, your Redeemer, even Jesus Christ. Amen.