Section 34 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to Orson Pratt, at Fayette, New
York, November 4, 1830. Brother Pratt was
nineteen years old at the time. He had been converted
and baptized when he first heard the preaching
of the restored gospel by his older brother,
Parley P. Pratt, six weeks before. This
revelation was received in the Peter Whitmer Sr. home.
1–4, The faithful become the sons of God
through the Atonement;
5–9, The preaching of the
gospel prepares the way for the Second Coming;
10–12, Prophecy comes by the power of the Holy Ghost.
1 My son Orson, hearken and hear and
behold what I, the Lord God, shall say
unto you, even Jesus Christ your Redeemer;
2 The light and the life of the
world, a light which shineth in darkness
and the darkness comprehendeth it not;
3 Who so loved the world that he
gave his own life, that as many as
would believe might become the
sons of God. Wherefore you are my son;
4 And blessed are you
because you have believed;
5 And more blessed
are you because you
are called of me
to preach my gospel—
6 To lift up your
voice as with the
sound of a trump,
both long and
loud, and cry
repentance unto a crooked
and perverse
generation, preparing
the way of the Lord
for his second coming.
7 For behold,
verily, verily,
I say unto you,
the time is
soon at hand that
I shall come
in a cloud with
power and great glory.
8 And it shall
be a great
day at the time
of my coming,
for all
nations shall tremble.
9 But before
that great
day shall come,
the sun
shall be
darkened, and the
moon be turned
into blood;
and the stars
shall refuse
their shining,
and some
shall fall, and
great
destructions await the wicked.
Wherefore, lift up
your voice and
spare not,
for the Lord
God hath
spoken;
therefore
prophesy, and it
shall be given
by the power
of the Holy Ghost.
11 And if
you are
faithful,
behold, I am
with you
until I come—
12 And
verily,
verily, I
say unto
you, I come
quickly.
I am
your Lord
and your
Redeemer.
Even so. Amen.