Section 17 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer, and
Martin Harris, at Fayette, New York, June 1829,
prior to their viewing the engraved plates that
contained the Book of Mormon record. Joseph and
his scribe, Oliver Cowdery, had learned from the
translation of the Book of Mormon plates that three
special witnesses would be designated (see
Ether 5:2–4;
2 Nephi 11:3;
27:12). Oliver Cowdery,
David Whitmer, and Martin Harris were moved upon
by an inspired desire to be the three special
witnesses. The Prophet inquired of the Lord, and
this revelation was given in answer through the Urim
and Thummim.
1–4, By faith the Three Witnesses
will see the plates and other sacred items;
5–9,
Christ bears testimony of the divinity of the Book of Mormon.
1 Behold, I say unto you, that you must rely
upon my word, which if you do with full purpose
of heart, you shall have a view of the
plates, and also of the breastplate, the sword of
Laban, the Urim and Thummim, which were given to
the brother of Jared upon the mount, when he
talked with the Lord face to face, and the
miraculous directors which were given to Lehi
while in the wilderness, on the borders of the Red Sea.
2 And it is by your faith that you shall
obtain a view of them, even by that
faith which was had by the prophets of old.
3 And after that you have
obtained faith, and have seen them
with your eyes, you shall
testify of them, by the power of God;
4 And this you shall do
that my servant Joseph Smith,
Jun., may not be destroyed,
that I may bring about my
righteous purposes unto the
children of men in this work.
5 And ye shall testify
that you have seen them,
even as my servant Joseph
Smith, Jun., has seen
them; for it is by my power
that he has seen them, and
it is because he had faith.
6 And he has translated
the book, even that part
which I have commanded
him, and as your Lord and
your God liveth it is true.
7 Wherefore, you have
received the same power,
and the same faith, and
the same gift like unto him;
8 And if you do these
last commandments of
mine, which I have
given you, the gates of
hell shall not prevail
against you; for my
grace is sufficient for
you, and you shall be
lifted up at the last day.
9 And I, Jesus
Christ, your Lord and your
God, have spoken it
unto you, that I might
bring about my
righteous purposes unto
the children of men. Amen.