Section 111 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Salem, Massachusetts, August 6,
1836. At this time the leaders of the Church were
heavily in debt due to their labors in the ministry.
Hearing that a large amount of money would be
available to them in Salem, the Prophet, Sidney
Rigdon, Hyrum Smith, and Oliver Cowdery traveled there
from Kirtland, Ohio, to investigate this claim,
along with preaching the gospel. The brethren
transacted several items of Church business and did some
preaching. When it became apparent that no money
was to be forthcoming, they returned to Kirtland.
Several of the factors prominent in the background
are reflected in the wording of this revelation.
1–5, The Lord looks to the temporal needs of His
servants;
6–11, He will deal mercifully with Zion
and arrange all things for the good of His
servants.
1 I, the Lord your God, am not displeased with
your coming this journey, notwithstanding your
follies
2 I have much treasure in this city for you, for
the benefit of Zion, and many people in this city,
whom I will gather out in due time for the benefit
of Zion, through your instrumentality
3 Therefore, it is expedient that you should form
acquaintance with men in this city, as you shall
be led, and as it shall be given you
4 And it shall come to pass in due time that I
will give this city into your hands, that you shall
have power over it, insomuch that they shall not
discover your secret parts; and its wealth
pertaining to gold and silver shall be yours
5 Concern not yourselves about your debts, for I
will give you power to pay them
6 Concern not yourselves about Zion, for I will
deal mercifully with her
7 Tarry in this place, and in the regions round
about
8 And the place where it is my will that you
should tarry, for the main, shall be signalized unto
you by the peace and power of my Spirit, that shall
flow unto you
9 This place you may obtain by hire. And inquire
diligently concerning the more ancient inhabitants
and founders of this city
10 For there are more treasures than one for you
in this city
11 Therefore, be ye as wise as serpents and yet
without sin; and I will order all things for your
good, as fast as ye are able to receive them. Amen.