Section 29 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, in the presence of six elders, at
Fayette, New York, September 1830. This revelation was
given some days prior to the conference,
beginning September 26, 1830.
1–8, Christ gathers His
elect;
9–11, His coming ushers in the Millennium;
12–13, The Twelve will judge all Israel;
14–21,
Signs, plagues, and desolations will precede the
Second Coming;
22–28, The last resurrection and
final judgment follow the Millennium;
29–35, All
things are spiritual unto the Lord;
36–39, The devil
and his hosts were cast out of heaven to tempt
man;
40–45, The Fall and Atonement bring salvation;
46–50, Little children are redeemed through the
Atonement.
1 Listen to the voice of Jesus Christ, your
Redeemer, the Great I Am, whose arm of mercy hath atoned
for your sins
2 Who will gather his people even as a hen
gathereth her chickens under her wings, even as many as
will hearken to my voice and humble themselves
before me, and call upon me in mighty prayer
3 Behold, verily, verily, I say unto you, that at
this time your sins are forgiven you, therefore ye
receive these things; but remember to sin no
more, lest perils shall come upon you
4 Verily, I say unto you that ye are chosen out of
the world to declare my gospel with the sound of
rejoicing, as with the voice of a trump
5 Lift up your hearts and be glad, for I am in
your midst, and am your advocate with the Father; and
it is his good will to give you the kingdom
6 And, as it is written—Whatsoever ye shall ask in
faith, being united in prayer according to my
command, ye shall receive
7 And ye are called to bring to pass the gathering
of mine elect; for mine elect hear my voice and
harden not their hearts
8 Wherefore the decree hath gone forth from the
Father that they shall be gathered in unto one place
upon the face of this land, to prepare their
hearts and be prepared in all things against the day
when tribulation and desolation are sent forth upon
the wicked
9 For the hour is nigh and the day soon at hand
when the earth is ripe; and all the proud and they
that do wickedly shall be as stubble; and I will
burn them up, saith the Lord of Hosts, that
wickedness shall not be upon the earth
10 For the hour is nigh, and that which was spoken
by mine apostles must be fulfilled; for as they
spoke so shall it come to pass
11 For I will reveal myself from heaven with power
and great glory, with all the hosts thereof, and
dwell in righteousness with men on earth a
thousand years, and the wicked shall not stand
12 And again, verily, verily, I say unto you, and
it hath gone forth in a firm decree, by the will
of the Father, that mine apostles, the Twelve which
were with me in my ministry at Jerusalem, shall
stand at my right hand at the day of my coming in a
pillar of fire, being clothed with robes of
righteousness, with crowns upon their heads, in glory
even as I am, to judge the whole house of Israel,
even as many as have loved me and kept my
commandments, and none else
13 For a trump shall sound both long and loud,
even as upon Mount Sinai, and all the earth shall
quake, and they shall come forth—yea, even the dead
which died in me, to receive a crown of
righteousness, and to be clothed upon, even as I am, to be
with me, that we may be one
14 But, behold, I say unto you that before this
great day shall come the sun shall be darkened, and
the moon shall be turned into blood, and the stars
shall fall from heaven, and there shall be
greater signs in heaven above and in the earth beneath
15 And there shall be weeping and wailing among
the hosts of men
16 And there shall be a great hailstorm sent forth
to destroy the crops of the earth
17 And it shall come to pass, because of the
wickedness of the world, that I will take vengeance
upon the wicked, for they will not repent; for the
cup of mine indignation is full; for behold, my
blood shall not cleanse them if they hear me not
18 Wherefore, I the Lord God will send forth flies
upon the face of the earth, which shall take hold
of the inhabitants thereof, and shall eat their
flesh, and shall cause maggots to come in upon
them
19 And their tongues shall be stayed that they
shall not utter against me; and their flesh shall
fall from off their bones, and their eyes from their
sockets
20 And it shall come to pass that the beasts of
the forest and the fowls of the air shall devour
them up
21 And the great and abominable church, which is
the whore of all the earth, shall be cast down by
devouring fire, according as it is spoken by the
mouth of Ezekiel the prophet, who spoke of these
things, which have not come to pass but surely must,
as I live, for abominations shall not reign
22 And again, verily, verily, I say unto you that
when the thousand years are ended, and men again
begin to deny their God, then will I spare the
earth but for a little season
23 And the end shall come, and the heaven and the
earth shall be consumed and pass away, and there
shall be a new heaven and a new earth
24 For all old things shall pass away, and all
things shall become new, even the heaven and the
earth, and all the fulness thereof, both men and
beasts, the fowls of the air, and the fishes of the
sea
25 And not one hair, neither mote, shall be lost,
for it is the workmanship of mine hand
26 But, behold, verily I say unto you, before the
earth shall pass away, Michael, mine archangel,
shall sound his trump, and then shall all the dead
awake, for their graves shall be opened, and they
shall come forth—yea, even all
27 And the righteous shall be gathered on my right
hand unto eternal life; and the wicked on my left
hand will I be ashamed to own before the Father
28 Wherefore I will say unto them—Depart from me,
ye cursed, into everlasting fire, prepared for the
devil and his angels
29 And now, behold, I say unto you, never at any
time have I declared from mine own mouth that they
should return, for where I am they cannot come,
for they have no power
30 But remember that all my judgments are not
given unto men; and as the words have gone forth out
of my mouth even so shall they be fulfilled, that
the first shall be last, and that the last shall be
first in all things whatsoever I have created by
the word of my power, which is the power of my
Spirit
31 For by the power of my Spirit created I them;
yea, all things both spiritual and temporal
32 First spiritual, secondly temporal, which is
the beginning of my work; and again, first temporal,
and secondly spiritual, which is the last of my
work
33 Speaking unto you that you may naturally
understand; but unto myself my works have no end,
neither beginning; but it is given unto you that ye may
understand, because ye have asked it of me and are
agreed
34 Wherefore, verily I say unto you that all
things unto me are spiritual, and not at any time have
I given unto you a law which was temporal; neither
any man, nor the children of men; neither Adam,
your father, whom I created
35 Behold, I gave unto him that he should be an
agent unto himself; and I gave unto him commandment,
but no temporal commandment gave I unto him, for
my commandments are spiritual; they are not
natural nor temporal, neither carnal nor sensual
36 And it came to pass that Adam, being tempted of
the devil—for, behold, the devil was before Adam,
for he rebelled against me, saying, Give me thine
honor, which is my power; and also a third part
of the hosts of heaven turned he away from me
because of their agency
37 And they were thrust down, and thus came the
devil and his angels
38 And, behold, there is a place prepared for them
from the beginning, which place is hell
39 And it must needs be that the devil should
tempt the children of men, or they could not be agents
unto themselves; for if they never should have
bitter they could not know the sweet
40 Wherefore, it came to pass that the devil
tempted Adam, and he partook of the forbidden fruit and
transgressed the commandment, wherein he became
subject to the will of the devil, because he
yielded unto temptation
41 Wherefore, I, the Lord God, caused that he
should be cast out from the Garden of Eden, from my
presence, because of his transgression, wherein he
became spiritually dead, which is the first death,
even that same death which is the last death,
which is spiritual, which shall be pronounced upon the
wicked when I shall say: Depart, ye cursed
42 But, behold, I say unto you that I, the Lord
God, gave unto Adam and unto his seed, that they
should not die as to the temporal death, until I, the
Lord God, should send forth angels to declare
unto them repentance and redemption, through faith on
the name of mine Only Begotten Son
43 And thus did I, the Lord God, appoint unto man
the days of his probation—that by his natural
death he might be raised in immortality unto eternal
life, even as many as would believe
44 And they that believe not unto eternal
damnation; for they cannot be redeemed from their
spiritual fall, because they repent not
45 For they love darkness rather than light, and
their deeds are evil, and they receive their wages
of whom they list to obey
46 But behold, I say unto you, that little
children are redeemed from the foundation of the world
through mine Only Begotten
47 Wherefore, they cannot sin, for power is not
given unto Satan to tempt little children, until
they begin to become accountable before me
48 For it is given unto them even as I will,
according to mine own pleasure, that great things may
be required at the hand of their fathers
49 And, again, I say unto you, that whoso having
knowledge, have I not commanded to repent
50 And he that hath no understanding, it remaineth
in me to do according as it is written. And now I
declare no more unto you at this time. Amen.