Section 47 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, March 8, 1831. John
Whitmer, who had already served as a clerk to the
Prophet, initially hesitated when he was asked to
serve as the Church historian and recorder,
replacing Oliver Cowdery. He wrote, “I would rather not
do it but observed that the will of the Lord be
done, and if he desires it, I desire that he would
manifest it through Joseph the Seer.” After Joseph
Smith received this revelation, John Whitmer
accepted and served in his appointed office.
1–4,
John Whitmer is designated to keep the history of the
Church and to write for the Prophet.
1 Behold, it is expedient in me that my servant
John should write and keep a regular history, and
assist you, my servant Joseph, in transcribing all
things which shall be given you, until he is called
to further duties
2 Again, verily I say unto you that he can also
lift up his voice in meetings, whenever it shall be
expedient
3 And again, I say unto you that it shall be
appointed unto him to keep the church record and
history continually; for Oliver Cowdery I have appointed
to another office
4 Wherefore, it shall be given him, inasmuch as he
is faithful, by the Comforter, to write these
things. Even so. Amen.