Section 2 An extract from Joseph Smith’s history
relating the words of the angel Moroni to
Joseph Smith the Prophet, while in the house of the
Prophet’s father at Manchester, New York, on the
evening of September 21, 1823. Moroni was the
last of a long line of historians who had made the
record that is now before the world as the Book
of Mormon. (Compare
Malachi 4:5–6; also
sections 27:9;
110:13–16; and
128:18.)
1, Elijah
is to reveal the priesthood;
2–3, The promises
of the fathers are planted in the hearts of the children.
1 Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood,
by the hand of Elijah the prophet, before the
coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord.
2 And he shall plant in the hearts of the
children the promises made to the fathers, and the
hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers.
3 If it were not so, the whole earth
would be utterly wasted at his coming.