Section 44 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at Kirtland, Ohio, in
the latter part of February 1831. In compliance
with the requirement herein set forth, the Church
appointed a conference to be held early in the
month of June following.
1–3, Elders are to
assemble in conference;
4–6, They are to organize
according to the laws of the land and to care for the poor.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto you my
servants, it is expedient in me that the elders of
my church should be called together, from the
east and from the west, and from the north
and from the south, by letter or some other way.
2 And it shall come to pass, that inasmuch
as they are faithful, and exercise faith in
me, I will pour out my Spirit upon them in
the day that they assemble themselves together.
3 And it shall come to pass that they
shall go forth into the regions round
about, and preach repentance unto the people.
4 And many shall be converted, insomuch
that ye shall obtain power to organize
yourselves according to the laws of man;
5 That your enemies may not have
power over you; that you may be
preserved in all things; that you may be
enabled to keep my laws; that
every bond may be broken wherewith the
enemy seeketh to destroy my people.
6 Behold, I say unto you, that ye
must visit the poor and the
needy and administer to their relief,
that they may be kept until all
things may be done according to
my law which ye have received. Amen.