Section 108 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, December
26, 1835. This section was received at the
request of Lyman Sherman, who had previously been
ordained a seventy and who had come to the
Prophet with a request for a revelation to make
known his duty.
1–3, Lyman Sherman forgiven of
his sins;
4–5, He is to be numbered with the
leading elders of the Church;
6–8, He is
called to preach the gospel and strengthen his brethren.
1 Verily thus saith the Lord unto you,
my servant Lyman: Your sins are
forgiven you, because you have obeyed my voice
in coming up hither this morning to
receive counsel of him whom I have appointed.
2 Therefore, let your soul be at
rest concerning your spiritual
standing, and resist no more my voice.
3 And arise up and be more
careful henceforth in observing
your vows, which you have made and
do make, and you shall be
blessed with exceeding great blessings.
4 Wait patiently until the
solemn assembly shall be called
of my servants, then you shall
be remembered with the first
of mine elders, and receive
right by ordination with the rest
of mine elders whom I have chosen.
5 Behold, this is the
promise of the Father unto you
if you continue faithful.
6 And it shall be
fulfilled upon you in that day
that you shall have right to
preach my gospel
wheresoever I shall send you, from
henceforth from that time.
7 Therefore,
strengthen your brethren in all
your conversation, in
all your prayers, in
all your exhortations,
and in all your doings.
8 And behold, and
lo, I am with you to
bless you and deliver
you forever. Amen.