Section 79 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, March 12, 1832.
1–4,
Jared Carter is called to preach the gospel by the
Comforter.
1 Verily I say unto you, that it is my will that
my servant Jared Carter should go again into the
eastern countries, from place to place, and from
city to city, in the power of the ordination
wherewith he has been ordained, proclaiming glad tidings
of great joy, even the everlasting gospel
2 And I will send upon him the Comforter, which
shall teach him the truth and the way whither he
shall go
3 And inasmuch as he is faithful, I will crown him
again with sheaves
4 Wherefore, let your heart be glad, my servant
Jared Carter, and fear not, saith your Lord, even
Jesus Christ. Amen.