verses 23 through 36) given on the same day.
The occasion was a conference at which Joseph
Smith was sustained and ordained President of the
High Priesthood. Certain elders desired to
learn more about their immediate duties. These
revelations followed.
1–5, Faithful elders who
preach the gospel will gain eternal life;
6–12,
Pray to receive the Comforter, who teaches all
things;
13–22, Elders will sit in judgment on
those who reject their message;
23–36, Families
of missionaries are to receive help from the Church.
1 Verily, verily, I say unto you, I who
speak even by the voice of my Spirit, even
Alpha and Omega, your Lord and your God—
2 Hearken, O ye who have given
your names to go forth to proclaim my
gospel, and to prune my vineyard.
3 Behold, I say unto you that
it is my will that you should go
forth and not tarry, neither
be idle but labor with your might—
4 Lifting up your voices as
with the sound of a trump,
proclaiming the truth according
to the revelations and
commandments which I have given you.
5 And thus, if ye are
faithful ye shall be laden with
many sheaves, and crowned
with honor, and glory, and
immortality, and eternal life.
6 Therefore, verily I
say unto my servant
William E. McLellin, I
revoke the commission which
I gave unto him to go
unto the eastern countries;
7 And I give unto him
a new commission and a
new commandment, in
the which I, the Lord,
chasten him for the
murmurings of his heart;
8 And he sinned;
nevertheless, I forgive
him and say unto
him again, Go ye into
the south countries.
9 And let my
servant Luke Johnson go
with him, and
proclaim the things which
I have commanded them—
10 Calling on
the name of the
Lord for the
Comforter, which
shall teach them all
things that are
expedient for them—
11 Praying
always that they
faint not; and
inasmuch as they
do this, I will
be with them
even unto the end.
12 Behold,
this is the
will of the Lord
your God
concerning you.
Even so. Amen.
13 And
again, verily
thus saith the
Lord, let my
servant
Orson Hyde and
my servant
Samuel H.
Smith take
their journey
into the
eastern
countries, and
proclaim the
things which I
have commanded
them; and
inasmuch as
they are
faithful, lo, I
will be with
them even unto the end.
14 And
again, verily I
say unto
my servant
Lyman
Johnson, and unto
my servant
Orson
Pratt, they
shall also
take their
journey into
the eastern
countries;
and behold,
and lo, I
am with
them also, even unto the end.
15 And
again, I say
unto my
servant Asa
Dodds, and
unto my
servant
Calves
Wilson, that
they also
shall take
their
journey unto the
western
countries,
and
proclaim my
gospel, even
as I have commanded them.
16 And he
who is
faithful
shall
overcome all
things,
and shall
be lifted
up at
the last day.
17 And
again, I
say unto
my
servant
Major N.
Ashley, and
my
servant Burr
Riggs,
let them
take
their
journey also
into
the south country.
18 Yea,
let
all those
take
their
journey,
as I
have
commanded
them,
going
from house
to
house, and
from
village
to
village,
and from city to city.
19 And
in
whatsoever
house ye
enter,
and
they
receive
you,
leave
your
blessing
upon that house.
And in
whatsoever
house ye
enter, and
they
receive
you
not, ye
shall
depart
speedily
from
that
house,
and
shake
off
the
dust of
your
feet
as a testimony against them.
And you
shall be
filled
with joy
and
gladness;
know
this,
that
in
the day
of
judgment
you
shall be
judges of
that
house,
and
condemn
them;
And
it
shall
be
more
tolerable
for
the
heathen in
day
of
judgment,
than
for
that
house;
therefore,
gird
up
your
loins
and
be
faithful,
and ye
shall
overcome
all
things,
and be lifted up at the last day. Even so. Amen.
And
again,
thus
saith
the
Lord
unto
you,
O ye
elders
of
my
church,
who
have
given
your
names
that
you
might
know
his
will
concerning
you—
Behold, I
say
unto
you,
that
it
is
the
duty
of
the
church
to
assist
in
supporting
the
families
of
those,
and
also
to
support
the
families
of
those
who
are
called
and
must
needs
be sent unto the world to proclaim the gospel unto the world.
Wherefore,
I,
the
Lord,
give
unto
you
this
commandment,
that
ye
obtain
places
for
your
families,
inasmuch
as
your
brethren
are
willing
to
open
their
hearts.
And
let
all
such
as
can
obtain
places
for
their
families,
and
support
of
the
church
for
them,
not
fail
to
go
into
the
world,
whether to the east or to the west, or to the north, or to the south.
27 Let them ask and they shall receive, knock and it shall be opened unto them, and be made known from on high, even by the Comforter, whither they shall
Let
them
ask
and
they
shall
receive,
knock
and
it
shall
be
opened
unto
them, and be made known from on high, even by the Comforter, whither they shall go.
28 And again, verily I say unto you, that every man who is obliged to provide for his own family, let him provide, and he shall in nowise lose his crown; and let him labor in the
And
again,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
that
every
man
who
is
obliged
to
provide
for
his
own
family,
let
him
provide,
and
he
shall
in
nowise
lose
his
crown;
and
let
him
labor
in
the
church.
29 Let every man be diligent in all things. And the idler shall not have place in the church, except he repent and mend his
Let
every
man
be
diligent
in
all
things.
And
the
idler
shall
not
have
place
in
the
church,
except
he
repent
and
mend
his
ways.
30 Wherefore, let my servant Simeon Carter and my servant Emer Harris be united in the
Wherefore,
let
my
servant
Simeon
Carter
and
my
servant
Emer
Harris
be
united
in
the
ministry;
31 And also my servant Ezra Thayre and my servant Thomas B.
And
also
my
servant
Ezra
Thayre
and
my
servant
Thomas B.
Marsh;
32 Also my servant Hyrum Smith and my servant Reynolds
Also
my
servant
Hyrum
Smith
and
my
servant
Reynolds
Cahoon;
33 And also my servant Daniel Stanton and my servant Seymour
And
also
my
servant
Daniel
Stanton
and
my
servant
Seymour
Brunson;
34 And also my servant Sylvester Smith and my servant Gideon
And
also
my
servant
Sylvester
Smith
and
my
servant
Gideon
Carter;
35 And also my servant Ruggles Eames and my servant Stephen
And
also
my
servant
Ruggles
Eames
and
my
servant
Stephen
Burnett;
36 And also my servant Micah B. Welton and also my servant Eden Smith. Even so. Amen.
And
also
my
servant
Micah B.
Welton
and
also
my
servant
Eden
Smith.
Even
so.
Amen.
verses 1 through 22 and the second in
through
and
the
second
in
Section 75 Revelation given through Joseph Smith the Prophet, at Amherst, Ohio, January 25, 1832. This section comprises two separate revelations (the first in
Revelation
given
through
Joseph
Smith
the
Prophet,
at
Amherst,
Ohio,
January
25,
1832.
This
section
comprises
two
separate
revelations
(the
first
in