Section 28 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to Oliver Cowdery, at Fayette,
New York, September 1830. Hiram Page, a member of
the Church, had a certain stone and professed
to be receiving revelations by its aid
concerning the upbuilding of Zion and the order of the
Church. Several members had been deceived by
these claims, and even Oliver Cowdery was wrongly
influenced thereby. Just prior to an appointed
conference, the Prophet inquired earnestly of
the Lord concerning the matter, and this
revelation followed.
1–7, Joseph Smith holds the
keys of the mysteries, and only he receives
revelations for the Church;
8–10, Oliver Cowdery is
to preach to the Lamanites;
11–16, Satan
deceived Hiram Page and gave him false revelations.
1 Behold, I say unto thee, Oliver, that it
shall be given unto thee that thou shalt be heard
by the church in all things whatsoever thou
shalt teach them by the Comforter, concerning the
revelations and commandments which I have given.
2 But, behold, verily, verily, I say unto
thee, no one shall be appointed to
receive commandments and revelations in this
church excepting my servant Joseph Smith,
Jun., for he receiveth them even as Moses.
3 And thou shalt be obedient unto the
things which I shall give unto him,
even as Aaron, to declare faithfully the
commandments and the revelations,
with power and authority unto the church.
4 And if thou art led at any time by
the Comforter to speak or teach, or
at all times by the way of
commandment unto the church, thou mayest do it.
5 But thou shalt not write by
way of commandment, but by wisdom;
6 And thou shalt not
command him who is at thy head,
and at the head of the church;
7 For I have given him
the keys of the
mysteries, and the revelations
which are sealed,
until I shall appoint unto
them another in his stead.
8 And now, behold, I
say unto you that you
shall go unto the
Lamanites and preach my
gospel unto them;
and inasmuch as they
receive thy teachings
thou shalt cause my
church to be
established among them; and
thou shalt have
revelations, but write them
not by way of commandment.
9 And now, behold,
I say unto you that
it is not
revealed, and no man
knoweth where the city
Zion shall be built,
but it shall be
given hereafter.
Behold, I say unto you
that it shall be on
the borders by the Lamanites.
10 Thou shalt not
leave this place
until after the
conference; and
my servant Joseph
shall be
appointed to preside over
the conference
by the voice of
it, and what he
saith to thee thou shalt tell.
11 And again,
thou shalt take
thy brother, Hiram
Page, between
him and thee
alone, and tell him
that those
things which he hath
written from
that stone are not
of me and that
Satan deceiveth him;
12 For, behold,
these things
have not been
appointed unto
him, neither
shall anything be
appointed unto
any of this
church contrary to
the church covenants.
13 For all
things must be
done in order,
and by common
consent in the
church, by the
prayer of faith.
14 And thou
shalt assist
to settle all
these things,
according to
the
covenants of the
church, before
thou shalt take
thy journey
among the Lamanites.
15 And it
shall be given
thee from
the time thou
shalt go,
until the
time thou shalt
return,
what thou shalt do.
16 And thou
must open
thy mouth
at all
times, declaring
my gospel
with the
sound of
rejoicing. Amen.