Section 3 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet, at Harmony, Pennsylvania, July 1828,
relating to the loss of 116 pages of manuscript
translated from the first part of the Book of
Mormon, which was called the book of Lehi. The
Prophet had reluctantly allowed these pages to
pass from his custody to that of Martin Harris,
who had served for a brief period as scribe in
the translation of the Book of Mormon. The
revelation was given through the Urim and Thummim.
(See
section 10.)
1–4, The Lord’s course is
one eternal round;
5–15, Joseph Smith must
repent or lose the gift to translate;
16–20, The
Book of Mormon comes forth to save the seed of Lehi.
1 The works, and the designs, and
the purposes of God cannot be
frustrated, neither can they come to naught.
2 For God doth not walk in
crooked paths, neither doth he turn
to the right hand nor to the
left, neither doth he vary from
that which he hath said,
therefore his paths are straight, and
his course is one eternal round.
3 Remember, remember that it
is not the work of God that is
frustrated, but the work of men;
4 For although a man may have
many revelations, and have
power to do many mighty works,
yet if he boasts in his own
strength, and sets at naught
the counsels of God, and
follows after the dictates of his
own will and carnal desires,
he must fall and incur the
vengeance of a just God upon him.
5 Behold, you have been
entrusted with these
things, but how strict were
your commandments; and
remember also the promises
which were made to you, if
you did not transgress them.
6 And behold, how oft you
have transgressed the
commandments and the laws
of God, and have gone on
in the persuasions of men.
7 For, behold, you
should not have feared
man more than God.
Although men set at
naught the counsels of
God, and despise his words—
8 Yet you should
have been faithful;
and he would have
extended his arm and
supported you
against all the fiery
darts of the
adversary; and he would
have been with you in
every time of trouble.
9 Behold, thou
art Joseph, and
thou wast chosen to
do the work of
the Lord, but
because of
transgression, if thou art
not aware thou wilt fall.
10 But remember,
God is
merciful; therefore,
repent of that
which thou hast done
which is
contrary to the
commandment which I
gave you, and thou
art still
chosen, and art again
called to the work;
11 Except thou
do this, thou
shalt be
delivered up and
become as other
men, and have
no more gift.
12 And when
thou
deliveredst up that
which God had
given thee
sight and power
to translate,
thou
deliveredst up that
which was
sacred into the
hands of a wicked man,
13 Who has
set at naught
the
counsels of God,
and has broken
the most
sacred
promises which were
made before
God, and
has depended
upon his own
judgment and
boasted in
his own wisdom.
14 And
this is the
reason that
thou hast
lost thy
privileges
for a season—
15 For
thou hast
suffered
the
counsel of thy
director
to be
trampled
upon from
the beginning.
Nevertheless,
my work
shall
go forth,
for
inasmuch as
the
knowledge
of a
Savior has
come unto
the
world,
through the
testimony of the
Jews,
even so
shall the
knowledge of a
Savior come unto my people—
17 And
to the
Nephites, and
the
Jacobites,
and
the
Josephites,
and the
Zoramites,
through
the
testimony
of their fathers—
18 And
this
testimony
shall
come to
the
knowledge
of the
Lamanites,
and the
Lemuelites, and
the
Ishmaelites, who
dwindled in
unbelief
because of
the
iniquity of
their
fathers,
whom
the Lord
has
suffered
to
destroy
their
brethren
the
Nephites,
because
of their
iniquities
and their
abominations.
19 And
for
this
very
purpose
are
these
plates
preserved,
which
contain
these
records—that
the
promises
of
the Lord
might
be
fulfilled,
which he made to his people;
And
that the
Lamanites
might
come to
the
knowledge
of
their
fathers, and
that
they
might
know the
promises
of
the
Lord,
and
that
they may
believe
the
gospel
and
rely
upon
the
merits
of
Jesus
Christ, and
be
glorified
through
faith in
his
name,
and
that
through their repentance they might be saved. Amen.