Section 76 A vision given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, at Hiram, Ohio, February
16, 1832. Prefacing the record of this vision,
Joseph Smith’s history states: “Upon my return from
Amherst conference, I resumed the translation of the
Scriptures. From sundry revelations which had been
received, it was apparent that many important
points touching the salvation of man had been taken
from the Bible, or lost before it was compiled. It
appeared self-evident from what truths were left,
that if God rewarded every one according to the
deeds done in the body the term ‘Heaven,’ as
intended for the Saints’ eternal home, must include more
kingdoms than one. Accordingly, … while
translating St. John’s Gospel, myself and Elder Rigdon saw
the following vision.” At the time this vision was
given, the Prophet was translating
John 5:29.
1–4, The Lord is God;
5–10, The mysteries of the
kingdom will be revealed to all the faithful;
11–17, All will come forth in the resurrection of the
just or the unjust;
18–24, The inhabitants of many
worlds are begotten sons and daughters unto God
through the Atonement of Jesus Christ;
25–29, An
angel of God fell and became the devil;
30–49,
Sons of perdition suffer eternal damnation; all
others gain some degree of salvation;
50–70, The glory
and reward of exalted beings in the celestial
kingdom is described;
71–80, Those who will inherit
the terrestrial kingdom are described;
81–113,
The status of those in the telestial, terrestrial,
and celestial glories is explained;
114–19, The
faithful may see and understand the mysteries of
God’s kingdom by the power of the Holy Spirit.
twenty-ninth verse of the fifth chapter of John, which
was given unto us as follows
1 Hear, O ye heavens, and give ear, O earth, and
rejoice ye inhabitants thereof, for the Lord is
God, and beside him there is no Savior
2 Great is his wisdom, marvelous are his ways, and
the extent of his doings none can find out
3 His purposes fail not, neither are there any who
can stay his hand
4 From eternity to eternity he is the same, and
his years never fail
5 For thus saith the Lord—I, the Lord, am merciful
and gracious unto those who fear me, and delight
to honor those who serve me in righteousness and
in truth unto the end
6 Great shall be their reward and eternal shall be
their glory
7 And to them will I reveal all mysteries, yea,
all the hidden mysteries of my kingdom from days of
old, and for ages to come, will I make known unto
them the good pleasure of my will concerning all
things pertaining to my kingdom
8 Yea, even the wonders of eternity shall they
know, and things to come will I show them, even the
things of many generations
9 And their wisdom shall be great, and their
understanding reach to heaven; and before them the
wisdom of the wise shall perish, and the understanding
of the prudent shall come to naught
10 For by my Spirit will I enlighten them, and by
my power will I make known unto them the secrets
of my will—yea, even those things which eye has not
seen, nor ear heard, nor yet entered into the
heart of man
11 We, Joseph Smith, Jun., and Sidney Rigdon,
being in the Spirit on the sixteenth day of February,
in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred
and thirty-two
12 By the power of the Spirit our eyes were opened
and our understandings were enlightened, so as to
see and understand the things of God
13 Even those things which were from the beginning
before the world was, which were ordained of the
Father, through his Only Begotten Son, who was in
the bosom of the Father, even from the beginning
14 Of whom we bear record; and the record which we
bear is the fulness of the gospel of Jesus
Christ, who is the Son, whom we saw and with whom we
conversed in the heavenly vision
15 For while we were doing the work of
translation, which the Lord had appointed unto us, we came to
the
16 Speaking of the resurrection of the dead,
concerning those who shall hear the voice of the Son of
Man
17 And shall come forth; they who have done good,
in the resurrection of the just; and they who have
done evil, in the resurrection of the unjust
18 Now this caused us to marvel, for it was given
unto us of the Spirit
19 And while we meditated upon these things, the
Lord touched the eyes of our understandings and
they were opened, and the glory of the Lord shone
round about
20 And we beheld the glory of the Son, on the
right hand of the Father, and received of his fulness
21 And saw the holy angels, and them who are
sanctified before his throne, worshiping God, and the
Lamb, who worship him forever and ever
22 And now, after the many testimonies which have
been given of him, this is the testimony, last of
all, which we give of him: That he lives
23 For we saw him, even on the right hand of God;
and we heard the voice bearing record that he is
the Only Begotten of the Father
24 That by him, and through him, and of him, the
worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants
thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God
25 And this we saw also, and bear record, that an
angel of God who was in authority in the presence
of God, who rebelled against the Only Begotten Son
whom the Father loved and who was in the bosom of
the Father, was thrust down from the presence of
God and the Son
26 And was called Perdition, for the heavens wept
over him—he was Lucifer, a son of the morning
27 And we beheld, and lo, he is fallen! is fallen,
even a son of the morning
28 And while we were yet in the Spirit, the Lord
commanded us that we should write the vision; for
we beheld Satan, that old serpent, even the devil,
who rebelled against God, and sought to take the
kingdom of our God and his Christ
29 Wherefore, he maketh war with the saints of
God, and encompasseth them round about
30 And we saw a vision of the sufferings of those
with whom he made war and overcame, for thus came
the voice of the Lord unto us
31 Thus saith the Lord concerning all those who
know my power, and have been made partakers thereof,
and suffered themselves through the power of the
devil to be overcome, and to deny the truth and
defy my power
32 They are they who are the sons of perdition, of
whom I say that it had been better for them never
to have been born
33 For they are vessels of wrath, doomed to suffer
the wrath of God, with the devil and his angels
in eternity
34 Concerning whom I have said there is no
forgiveness in this world nor in the world to come
35 Having denied the Holy Spirit after having
received it, and having denied the Only Begotten Son
of the Father, having crucified him unto themselves
and put him to an open shame
36 These are they who shall go away into the lake
of fire and brimstone, with the devil and his
angels
37 And the only ones on whom the second death
shall have any power
38 Yea, verily, the only ones who shall not be
redeemed in the due time of the Lord, after the
sufferings of his wrath
39 For all the rest shall be brought forth by the
resurrection of the dead, through the triumph and
the glory of the Lamb, who was slain, who was in
the bosom of the Father before the worlds were
made
40 And this is the gospel, the glad tidings, which
the voice out of the heavens bore record unto us
41 That he came into the world, even Jesus, to be
crucified for the world, and to bear the sins of
the world, and to sanctify the world, and to
cleanse it from all unrighteousness
42 That through him all might be saved whom the
Father had put into his power and made by him
43 Who glorifies the Father, and saves all the
works of his hands, except those sons of perdition
who deny the Son after the Father has revealed him
44 Wherefore, he saves all except them—they shall
go away into everlasting punishment, which is
endless punishment, which is eternal punishment, to
reign with the devil and his angels in eternity,
where their worm dieth not, and the fire is not
quenched, which is their torment
45 And the end thereof, neither the place thereof,
nor their torment, no man knows
46 Neither was it revealed, neither is, neither
will be revealed unto man, except to them who are
made partakers thereof
47 Nevertheless, I, the Lord, show it by vision
unto many, but straightway shut it up again
48 Wherefore, the end, the width, the height, the
depth, and the misery thereof, they understand
not, neither any man except those who are ordained
unto this condemnation
49 And we heard the voice, saying: Write the
vision, for lo, this is the end of the vision of the
sufferings of the ungodly
50 And again we bear record—for we saw and heard,
and this is the testimony of the gospel of Christ
concerning them who shall come forth in the
resurrection of the just
51 They are they who received the testimony of
Jesus, and believed on his name and were baptized
after the manner of his burial, being buried in the
water in his name, and this according to the
commandment which he has given
52 That by keeping the commandments they might be
washed and cleansed from all their sins, and
receive the Holy Spirit by the laying on of the hands
of him who is ordained and sealed unto this power
53 And who overcome by faith, and are sealed by
the Holy Spirit of promise, which the Father sheds
forth upon all those who are just and true
54 They are they who are the church of the
Firstborn
55 They are they into whose hands the Father has
given all things
56 They are they who are priests and kings, who
have received of his fulness, and of his glory
57 And are priests of the Most High, after the
order of Melchizedek, which was after the order of
Enoch, which was after the order of the Only
Begotten Son
58 Wherefore, as it is written, they are gods,
even the sons of God
59 Wherefore, all things are theirs, whether life
or death, or things present, or things to come,
all are theirs and they are Christ’s, and Christ is
God’s
60 And they shall overcome all things
61 Wherefore, let no man glory in man, but rather
let him glory in God, who shall subdue all enemies
under his feet
62 These shall dwell in the presence of God and
his Christ forever and ever
63 These are they whom he shall bring with him,
when he shall come in the clouds of heaven to reign
on the earth over his people
64 These are they who shall have part in the first
resurrection
65 These are they who shall come forth in the
resurrection of the just
66 These are they who are come unto Mount Zion,
and unto the city of the living God, the heavenly
place, the holiest of all
67 These are they who have come to an innumerable
company of angels, to the general assembly and
church of Enoch, and of the Firstborn
68 These are they whose names are written in
heaven, where God and Christ are the judge of all
69 These are they who are just men made perfect
through Jesus the mediator of the new covenant, who
wrought out this perfect atonement through the
shedding of his own blood
70 These are they whose bodies are celestial,
whose glory is that of the sun, even the glory of God,
the highest of all, whose glory the sun of the
firmament is written of as being typical
71 And again, we saw the terrestrial world, and
behold and lo, these are they who are of the
terrestrial, whose glory differs from that of the church
of the Firstborn who have received the fulness of
the Father, even as that of the moon differs from
the sun in the firmament
72 Behold, these are they who died without law
73 And also they who are the spirits of men kept
in prison, whom the Son visited, and preached the
gospel unto them, that they might be judged
according to men in the flesh
74 Who received not the testimony of Jesus in the
flesh, but afterwards received it
75 These are they who are honorable men of the
earth, who were blinded by the craftiness of men
76 These are they who receive of his glory, but
not of his fulness
77 These are they who receive of the presence of
the Son, but not of the fulness of the Father
78 Wherefore, they are bodies terrestrial, and not
bodies celestial, and differ in glory as the moon
differs from the sun
79 These are they who are not valiant in the
testimony of Jesus; wherefore, they obtain not the
crown over the kingdom of our God
80 And now this is the end of the vision which we
saw of the terrestrial, that the Lord commanded us
to write while we were yet in the Spirit
81 And again, we saw the glory of the telestial,
which glory is that of the lesser, even as the
glory of the stars differs from that of the glory of
the moon in the firmament
82 These are they who received not the gospel of
Christ, neither the testimony of Jesus
83 These are they who deny not the Holy Spirit
84 These are they who are thrust down to hell
85 These are they who shall not be redeemed from
the devil until the last resurrection, until the
Lord, even Christ the Lamb, shall have finished his
work
86 These are they who receive not of his fulness
in the eternal world, but of the Holy Spirit
through the ministration of the terrestrial
87 And the terrestrial through the ministration of
the celestial
88 And also the telestial receive it of the
administering of angels who are appointed to minister
for them, or who are appointed to be ministering
spirits for them; for they shall be heirs of
salvation
89 And thus we saw, in the heavenly vision, the
glory of the telestial, which surpasses all
understanding
90 And no man knows it except him to whom God has
revealed it
91 And thus we saw the glory of the terrestrial
which excels in all things the glory of the
telestial, even in glory, and in power, and in might, and
in dominion
92 And thus we saw the glory of the celestial,
which excels in all things—where God, even the
Father, reigns upon his throne forever and ever
93 Before whose throne all things bow in humble
reverence, and give him glory forever and ever
94 They who dwell in his presence are the church
of the Firstborn; and they see as they are seen,
and know as they are known, having received of his
fulness and of his grace
95 And he makes them equal in power, and in might,
and in dominion
96 And the glory of the celestial is one, even as
the glory of the sun is one
97 And the glory of the terrestrial is one, even
as the glory of the moon is one
98 And the glory of the telestial is one, even as
the glory of the stars is one; for as one star
differs from another star in glory, even so differs
one from another in glory in the telestial world
99 For these are they who are of Paul, and of
Apollos, and of Cephas
100 These are they who say they are some of one
and some of another—some of Christ and some of John,
and some of Moses, and some of Elias, and some of
Esaias, and some of Isaiah, and some of Enoch
101 But received not the gospel, neither the
testimony of Jesus, neither the prophets, neither the
everlasting covenant
102 Last of all, these all are they who will not
be gathered with the saints, to be caught up unto
the church of the Firstborn, and received into the
cloud
103 These are they who are liars, and sorcerers,
and adulterers, and whoremongers, and whosoever
loves and makes a lie
104 These are they who suffer the wrath of God on
earth
105 These are they who suffer the vengeance of
eternal fire
106 These are they who are cast down to hell and
suffer the wrath of Almighty God, until the fulness
of times, when Christ shall have subdued all
enemies under his feet, and shall have perfected his
work
107 When he shall deliver up the kingdom, and
present it unto the Father, spotless, saying: I have
overcome and have trodden the wine-press alone,
even the wine-press of the fierceness of the wrath of
Almighty God
108 Then shall he be crowned with the crown of his
glory, to sit on the throne of his power to reign
forever and ever
109 But behold, and lo, we saw the glory and the
inhabitants of the telestial world, that they were
as innumerable as the stars in the firmament of
heaven, or as the sand upon the seashore
110 And heard the voice of the Lord saying: These
all shall bow the knee, and every tongue shall
confess to him who sits upon the throne forever and
ever
111 For they shall be judged according to their
works, and every man shall receive according to his
own works, his own dominion, in the mansions which
are prepared
112 And they shall be servants of the Most High;
but where God and Christ dwell they cannot come,
worlds without end
113 This is the end of the vision which we saw,
which we were commanded to write while we were yet
in the Spirit
114 But great and marvelous are the works of the
Lord, and the mysteries of his kingdom which he
showed unto us, which surpass all understanding in
glory, and in might, and in dominion
115 Which he commanded us we should not write
while we were yet in the Spirit, and are not lawful
for man to utter
116 Neither is man capable to make them known, for
they are only to be seen and understood by the
power of the Holy Spirit, which God bestows on those
who love him, and purify themselves before him
117 To whom he grants this privilege of seeing and
knowing for themselves
118 That through the power and manifestation of
the Spirit, while in the flesh, they may be able to
bear his presence in the world of glory
119 And to God and the Lamb be glory, and honor,
and dominion forever and ever. Amen.