Section 37 Revelation given to Joseph Smith the
Prophet and Sidney Rigdon, near Fayette, New York,
December 1830. Herein is given the first
commandment concerning a gathering in this dispensation.
1–4, The Saints are called to gather at the Ohio.
1 Behold, I say unto you that it is not
expedient in me that ye should translate any
more until ye shall go to the Ohio, and
this because of the enemy and for your sakes.
2 And again, I say unto you that ye
shall not go until ye have preached my
gospel in those parts, and have strengthened
up the church whithersoever it is found,
and more especially in Colesville; for,
behold, they pray unto me in much faith.
3 And again, a commandment I give unto
the church, that it is expedient in me
that they should assemble together at
the Ohio, against the time that my
servant Oliver Cowdery shall return unto them.
4 Behold, here is wisdom, and
let every man choose for
himself until I come. Even so. Amen.