Section 51 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Thompson, Ohio, May 20, 1831.
At this time the Saints migrating from the
eastern states began to arrive in Ohio, and it
became necessary to make definite arrangements for
their settlement. As this undertaking belonged
particularly to the bishop’s office, Bishop
Edward Partridge sought instruction on the
matter, and the Prophet inquired of the Lord.
1–8,
Edward Partridge is appointed to regulate
stewardships and properties;
9–12, The Saints are to
deal honestly and receive alike;
13–15, They
are to have a bishop’s storehouse and to
organize properties according to the Lord’s law;
16–20, Ohio is to be a temporary gathering place.
1 Hearken unto me, saith the Lord your
God, and I will speak unto my servant
Edward Partridge, and give unto him
directions; for it must needs be that he
receive directions how to organize this people.
2 For it must needs be that they
be organized according to my laws;
if otherwise, they will be cut off.
3 Wherefore, let my servant
Edward Partridge, and those whom
he has chosen, in whom I am
well pleased, appoint unto this
people their portions, every
man equal according to his
family, according to his
circumstances and his wants and needs.
4 And let my servant Edward
Partridge, when he shall
appoint a man his portion, give
unto him a writing that
shall secure unto him his
portion, that he shall hold it,
even this right and this
inheritance in the church, until
he transgresses and is not
accounted worthy by the
voice of the church, according
to the laws and covenants of
the church, to belong to the church.
5 And if he shall
transgress and is not accounted
worthy to belong to the
church, he shall not have
power to claim that portion
which he has consecrated
unto the bishop for the poor
and needy of my church;
therefore, he shall not
retain the gift, but shall
only have claim on that
portion that is deeded unto him.
6 And thus all things
shall be made sure,
according to the laws of the land.
7 And let that which
belongs to this people be
appointed unto this people.
8 And the money which
is left unto this
people—let there be an
agent appointed unto this
people, to take the
money to provide food
and raiment, according
to the wants of this people.
9 And let every man
deal honestly, and
be alike among
this people, and
receive alike, that ye
may be one, even as
I have commanded you.
10 And let that
which belongeth
to this people
not be taken and
given unto that
of another church.
11 Wherefore,
if another
church would
receive money of
this church,
let them pay
unto this church
again
according as they shall agree;
12 And this
shall be done
through the
bishop or the
agent, which
shall be
appointed by the
voice of the church.
13 And
again, let the
bishop appoint
a
storehouse unto this
church; and
let all
things both in
money and in
meat, which
are more
than is needful
for the
wants of this
people, be
kept in the
hands of the bishop.
14 And let
him also
reserve unto
himself for
his own
wants, and
for the wants
of his
family, as he
shall be
employed in
doing this business.
15 And
thus I grant
unto this
people a
privilege
of
organizing
themselves
according to my laws.
16 And I
consecrate unto
them this
land for a
little
season,
until I,
the Lord,
shall
provide for
them
otherwise, and
command
them to go hence;
17 And
the hour
and the
day is
not given
unto
them,
wherefore
let them
act upon
this
land as for
years,
and this
shall
turn unto
them for their good.
Behold,
this shall
be an
example
unto
my
servant
Edward
Partridge,
in
other
places, in all churches.
19 And
whoso
is
found a
faithful, a
just,
and a
wise
steward
shall
enter
into
the
joy of
his
Lord, and
shall
inherit eternal life.
Verily,
I
say
unto
you, I
am
Jesus
Christ,
who
cometh
quickly,
in
an
hour you
think not. Even so. Amen.