Section 12 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to Joseph Knight Sr., at Harmony,
Pennsylvania, May 1829. Joseph Knight believed
the declarations of Joseph Smith concerning
his possession of the Book of Mormon plates and
the work of translation then in progress and
several times had given material assistance to
Joseph Smith and his scribe, which enabled them to
continue translating. At Joseph Knight’s
request, the Prophet inquired of the Lord and
received the revelation.
1–6, Laborers in the
vineyard are to gain salvation;
7–9, All who desire
and are qualified may assist in the Lord’s work.
1 A great and marvelous work is about
to come forth among the children of men.
2 Behold, I am God; give heed to my
word, which is quick and powerful,
sharper than a two-edged sword, to the
dividing asunder of both joints and
marrow; therefore, give heed unto my word.
3 Behold, the field is white
already to harvest; therefore, whoso
desireth to reap let him thrust in
his sickle with his might, and reap
while the day lasts, that he may
treasure up for his soul
everlasting salvation in the kingdom of God.
4 Yea, whosoever will
thrust in his sickle and reap,
the same is called of God.
5 Therefore, if you will
ask of me you shall
receive; if you will knock it
shall be opened unto you.
6 Now, as you have
asked, behold, I say
unto you, keep my
commandments, and seek to
bring forth and
establish the cause of Zion.
7 Behold, I speak
unto you, and
also to all those
who have desires
to bring forth and
establish this work;
8 And no one can
assist in this
work except he
shall be humble and
full of love,
having faith, hope,
and charity, being
temperate in all
things,
whatsoever shall be
entrusted to his care.
9 Behold, I am
the light and the
life of the
world, that speak
these words,
therefore give heed
with your might,
and then you
are called. Amen.