Section 63 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, August 30, 1831.
The Prophet, Sidney Rigdon, and Oliver Cowdery had
arrived in Kirtland on August 27 from their visit
to Missouri. Joseph Smith’s history describes this
revelation: “In these infant days of the Church,
there was a great anxiety to obtain the word of the
Lord upon every subject that in any way concerned
our salvation; and as the land of Zion was now
the most important temporal object in view, I
enquired of the Lord for further information upon the
gathering of the Saints, and the purchase of the
land, and other matters.”
1–6, A day of wrath will
come upon the wicked;
7–12, Signs come by faith;
13–19, The adulterous in heart will deny the faith
and be cast into the lake of fire;
20, The
faithful will receive an inheritance upon the
transfigured earth;
21, A full account of the events on
the Mount of Transfiguration has not yet been
revealed;
22–23, The obedient receive the mysteries of
the kingdom;
24–31, Inheritances in Zion are to
be purchased;
32–35, The Lord decrees wars, and
the wicked slay the wicked;
36–48, The Saints are
to gather to Zion and provide moneys to build it
up;
49–54, Blessings are assured the faithful at
the Second Coming, in the Resurrection, and during
the Millennium;
55–58, This is a day of warning;
59–66, The Lord’s name is taken in vain by those
who use it without authority.
1 Hearken, O ye people, and open your hearts and
give ear from afar; and listen, you that call
yourselves the people of the Lord, and hear the word of
the Lord and his will concerning you
2 Yea, verily, I say, hear the word of him whose
anger is kindled against the wicked and rebellious
3 Who willeth to take even them whom he will take,
and preserveth in life them whom he will
preserve
4 Who buildeth up at his own will and pleasure;
and destroyeth when he pleases, and is able to cast
the soul down to hell
5 Behold, I, the Lord, utter my voice, and it
shall be obeyed
6 Wherefore, verily I say, let the wicked take
heed, and let the rebellious fear and tremble; and
let the unbelieving hold their lips, for the day of
wrath shall come upon them as a whirlwind, and all
flesh shall know that I am God
7 And he that seeketh signs shall see signs, but
not unto salvation
8 Verily, I say unto you, there are those among
you who seek signs, and there have been such even
from the beginning
9 But, behold, faith cometh not by signs, but
signs follow those that believe
10 Yea, signs come by faith, not by the will of
men, nor as they please, but by the will of God
11 Yea, signs come by faith, unto mighty works,
for without faith no man pleaseth God; and with whom
God is angry he is not well pleased; wherefore,
unto such he showeth no signs, only in wrath unto
their condemnation
12 Wherefore, I, the Lord, am not pleased with
those among you who have sought after signs and
wonders for faith, and not for the good of men unto my
glory
13 Nevertheless, I give commandments, and many
have turned away from my commandments and have not
kept them
14 There were among you adulterers and
adulteresses; some of whom have turned away from you, and
others remain with you that hereafter shall be
revealed
15 Let such beware and repent speedily, lest
judgment shall come upon them as a snare, and their
folly shall be made manifest, and their works shall
follow them in the eyes of the people
16 And verily I say unto you, as I have said
before, he that looketh on a woman to lust after her,
or if any shall commit adultery in their hearts,
they shall not have the Spirit, but shall deny the
faith and shall fear
17 Wherefore, I, the Lord, have said that the
fearful, and the unbelieving, and all liars, and
whosoever loveth and maketh a lie, and the whoremonger,
and the sorcerer, shall have their part in that
lake which burneth with fire and brimstone, which
is the second death
18 Verily I say, that they shall not have part in
the first resurrection
19 And now behold, I, the Lord, say unto you that
ye are not justified, because these things are
among you
20 Nevertheless, he that endureth in faith and
doeth my will, the same shall overcome, and shall
receive an inheritance upon the earth when the day of
transfiguration shall come
21 When the earth shall be transfigured, even
according to the pattern which was shown unto mine
apostles upon the mount; of which account the fulness
ye have not yet received
22 And now, verily I say unto you, that as I said
that I would make known my will unto you, behold I
will make it known unto you, not by the way of
commandment, for there are many who observe not to
keep my commandments
23 But unto him that keepeth my commandments I
will give the mysteries of my kingdom, and the same
shall be in him a well of living water, springing
up unto everlasting life
24 And now, behold, this is the will of the Lord
your God concerning his saints, that they should
assemble themselves together unto the land of Zion,
not in haste, lest there should be confusion,
which bringeth pestilence
25 Behold, the land of Zion—I, the Lord, hold it
in mine own hands
26 Nevertheless, I, the Lord, render unto Cæsar
the things which are Cæsar’s
27 Wherefore, I the Lord will that you should
purchase the lands, that you may have advantage of the
world, that you may have claim on the world, that
they may not be stirred up unto anger
28 For Satan putteth it into their hearts to anger
against you, and to the shedding of blood
29 Wherefore, the land of Zion shall not be
obtained but by purchase or by blood, otherwise there is
none inheritance for you
30 And if by purchase, behold you are blessed
31 And if by blood, as you are forbidden to shed
blood, lo, your enemies are upon you, and ye shall
be scourged from city to city, and from synagogue
to synagogue, and but few shall stand to receive
an inheritance
32 I, the Lord, am angry with the wicked; I am
holding my Spirit from the inhabitants of the earth
33 I have sworn in my wrath, and decreed wars upon
the face of the earth, and the wicked shall slay
the wicked, and fear shall come upon every man
34 And the saints also shall hardly escape;
nevertheless, I, the Lord, am with them, and will come
down in heaven from the presence of my Father and
consume the wicked with unquenchable fire
35 And behold, this is not yet, but by and by
36 Wherefore, seeing that I, the Lord, have
decreed all these things upon the face of the earth, I
will that my saints should be assembled upon the
land of Zion
37 And that every man should take righteousness in
his hands and faithfulness upon his loins, and
lift a warning voice unto the inhabitants of the
earth; and declare both by word and by flight that
desolation shall come upon the wicked
38 Wherefore, let my disciples in Kirtland arrange
their temporal concerns, who dwell upon this
farm
39 Let my servant Titus Billings, who has the care
thereof, dispose of the land, that he may be
prepared in the coming spring to take his journey up
unto the land of Zion, with those that dwell upon
the face thereof, excepting those whom I shall
reserve unto myself, that shall not go until I shall
command them
40 And let all the moneys which can be spared, it
mattereth not unto me whether it be little or
much, be sent up unto the land of Zion, unto them whom
I have appointed to receive
41 Behold, I, the Lord, will give unto my servant
Joseph Smith, Jun., power that he shall be enabled
to discern by the Spirit those who shall go up
unto the land of Zion, and those of my disciples who
shall tarry
42 Let my servant Newel K. Whitney retain his
store, or in other words, the store, yet for a little
season
43 Nevertheless, let him impart all the money
which he can impart, to be sent up unto the land of
Zion
44 Behold, these things are in his own hands, let
him do according to wisdom
45 Verily I say, let him be ordained as an agent
unto the disciples that shall tarry, and let him be
ordained unto this power
46 And now speedily visit the churches, expounding
these things unto them, with my servant Oliver
Cowdery. Behold, this is my will, obtaining moneys
even as I have directed
47 He that is faithful and endureth shall overcome
the world
48 He that sendeth up treasures unto the land of
Zion shall receive an inheritance in this world,
and his works shall follow him, and also a reward in
the world to come
49 Yea, and blessed are the dead that die in the
Lord, from henceforth, when the Lord shall come,
and old things shall pass away, and all things
become new, they shall rise from the dead and shall not
die after, and shall receive an inheritance
before the Lord, in the holy city
50 And he that liveth when the Lord shall come,
and hath kept the faith, blessed is he;
nevertheless, it is appointed to him to die at the age of man
51 Wherefore, children shall grow up until they
become old; old men shall die; but they shall not
sleep in the dust, but they shall be changed in the
twinkling of an eye
52 Wherefore, for this cause preached the apostles
unto the world the resurrection of the dead
53 These things are the things that ye must look
for; and, speaking after the manner of the Lord,
they are now nigh at hand, and in a time to come,
even in the day of the coming of the Son of Man
54 And until that hour there will be foolish
virgins among the wise; and at that hour cometh an
entire separation of the righteous and the wicked; and
in that day will I send mine angels to pluck out
the wicked and cast them into unquenchable fire
55 And now behold, verily I say unto you, I, the
Lord, am not pleased with my servant Sidney Rigdon;
he exalted himself in his heart, and received not
counsel, but grieved the Spirit
56 Wherefore his writing is not acceptable unto
the Lord, and he shall make another; and if the Lord
receive it not, behold he standeth no longer in
the office to which I have appointed him
57 And again, verily I say unto you, those who
desire in their hearts, in meekness, to warn sinners
to repentance, let them be ordained unto this
power
58 For this is a day of warning, and not a day of
many words. For I, the Lord, am not to be mocked
in the last days
59 Behold, I am from above, and my power lieth
beneath. I am over all, and in all, and through all,
and search all things, and the day cometh that all
things shall be subject unto me
60 Behold, I am Alpha and Omega, even Jesus
Christ
61 Wherefore, let all men beware how they take my
name in their lips
62 For behold, verily I say, that many there be
who are under this condemnation, who use the name of
the Lord, and use it in vain, having not
authority
63 Wherefore, let the church repent of their sins,
and I, the Lord, will own them; otherwise they
shall be cut off
64 Remember that that which cometh from above is
sacred, and must be spoken with care, and by
constraint of the Spirit; and in this there is no
condemnation, and ye receive the Spirit through prayer;
wherefore, without this there remaineth
condemnation
65 Let my servants, Joseph Smith, Jun., and Sidney
Rigdon, seek them a home, as they are taught
through prayer by the Spirit
66 These things remain to overcome through
patience, that such may receive a more exceeding and
eternal weight of glory, otherwise, a greater
condemnation. Amen.