Section 126 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, in the house of Brigham Young, at
Nauvoo, Illinois, July 9, 1841. At this time
Brigham Young was President of the Quorum of the
Twelve Apostles.
1–3, Brigham Young is commended for
his labors and is relieved of future travel abroad.
1 Dear and well-beloved brother, Brigham
Young, verily thus saith the Lord unto you:
My servant Brigham, it is no more required
at your hand to leave your family as in
times past, for your offering is acceptable to me.
2 I have seen your labor and
toil in journeyings for my name.
3 I therefore command you
to send my word abroad,
and take especial care of
your family from this time,
henceforth and forever. Amen.