Section 55 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to William W. Phelps, at
Kirtland, Ohio, June 14, 1831. William W. Phelps,
a printer, and his family had just arrived
at Kirtland, and the Prophet sought the Lord
for information concerning him.
1–3,
William W. Phelps is called and chosen to be
baptized, to be ordained an elder, and to preach the
gospel;
4, He is also to write books for
children in Church schools;
5–6, He is to
travel to Missouri, which will be the area of his labors.
1 Behold, thus saith the Lord unto you,
my servant William, yea, even the Lord
of the whole earth, thou art called and
chosen; and after thou hast been baptized
by water, which if you do with an eye
single to my glory, you shall have a
remission of your sins and a reception of
the Holy Spirit by the laying on of hands;
2 And then thou shalt be ordained by
the hand of my servant Joseph Smith,
Jun., to be an elder unto this church,
to preach repentance and remission of
sins by way of baptism in the name of
Jesus Christ, the Son of the living God.
3 And on whomsoever you shall
lay your hands, if they are
contrite before me, you shall
have power to give the Holy Spirit.
4 And again, you shall be
ordained to assist my
servant Oliver Cowdery to do the
work of printing, and of
selecting and writing books
for schools in this church,
that little children also
may receive instruction
before me as is pleasing unto me.
5 And again, verily I say
unto you, for this cause
you shall take your
journey with my servants
Joseph Smith, Jun., and
Sidney Rigdon, that you may be
planted in the land of
your inheritance to do this work.
6 And again, let my
servant Joseph Coe also
take his journey with
them. The residue
shall be made known
hereafter, even as I will. Amen.