Section 106 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, November 25, 1834.
This revelation is directed to Warren A. Cowdery,
an older brother of Oliver Cowdery.
1–3,
Warren A. Cowdery is called as a local presiding officer;
4–5, The Second Coming will not overtake the
children of light as a thief;
6–8, Great blessings
follow faithful service in the Church.
1 It is my will that my servant Warren A. Cowdery
should be appointed and ordained a presiding high
priest over my church, in the land of Freedom and
the regions round about
2 And should preach my everlasting gospel, and
lift up his voice and warn the people, not only in
his own place, but in the adjoining counties
3 And devote his whole time to this high and holy
calling, which I now give unto him, seeking
diligently the kingdom of heaven and its righteousness,
and all things necessary shall be added thereunto;
for the laborer is worthy of his hire
4 And again, verily I say unto you, the coming of
the Lord draweth nigh, and it overtaketh the world
as a thief in the night
5 Therefore, gird up your loins, that you may be
the children of light, and that day shall not
overtake you as a thief
6 And again, verily I say unto you, there was joy
in heaven when my servant Warren bowed to my
scepter, and separated himself from the crafts of men
7 Therefore, blessed is my servant Warren, for I
will have mercy on him; and, notwithstanding the
vanity of his heart, I will lift him up inasmuch as
he will humble himself before me
8 And I will give him grace and assurance
wherewith he may stand; and if he continue to be a
faithful witness and a light unto the church I have
prepared a crown for him in the mansions of my Father.
Even so. Amen.