Section 89 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, February 27, 1833.
As a consequence of the early brethren using
tobacco in their meetings, the Prophet was led to
ponder upon the matter; consequently, he inquired of
the Lord concerning it. This revelation, known as
the Word of Wisdom, was the result.
1–9, The use of
wine, strong drinks, tobacco, and hot drinks is
proscribed;
10–17, Herbs, fruits, flesh, and grain
are ordained for the use of man and of animals;
18–21, Obedience to gospel law, including the Word
of Wisdom, brings temporal and spiritual
blessings.
1 A Word of Wisdom, for the benefit of the council
of high priests, assembled in Kirtland, and the
church, and also the saints in Zion
2 To be sent greeting; not by commandment or
constraint, but by revelation and the word of wisdom,
showing forth the order and will of God in the
temporal salvation of all saints in the last days
3 Given for a principle with promise, adapted to
the capacity of the weak and the weakest of all
saints, who are or can be called saints
4 Behold, verily, thus saith the Lord unto you: In
consequence of evils and designs which do and
will exist in the hearts of conspiring men in the
last days, I have warned you, and forewarn you, by
giving unto you this word of wisdom by revelation
5 That inasmuch as any man drinketh wine or strong
drink among you, behold it is not good, neither
meet in the sight of your Father, only in
assembling yourselves together to offer up your sacraments
before him
6 And, behold, this should be wine, yea, pure wine
of the grape of the vine, of your own make
7 And, again, strong drinks are not for the belly,
but for the washing of your bodies
8 And again, tobacco is not for the body, neither
for the belly, and is not good for man, but is an
herb for bruises and all sick cattle, to be used
with judgment and skill
9 And again, hot drinks are not for the body or
belly
10 And again, verily I say unto you, all wholesome
herbs God hath ordained for the constitution,
nature, and use of man
11 Every herb in the season thereof, and every
fruit in the season thereof; all these to be used
with prudence and thanksgiving
12 Yea, flesh also of beasts and of the fowls of
the air, I, the Lord, have ordained for the use of
man with thanksgiving; nevertheless they are to be
used sparingly
13 And it is pleasing unto me that they should not
be used, only in times of winter, or of cold, or
famine
14 All grain is ordained for the use of man and of
beasts, to be the staff of life, not only for man
but for the beasts of the field, and the fowls of
heaven, and all wild animals that run or creep on
the earth
15 And these hath God made for the use of man only
in times of famine and excess of hunger
16 All grain is good for the food of man; as also
the fruit of the vine; that which yieldeth fruit,
whether in the ground or above the ground
17 Nevertheless, wheat for man, and corn for the
ox, and oats for the horse, and rye for the fowls
and for swine, and for all beasts of the field, and
barley for all useful animals, and for mild
drinks, as also other grain
18 And all saints who remember to keep and do
these sayings, walking in obedience to the
commandments, shall receive health in their navel and marrow
to their bones
19 And shall find wisdom and great treasures of
knowledge, even hidden treasures
20 And shall run and not be weary, and shall walk
and not faint
21 And I, the Lord, give unto them a promise, that
the destroying angel shall pass by them, as the
children of Israel, and not slay them. Amen.