Section 121 Prayer and prophecies written by
Joseph Smith the Prophet in an epistle to the Church
while he was a prisoner in the jail at Liberty,
Missouri, dated March 20, 1839. The Prophet and
several companions had been months in prison. Their
petitions and appeals directed to the executive
officers and the judiciary had failed to bring them
relief.
1–6, The Prophet pleads with the Lord for the
suffering Saints;
7–10, The Lord speaks peace to
him;
11–17, Cursed are all those who raise false
cries of transgression against the Lord’s people;
18–25, They will not have right to the
priesthood and will be damned;
26–32, Glorious revelations
promised those who endure valiantly;
33–40, Why
many are called and few are chosen;
41–46, The
priesthood should be used only in righteousness.
1 O God, where art thou? And where is the pavilion
that covereth thy hiding place
2 How long shall thy hand be stayed, and thine
eye, yea thy pure eye, behold from the eternal
heavens the wrongs of thy people and of thy servants,
and thine ear be penetrated with their cries
3 Yea, O Lord, how long shall they suffer these
wrongs and unlawful oppressions, before thine heart
shall be softened toward them, and thy bowels be
moved with compassion toward them
4 O Lord God Almighty, maker of heaven, earth, and
seas, and of all things that in them are, and who
controllest and subjectest the devil, and the
dark and benighted dominion of Sheol—stretch forth
thy hand; let thine eye pierce; let thy pavilion be
taken up; let thy hiding place no longer be
covered; let thine ear be inclined; let thine heart be
softened, and thy bowels moved with compassion
toward us
5 Let thine anger be kindled against our enemies;
and, in the fury of thine heart, with thy sword
avenge us of our wrongs
6 Remember thy suffering saints, O our God; and
thy servants will rejoice in thy name forever
7 My son, peace be unto thy soul; thine adversity
and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment
8 And then, if thou endure it well, God shall
exalt thee on high; thou shalt triumph over all thy
foes
9 Thy friends do stand by thee, and they shall
hail thee again with warm hearts and friendly hands
10 Thou art not yet as Job; thy friends do not
contend against thee, neither charge thee with
transgression, as they did Job
11 And they who do charge thee with transgression,
their hope shall be blasted, and their prospects
shall melt away as the hoar frost melteth before
the burning rays of the rising sun
12 And also that God hath set his hand and seal to
change the times and seasons, and to blind their
minds, that they may not understand his marvelous
workings; that he may prove them also and take
them in their own craftiness
13 Also because their hearts are corrupted, and
the things which they are willing to bring upon
others, and love to have others suffer, may come upon
themselves to the very uttermost
14 That they may be disappointed also, and their
hopes may be cut off
15 And not many years hence, that they and their
posterity shall be swept from under heaven, saith
God, that not one of them is left to stand by the
wall
16 Cursed are all those that shall lift up the
heel against mine anointed, saith the Lord, and cry
they have sinned when they have not sinned before
me, saith the Lord, but have done that which was
meet in mine eyes, and which I commanded them
17 But those who cry transgression do it because
they are the servants of sin, and are the children
of disobedience themselves
18 And those who swear falsely against my
servants, that they might bring them into bondage and
death
19 Wo unto them; because they have offended my
little ones they shall be severed from the ordinances
of mine house
20 Their basket shall not be full, their houses
and their barns shall perish, and they themselves
shall be despised by those that flattered them
21 They shall not have right to the priesthood,
nor their posterity after them from generation to
generation
22 It had been better for them that a millstone
had been hanged about their necks, and they drowned
in the depth of the sea
23 Wo unto all those that discomfort my people,
and drive, and murder, and testify against them,
saith the Lord of Hosts; a generation of vipers shall
not escape the damnation of hell
24 Behold, mine eyes see and know all their works,
and I have in reserve a swift judgment in the
season thereof, for them all
25 For there is a time appointed for every man,
according as his works shall be
26 God shall give unto you knowledge by his Holy
Spirit, yea, by the unspeakable gift of the Holy
Ghost, that has not been revealed since the world
was until now
27 Which our forefathers have awaited with anxious
expectation to be revealed in the last times,
which their minds were pointed to by the angels, as
held in reserve for the fulness of their glory
28 A time to come in the which nothing shall be
withheld, whether there be one God or many gods,
they shall be manifest
29 All thrones and dominions, principalities and
powers, shall be revealed and set forth upon all
who have endured valiantly for the gospel of Jesus
Christ
30 And also, if there be bounds set to the heavens
or to the seas, or to the dry land, or to the
sun, moon, or stars
31 All the times of their revolutions, all the
appointed days, months, and years, and all the days
of their days, months, and years, and all their
glories, laws, and set times, shall be revealed in
the days of the dispensation of the fulness of
times
32 According to that which was ordained in the
midst of the Council of the Eternal God of all other
gods before this world was, that should be
reserved unto the finishing and the end thereof, when
every man shall enter into his eternal presence and
into his immortal rest
33 How long can rolling waters remain impure? What
power shall stay the heavens? As well might man
stretch forth his puny arm to stop the Missouri
river in its decreed course, or to turn it up stream,
as to hinder the Almighty from pouring down
knowledge from heaven upon the heads of the Latter-day
Saints
34 Behold, there are many called, but few are
chosen. And why are they not chosen
35 Because their hearts are set so much upon the
things of this world, and aspire to the honors of
men, that they do not learn this one lesson
36 That the rights of the priesthood are
inseparably connected with the powers of heaven, and that
the powers of heaven cannot be controlled nor
handled only upon the principles of righteousness
37 That they may be conferred upon us, it is true;
but when we undertake to cover our sins, or to
gratify our pride, our vain ambition, or to exercise
control or dominion or compulsion upon the souls
of the children of men, in any degree of
unrighteousness, behold, the heavens withdraw themselves;
the Spirit of the Lord is grieved; and when it is
withdrawn, Amen to the priesthood or the authority
of that man
38 Behold, ere he is aware, he is left unto
himself, to kick against the pricks, to persecute the
saints, and to fight against God
39 We have learned by sad experience that it is
the nature and disposition of almost all men, as
soon as they get a little authority, as they suppose,
they will immediately begin to exercise
unrighteous dominion
40 Hence many are called, but few are chosen
41 No power or influence can or ought to be
maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by
persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness,
and by love unfeigned
42 By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall
greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and
without guile
43 Reproving betimes with sharpness, when moved
upon by the Holy Ghost; and then showing forth
afterwards an increase of love toward him whom thou
hast reproved, lest he esteem thee to be his enemy
44 That he may know that thy faithfulness is
stronger than the cords of death
45 Let thy bowels also be full of charity towards
all men, and to the household of faith, and let
virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall
thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God;
and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil
upon thy soul as the dews from heaven
46 The Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion,
and thy scepter an unchanging scepter of
righteousness and truth; and thy dominion shall be an
everlasting dominion, and without compulsory means it
shall flow unto thee forever and ever.