Section 25 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet, at Harmony, Pennsylvania,
July 1830 (see the
heading to section 24).
This revelation manifests the will of the Lord
to Emma Smith, the Prophet’s wife.
1–6, Emma
Smith, an elect lady, is called to aid and
comfort her husband;
7–11, She is also called
to write, to expound scriptures, and to
select hymns;
12–14, The song of the righteous is
a prayer unto the Lord;
15–16, Principles
of obedience in this revelation are applicable to all.
1 Hearken unto the voice of the Lord
your God, while I speak unto you, Emma
Smith, my daughter; for verily I say
unto you, all those who receive my
gospel are sons and daughters in my kingdom.
2 A revelation I give unto you
concerning my will; and if thou
art faithful and walk in the
paths of virtue before me, I
will preserve thy life, and thou
shalt receive an inheritance in Zion.
3 Behold, thy sins are
forgiven thee, and thou art an
elect lady, whom I have called.
4 Murmur not because of
the things which thou hast
not seen, for they are
withheld from thee and
from the world, which is
wisdom in me in a time to come.
5 And the office of thy
calling shall be for a
comfort unto my servant,
Joseph Smith, Jun., thy
husband, in his
afflictions, with consoling
words, in the spirit of meekness.
6 And thou shalt go
with him at the time
of his going, and be
unto him for a scribe,
while there is no
one to be a scribe for
him, that I may send
my servant, Oliver
Cowdery, whithersoever I will.
7 And thou shalt be
ordained under his
hand to expound
scriptures, and to exhort
the church,
according as it shall be
given thee by my Spirit.
8 For he shall lay
his hands upon thee,
and thou shalt
receive the Holy Ghost,
and thy time shall be
given to writing,
and to learning much.
9 And thou needest
not fear, for thy
husband shall
support thee in the
church; for unto them is
his calling, that
all things might be
revealed unto
them, whatsoever I
will, according to their faith.
10 And verily I
say unto thee
that thou shalt
lay aside the
things of this
world, and seek for
the things of a better.
11 And it shall
be given thee,
also, to make
a selection of
sacred hymns,
as it shall be
given thee,
which is pleasing
unto me, to be
had in my church.
12 For my soul
delighteth in
the song of
the heart; yea,
the righteous
is a prayer
unto me, and it
shall be
answered with a
blessing upon their heads.
13 Wherefore,
lift up thy
heart and
rejoice, and
cleave unto the
covenants
which thou hast made.
14 Continue
in the
spirit of
meekness, and
beware of pride.
Let thy soul
delight in
thy husband,
and the
glory which
shall come upon him.
15 Keep my
commandments
continually, and a
crown of
righteousness
thou shalt
receive.
And except
thou do this,
where I am
you cannot come.
16 And
verily, verily,
I say unto
you, that
this is my
voice unto
all. Amen.