Section 4 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet to his father, Joseph Smith Sr.,
at Harmony, Pennsylvania, February 1829.
1–4,
Valiant service saves the Lord’s ministers;
5–6, Godly attributes qualify them for the
ministry;
7, The things of God must be sought after.
1 Now behold, a marvelous work is about
to come forth among the children of men.
2 Therefore, O ye that embark in
the service of God, see that ye serve
him with all your heart, might,
mind and strength, that ye may stand
blameless before God at the last day.
3 Therefore, if ye have
desires to serve God
ye are called to the work;
4 For behold the
field is white already to
harvest; and lo, he
that thrusteth in his
sickle with his
might, the same layeth up
in store that he
perisheth not, but
bringeth salvation to his soul;
5 And faith, hope,
charity and love,
with an eye single to
the glory of God,
qualify him for the work.
6 Remember faith,
virtue, knowledge,
temperance,
patience, brotherly
kindness, godliness,
charity, humility, diligence.
7 Ask, and ye
shall receive; knock,
and it shall be
opened unto you. Amen.