Section 5 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Harmony, Pennsylvania, March 1829,
at the request of Martin Harris.
1–10, This
generation will receive the Lord’s word through Joseph
Smith;
11–18, Three witnesses will testify of the
Book of Mormon;
19–20, The word of the Lord will
be verified as in previous times;
21–35, Martin
Harris may repent and be one of the witnesses.
1 Behold, I say unto you, that as my servant
Martin Harris has desired a witness at my hand, that
you, my servant Joseph Smith, Jun., have got the
plates of which you have testified and borne record
that you have received of me
2 And now, behold, this shall you say unto him—he
who spake unto you, said unto you: I, the Lord, am
God, and have given these things unto you, my
servant Joseph Smith, Jun., and have commanded you
that you should stand as a witness of these things
3 And I have caused you that you should enter into
a covenant with me, that you should not show them
except to those persons to whom I commanded you;
and you have no power over them except I grant it
unto you
4 And you have a gift to translate the plates; and
this is the first gift that I bestowed upon you;
and I have commanded that you should pretend to no
other gift until my purpose is fulfilled in this;
for I will grant unto you no other gift until it
is finished
5 Verily, I say unto you, that woe shall come unto
the inhabitants of the earth if they will not
hearken unto my words
6 For hereafter you shall be ordained and go forth
and deliver my words unto the children of men
7 Behold, if they will not believe my words, they
would not believe you, my servant Joseph, if it
were possible that you should show them all these
things which I have committed unto you
8 Oh, this unbelieving and stiffnecked
generation—mine anger is kindled against them
9 Behold, verily I say unto you, I have reserved
those things which I have entrusted unto you, my
servant Joseph, for a wise purpose in me, and it
shall be made known unto future generations
10 But this generation shall have my word through
you
11 And in addition to your testimony, the
testimony of three of my servants, whom I shall call and
ordain, unto whom I will show these things, and
they shall go forth with my words that are given
through you
12 Yea, they shall know of a surety that these
things are true, for from heaven will I declare it
unto them
13 I will give them power that they may behold and
view these things as they are
14 And to none else will I grant this power, to
receive this same testimony among this generation,
in this the beginning of the rising up and the
coming forth of my church out of the wilderness—clear
as the moon, and fair as the sun, and terrible as
an army with banners
15 And the testimony of three witnesses will I
send forth of my word
16 And behold, whosoever believeth on my words,
them will I visit with the manifestation of my
Spirit; and they shall be born of me, even of water and
of the Spirit
17 And you must wait yet a little while, for ye
are not yet ordained
18 And their testimony shall also go forth unto
the condemnation of this generation if they harden
their hearts against them
19 For a desolating scourge shall go forth among
the inhabitants of the earth, and shall continue to
be poured out from time to time, if they repent
not, until the earth is empty, and the inhabitants
thereof are consumed away and utterly destroyed by
the brightness of my coming
20 Behold, I tell you these things, even as I also
told the people of the destruction of Jerusalem;
and my word shall be verified at this time as it
hath hitherto been verified
21 And now I command you, my servant Joseph, to
repent and walk more uprightly before me, and to
yield to the persuasions of men no more
22 And that you be firm in keeping the
commandments wherewith I have commanded you; and if you do
this, behold I grant unto you eternal life, even if
you should be slain
23 And now, again, I speak unto you, my servant
Joseph, concerning the man that desires the witness
24 Behold, I say unto him, he exalts himself and
does not humble himself sufficiently before me; but
if he will bow down before me, and humble himself
in mighty prayer and faith, in the sincerity of
his heart, then will I grant unto him a view of the
things which he desires to see
25 And then he shall say unto the people of this
generation: Behold, I have seen the things which
the Lord hath shown unto Joseph Smith, Jun., and I
know of a surety that they are true, for I have
seen them, for they have been shown unto me by the
power of God and not of man
26 And I the Lord command him, my servant Martin
Harris, that he shall say no more unto them
concerning these things, except he shall say: I have seen
them, and they have been shown unto me by the
power of God; and these are the words which he shall
say
27 But if he deny this he will break the covenant
which he has before covenanted with me, and
behold, he is condemned
28 And now, except he humble himself and
acknowledge unto me the things that he has done which are
wrong, and covenant with me that he will keep my
commandments, and exercise faith in me, behold, I
say unto him, he shall have no such views, for I
will grant unto him no views of the things of which I
have spoken
29 And if this be the case, I command you, my
servant Joseph, that you shall say unto him, that he
shall do no more, nor trouble me any more
concerning this matter
30 And if this be the case, behold, I say unto
thee Joseph, when thou hast translated a few more
pages thou shalt stop for a season, even until I
command thee again; then thou mayest translate again
31 And except thou do this, behold, thou shalt
have no more gift, and I will take away the things
which I have entrusted with thee
32 And now, because I foresee the lying in wait to
destroy thee, yea, I foresee that if my servant
Martin Harris humbleth not himself and receive a
witness from my hand, that he will fall into
transgression
33 And there are many that lie in wait to destroy
thee from off the face of the earth; and for this
cause, that thy days may be prolonged, I have
given unto thee these commandments
34 Yea, for this cause I have said: Stop, and
stand still until I command thee, and I will provide
means whereby thou mayest accomplish the thing
which I have commanded thee
35 And if thou art faithful in keeping my
commandments, thou shalt be lifted up at the last day.
Amen.