verses 24 through 26 were given, providing
instructions concerning the gathering to Zion.
1–8,
Elders are to render an account of their
stewardship unto the bishop;
9–15, The bishop keeps the
storehouse and cares for the poor and needy;
16–26, Bishops are to certify the worthiness of elders.
1 Hearken, and listen to the voice of the
Lord, O ye who have assembled yourselves
together, who are the high priests of my church,
to whom the kingdom and power have been given.
2 For verily thus saith the Lord, it is
expedient in me for a bishop to be
appointed unto you, or of you, unto the
church in this part of the Lord’s vineyard.
3 And verily in this thing ye have
done wisely, for it is required of
the Lord, at the hand of every
steward, to render an account of his
stewardship, both in time and in eternity.
4 For he who is faithful and
wise in time is accounted
worthy to inherit the mansions
prepared for him of my Father.
5 Verily I say unto you, the
elders of the church in
this part of my vineyard shall
render an account of their
stewardship unto the bishop,
who shall be appointed of me
in this part of my vineyard.
6 These things shall be had
on record, to be handed
over unto the bishop in Zion.
7 And the duty of the
bishop shall be made known
by the commandments
which have been given, and
the voice of the conference.
8 And now, verily I
say unto you, my
servant Newel K. Whitney
is the man who shall
be appointed and
ordained unto this power.
This is the will of
the Lord your God,
your Redeemer. Even so. Amen.
9 The word of the
Lord, in addition to
the law which has
been given, making
known the duty of
the bishop who has
been ordained unto
the church in this
part of the
vineyard, which is verily this—
10 To keep the
Lord’s
storehouse; to receive the
funds of the
church in this
part of the vineyard;
11 To take an
account of the
elders as before
has been
commanded; and to
administer to
their wants, who
shall pay for
that which they
receive,
inasmuch as they have
wherewith to pay;
12 That this
also may be
consecrated to
the good of the
church, to the
poor and needy.
13 And he who
hath not
wherewith to
pay, an account
shall be
taken and handed
over to the
bishop of
Zion, who shall
pay the debt
out of that
which the Lord
shall put into his hands.
14 And the
labors of the
faithful
who labor in
spiritual
things, in
administering
the gospel and
the things
of the
kingdom unto the
church, and
unto the
world, shall
answer the
debt unto the bishop in Zion;
15 Thus it
cometh out
of the
church, for
according to
the law
every man that
cometh up
to Zion must
lay all
things before
the bishop in Zion.
16 And
now, verily I
say unto
you, that
as every
elder in
this part of
the
vineyard must
give an
account of
his
stewardship unto
the bishop
in this
part of the vineyard—
17 A
certificate
from the
judge or
bishop in
this part
of the
vineyard,
unto the
bishop in
Zion,
rendereth
every man
acceptable, and
answereth
all
things, for an
inheritance, and
to be
received as a
wise
steward and as a faithful laborer;
Otherwise he
shall
not be
accepted of
the
bishop of Zion.
19 And
now,
verily I
say
unto you,
let
every
elder who
shall
give an
account
unto
the
bishop of
church in
this part
of the
vineyard be
recommended by
the
church or
churches, in
which he
labors, that
he may
render
himself
and
his accounts approved in all things.
20 And
again, let
my
servants
who
are
appointed
as
stewards
over
the
literary
concerns of
my
church
have
claim for
assistance
upon
the
bishop or bishops in all things—
That
the
revelations
may be
published, and
go
forth
unto
the
ends
of the
earth;
that
they
also
may
obtain
funds
which
shall
benefit the church in all things;
That
they
also
may
render
themselves
approved
in
all
things,
and
be
accounted as wise stewards.
And
now,
behold,
this
shall
be
an
ensample
for
all
the
extensive
branches
of
my
church,
in
whatsoever
land
they
shall
be
established. And now I make an end of my sayings. Amen.
A
few
words
in
addition
to
the
laws
of
the
kingdom,
respecting
the
members
of
the
church—they
that
are
appointed
by
the
Holy
Spirit
to go up unto Zion, and they who are privileged to go up unto Zion—
25 Let them carry up unto the bishop a certificate from three elders of the church, or a certificate from the
Let
them
carry
up
unto
the
bishop
a
certificate
from
three elders of the church, or a certificate from the bishop;
26 Otherwise he who shall go up unto the land of Zion shall not be accounted as a wise steward. This is also an ensample. Amen.
Otherwise
he
who
shall
go
up
unto
the
land
of
Zion
shall
not
be
accounted
as
a
wise
steward.
This
is
also
an
ensample.
Amen.
verses 9 through 23 were received, giving additional information as to a bishop’s duties. Thereafter,
through
were
received,
giving
additional
information
as
to
a
bishop’s
duties.
Thereafter,
Verses 1 through 8 make known the calling of Newel K. Whitney as a bishop. He was then called and ordained, after which
through
make
known
the
calling
of
Newel K.
Whitney
as
a
bishop.
He
was
then
called
and
ordained,
after
which
Section 72 Revelation given through Joseph Smith the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, December 4, 1831. Several elders and members had assembled to learn their duty and to be further edified in the teachings of the Church. This section is a compilation of three revelations received on the same day.
Revelation
given
through
Joseph
Smith
the
Prophet,
at
Kirtland,
Ohio,
December
4,
1831.
Several
elders
and
members
had
assembled
to
learn
their
duty
and
to
be
further
edified
in
the
teachings
of
the
Church.
This
section
is
a
compilation
of
three
revelations
received
on
the
same
day.