Section 23 A series of five revelations given
through Joseph Smith the Prophet, at Manchester,
New York, April 1830, to Oliver Cowdery, Hyrum
Smith, Samuel H. Smith, Joseph Smith Sr., and
Joseph Knight Sr. As the result of earnest
desire on the part of the five persons named to
know of their respective duties, the Prophet
inquired of the Lord and received a revelation for
each person.
1–7, These early disciples are
called to preach, exhort, and strengthen the Church.
1 Behold, I speak unto you, Oliver, a few
words. Behold, thou art blessed, and art
under no condemnation. But beware of pride,
lest thou shouldst enter into temptation.
2 Make known thy calling unto the
church, and also before the world, and thy
heart shall be opened to preach the
truth from henceforth and forever. Amen.
3 Behold, I speak unto you, Hyrum, a
few words; for thou also art under no
condemnation, and thy heart is
opened, and thy tongue loosed; and thy
calling is to exhortation, and to
strengthen the church continually.
Wherefore thy duty is unto the church
forever, and this because of thy family. Amen.
4 Behold, I speak a few words unto
you, Samuel; for thou also art under
no condemnation, and thy calling is
to exhortation, and to strengthen
the church; and thou art not as yet
called to preach before the world. Amen.
5 Behold, I speak a few words unto
you, Joseph; for thou also art
under no condemnation, and thy calling
also is to exhortation, and to
strengthen the church; and this is thy
duty from henceforth and forever. Amen.
6 Behold, I manifest unto you,
Joseph Knight, by these words, that
you must take up your cross, in
the which you must pray vocally
before the world as well as in
secret, and in your family, and
among your friends, and in all places.
7 And, behold, it is your
duty to unite with the true
church, and give your
language to exhortation
continually, that you may receive
the reward of the laborer. Amen.