Section 30 Revelation given through Joseph
Smith the Prophet to David Whitmer, Peter Whitmer
Jr., and John Whitmer, at Fayette, New York,
September 1830, following the three-day conference
at Fayette, but before the elders of the
Church had separated. Originally this material was
published as three revelations; it was combined
into one section by the Prophet for the 1835
edition of the Doctrine and Covenants.
1–4,
David Whitmer is chastened for failure to serve
diligently;
5–8, Peter Whitmer Jr. is to
accompany Oliver Cowdery on a mission to the Lamanites;
9–11, John Whitmer is called to preach the gospel.
1 Behold, I say unto you, David,
that you have feared man and have not
relied on me for strength as you ought.
2 But your mind has been on the
things of the earth more than on the
things of me, your Maker, and the
ministry whereunto you have been
called; and you have not given heed
unto my Spirit, and to those who were
set over you, but have been
persuaded by those whom I have not commanded.
3 Wherefore, you are left to
inquire for yourself at my
hand, and ponder upon the
things which you have received.
4 And your home shall be
at your father’s house,
until I give unto you
further commandments. And you
shall attend to the
ministry in the church, and
before the world, and in
the regions round about. Amen.
5 Behold, I say unto
you, Peter, that you shall
take your journey with
your brother Oliver; for
the time has come that
it is expedient in me
that you shall open your
mouth to declare my
gospel; therefore, fear not,
but give heed unto the
words and advice of your
brother, which he shall give you.
6 And be you afflicted
in all his afflictions,
ever lifting up your
heart unto me in prayer
and faith, for his and
your deliverance; for I
have given unto him
power to build up my
church among the Lamanites;
7 And none have I
appointed to be his
counselor over him in
the church,
concerning church matters,
except it is his
brother, Joseph Smith, Jun.
8 Wherefore, give
heed unto these
things and be diligent
in keeping my
commandments, and you
shall be blessed unto
eternal life. Amen.
9 Behold, I say
unto you, my
servant John, that
thou shalt commence
from this time
forth to proclaim
my gospel, as with
the voice of a trump.
10 And your
labor shall be at
your brother
Philip Burroughs’,
and in that region
round about,
yea, wherever you
can be heard,
until I command
you to go from hence.
11 And your
whole labor shall
be in Zion,
with all your
soul, from
henceforth; yea, you
shall ever open
your mouth in my
cause, not
fearing what man
can do, for I am
with you. Amen.