Section 43 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, at Kirtland, Ohio, in February
1831. At this time some members of the Church were
disturbed by people making false claims as
revelators. The Prophet inquired of the Lord and
received this communication addressed to the elders
of the Church. The first part deals with matters
of Church polity; the latter part contains a
warning that the elders are to give to the nations
of the earth.
1–7, Revelations and
commandments come only through the one appointed;
8–14,
The Saints are sanctified by acting in all
holiness before the Lord;
15–22, Elders are sent forth
to cry repentance and prepare men for the great
day of the Lord;
23–28, The Lord calls upon
men by His own voice and through the forces of
nature;
29–35, The Millennium and the binding of Satan will come.
1 O hearken, ye elders of my church, and give
ear to the words which I shall speak unto you.
2 For behold, verily, verily, I say unto
you, that ye have received a
commandment for a law unto my church, through him
whom I have appointed unto you to
receive commandments and revelations from my hand.
3 And this ye shall know assuredly—that
there is none other appointed unto you
to receive commandments and
revelations until he be taken, if he abide in me.
4 But verily, verily, I say unto
you, that none else shall be
appointed unto this gift except it be
through him; for if it be taken from
him he shall not have power
except to appoint another in his stead.
5 And this shall be a law unto
you, that ye receive not the
teachings of any that shall come before
you as revelations or commandments;
6 And this I give unto you that
you may not be deceived, that
you may know they are not of me.
7 For verily I say unto you,
that he that is ordained of
me shall come in at the gate
and be ordained as I have told
you before, to teach those
revelations which you have
received and shall receive
through him whom I have appointed.
8 And now, behold, I give
unto you a commandment, that
when ye are assembled
together ye shall instruct and
edify each other, that ye
may know how to act and
direct my church, how to act
upon the points of my law and
commandments, which I have given.
9 And thus ye shall
become instructed in the law
of my church, and be
sanctified by that which ye
have received, and ye shall
bind yourselves to act
in all holiness before me—
10 That inasmuch as ye
do this, glory shall be
added to the kingdom
which ye have received.
Inasmuch as ye do it not, it
shall be taken, even
that which ye have received.
11 Purge ye out the
iniquity which is
among you; sanctify
yourselves before me;
12 And if ye
desire the glories of
the kingdom,
appoint ye my
servant Joseph Smith,
Jun., and uphold
him before me by
the prayer of faith.
13 And again, I
say unto you,
that if ye desire
the mysteries of
the kingdom,
provide for him
food and raiment,
and whatsoever
thing he needeth
to accomplish
the work wherewith
I have commanded him;
14 And if ye do
it not he shall
remain unto them
that have
received him, that I
may reserve unto
myself a pure
people before me.
15 Again I say,
hearken ye
elders of my
church, whom I have
appointed: Ye
are not sent
forth to be
taught, but to teach
the children of
men the things
which I have
put into your
hands by the
power of my Spirit;
16 And ye are
to be taught
from on
high. Sanctify
yourselves and
ye shall be
endowed with
power, that ye
may give
even as I have spoken.
17 Hearken
ye, for,
behold, the
great day of
the Lord
is nigh at hand.
18 For the
day
cometh that the
Lord
shall utter
his voice
out of
heaven; the
heavens shall
shake and
the earth
shall
tremble, and
the trump
of God
shall sound
both long
and loud,
and shall
say to the
sleeping
nations: Ye
saints
arise and
live; ye
sinners stay
and sleep until I shall call again.
Wherefore gird
up your
loins lest
ye be
found among
the wicked.
20 Lift
up your
voices
and spare
not.
Call upon
the
nations to
repent,
both old
and
young, both
bond and
free,
saying:
Prepare
yourselves for
the great day of the Lord;
21 For
if I, who
am a
man, do
lift up my
voice
and call
upon you
to
repent, and
ye hate
me, what
will ye
say
when the
day cometh
when
the
thunders shall
utter
their
voices from
the
ends of the
earth,
speaking
to the
ears of
all that
live,
saying—Repent,
and
prepare for
the great
day of
the Lord?
22 Yea,
and
again,
when the
lightnings
shall
streak
forth from
the
east unto
west, and
shall
utter
forth
their
voices unto
all
that
live, and
make the
ears
of all
tingle
that
hear,
saying
these
words—Repent
ye,
for the great day of the Lord is come?
23 And
again, the
Lord
shall
utter
his
voice out
of
heaven,
saying:
Hearken, O
ye
nations
of the
earth, and
hear
the
words of
that God who made you.
24 O,
ye
nations of
the
earth,
how
often
would I
have
gathered
you
together
as a
hen
gathereth
her
chickens
under
her wings, but ye would not!
How
oft
have
I
called
upon
you by
the
mouth
of my
servants,
and
by
the
ministering of
angels,
and
by
mine
own
voice,
and
by
the
voice
of
thunderings,
and
by
the
voice of
lightnings,
and
by
the
voice of
tempests,
and
by
the
voice
of
earthquakes,
and
great
hailstorms,
and by
the
voice
of
famines
and
pestilences of
every
kind,
and
by
the
great
sound
of a
trump,
and
by
the
voice
of
judgment,
and by
the
voice
of
mercy
all
the
day
long,
and by
the
voice
of
glory and honor and the riches of eternal life, and would have saved you with an everlasting salvation, but ye would not!
Behold,
the
day
has
come,
when
the
cup
of
the
wrath
of
mine indignation is full.
Behold,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
that
these
are
the
words of the Lord your God.
28 Wherefore, labor ye, labor ye in my vineyard for the last time—for the last time call upon the inhabitants of the
Wherefore,
labor
ye,
ye
in
my
vineyard
for
the
last
time—for the last time call upon the inhabitants of the earth.
29 For in mine own due time will I come upon the earth in judgment, and my people shall be redeemed and shall reign with me on
For
in
mine
own
due
time
will
I
come
upon
the
earth
in
judgment,
and
my
people
shall
be
redeemed
and
shall
reign
with
me
on
earth.
30 For the great Millennium, of which I have spoken by the mouth of my servants, shall
For
the
great
Millennium,
of
which
I
have
spoken
by
the
mouth
of
my
servants,
shall
come.
31 For Satan shall be bound, and when he is loosed again he shall only reign for a little season, and then cometh the end of the
For
Satan
shall
be
bound,
and
when
he
is
loosed
again
he
shall
only
reign
for
a
little
season,
and
then
cometh
the
end
of
the
earth.
32 And he that liveth in righteousness shall be changed in the twinkling of an eye, and the earth shall pass away so as by
And
he
that
liveth
in
righteousness
shall
be
changed
in
the
twinkling
of
an
eye,
and
the
earth
shall
pass
away
so
as
by
fire.
33 And the wicked shall go away into unquenchable fire, and their end no man knoweth on earth, nor ever shall know, until they come before me in
And
the
wicked
shall
go
away
into
unquenchable
fire,
and
their
end
no
man
knoweth
on
earth,
nor
ever
shall
know,
until
they
come
before
me
in
judgment.
34 Hearken ye to these words. Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Savior of the world. Treasure these things up in your hearts, and let the solemnities of eternity rest upon your
Hearken
ye
to
these
words.
Behold,
I
am
Jesus
Christ,
the
Savior
of
the
world.
Treasure
these
things
up
in
your
hearts,
and
let
the
solemnities
of
eternity
rest
upon
your
minds.
35 Be sober. Keep all my commandments. Even so. Amen.
Be
sober.
Keep
all
my
commandments.
Even
so.
Amen.