sections 15 and
16) were given in answer to
an inquiry through the Urim and Thummim.
David Whitmer later became one of the Three
Witnesses to the Book of Mormon.
1–6, Laborers in
the vineyard will gain salvation;
7–8,
Eternal life is the greatest of God’s gifts;
9–11, Christ created the heavens and the earth.
1 A great and marvelous work is about
to come forth unto the children of men.
2 Behold, I am God; give heed to my
word, which is quick and powerful,
sharper than a two-edged sword, to the
dividing asunder of both joints and
marrow; therefore give heed unto my word.
3 Behold, the field is white
already to harvest; therefore, whoso
desireth to reap let him thrust in
his sickle with his might, and reap
while the day lasts, that he may
treasure up for his soul
everlasting salvation in the kingdom of God.
4 Yea, whosoever will
thrust in his sickle and reap,
the same is called of God.
5 Therefore, if you will
ask of me you shall
receive; if you will knock it
shall be opened unto you.
6 Seek to bring
forth and establish my
Zion. Keep my
commandments in all things.
7 And, if you keep
my commandments and
endure to the end
you shall have
eternal life, which
gift is the greatest
of all the gifts of God.
8 And it shall
come to pass, that if
you shall ask the
Father in my
name, in faith
believing, you shall
receive the Holy
Ghost, which giveth
utterance, that you
may stand as a
witness of the things
of which you shall
both hear and
see, and also that
you may declare
repentance unto this generation.
9 Behold, I am
Jesus Christ, the
Son of the
living God, who
created the heavens
and the earth, a
light which
cannot be hid in darkness;
10 Wherefore,
I must bring
forth the
fulness of my
gospel from the
Gentiles unto the
house of Israel.
11 And
behold, thou art
David, and thou
art called
to assist;
which thing if
ye do, and are
faithful, ye
shall be
blessed both
spiritually and
temporally,
and great
shall be your reward. Amen.
Section 14
Revelation
given through
Joseph Smith
the Prophet
to David
Whitmer, at
Fayette, New
York, June
1829. The
Whitmer family
had become
greatly
interested in the
translating
of the Book
of Mormon.
The Prophet
established
his residence
at the home
of Peter
Whitmer Sr.,
where he
dwelt until the
work of
translation was
carried to
completion
and the
copyright on the
forthcoming
book was
secured. Three
of the
Whitmer sons, each
having
received a
testimony as to
the
genuineness of the
work, became
deeply
concerned over the
matter of
their
individual duty. This revelation and the two following (