Section 61 Revelation given through Joseph Smith
the Prophet, on the bank of the Missouri River,
McIlwaine’s Bend, August 12, 1831. On their
return trip to Kirtland, the Prophet and ten elders
had traveled down the Missouri River in canoes.
On the third day of the journey, many dangers
were experienced. Elder William W. Phelps, in a
daylight vision, saw the destroyer riding in
power upon the face of the waters.
1–12, The Lord
has decreed many destructions upon the waters;
13–22, The waters were cursed by John, and the
destroyer rides upon their face;
23–29, Some have
power to command the waters;
30–35, Elders are
to journey two by two and preach the gospel;
36–39, They are to prepare for the coming of the Son of Man.
1 Behold, and hearken unto the voice
of him who has all power, who is from
everlasting to everlasting, even
Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end.
2 Behold, verily thus saith the
Lord unto you, O ye elders of my
church, who are assembled upon this
spot, whose sins are now forgiven
you, for I, the Lord, forgive sins,
and am merciful unto those who
confess their sins with humble hearts;
3 But verily I say unto you,
that it is not needful for this
whole company of mine elders to be
moving swiftly upon the waters,
whilst the inhabitants on either
side are perishing in unbelief.
4 Nevertheless, I suffered
it that ye might bear
record; behold, there are many
dangers upon the waters, and
more especially hereafter;
5 For I, the Lord, have
decreed in mine anger
many destructions upon
the waters; yea, and
especially upon these waters.
6 Nevertheless, all
flesh is in mine hand,
and he that is
faithful among you shall
not perish by the waters.
7 Wherefore, it is
expedient that my
servant Sidney
Gilbert and my servant
William W. Phelps be
in haste upon
their errand and mission.
8 Nevertheless, I
would not suffer
that ye should part
until you were
chastened for all
your sins, that you
might be one, that
you might not
perish in wickedness;
9 But now, verily
I say, it
behooveth me that ye
should part.
Wherefore let my
servants Sidney Gilbert
and William W.
Phelps take their
former company,
and let them take
their journey in
haste that they
may fill their
mission, and through
faith they shall overcome;
10 And inasmuch
as they are
faithful they shall
be preserved,
and I, the Lord,
will be with them.
11 And let the
residue take
that which is
needful for clothing.
12 Let my
servant Sidney
Gilbert take
that which is
not needful
with him, as
you shall agree.
13 And now,
behold, for
your good I
gave unto
you a
commandment
concerning these
things; and I,
the Lord,
will reason
with you as
with men in days of old.
14 Behold,
I, the
Lord, in the
beginning
blessed the
waters; but
in the last
days, by
the mouth of
my servant
John, I
cursed the waters.
Wherefore, the days
will come
that no
flesh shall be
safe upon
the waters.
16 And it
shall be
said in
days to come
that none
is able to
go up to
the land
of Zion
upon the
waters, but he
that is
upright in heart.
17 And,
as I, the
Lord, in
the
beginning
cursed the
land, even
so in the
last
days have I
blessed
it, in its
time,
for the use
of my
saints,
that they
may partake
the fatness thereof.
18 And
now I
give unto
you a
commandment
that
what I say
unto
one I say
all, that
you shall
forewarn your
brethren
concerning these
waters,
that
they come
not in
journeying upon
them,
lest their
faith
fail and they are caught in snares;
19 I,
the
Lord, have
decreed, and
the
destroyer
rideth
upon the
face
thereof,
and I
revoke
not the decree.
20 I,
the
Lord,
was
angry with
you
yesterday,
but
today mine
anger
is turned away.
Wherefore,
let
those
concerning
whom
I
have
spoken,
that
should
take
their
journey
in
haste—again
I
say
unto
you, let
them
take their journey in haste.
And
it
mattereth
not
unto
me,
after a
little,
if
it
so be
that
they
fill
their
mission,
whether
they
go
by
water
or
by
land;
let
this
be
as
it is
made
known
unto
them according to their judgments hereafter.
And
now,
concerning
my
servants,
Sidney
Rigdon,
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.,
and
Oliver
Cowdery,
let
them
come
not
again
upon
the
waters,
save
it
be
upon
the
canal,
while
journeying
unto
their
homes; or
in
other
words
they
shall
not
come
upon
the
waters
to
journey,
save
upon
the
canal.
Behold,
I,
the
Lord,
have
appointed a
way
for
the
journeying
of
my
saints;
and
behold,
this
is
the
way—that
after
they
leave
the
canal
they
shall
journey
by
land,
inasmuch
as
they
are
commanded
to
journey
and
go
up
unto
the
land
of
Zion;
And
they
shall
do
like
unto
the
children
of
Israel,
pitching
their tents by the way.
And,
behold,
this
commandment
you
shall
give unto all your brethren.
27 Nevertheless, unto whom is given power to command the waters, unto him it is given by the Spirit to know all his
Nevertheless,
unto
whom
is
given
power
to
command
the
waters, unto him it is given by the Spirit to know all his ways;
28 Wherefore, let him do as the Spirit of the living God commandeth him, whether upon the land or upon the waters, as it remaineth with me to do
Wherefore,
Spirit
of
the
living
God
commandeth
him,
whether
upon
the
land
or
upon
the
waters,
as
it
remaineth
with
me
to
do
hereafter.
29 And unto you is given the course for the saints, or the way for the saints of the camp of the Lord, to
And
unto
you
is
given
the
course
for
the
saints,
saints
of
the
camp
of
the
Lord,
to
journey.
30 And again, verily I say unto you, my servants, Sidney Rigdon, Joseph Smith, Jun., and Oliver Cowdery, shall not open their mouths in the congregations of the wicked until they arrive at
And
again,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
my
servants,
Sidney
Rigdon,
Joseph
Smith,
Jun.,
and
Oliver
Cowdery,
shall
not
open
their
mouths
in
the
congregations
of
the
wicked
until
they
arrive
at
Cincinnati;
31 And in that place they shall lift up their voices unto God against that people, yea, unto him whose anger is kindled against their wickedness, a people who are well-nigh ripened for
And
in
that
place
they
shall
lift
up
their
voices
unto
God
against
that
people,
yea,
unto
him
whose
anger
is
kindled
against
their
wickedness,
a
people
who
are
well-nigh
ripened
for
destruction.
32 And from thence let them journey for the congregations of their brethren, for their labors even now are wanted more abundantly among them than among the congregations of the
And
from
thence
let
them
journey
for
the
congregations
of
their
brethren,
for
their
labors
even
now
are
wanted
more
abundantly
among
them
than
among
the
congregations
of
the
wicked.
33 And now, concerning the residue, let them journey and declare the word among the congregations of the wicked, inasmuch as it is
And
now,
concerning
the
residue,
let
them
journey
and
declare
the
word
among
the
congregations
of
the
wicked,
inasmuch
as
it
is
given;
34 And inasmuch as they do this they shall rid their garments, and they shall be spotless before
And
inasmuch
as
they
do
this
they
shall
rid
their
garments,
and
they
shall
be
spotless
before
me.
35 And let them journey together, or two by two, as seemeth them good, only let my servant Reynolds Cahoon, and my servant Samuel H. Smith, with whom I am well pleased, be not separated until they return to their homes, and this for a wise purpose in
And
let
them
journey
together,
or
two
by
two,
as
seemeth
them
good,
only
let
my
servant
Reynolds
Cahoon,
and
my
servant
Samuel H.
Smith,
with
whom
I
am
well
pleased,
be
not
separated
until
they
return
to
their
homes,
and
this
for
a
wise
purpose
in
me.
36 And now, verily I say unto you, and what I say unto one I say unto all, be of good cheer, little children; for I am in your midst, and I have not forsaken
And
now,
verily
I
say
unto
you,
and
what
I
say
unto
one
I
say
unto
all,
be
of
good
cheer,
little
children;
for
I
am
in
your
midst,
and
I
have
not
forsaken
you;
37 And inasmuch as you have humbled yourselves before me, the blessings of the kingdom are
And
inasmuch
as
you
have
humbled
yourselves
before
me,
the
blessings
of
the
kingdom
are
yours.
38 Gird up your loins and be watchful and be sober, looking forth for the coming of the Son of Man, for he cometh in an hour you think
Gird
up
your
loins
and
be
watchful
and
be
sober,
looking
forth
for
the
coming
of
the
Son
of
Man,
for
he
cometh
in
an
hour
you
think
not.
39 Pray always that you enter not into temptation, that you may abide the day of his coming, whether in life or in death. Even so. Amen.
Pray
always
that
you
enter
not
into
temptation,
that
you
may
abide
the
day
of
his
coming,
whether
in
life
or
in
death.
Even
so.
Amen.