Section 65 Revelation on prayer given through
Joseph Smith the Prophet, at Hiram, Ohio, October
30, 1831.
1–2, The keys of the kingdom of God are
committed to man on earth, and the gospel cause
will triumph;
3–6, The millennial kingdom of
heaven will come and join the kingdom of God on earth.
1 Hearken, and lo, a voice as of one sent
down from on high, who is mighty and powerful,
whose going forth is unto the ends of the
earth, yea, whose voice is unto men—Prepare
ye the way of the Lord, make his paths straight.
2 The keys of the kingdom of God are
committed unto man on the earth, and from
thence shall the gospel roll forth unto the
ends of the earth, as the stone which is cut
out of the mountain without hands shall
roll forth, until it has filled the whole earth.
3 Yea, a voice crying—Prepare ye the
way of the Lord, prepare ye the supper of
the Lamb, make ready for the Bridegroom.
4 Pray unto the Lord, call upon
his holy name, make known his
wonderful works among the people.
5 Call upon the Lord, that his
kingdom may go forth upon the
earth, that the inhabitants
thereof may receive it, and be
prepared for the days to come,
in the which the Son of Man
shall come down in heaven,
clothed in the brightness of his
glory, to meet the kingdom of
God which is set up on the earth.
6 Wherefore, may the
kingdom of God go forth, that the
kingdom of heaven may
come, that thou, O God, mayest
be glorified in heaven so
on earth, that thine enemies
may be subdued; for thine
is the honor, power and
glory, forever and ever. Amen.