Section 109 Prayer offered at the dedication of
the temple at Kirtland, Ohio, March 27, 1836.
According to the Prophet’s written statement, this
prayer was given to him by revelation.
1–5, The
Kirtland Temple was built as a place for the Son of Man
to visit;
6–21, It is to be a house of prayer,
fasting, faith, learning, glory, and order, and a
house of God;
22–33, May the unrepentant who oppose
the Lord’s people be confounded;
34–42, May the
Saints go forth in power to gather the righteous
to Zion;
43–53, May the Saints be delivered from
the terrible things to be poured out upon the
wicked in the last days;
54–58, May nations and
peoples and churches be prepared for the gospel;
59–67,
May the Jews, the Lamanites, and all Israel be
redeemed;
68–80, May the Saints be crowned with
glory and honor and gain eternal salvation.
1 Thanks be to thy name, O Lord God of Israel, who
keepest covenant and showest mercy unto thy
servants who walk uprightly before thee, with all their
hearts
2 Thou who hast commanded thy servants to build a
house to thy name in this place [Kirtland]
3 And now thou beholdest, O Lord, that thy
servants have done according to thy commandment
4 And now we ask thee, Holy Father, in the name of
Jesus Christ, the Son of thy bosom, in whose name
alone salvation can be administered to the
children of men, we ask thee, O Lord, to accept of this
house, the workmanship of the hands of us, thy
servants, which thou didst command us to build
5 For thou knowest that we have done this work
through great tribulation; and out of our poverty we
have given of our substance to build a house to
thy name, that the Son of Man might have a place to
manifest himself to his people
6 And as thou hast said in a revelation, given to
us, calling us thy friends, saying—Call your
solemn assembly, as I have commanded you
7 And as all have not faith, seek ye diligently
and teach one another words of wisdom; yea, seek ye
out of the best books words of wisdom, seek
learning even by study and also by faith
8 Organize yourselves; prepare every needful
thing, and establish a house, even a house of prayer, a
house of fasting, a house of faith, a house of
learning, a house of glory, a house of order, a
house of God
9 That your incomings may be in the name of the
Lord, that your outgoings may be in the name of the
Lord, that all your salutations may be in the name
of the Lord, with uplifted hands unto the Most
High
10 And now, Holy Father, we ask thee to assist us,
thy people, with thy grace, in calling our solemn
assembly, that it may be done to thine honor and
to thy divine acceptance
11 And in a manner that we may be found worthy, in
thy sight, to secure a fulfilment of the promises
which thou hast made unto us, thy people, in the
revelations given unto us
12 That thy glory may rest down upon thy people,
and upon this thy house, which we now dedicate to
thee, that it may be sanctified and consecrated to
be holy, and that thy holy presence may be
continually in this house
13 And that all people who shall enter upon the
threshold of the Lord’s house may feel thy power,
and feel constrained to acknowledge that thou hast
sanctified it, and that it is thy house, a place of
thy holiness
14 And do thou grant, Holy Father, that all those
who shall worship in this house may be taught
words of wisdom out of the best books, and that they
may seek learning even by study, and also by faith,
as thou hast said
15 And that they may grow up in thee, and receive
a fulness of the Holy Ghost, and be organized
according to thy laws, and be prepared to obtain every
needful thing
16 And that this house may be a house of prayer, a
house of fasting, a house of faith, a house of
glory and of God, even thy house
17 That all the incomings of thy people, into this
house, may be in the name of the Lord
18 That all their outgoings from this house may be
in the name of the Lord
19 And that all their salutations may be in the
name of the Lord, with holy hands, uplifted to the
Most High
20 And that no unclean thing shall be permitted to
come into thy house to pollute it
21 And when thy people transgress, any of them,
they may speedily repent and return unto thee, and
find favor in thy sight, and be restored to the
blessings which thou hast ordained to be poured out
upon those who shall reverence thee in thy house
22 And we ask thee, Holy Father, that thy servants
may go forth from this house armed with thy
power, and that thy name may be upon them, and thy
glory be round about them, and thine angels have
charge over them
23 And from this place they may bear exceedingly
great and glorious tidings, in truth, unto the ends
of the earth, that they may know that this is thy
work, and that thou hast put forth thy hand, to
fulfil that which thou hast spoken by the mouths of
the prophets, concerning the last days
24 We ask thee, Holy Father, to establish the
people that shall worship, and honorably hold a name
and standing in this thy house, to all generations
and for eternity
25 That no weapon formed against them shall
prosper; that he who diggeth a pit for them shall fall
into the same himself
26 That no combination of wickedness shall have
power to rise up and prevail over thy people upon
whom thy name shall be put in this house
27 And if any people shall rise against this
people, that thine anger be kindled against them
28 And if they shall smite this people thou wilt
smite them; thou wilt fight for thy people as thou
didst in the day of battle, that they may be
delivered from the hands of all their enemies
29 We ask thee, Holy Father, to confound, and
astonish, and to bring to shame and confusion, all
those who have spread lying reports abroad, over the
world, against thy servant or servants, if they
will not repent, when the everlasting gospel shall
be proclaimed in their ears
30 And that all their works may be brought to
naught, and be swept away by the hail, and by the
judgments which thou wilt send upon them in thine
anger, that there may be an end to lyings and slanders
against thy people
31 For thou knowest, O Lord, that thy servants
have been innocent before thee in bearing record of
thy name, for which they have suffered these
things
32 Therefore we plead before thee for a full and
complete deliverance from under this yoke
33 Break it off, O Lord; break it off from the
necks of thy servants, by thy power, that we may rise
up in the midst of this generation and do thy
work
34 O Jehovah, have mercy upon this people, and as
all men sin, forgive the transgressions of thy
people, and let them be blotted out forever
35 Let the anointing of thy ministers be sealed
upon them with power from on high
36 Let it be fulfilled upon them, as upon those on
the day of Pentecost; let the gift of tongues be
poured out upon thy people, even cloven tongues as
of fire, and the interpretation thereof
37 And let thy house be filled, as with a rushing
mighty wind, with thy glory
38 Put upon thy servants the testimony of the
covenant, that when they go out and proclaim thy word
they may seal up the law, and prepare the hearts
of thy saints for all those judgments thou art
about to send, in thy wrath, upon the inhabitants of
the earth, because of their transgressions, that
thy people may not faint in the day of trouble
39 And whatsoever city thy servants shall enter,
and the people of that city receive their
testimony, let thy peace and thy salvation be upon that
city; that they may gather out of that city the
righteous, that they may come forth to Zion, or to her
stakes, the places of thine appointment, with
songs of everlasting joy
40 And until this be accomplished, let not thy
judgments fall upon that city
41 And whatsoever city thy servants shall enter,
and the people of that city receive not the
testimony of thy servants, and thy servants warn them to
save themselves from this untoward generation, let
it be upon that city according to that which thou
hast spoken by the mouths of thy prophets
42 But deliver thou, O Jehovah, we beseech thee,
thy servants from their hands, and cleanse them
from their blood
43 O Lord, we delight not in the destruction of
our fellow men; their souls are precious before
thee
44 But thy word must be fulfilled. Help thy
servants to say, with thy grace assisting them: Thy will
be done, O Lord, and not ours
45 We know that thou hast spoken by the mouth of
thy prophets terrible things concerning the wicked,
in the last days—that thou wilt pour out thy
judgments, without measure
46 Therefore, O Lord, deliver thy people from the
calamity of the wicked; enable thy servants to
seal up the law, and bind up the testimony, that they
may be prepared against the day of burning
47 We ask thee, Holy Father, to remember those who
have been driven by the inhabitants of Jackson
county, Missouri, from the lands of their
inheritance, and break off, O Lord, this yoke of affliction
that has been put upon them
48 Thou knowest, O Lord, that they have been
greatly oppressed and afflicted by wicked men; and our
hearts flow out with sorrow because of their
grievous burdens
49 O Lord, how long wilt thou suffer this people
to bear this affliction, and the cries of their
innocent ones to ascend up in thine ears, and their
blood come up in testimony before thee, and not
make a display of thy testimony in their behalf
50 Have mercy, O Lord, upon the wicked mob, who
have driven thy people, that they may cease to
spoil, that they may repent of their sins if repentance
is to be found
51 But if they will not, make bare thine arm, O
Lord, and redeem that which thou didst appoint a
Zion unto thy people
52 And if it cannot be otherwise, that the cause
of thy people may not fail before thee may thine
anger be kindled, and thine indignation fall upon
them, that they may be wasted away, both root and
branch, from under heaven
53 But inasmuch as they will repent, thou art
gracious and merciful, and wilt turn away thy wrath
when thou lookest upon the face of thine Anointed
54 Have mercy, O Lord, upon all the nations of the
earth; have mercy upon the rulers of our land;
may those principles, which were so honorably and
nobly defended, namely, the Constitution of our
land, by our fathers, be established forever
55 Remember the kings, the princes, the nobles,
and the great ones of the earth, and all people, and
the churches, all the poor, the needy, and
afflicted ones of the earth
56 That their hearts may be softened when thy
servants shall go out from thy house, O Jehovah, to
bear testimony of thy name; that their prejudices
may give way before the truth, and thy people may
obtain favor in the sight of all
57 That all the ends of the earth may know that
we, thy servants, have heard thy voice, and that
thou hast sent us
58 That from among all these, thy servants, the
sons of Jacob, may gather out the righteous to build
a holy city to thy name, as thou hast commanded
them
59 We ask thee to appoint unto Zion other stakes
besides this one which thou hast appointed, that
the gathering of thy people may roll on in great
power and majesty, that thy work may be cut short in
righteousness
60 Now these words, O Lord, we have spoken before
thee, concerning the revelations and commandments
which thou hast given unto us, who are identified
with the Gentiles
61 But thou knowest that thou hast a great love
for the children of Jacob, who have been scattered
upon the mountains for a long time, in a cloudy and
dark day
62 We therefore ask thee to have mercy upon the
children of Jacob, that Jerusalem, from this hour,
may begin to be redeemed
63 And the yoke of bondage may begin to be broken
off from the house of David
64 And the children of Judah may begin to return
to the lands which thou didst give to Abraham,
their father
65 And cause that the remnants of Jacob, who have
been cursed and smitten because of their
transgression, be converted from their wild and savage
condition to the fulness of the everlasting gospel
66 That they may lay down their weapons of
bloodshed, and cease their rebellions
67 And may all the scattered remnants of Israel,
who have been driven to the ends of the earth, come
to a knowledge of the truth, believe in the
Messiah, and be redeemed from oppression, and rejoice
before thee
68 O Lord, remember thy servant, Joseph Smith,
Jun., and all his afflictions and persecutions—how he
has covenanted with Jehovah, and vowed to thee, O
Mighty God of Jacob—and the commandments which
thou hast given unto him, and that he hath sincerely
striven to do thy will
69 Have mercy, O Lord, upon his wife and children,
that they may be exalted in thy presence, and
preserved by thy fostering hand
70 Have mercy upon all their immediate
connections, that their prejudices may be broken up and swept
away as with a flood; that they may be converted
and redeemed with Israel, and know that thou art
God
71 Remember, O Lord, the presidents, even all the
presidents of thy church, that thy right hand may
exalt them, with all their families, and their
immediate connections, that their names may be
perpetuated and had in everlasting remembrance from
generation to generation
72 Remember all thy church, O Lord, with all their
families, and all their immediate connections,
with all their sick and afflicted ones, with all the
poor and meek of the earth; that the kingdom,
which thou hast set up without hands, may become a
great mountain and fill the whole earth
73 That thy church may come forth out of the
wilderness of darkness, and shine forth fair as the
moon, clear as the sun, and terrible as an army with
banners
74 And be adorned as a bride for that day when
thou shalt unveil the heavens, and cause the
mountains to flow down at thy presence, and the valleys to
be exalted, the rough places made smooth; that
thy glory may fill the earth
75 That when the trump shall sound for the dead,
we shall be caught up in the cloud to meet thee,
that we may ever be with the Lord
76 That our garments may be pure, that we may be
clothed upon with robes of righteousness, with
palms in our hands, and crowns of glory upon our
heads, and reap eternal joy for all our sufferings
77 O Lord God Almighty, hear us in these our
petitions, and answer us from heaven, thy holy
habitation, where thou sittest enthroned, with glory,
honor, power, majesty, might, dominion, truth,
justice, judgment, mercy, and an infinity of fulness,
from everlasting to everlasting
78 O hear, O hear, O hear us, O Lord! And answer
these petitions, and accept the dedication of this
house unto thee, the work of our hands, which we
have built unto thy name
79 And also this church, to put upon it thy name.
And help us by the power of thy Spirit, that we
may mingle our voices with those bright, shining
seraphs around thy throne, with acclamations of
praise, singing Hosanna to God and the Lamb
80 And let these, thine anointed ones, be clothed
with salvation, and thy saints shout aloud for
joy. Amen, and Amen.