Chapter 4 All the prophets worshiped the Father in
the name of Christ—Abraham’s offering of Isaac
was in similitude of God and His Only Begotten—Men
should reconcile themselves to God through the
Atonement—The Jews will reject the foundation stone.
About 544–421 B.C.
1 Now behold, it came to pass that I, Jacob,
having ministered much unto my people in word, (and I
cannot write but a little of my words, because of
the difficulty of engraving our words upon plates)
and we know that the things which we write upon
plates must remain
2 But whatsoever things we write upon anything
save it be upon plates must perish and vanish away;
but we can write a few words upon plates, which
will give our children, and also our beloved
brethren, a small degree of knowledge concerning us, or
concerning their fathers
3 Now in this thing we do rejoice; and we labor
diligently to engraven these words upon plates,
hoping that our beloved brethren and our children will
receive them with thankful hearts, and look upon
them that they may learn with joy and not with
sorrow, neither with contempt, concerning their first
parents
4 For, for this intent have we written these
things, that they may know that we knew of Christ, and
we had a hope of his glory many hundred years
before his coming; and not only we ourselves had a
hope of his glory, but also all the holy prophets
which were before us
5 Behold, they believed in Christ and worshiped
the Father in his name, and also we worship the
Father in his name. And for this intent we keep the
law of Moses, it pointing our souls to him; and for
this cause it is sanctified unto us for
righteousness, even as it was accounted unto Abraham in the
wilderness to be obedient unto the commands of God
in offering up his son Isaac, which is a
similitude of God and his Only Begotten Son
6 Wherefore, we search the prophets, and we have
many revelations and the spirit of prophecy; and
having all these witnesses we obtain a hope, and our
faith becometh unshaken, insomuch that we truly
can command in the name of Jesus and the very trees
obey us, or the mountains, or the waves of the
sea
7 Nevertheless, the Lord God showeth us our
weakness that we may know that it is by his grace, and
his great condescensions unto the children of men,
that we have power to do these things
8 Behold, great and marvelous are the works of the
Lord. How unsearchable are the depths of the
mysteries of him; and it is impossible that man should
find out all his ways. And no man knoweth of his
ways save it be revealed unto him; wherefore,
brethren, despise not the revelations of God
9 For behold, by the power of his word man came
upon the face of the earth, which earth was created
by the power of his word. Wherefore, if God being
able to speak and the world was, and to speak and
man was created, O then, why not able to command
the earth, or the workmanship of his hands upon the
face of it, according to his will and pleasure
10 Wherefore, brethren, seek not to counsel the
Lord, but to take counsel from his hand. For behold,
ye yourselves know that he counseleth in wisdom,
and in justice, and in great mercy, over all his
works
11 Wherefore, beloved brethren, be reconciled unto
him through the atonement of Christ, his Only
Begotten Son, and ye may obtain a resurrection,
according to the power of the resurrection which is in
Christ, and be presented as the first-fruits of
Christ unto God, having faith, and obtained a good
hope of glory in him before he manifesteth himself
in the flesh
12 And now, beloved, marvel not that I tell you
these things; for why not speak of the atonement of
Christ, and attain to a perfect knowledge of him,
as to attain to the knowledge of a resurrection
and the world to come
15 And now I, Jacob, am led on by the Spirit unto
prophesying; for I perceive by the workings of the
Spirit which is in me, that by the stumbling of
the Jews they will reject the stone upon which they
might build and have safe foundation
16 But behold, according to the scriptures, this
stone shall become the great, and the last, and the
only sure foundation, upon which the Jews can
build
17 And now, my beloved, how is it possible that
these, after having rejected the sure foundation,
can ever build upon it, that it may become the head
of their corner
18 Behold, my beloved brethren, I will unfold this
mystery unto you; if I do not, by any means, get
shaken from my firmness in the Spirit, and stumble
because of my over anxiety for you.