Chapter 3 The pure in heart receive the pleasing
word of God—Lamanite righteousness exceeds that of
the Nephites—Jacob warns against fornication,
lasciviousness, and every sin. About 544–421 B.C.
1 But behold, I, Jacob, would speak unto you that
are pure in heart. Look unto God with firmness of
mind, and pray unto him with exceeding faith, and
he will console you in your afflictions, and he
will plead your cause, and send down justice upon
those who seek your destruction
2 O all ye that are pure in heart, lift up your
heads and receive the pleasing word of God, and
feast upon his love; for ye may, if your minds are
firm, forever
3 But, wo, wo, unto you that are not pure in
heart, that are filthy this day before God; for except
ye repent the land is cursed for your sakes; and
the Lamanites, which are not filthy like unto you,
nevertheless they are cursed with a sore cursing,
shall scourge you even unto destruction
4 And the time speedily cometh, that except ye
repent they shall possess the land of your
inheritance, and the Lord God will lead away the righteous
out from among you
5 Behold, the Lamanites your brethren, whom ye
hate because of their filthiness and the cursing
which hath come upon their skins, are more righteous
than you; for they have not forgotten the
commandment of the Lord, which was given unto our
father—that they should have save it were one wife, and
concubines they should have none, and there should
not be whoredoms committed among them
6 And now, this commandment they observe to keep;
wherefore, because of this observance, in keeping
this commandment, the Lord God will not destroy
them, but will be merciful unto them; and one day
they shall become a blessed people
7 Behold, their husbands love their wives, and
their wives love their husbands; and their husbands
and their wives love their children; and their
unbelief and their hatred towards you is because of
the iniquity of their fathers; wherefore, how much
better are you than they, in the sight of your
great Creator
8 O my brethren, I fear that unless ye shall
repent of your sins that their skins will be whiter
than yours, when ye shall be brought with them before
the throne of God
9 Wherefore, a commandment I give unto you, which
is the word of God, that ye revile no more against
them because of the darkness of their skins;
neither shall ye revile against them because of their
filthiness; but ye shall remember your own
filthiness, and remember that their filthiness came
because of their fathers
12 And now I, Jacob, spake many more things unto
the people of Nephi, warning them against
fornication and lasciviousness, and every kind of sin,
telling them the awful consequences of them
13 And a hundredth part of the proceedings of this
people, which now began to be numerous, cannot be
written upon these plates; but many of their
proceedings are written upon the larger plates, and
their wars, and their contentions, and the reigns of
their kings
14 These plates are called the plates of Jacob,
and they were made by the hand of Nephi. And I make
an end of speaking these words.