Chapter 2 Jacob denounces the love of
riches, pride, and unchastity—Men may seek
riches to help their fellowmen—The Lord
commands that no man among the Nephites may
have more than one wife—The Lord delights in
the chastity of women. About 544–421 B.C.
1 The words which Jacob, the
brother of Nephi, spake unto the people
of Nephi, after the death of Nephi:
2 Now, my beloved brethren, I,
Jacob, according to the
responsibility which I am under to God,
to magnify mine office with
soberness, and that I might rid my
garments of your sins, I come up
into the temple this day that I
might declare unto you the word of God.
3 And ye yourselves know that
I have hitherto been diligent
in the office of my calling;
but I this day am weighed down
with much more desire and
anxiety for the welfare of your
souls than I have hitherto been.
4 For behold, as yet, ye
have been obedient unto
the word of the Lord,
which I have given unto you.
5 But behold, hearken
ye unto me, and know
that by the help of the
all-powerful Creator
of heaven and earth I
can tell you
concerning your thoughts, how
that ye are beginning
to labor in sin, which
sin appeareth very
abominable unto me, yea,
and abominable unto God.
6 Yea, it grieveth
my soul and causeth
me to shrink with
shame before the
presence of my Maker, that
I must testify unto
you concerning the
wickedness of your hearts.
7 And also it
grieveth me that I must
use so much
boldness of speech
concerning you, before
your wives and your
children, many of
whose feelings are
exceedingly tender and
chaste and
delicate before God, which
thing is pleasing unto God;
8 And it supposeth
me that they have
come up hither to
hear the pleasing
word of God, yea,
the word which
healeth the wounded soul.
9 Wherefore, it
burdeneth my soul
that I should be
constrained,
because of the strict
commandment
which I have received
from God, to
admonish you
according to your
crimes, to enlarge the
wounds of those
who are already
wounded, instead of
consoling and
healing their
wounds; and those who
have not been
wounded, instead of
feasting upon the
pleasing word of
God have daggers
placed to pierce
their souls and
wound their delicate minds.
10 But,
notwithstanding the
greatness of the
task, I must do
according to the
strict commands of
God, and tell
you concerning
your wickedness
and abominations,
in the presence
of the pure in
heart, and the
broken heart, and
under the glance
of the piercing
eye of the Almighty God.
11 Wherefore, I
must tell you
the truth
according to the
plainness of the
word of God. For
behold, as I
inquired of the
Lord, thus came
the word unto
me, saying:
Jacob, get thou up
into the
temple on the
morrow, and declare
the word which I
shall give
thee unto this people.
12 And now
behold, my
brethren, this is
the word which I
declare unto
you, that many
of you have
begun to search
for gold, and
for silver,
and for all
manner of
precious ores, in the
which this
land, which is a
land of
promise unto you
and to your
seed, doth abound most plentifully.
13 And the
hand of
providence hath
smiled upon you
most
pleasingly, that you
have obtained
many riches;
and because
some of you
have obtained
more
abundantly than that
of your
brethren ye are
lifted up in the
pride of
your hearts, and
wear stiff
necks and high
heads
because of the
costliness of
your apparel,
and persecute
your brethren
because ye
suppose that ye are better than they.
14 And now,
my brethren,
do ye
suppose that God
justifieth
you in this
thing?
Behold, I say unto
you, Nay.
But he
condemneth you,
and if ye
persist in these
things his
judgments
must speedily come unto you.
15 O that
he would
show you that
he can
pierce you, and
with one
glance of
his eye he
can smite you
to the dust!
16 O that
he would
rid you
from this
iniquity and
abomination. And, O
that ye
would listen
unto the
word of
his
commands, and let
not this
pride of
your hearts
destroy your souls!
17 Think
of your
brethren
like unto
yourselves, and be
familiar
with all
and free
with
your
substance, that
they may
be rich like unto you.
18 But
before ye
seek
for
riches, seek
ye for
the
kingdom of God.
19 And
after
ye have
obtained a
hope in
Christ ye
shall
obtain
riches,
if ye
seek
them; and
ye
will seek
them
for the
intent
to do
good—to
clothe
the
naked, and
to feed
the
hungry,
and to
liberate
the
captive,
and
administer
relief to the sick and the afflicted.
20 And
now,
my
brethren,
I
have
spoken
unto you
concerning
pride;
and
those of
you
which
have
afflicted your
neighbor,
and
persecuted him
because ye
were
proud in
your
hearts, of
the
things
which
God hath given you, what say ye of it?
21 Do
ye
not
suppose
that
such
things
are
abominable
unto
him who
created
all
flesh?
And
the
one
being is
as
precious in
his
sight
as
the
other.
And
all
flesh
is of
the
dust;
and
for
the
selfsame
end
hath
he
created
them,
that
they
should keep his commandments and glorify him forever.
And now
I
make an
end
of
speaking
unto you
concerning
this
pride.
And
were it
not
that
I
must
speak
unto
you
concerning a
grosser
crime,
my
heart
would
rejoice
exceedingly
because of
you.
But
the
word
of
God
burdens
me
because of
your
grosser
crimes.
For
behold,
thus
saith
the
Lord:
This
people
begin
to
wax
in
iniquity;
they
understand
not
the
scriptures,
for
they
seek
to
excuse
themselves
in
committing
whoredoms,
because
of
the
things which were written concerning David, and Solomon his son.
Behold,
David
and
Solomon
truly
had
many
wives
and
concubines,
which
thing
was
abominable before me, saith the Lord.
Wherefore,
thus
saith
the
Lord, I
have
led
this
people
forth
out
of
the
land
of
Jerusalem,
by
the
power
of
mine
arm,
that I
might
raise
up
unto
me
a
righteous
branch
from
the
fruit
of
the
loins
of
Joseph.
Wherefore, I
the
Lord
God
will
not
suffer
that
this
people
shall
do
like
unto
them
of
old.
Wherefore,
my
brethren,
hear
me,
and
hearken
to
the
word
of
the
Lord:
For
there
shall
not
any
man
among
you
have
save
it
be
one
wife;
and
concubines
he
shall
have
none;
For
I,
the
Lord
God,
delight
in
the
chastity
of
women.
And
whoredoms
are
an
abomination before me; thus saith the Lord of Hosts.
29 Wherefore, this people shall keep my commandments, saith the Lord of Hosts, or cursed be the land for their
Wherefore,
this
people
shall
keep
my
commandments,
saith the Lord of Hosts, or cursed be the land for their sakes.
30 For if I will, saith the Lord of Hosts, raise up seed unto me, I will command my people; otherwise they shall hearken unto these
For
if
I
will,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts,
raise
up
seed
unto
me,
I
will
command
my
people;
otherwise
they
shall
hearken
unto
these
things.
31 For behold, I, the Lord, have seen the sorrow, and heard the mourning of the daughters of my people in the land of Jerusalem, yea, and in all the lands of my people, because of the wickedness and abominations of their
For
behold,
I,
the
Lord,
have
seen
the
sorrow,
and
heard
the
mourning
of
the
daughters
of
my
people
in
the
land
of
Jerusalem,
yea,
and
in
all
the
lands
of
my
people,
because
of
the
wickedness
and
abominations
of
their
husbands.
32 And I will not suffer, saith the Lord of Hosts, that the cries of the fair daughters of this people, which I have led out of the land of Jerusalem, shall come up unto me against the men of my people, saith the Lord of
And
I
will
not
suffer,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts,
that
the
cries
of
the
fair
daughters
of
this
people,
which
I
have
led
out
of
the
land
of
Jerusalem,
shall
come
up
unto
me
against
the
men
of
my
people,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts.
33 For they shall not lead away captive the daughters of my people because of their tenderness, save I shall visit them with a sore curse, even unto destruction; for they shall not commit whoredoms, like unto them of old, saith the Lord of
For
they
shall
not
lead
away
captive
the
daughters
of
my
people
because
of
their
tenderness,
save
I
shall
visit
them
with
a
sore
curse,
even
unto
destruction;
for
they
shall
not
commit
whoredoms,
like
unto
them
of
old,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts.
34 And now behold, my brethren, ye know that these commandments were given to our father, Lehi; wherefore, ye have known them before; and ye have come unto great condemnation; for ye have done these things which ye ought not to have
And
now
behold,
my
brethren,
ye
know
that
these
commandments
were
given
to
our
father,
Lehi;
wherefore,
ye
have
known
them
before;
and
ye
have
come
unto
great
condemnation;
for
ye
have
done
these
things
which
ye
ought
not
to
have
done.
35 Behold, ye have done greater iniquities than the Lamanites, our brethren. Ye have broken the hearts of your tender wives, and lost the confidence of your children, because of your bad examples before them; and the sobbings of their hearts ascend up to God against you. And because of the strictness of the word of God, which cometh down against you, many hearts died, pierced with deep wounds.
Behold,
ye
have
done
greater
iniquities
than
the
Lamanites,
our
brethren.
Ye
have
broken
the
hearts
of
your
tender
wives,
and
lost
the
confidence
of
your
children,
because
of
your
bad
examples
before
them;
and
the
sobbings
of
their
hearts
ascend
up
to
God
against
you.
And
because
of
the
strictness
of
the
word
of
God,
which
cometh
down
against
you,
many
hearts
died,
pierced
with
deep
wounds.