The Book of Jacob the Brother of NephiThe words of
his preaching unto his brethren. He confoundeth a
man who seeketh to overthrow the doctrine of
Christ. A few words concerning the history of the
people of Nephi.Chapter 1 Jacob and Joseph seek to
persuade men to believe in Christ and keep His
commandments—Nephi dies—Wickedness prevails among the
Nephites. About 544–421 B.C.
1 For behold, it came to pass that fifty and five
years had passed away from the time that Lehi left
Jerusalem; wherefore, Nephi gave me, Jacob, a
commandment concerning the small plates, upon which
these things are engraven
2 And he gave me, Jacob, a commandment that I
should write upon these plates a few of the things
which I considered to be most precious; that I should
not touch, save it were lightly, concerning the
history of this people which are called the people
of Nephi
3 For he said that the history of his people
should be engraven upon his other plates, and that I
should preserve these plates and hand them down unto
my seed, from generation to generation
4 And if there were preaching which was sacred, or
revelation which was great, or prophesying, that
I should engraven the heads of them upon these
plates, and touch upon them as much as it were
possible, for Christ’s sake, and for the sake of our
people
5 For because of faith and great anxiety, it truly
had been made manifest unto us concerning our
people, what things should happen unto them
6 And we also had many revelations, and the spirit
of much prophecy; wherefore, we knew of Christ
and his kingdom, which should come
7 Wherefore we labored diligently among our
people, that we might persuade them to come unto Christ,
and partake of the goodness of God, that they
might enter into his rest, lest by any means he
should swear in his wrath they should not enter in, as
in the provocation in the days of temptation while
the children of Israel were in the wilderness
8 Wherefore, we would to God that we could
persuade all men not to rebel against God, to provoke him
to anger, but that all men would believe in
Christ, and view his death, and suffer his cross and
bear the shame of the world; wherefore, I, Jacob,
take it upon me to fulfil the commandment of my
brother Nephi
9 Now Nephi began to be old, and he saw that he
must soon die; wherefore, he anointed a man to be a
king and a ruler over his people now, according to
the reigns of the kings
10 The people having loved Nephi exceedingly, he
having been a great protector for them, having
wielded the sword of Laban in their defence, and
having labored in all his days for their welfare
11 Wherefore, the people were desirous to retain
in remembrance his name. And whoso should reign in
his stead were called by the people, second Nephi,
third Nephi, and so forth, according to the
reigns of the kings; and thus they were called by the
people, let them be of whatever name they would
12 And it came to pass that Nephi died
13 Now the people which were not Lamanites were
Nephites; nevertheless, they were called Nephites,
Jacobites, Josephites, Zoramites, Lamanites,
Lemuelites, and Ishmaelites
14 But I, Jacob, shall not hereafter distinguish
them by these names, but I shall call them
Lamanites that seek to destroy the people of Nephi, and
those who are friendly to Nephi I shall call
Nephites, or the people of Nephi, according to the reigns
of the kings
17 Wherefore I, Jacob, gave unto them these words
as I taught them in the temple, having first
obtained mine errand from the Lord
18 For I, Jacob, and my brother Joseph had been
consecrated priests and teachers of this people, by
the hand of Nephi
19 And we did magnify our office unto the Lord,
taking upon us the responsibility, answering the
sins of the people upon our own heads if we did not
teach them the word of God with all diligence;
wherefore, by laboring with our might their blood
might not come upon our garments; otherwise their
blood would come upon our garments, and we would not
be found spotless at the last day.