Chapter 7 Sherem denies Christ, contends with
Jacob, demands a sign, and is smitten of God—All of
the prophets have spoken of Christ and His
Atonement—The Nephites lived out their days as wanderers,
born in tribulation, and hated by the Lamanites.
About 544–421 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass after some years had
passed away, there came a man among the people of
Nephi, whose name was Sherem
2 And it came to pass that he began to preach
among the people, and to declare unto them that there
should be no Christ. And he preached many things
which were flattering unto the people; and this he
did that he might overthrow the doctrine of
Christ
3 And he labored diligently that he might lead
away the hearts of the people, insomuch that he did
lead away many hearts; and he knowing that I,
Jacob, had faith in Christ who should come, he sought
much opportunity that he might come unto me
4 And he was learned, that he had a perfect
knowledge of the language of the people; wherefore, he
could use much flattery, and much power of speech,
according to the power of the devil
5 And he had hope to shake me from the faith,
notwithstanding the many revelations and the many
things which I had seen concerning these things; for I
truly had seen angels, and they had ministered
unto me. And also, I had heard the voice of the Lord
speaking unto me in very word, from time to time;
wherefore, I could not be shaken
6 And it came to pass that he came unto me, and on
this wise did he speak unto me, saying: Brother
Jacob, I have sought much opportunity that I might
speak unto you; for I have heard and also know
that thou goest about much, preaching that which ye
call the gospel, or the doctrine of Christ
7 And ye have led away much of this people that
they pervert the right way of God, and keep not the
law of Moses which is the right way; and convert
the law of Moses into the worship of a being which
ye say shall come many hundred years hence. And
now behold, I, Sherem, declare unto you that this is
blasphemy; for no man knoweth of such things; for
he cannot tell of things to come. And after this
manner did Sherem contend against me
8 But behold, the Lord God poured in his Spirit
into my soul, insomuch that I did confound him in
all his words
9 And I said unto him: Deniest thou the Christ who
shall come? And he said: If there should be a
Christ, I would not deny him; but I know that there
is no Christ, neither has been, nor ever will be
10 And I said unto him: Believest thou the
scriptures? And he said, Yea
11 And I said unto him: Then ye do not understand
them; for they truly testify of Christ. Behold, I
say unto you that none of the prophets have
written, nor prophesied, save they have spoken
concerning this Christ
12 And this is not all—it has been made manifest
unto me, for I have heard and seen; and it also has
been made manifest unto me by the power of the
Holy Ghost; wherefore, I know if there should be no
atonement made all mankind must be lost
15 And it came to pass that when I, Jacob, had
spoken these words, the power of the Lord came upon
him, insomuch that he fell to the earth. And it
came to pass that he was nourished for the space of
many days
16 And it came to pass that he said unto the
people: Gather together on the morrow, for I shall die;
wherefore, I desire to speak unto the people
before I shall die
17 And it came to pass that on the morrow the
multitude were gathered together; and he spake plainly
unto them and denied the things which he had
taught them, and confessed the Christ, and the power
of the Holy Ghost, and the ministering of angels
18 And he spake plainly unto them, that he had
been deceived by the power of the devil. And he spake
of hell, and of eternity, and of eternal
punishment
19 And he said: I fear lest I have committed the
unpardonable sin, for I have lied unto God; for I
denied the Christ, and said that I believed the
scriptures; and they truly testify of him. And
because I have thus lied unto God I greatly fear lest my
case shall be awful; but I confess unto God
20 And it came to pass that when he had said these
words he could say no more, and he gave up the
ghost
21 And when the multitude had witnessed that he
spake these things as he was about to give up the
ghost, they were astonished exceedingly; insomuch
that the power of God came down upon them, and they
were overcome that they fell to the earth
22 Now, this thing was pleasing unto me, Jacob,
for I had requested it of my Father who was in
heaven; for he had heard my cry and answered my prayer
23 And it came to pass that peace and the love of
God was restored again among the people; and they
searched the scriptures, and hearkened no more to
the words of this wicked man
24 And it came to pass that many means were
devised to reclaim and restore the Lamanites to the
knowledge of the truth; but it all was vain, for they
delighted in wars and bloodshed, and they had an
eternal hatred against us, their brethren. And they
sought by the power of their arms to destroy us
continually
25 Wherefore, the people of Nephi did fortify
against them with their arms, and with all their
might, trusting in the God and rock of their salvation;
wherefore, they became as yet, conquerors of
their enemies