Chapter 5 Jacob quotes Zenos relative to the
allegory of the tame and wild olive trees—They are a
likeness of Israel and the Gentiles—The scattering
and gathering of Israel are prefigured—Allusions
are made to the Nephites and Lamanites and all the
house of Israel—The Gentiles will be grafted into
Israel—Eventually the vineyard will be burned.
About 544–421 B.C.
1 Behold, my brethren, do ye not remember to have
read the words of the prophet Zenos, which he
spake unto the house of Israel, saying
2 Hearken, O ye house of Israel, and hear the
words of me, a prophet of the Lord
3 For behold, thus saith the Lord, I will liken
thee, O house of Israel, like unto a tame olive
tree, which a man took and nourished in his vineyard;
and it grew, and waxed old, and began to decay
4 And it came to pass that the master of the
vineyard went forth, and he saw that his olive tree
began to decay; and he said: I will prune it, and dig
about it, and nourish it, that perhaps it may
shoot forth young and tender branches, and it perish
not
5 And it came to pass that he pruned it, and
digged about it, and nourished it according to his
word
6 And it came to pass that after many days it
began to put forth somewhat a little, young and tender
branches; but behold, the main top thereof began
to perish
7 And it came to pass that the master of the
vineyard saw it, and he said unto his servant: It
grieveth me that I should lose this tree; wherefore, go
and pluck the branches from a wild olive tree,
and bring them hither unto me; and we will pluck off
those main branches which are beginning to wither
away, and we will cast them into the fire that
they may be burned
8 And behold, saith the Lord of the vineyard, I
take away many of these young and tender branches,
and I will graft them whithersoever I will; and it
mattereth not that if it so be that the root of
this tree will perish, I may preserve the fruit
thereof unto myself; wherefore, I will take these
young and tender branches, and I will graft them
whithersoever I will
9 Take thou the branches of the wild olive tree,
and graft them in, in the stead thereof; and these
which I have plucked off I will cast into the fire
and burn them, that they may not cumber the
ground of my vineyard
10 And it came to pass that the servant of the
Lord of the vineyard did according to the word of the
Lord of the vineyard, and grafted in the branches
of the wild olive tree
11 And the Lord of the vineyard caused that it
should be digged about, and pruned, and nourished,
saying unto his servant: It grieveth me that I
should lose this tree; wherefore, that perhaps I might
preserve the roots thereof that they perish not,
that I might preserve them unto myself, I have done
this thing
12 Wherefore, go thy way; watch the tree, and
nourish it, according to my words
13 And these will I place in the nethermost part
of my vineyard, whithersoever I will, it mattereth
not unto thee; and I do it that I may preserve
unto myself the natural branches of the tree; and
also, that I may lay up fruit thereof against the
season, unto myself; for it grieveth me that I should
lose this tree and the fruit thereof
14 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard went his way, and hid the natural branches of
the tame olive tree in the nethermost parts of the
vineyard, some in one and some in another,
according to his will and pleasure
15 And it came to pass that a long time passed
away, and the Lord of the vineyard said unto his
servant: Come, let us go down into the vineyard, that
we may labor in the vineyard
16 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard, and also the servant, went down into the
vineyard to labor. And it came to pass that the servant
said unto his master: Behold, look here; behold
the tree
17 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard looked and beheld the tree in the which the
wild olive branches had been grafted; and it had
sprung forth and begun to bear fruit. And he beheld
that it was good; and the fruit thereof was like
unto the natural fruit
18 And he said unto the servant: Behold, the
branches of the wild tree have taken hold of the
moisture of the root thereof, that the root thereof hath
brought forth much strength; and because of the
much strength of the root thereof the wild branches
have brought forth tame fruit. Now, if we had not
grafted in these branches, the tree thereof would
have perished. And now, behold, I shall lay up
much fruit, which the tree thereof hath brought
forth; and the fruit thereof I shall lay up against
the season, unto mine own self
19 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said unto the servant: Come, let us go to the
nethermost part of the vineyard, and behold if the
natural branches of the tree have not brought
forth much fruit also, that I may lay up of the fruit
thereof against the season, unto mine own self
20 And it came to pass that they went forth
whither the master had hid the natural branches of the
tree, and he said unto the servant: Behold these;
and he beheld the first that it had brought forth
much fruit; and he beheld also that it was good.
And he said unto the servant: Take of the fruit
thereof, and lay it up against the season, that I may
preserve it unto mine own self; for behold, said
he, this long time have I nourished it, and it hath
brought forth much fruit
21 And it came to pass that the servant said unto
his master: How comest thou hither to plant this
tree, or this branch of the tree? For behold, it
was the poorest spot in all the land of thy
vineyard
22 And the Lord of the vineyard said unto him:
Counsel me not; I knew that it was a poor spot of
ground; wherefore, I said unto thee, I have nourished
it this long time, and thou beholdest that it
hath brought forth much fruit
23 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said unto his servant: Look hither; behold I
have planted another branch of the tree also; and
thou knowest that this spot of ground was poorer
than the first. But, behold the tree. I have
nourished it this long time, and it hath brought forth
much fruit; therefore, gather it, and lay it up
against the season, that I may preserve it unto mine
own self
24 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said again unto his servant: Look hither, and
behold another branch also, which I have planted;
behold that I have nourished it also, and it hath
brought forth fruit
25 And he said unto the servant: Look hither and
behold the last. Behold, this have I planted in a
good spot of ground; and I have nourished it this
long time, and only a part of the tree hath brought
forth tame fruit, and the other part of the tree
hath brought forth wild fruit; behold, I have
nourished this tree like unto the others
26 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said unto the servant: Pluck off the branches
that have not brought forth good fruit, and cast
them into the fire
27 But behold, the servant said unto him: Let us
prune it, and dig about it, and nourish it a little
longer, that perhaps it may bring forth good
fruit unto thee, that thou canst lay it up against the
season
28 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard and the servant of the Lord of the vineyard did
nourish all the fruit of the vineyard
29 And it came to pass that a long time had passed
away, and the Lord of the vineyard said unto his
servant: Come, let us go down into the vineyard,
that we may labor again in the vineyard. For
behold, the time draweth near, and the end soon cometh;
wherefore, I must lay up fruit against the season,
unto mine own self
32 But behold, this time it hath brought forth
much fruit, and there is none of it which is good.
And behold, there are all kinds of bad fruit; and it
profiteth me nothing, notwithstanding all our
labor; and now it grieveth me that I should lose this
tree
33 And the Lord of the vineyard said unto the
servant: What shall we do unto the tree, that I may
preserve again good fruit thereof unto mine own
self
34 And the servant said unto his master: Behold,
because thou didst graft in the branches of the
wild olive tree they have nourished the roots, that
they are alive and they have not perished;
wherefore thou beholdest that they are yet good
35 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said unto his servant: The tree profiteth me
nothing, and the roots thereof profit me nothing so
long as it shall bring forth evil fruit
36 Nevertheless, I know that the roots are good,
and for mine own purpose I have preserved them; and
because of their much strength they have hitherto
brought forth, from the wild branches, good
fruit
37 But behold, the wild branches have grown and
have overrun the roots thereof; and because that the
wild branches have overcome the roots thereof it
hath brought forth much evil fruit; and because
that it hath brought forth so much evil fruit thou
beholdest that it beginneth to perish; and it will
soon become ripened, that it may be cast into the
fire, except we should do something for it to
preserve it
38 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said unto his servant: Let us go down into the
nethermost parts of the vineyard, and behold if
the natural branches have also brought forth evil
fruit
39 And it came to pass that they went down into
the nethermost parts of the vineyard. And it came to
pass that they beheld that the fruit of the
natural branches had become corrupt also; yea, the
first and the second and also the last; and they had
all become corrupt
40 And the wild fruit of the last had overcome
that part of the tree which brought forth good fruit,
even that the branch had withered away and died
41 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard wept, and said unto the servant: What could I
have done more for my vineyard
42 Behold, I knew that all the fruit of the
vineyard, save it were these, had become corrupted. And
now these which have once brought forth good fruit
have also become corrupted; and now all the trees
of my vineyard are good for nothing save it be to
be hewn down and cast into the fire
43 And behold this last, whose branch hath
withered away, I did plant in a good spot of ground; yea,
even that which was choice unto me above all
other parts of the land of my vineyard
44 And thou beheldest that I also cut down that
which cumbered this spot of ground, that I might
plant this tree in the stead thereof
45 And thou beheldest that a part thereof brought
forth good fruit, and a part thereof brought forth
wild fruit; and because I plucked not the
branches thereof and cast them into the fire, behold,
they have overcome the good branch that it hath
withered away
46 And now, behold, notwithstanding all the care
which we have taken of my vineyard, the trees
thereof have become corrupted, that they bring forth no
good fruit; and these I had hoped to preserve, to
have laid up fruit thereof against the season,
unto mine own self. But, behold, they have become
like unto the wild olive tree, and they are of no
worth but to be hewn down and cast into the fire;
and it grieveth me that I should lose them
47 But what could I have done more in my vineyard?
Have I slackened mine hand, that I have not
nourished it? Nay, I have nourished it, and I have
digged about it, and I have pruned it, and I have
dunged it; and I have stretched forth mine hand almost
all the day long, and the end draweth nigh. And
it grieveth me that I should hew down all the trees
of my vineyard, and cast them into the fire that
they should be burned. Who is it that has
corrupted my vineyard
48 And it came to pass that the servant said unto
his master: Is it not the loftiness of thy
vineyard—have not the branches thereof overcome the roots
which are good? And because the branches have
overcome the roots thereof, behold they grew faster
than the strength of the roots, taking strength
unto themselves. Behold, I say, is not this the cause
that the trees of thy vineyard have become
corrupted
49 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard said unto the servant: Let us go to and hew
down the trees of the vineyard and cast them into the
fire, that they shall not cumber the ground of my
vineyard, for I have done all. What could I have
done more for my vineyard
50 But, behold, the servant said unto the Lord of
the vineyard: Spare it a little longer
51 And the Lord said: Yea, I will spare it a
little longer, for it grieveth me that I should lose
the trees of my vineyard
52 Wherefore, let us take of the branches of these
which I have planted in the nethermost parts of
my vineyard, and let us graft them into the tree
from whence they came; and let us pluck from the
tree those branches whose fruit is most bitter, and
graft in the natural branches of the tree in the
stead thereof
53 And this will I do that the tree may not
perish, that, perhaps, I may preserve unto myself the
roots thereof for mine own purpose
54 And, behold, the roots of the natural branches
of the tree which I planted whithersoever I would
are yet alive; wherefore, that I may preserve them
also for mine own purpose, I will take of the
branches of this tree, and I will graft them in unto
them. Yea, I will graft in unto them the branches
of their mother tree, that I may preserve the
roots also unto mine own self, that when they shall be
sufficiently strong perhaps they may bring forth
good fruit unto me, and I may yet have glory in
the fruit of my vineyard
55 And it came to pass that they took from the
natural tree which had become wild, and grafted in
unto the natural trees, which also had become wild
56 And they also took of the natural trees which
had become wild, and grafted into their mother
tree
57 And the Lord of the vineyard said unto the
servant: Pluck not the wild branches from the trees,
save it be those which are most bitter; and in them
ye shall graft according to that which I have
said
58 And we will nourish again the trees of the
vineyard, and we will trim up the branches thereof;
and we will pluck from the trees those branches
which are ripened, that must perish, and cast them
into the fire
59 And this I do that, perhaps, the roots thereof
may take strength because of their goodness; and
because of the change of the branches, that the
good may overcome the evil
60 And because that I have preserved the natural
branches and the roots thereof, and that I have
grafted in the natural branches again into their
mother tree, and have preserved the roots of their
mother tree, that, perhaps, the trees of my vineyard
may bring forth again good fruit; and that I may
have joy again in the fruit of my vineyard, and,
perhaps, that I may rejoice exceedingly that I have
preserved the roots and the branches of the first
fruit
63 Graft in the branches; begin at the last that
they may be first, and that the first may be last,
and dig about the trees, both old and young, the
first and the last; and the last and the first,
that all may be nourished once again for the last
time
64 Wherefore, dig about them, and prune them, and
dung them once more, for the last time, for the
end draweth nigh. And if it be so that these last
grafts shall grow, and bring forth the natural
fruit, then shall ye prepare the way for them, that
they may grow
65 And as they begin to grow ye shall clear away
the branches which bring forth bitter fruit,
according to the strength of the good and the size
thereof; and ye shall not clear away the bad thereof
all at once, lest the roots thereof should be too
strong for the graft, and the graft thereof shall
perish, and I lose the trees of my vineyard
66 For it grieveth me that I should lose the trees
of my vineyard; wherefore ye shall clear away the
bad according as the good shall grow, that the
root and the top may be equal in strength, until the
good shall overcome the bad, and the bad be hewn
down and cast into the fire, that they cumber not
the ground of my vineyard; and thus will I sweep
away the bad out of my vineyard
67 And the branches of the natural tree will I
graft in again into the natural tree
68 And the branches of the natural tree will I
graft into the natural branches of the tree; and thus
will I bring them together again, that they shall
bring forth the natural fruit, and they shall be
one
69 And the bad shall be cast away, yea, even out
of all the land of my vineyard; for behold, only
this once will I prune my vineyard
70 And it came to pass that the Lord of the
vineyard sent his servant; and the servant went and did
as the Lord had commanded him, and brought other
servants; and they were few
71 And the Lord of the vineyard said unto them: Go
to, and labor in the vineyard, with your might.
For behold, this is the last time that I shall
nourish my vineyard; for the end is nigh at hand, and
the season speedily cometh; and if ye labor with
your might with me ye shall have joy in the fruit
which I shall lay up unto myself against the time
which will soon come
72 And it came to pass that the servants did go
and labor with their mights; and the Lord of the
vineyard labored also with them; and they did obey
the commandments of the Lord of the vineyard in all
things
73 And there began to be the natural fruit again
in the vineyard; and the natural branches began to
grow and thrive exceedingly; and the wild branches
began to be plucked off and to be cast away; and
they did keep the root and the top thereof equal,
according to the strength thereof
74 And thus they labored, with all diligence,
according to the commandments of the Lord of the
vineyard, even until the bad had been cast away out of
the vineyard, and the Lord had preserved unto
himself that the trees had become again the natural
fruit; and they became like unto one body; and the
fruits were equal; and the Lord of the vineyard had
preserved unto himself the natural fruit, which
was most precious unto him from the beginning
75 And it came to pass that when the Lord of the
vineyard saw that his fruit was good, and that his
vineyard was no more corrupt, he called up his
servants, and said unto them: Behold, for this last
time have we nourished my vineyard; and thou
beholdest that I have done according to my will; and I
have preserved the natural fruit, that it is good,
even like as it was in the beginning. And blessed
art thou; for because ye have been diligent in
laboring with me in my vineyard, and have kept my
commandments, and have brought unto me again the
natural fruit, that my vineyard is no more corrupted,
and the bad is cast away, behold ye shall have joy
with me because of the fruit of my vineyard
76 For behold, for a long time will I lay up of
the fruit of my vineyard unto mine own self against
the season, which speedily cometh; and for the
last time have I nourished my vineyard, and pruned
it, and dug about it, and dunged it; wherefore I
will lay up unto mine own self of the fruit, for a
long time, according to that which I have spoken
77 And when the time cometh that evil fruit shall
again come into my vineyard, then will I cause the
good and the bad to be gathered; and the good
will I preserve unto myself, and the bad will I cast
away into its own place. And then cometh the
season and the end; and my vineyard will I cause to be
burned with fire.