Chapter 6 The Lord will recover Israel in
the last days—The world will be burned with
fire—Men must follow Christ to avoid the
lake of fire and brimstone. About 544–421 B.C.
1 And now, behold, my brethren, as I
said unto you that I would prophesy,
behold, this is my prophecy—that the
things which this prophet Zenos
spake, concerning the house of Israel, in
the which he likened them unto a tame
olive tree, must surely come to pass.
2 And the day that he shall set his
hand again the second time to
recover his people, is the day, yea, even
the last time, that the servants of
the Lord shall go forth in his
power, to nourish and prune his vineyard;
and after that the end soon cometh.
3 And how blessed are they who have
labored diligently in his vineyard;
and how cursed are they who shall be
cast out into their own place! And
the world shall be burned with fire.
4 And how merciful is our God
unto us, for he remembereth the
house of Israel, both roots and
branches; and he stretches forth his
hands unto them all the day long;
and they are a stiffnecked and a
gainsaying people; but as many as
will not harden their hearts
shall be saved in the kingdom of God.
5 Wherefore, my beloved
brethren, I beseech of you in words
of soberness that ye would
repent, and come with full
purpose of heart, and cleave unto
God as he cleaveth unto you. And
while his arm of mercy is
extended towards you in the light
of the day, harden not your hearts.
6 Yea, today, if ye will
hear his voice, harden not your
hearts; for why will ye die?
7 For behold, after ye have
been nourished by the good
word of God all the day
long, will ye bring forth
evil fruit, that ye must be
hewn down and cast into the fire?
8 Behold, will ye reject
these words? Will ye reject
the words of the
prophets; and will ye reject all
the words which have been
spoken concerning Christ,
after so many have spoken
concerning him; and deny
the good word of Christ, and
the power of God, and the
gift of the Holy Ghost,
and quench the Holy Spirit,
and make a mock of the
great plan of redemption,
which hath been laid for you?
9 Know ye not that if ye
will do these things,
that the power of the
redemption and the
resurrection, which is in
Christ, will bring you to
stand with shame and awful
guilt before the bar of God?
10 And according to the
power of justice, for
justice cannot be
denied, ye must go away into
that lake of fire and
brimstone, whose flames
are unquenchable, and
whose smoke ascendeth
up forever and ever,
which lake of fire and
brimstone is endless torment.
11 O then, my beloved
brethren, repent ye,
and enter in at the
strait gate, and
continue in the way which
is narrow, until ye
shall obtain eternal life.
12 O be wise;
what can I say more?
13 Finally, I
bid you farewell,
until I shall
meet you before
the pleasing bar
of God, which bar
striketh the
wicked with awful
dread and fear. Amen.