1 We believe in God, the
Eternal Father, and in His Son, Jesus
Christ, and in the Holy Ghost.
2 We believe that men will be
punished for their own sins,
and not for Adam’s transgression.
3 We believe that through
the Atonement of Christ,
all mankind may be saved,
by obedience to the laws
and ordinances of the Gospel.
4 We believe that the
first principles and
ordinances of the Gospel are:
first, Faith in the
Lord Jesus Christ; second,
Repentance; third,
Baptism by immersion for the
remission of sins;
fourth, Laying on of hands
for the gift of the Holy Ghost.
5 We believe that a
man must be called of
God, by prophecy, and by
the laying on of
hands by those who are in
authority, to preach
the Gospel and
administer in the ordinances thereof.
6 We believe in the
same organization that
existed in the
Primitive Church, namely,
apostles, prophets,
pastors, teachers,
evangelists, and so forth.
7 We believe in the
gift of tongues,
prophecy,
revelation, visions, healing,
interpretation of
tongues, and so forth.
8 We believe the
Bible to be the
word of God as far
as it is
translated correctly; we
also believe the
Book of Mormon
to be the word of God.
9 We believe
all that God has
revealed, all
that He does now
reveal, and we
believe that
He will yet
reveal many great
and important
things pertaining
to the Kingdom of God.
10 We believe
in the literal
gathering of
Israel and in the
restoration of
the Ten Tribes;
that Zion (the
New Jerusalem)
will be built
upon the
American continent;
that Christ will
reign
personally upon the
earth; and, that
the earth will
be renewed and
receive its
paradisiacal glory.
11 We claim
the privilege of
worshiping
Almighty God
according to the
dictates of
our own
conscience, and allow
all men the
same privilege,
let them
worship how, where,
or what they may.
12 We believe
in being
subject to
kings, presidents,
rulers, and
magistrates,
in obeying,
honoring, and
sustaining the law.
13 We
believe in being
honest, true,
chaste,
benevolent,
virtuous, and
in doing good
to all men;
indeed, we
may say that
we follow
the
admonition of Paul—We
believe all
things, we
hope all
things, we have
endured
many things,
and hope to be
able to
endure all
things. If there
is anything
virtuous,
lovely, or of
good report
or
praiseworthy, we
seek after these things.Joseph Smith.