HIS REIGN AND MINISTRY
An account of Lehi and his wife
Sariah, and his four sons, being
called, (beginning at the
eldest) Laman, Lemuel, Sam, and
Nephi. The Lord warns Lehi to
depart out of the land of
Jerusalem, because he
prophesieth unto the people
concerning their iniquity and
they seek to destroy his life.
He taketh three days' journey
into the wilderness with his
family. Nephi taketh his
brethren and returneth to the
land of Jerusalem after the
record of the Jews. The account
of their sufferings. They take
the daughters of Ishmael to
wife. They take their families
and depart into the wilderness.
Their sufferings and afflictions
in the wilderness. The course of
their travels. They come to the
large waters. Nephi's brethren
rebel against him. He
confoundeth them, and buildeth a
ship. They call the name of the
place Bountiful. They cross the
large waters into the promised
land, and so forth. This is
according to the account of
Nephi; or in other words, I,
Nephi, wrote this record.
CHAPTER 1
Nephi begins the record of his
people--Lehi sees in vision a
pillar of fire and reads from a
book of prophecy--He praises
God, foretells the coming of the
Messiah, and prophesies the
destruction of Jerusalem--He is
persecuted by the Jews.
About 600 B.C.
I, NEPHI, having been born of
goodly parents, therefore I was
taught somewhat in all the
learning of my father; and
having seen many afflictions in
the course of my days,
nevertheless, having been highly
favored of the Lord in all my
days; yea, having had a great
knowledge of the goodness and
the mysteries of God, therefore
I make a record of my
proceedings in my days.
2 Yea, I make a record in the
language of my father, which
consists of the learning of the
Jews and the language of the
Egyptians.
3 And I know that the record
which I make is true; and I make
it with mine own hand; and I
make it according to my
knowledge.
4 For it came to pass in the
commencement of the first year
of the reign of Zedekiah, king
of Judah, (my father, Lehi,
having dwelt at Jerusalem in all
his days); and in that same year
there came many prophets,
prophesying unto the people that
they must repent, or the great
city Jerusalem must be
destroyed.
5 Wherefore it came to pass that
my father, Lehi, as he went
forth prayed unto the Lord, yea,
even with all his heart, in
behalf of his people.
6 And it came to pass as he
prayed unto the Lord, there came
a pillar of fire and dwelt upon
a rock before him; and he saw
and heard much; and because of
the things which he saw and
heard he did quake and tremble
exceedingly.
7 And it came to pass that he
returned to his own house at
Jerusalem; and he cast himself
upon his bed, being overcome
with the Spirit and the things
which he had seen.
8 And being thus overcome with
the Spirit, he was carried away
in a vision, even that he saw
the heavens open, and he thought
he saw God sitting upon his
throne, surrounded with
numberless concourses of angels
in the attitude of singing and
praising their God.
9 And it came to pass that he
saw One descending out of the
midst of heaven, and he beheld
that his luster was above that
of the sun at noon-day.
10 And he also saw twelve others
following him, and their
brightness did exceed that of
the stars in the firmament.
11 And they came down and went
forth upon the face of the
earth; and the first came and
stood before my father, and gave
unto him a book, and bade him
that he should read.
12 And it came to pass that as
he read, he was filled with the
Spirit of the Lord.
13 And he read, saying: Wo, wo,
unto Jerusalem, for I have seen
thine abominations! Yea, and
many things did my father read
concerning Jerusalem--that it
should be destroyed, and the
inhabitants thereof; many should
perish by the sword, and many
should be carried away captive
into Babylon.
14 And it came to pass that when
my father had read and seen many
great and marvelous things, he
did exclaim many things unto the
Lord; such as: Great and
marvelous are thy works, O Lord
God Almighty! Thy throne is high
in the heavens, and thy power,
and goodness, and mercy are over
all the inhabitants of the
earth; and, because thou art
merciful, thou wilt not suffer
those who come unto thee that
they shall perish!
15 And after this manner was the
language of my father in the
praising of his God; for his
soul did rejoice, and his whole
heart was filled, because of the
things which he had seen, yea,
which the Lord had shown unto
him.
16 And now I, Nephi, do not make
a full account of the things
which my father hath written,
for he hath written many things
which he saw in visions and in
dreams; and he also hath written
many things which he prophesied
and spake unto his children, of
which I shall not make a full
account.
17 But I shall make an account
of my proceedings in my days.
Behold, I make an abridgment of
the record of my father, upon
plates which I have made with
mine own hands; wherefore, after
I have abridged the record of my
father then will I make an
account of mine own life.
18 Therefore, I would that ye
should know, that after the Lord
had shown so many marvelous
things unto my father, Lehi,
yea, concerning the destruction
of Jerusalem, behold he went
forth among the people, and
began to prophesy and to declare
unto them concerning the things
which he had both seen and
heard.
19 And it came to pass that the
Jews did mock him because of the
things which he testified of
them; for he truly testified of
their wickedness and their
abominations; and he testified
that the things which he saw and
heard, and also the things which
he read in the book, manifested
plainly of the coming of a
Messiah, and also the redemption
of the world.
20 And when the Jews heard these
things they were angry with him;
yea, even as with the prophets
of old, whom they had cast out,
and stoned, and slain; and they
also sought his life, that they
might take it away. But behold,
I, Nephi, will show unto you
that the tender mercies of the
Lord are over all those whom he
hath chosen, because of their
faith, to make them mighty even
unto the power of deliverance.
CHAPTER 2
Lehi takes his family into the
wilderness by the Red Sea--They
leave their property--Lehi
offers a sacrifice to the Lord
and teaches his sons to keep the
commandments--Laman and Lemuel
murmur against their father--
Nephi is obedient and prays in
faith; the Lord speaks to him,
and he is chosen to rule over
his brethren.
About 600 B.C.
FOR behold, it came to pass that
the Lord spake unto my father,
yea, even in a dream, and said
unto him: Blessed art thou Lehi,
because of the things which thou
hast done; and because thou hast
been faithful and declared unto
this people the things which I
commanded thee, behold, they
seek to take away thy life.
2 And it came to pass that the
Lord commanded my father, even
in a dream, that he should take
his family and depart into the
wilderness.
3 And it came to pass that he
was obedient unto the word of
the Lord, wherefore he did as
the Lord commanded him.
4 And it came to pass that he
departed into the wilderness.
And he left his house, and the
land of his inheritance, and his
gold, and his silver, and his
precious things, and took
nothing with him, save it were
his family, and provisions, and
tents, and departed into the
wilderness.
5 And he came down by the
borders near the shore of the
Red Sea; and he traveled in the
wilderness in the borders which
are nearer the Red Sea; and he
did travel in the wilderness
with his family, which consisted
of my mother, Sariah, and my
elder brothers, who were Laman,
Lemuel, and Sam.
6 And it came to pass that when
he had traveled three days in
the wilderness, he pitched his
tent in a valley by the side of
a river of water.
7 And it came to pass that he
built an altar of stones, and
made an offering unto the Lord,
and gave thanks unto the Lord
our God.
8 And it came to pass that he
called the name of the river,
Laman, and it emptied into the
Red Sea; and the valley was in
the borders near the mouth
thereof.
9 And when my father saw that
the waters of the river emptied
into the fountain of the Red
Sea, he spake unto Laman,
saying: O that thou mightest be
like unto this river,
continually running into the
fountain of all righteousness!
10 And he also spake unto
Lemuel: O that thou mightest be
like unto this valley, firm and
steadfast, and immovable in
keeping the commandments of the
Lord!
11 Now this he spake because of
the stiffneckedness of Laman and
Lemuel; for behold they did
murmur in many things against
their father, because he was a
visionary man, and had led them
out of the land of Jerusalem, to
leave the land of their
inheritance, and their gold, and
their silver, and their precious
things, to perish in the
wilderness. And this they said
he had done because of the
foolish imaginations of his
heart.
12 And thus Laman and Lemuel,
being the eldest, did murmur
against their father. And they
did murmur because they knew not
the dealings of that God who had
created them.
13 Neither did they believe that
Jerusalem, that great city,
could be destroyed according to
the words of the prophets. And
they were like unto the Jews who
were at Jerusalem, who sought to
take away the life of my father.
14 And it came to pass that my
father did speak unto them in
the valley of Lemuel, with
power, being filled with the
Spirit, until their frames did
shake before him. And he did
confound them, that they durst
not utter against him;
wherefore, they did as he
commanded them.
15 And my father dwelt in a
tent.
16 And it came to pass that I,
Nephi, being exceedingly young,
nevertheless being large in
stature, and also having great
desires to know of the mysteries
of God, wherefore, I did cry
unto the Lord; and behold he did
visit me, and did soften my
heart that I did believe all the
words which had been spoken by
my father; wherefore, I did not
rebel against him like unto my
brothers.
17 And I spake unto Sam, making
known unto him the things which
the Lord had manifested unto me
by his Holy Spirit. And it came
to pass that he believed in my
words.
18 But, behold, Laman and Lemuel
would not hearken unto my words;
and being grieved because of the
hardness of their hearts I cried
unto the Lord for them.
19 And it came to pass that the
Lord spake unto me, saying:
Blessed art thou, Nephi, because
of thy faith, for thou hast
sought me diligently, with
lowliness of heart.
20 And inasmuch as ye shall keep
my commandments, ye shall
prosper, and shall be led to a
land of promise; yea, even a
land which I have prepared for
you; yea, a land which is choice
above all other lands.
21 And inasmuch as thy brethren
shall rebel against thee, they
shall be cut off from the
presence of the Lord.
22 And inasmuch as thou shalt
keep my commandments, thou shalt
be made a ruler and a teacher
over thy brethren.
23 For behold, in that day that
they shall rebel against me, I
will curse them even with a sore
curse, and they shall have no
power over thy seed except they
shall rebel against me also.
24 And if it so be that they
rebel against me, they shall be
a scourge unto thy seed, to stir
them up in the ways of
remembrance.
CHAPTER 3
Lehi's sons return to Jerusalem
to obtain the plates of brass--
Laban refuses to give the plates
up--Nephi exhorts and encourages
his brethren--Laban steals their
property and attempts to slay
them--Laman and Lemuel smite
Nephi and Sam and are reproved
by an angel.
About 600-592 B.C.
AND it came to pass that I,
Nephi, returned from speaking
with the Lord, to the tent of my
father.
2 And it came to pass that he
spake unto me, saying: Behold I
have dreamed a dream, in the
which the Lord hath commanded me
that thou and thy brethren shall
return to Jerusalem.
3 For behold, Laban hath the
record of the Jews and also a
genealogy of my forefathers, and
they are engraven upon plates of
brass.
4 Wherefore, the Lord hath
commanded me that thou and thy
brothers should go unto the
house of Laban, and seek the
records, and bring them down
hither into the wilderness.
5 And now, behold thy brothers
murmur, saying it is a hard
thing which I have required of
them; but behold I have not
required it of them, but it is a
commandment of the Lord.
6 Therefore go, my son, and thou
shalt be favored of the Lord,
because thou hast not murmured.
7 And it came to pass that I,
Nephi, said unto my father: I
will go and do the things which
the Lord hath commanded, for I
know that the Lord giveth no
commandments unto the children
of men, save he shall prepare a
way for them that they may