The Book of EnosChapter 1 Enos prays
mightily and gains a remission of his sins—The
voice of the Lord comes into his mind, promising
salvation for the Lamanites in a future
day—The Nephites sought to reclaim the
Lamanites—Enos rejoices in his Redeemer. About 420 B.C.
1 Behold, it came to pass that I, Enos,
knowing my father that he was a just
man—for he taught me in his language, and also
in the nurture and admonition of the
Lord—and blessed be the name of my God for it—
2 And I will tell you of the
wrestle which I had before God, before
I received a remission of my sins.
3 Behold, I went to hunt
beasts in the forests; and the
words which I had often heard
my father speak concerning
eternal life, and the joy of the
saints, sunk deep into my heart.
4 And my soul hungered;
and I kneeled down before my
Maker, and I cried unto
him in mighty prayer and
supplication for mine own
soul; and all the day long
did I cry unto him; yea,
and when the night came I
did still raise my voice
high that it reached the heavens.
5 And there came a voice
unto me, saying: Enos,
thy sins are forgiven thee,
and thou shalt be blessed.
6 And I, Enos, knew
that God could not
lie; wherefore, my
guilt was swept away.
7 And I said:
Lord, how is it done?
8 And he said
unto me: Because
of thy faith in
Christ, whom thou
hast never
before heard nor
seen. And many
years pass away
before he shall
manifest himself in
the flesh;
wherefore, go to, thy
faith hath made thee whole.
9 Now, it came
to pass that
when I had heard
these words I
began to feel a
desire for the
welfare of my
brethren, the
Nephites;
wherefore, I did pour
out my whole
soul unto God for them.
10 And while I
was thus
struggling in the
spirit,
behold, the voice of
the Lord came
into my mind
again, saying:
I will visit
thy brethren
according to
their diligence
in keeping my
commandments.
I have given
unto them this
land, and it
is a holy land;
and I curse
it not save it
be for the
cause of
iniquity; wherefore, I
will visit
thy brethren
according as I
have said; and
their
transgressions will I
bring down with sorrow upon their own heads.
11 And after
I, Enos, had
heard these
words, my faith
began to be
unshaken in the
Lord; and I
prayed unto him
with many long
strugglings for
my brethren,
the Lamanites.
12 And it
came to pass
that after I had
prayed and
labored with
all diligence,
the Lord
said unto me: I
will grant
unto thee
according to thy
desires,
because of thy faith.
13 And now
behold, this
was the
desire which I
desired of
him—that if it
should so
be, that my
people, the
Nephites,
should fall
into
transgression, and by
any means be
destroyed,
and the
Lamanites should
not be
destroyed, that
the Lord God
would
preserve a record
of my
people, the
Nephites; even if
it so be by
the power
of his holy
arm, that it
might be
brought forth
at some
future day unto
the
Lamanites, that,
perhaps, they might be brought unto salvation—
14 For at
the present
our
strugglings were
vain in
restoring them
to the true
faith. And
they swore
in their
wrath that,
if it were
possible,
they would
destroy our
records and
us, and
also all the
traditions of our fathers.
Wherefore, I
knowing that
the Lord
God was able
to
preserve our
records, I
cried unto
him
continually, for
he had
said unto me:
Whatsoever thing ye
shall ask
in faith,
believing
that ye
shall
receive in the
name of
Christ, ye shall receive it.
16 And I
had
faith, and I
did cry
unto God
that he
would
preserve the
records;
and he
covenanted
with me
that he
would bring
them forth
unto the
Lamanites in his own due time.
17 And
I, Enos,
knew it
would be
according to
the
covenant which
he had
made;
wherefore
my soul did rest.
18 And
the
Lord said
unto
me: Thy
fathers
have
also
required of
me
this
thing; and
it shall
be
done unto
them
according
to
their
faith; for
faith was like unto thine.
19 And
now
it came
to
pass
that I,
Enos,
went
about
among
the
people of
Nephi,
prophesying
of
things
to
come, and
testifying
of the
things
which I had heard and seen.
And I
bear
record
that
the
people of
Nephi
did
seek
diligently
to
restore the
Lamanites
unto
the
true
faith
in
God.
But
our
labors
were
vain;
their
hatred
was
fixed,
and
they
were
led by
their
evil
nature
that
they
became
wild,
and
ferocious,
a
blood-thirsty
people,
full
of
idolatry
and
filthiness;
feeding
upon
beasts of
prey;
dwelling
in
tents,
and
wandering
about
in
the
wilderness
with a
short
skin
girdle
about
their
loins
and
their
heads
shaven;
and
their
skill
was
in
the
bow, and
in
the
cimeter, and
ax. And many of them did eat nothing save it was raw meat; and they were continually seeking to destroy us.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
people
of
Nephi
did
till
the
land,
and
raise
all
manner
of
grain,
and of
fruit,
and
flocks
of
herds,
and
flocks
of
all
manner of
cattle
of
every
kind,
and goats, and wild goats, and also many horses.
And
there
were
exceedingly
many
prophets
among
us.
And
the
people
were a
stiffnecked people, hard to understand.
And
there
was
nothing
save
it
was
exceeding
harshness,
preaching
and
prophesying
of
wars,
and
contentions,
destructions,
and
continually
reminding
them
of
death,
and
the
duration
of
eternity,
and
the
judgments
and
the
power
of
God,
and
all
these
things—stirring
them
up
continually
to
keep
them
in
the
fear
of
the
Lord.
I
say
there
was
nothing short of these things, and exceedingly great plainness of speech, would keep them from going down speedily to destruction. And after this manner do I write concerning them.
And
I
saw
wars
between
the
Nephites
and
Lamanites
in
the
course
of
my
days.
25 And it came to pass that I began to be old, and an hundred and seventy and nine years had passed away from the time that our father Lehi left
And
it
came
to
pass
that
I
began
to
be
old,
and
an
hundred
and
seventy
nine years had passed away from the time that our father Lehi left Jerusalem.
26 And I saw that I must soon go down to my grave, having been wrought upon by the power of God that I must preach and prophesy unto this people, and declare the word according to the truth which is in Christ. And I have declared it in all my days, and have rejoiced in it above that of the
And
I
saw
that
I
must
soon
go
down
to
my
grave,
having
been
wrought
upon
by
the
power
of
God
that
I
must
preach
and
prophesy
unto
this
people,
and
declare
the
word
according
to
the
truth
which
is
in
Christ.
And
I
have
declared
it
in
all
my
days,
and
have
rejoiced
in
it
above
that
of
the
world.
27 And I soon go to the place of my rest, which is with my Redeemer; for I know that in him I shall rest. And I rejoice in the day when my mortal shall put on immortality, and shall stand before him; then shall I see his face with pleasure, and he will say unto me: Come unto me, ye blessed, there is a place prepared for you in the mansions of my Father. Amen.
And
I
soon
go
to
the
place
of
my
rest,
which
is
with
my
Redeemer;
for
I
know
that
in
him
I
shall
rest.
And
I
rejoice
in
the
day
when
my
mortal
shall
put
on
immortality,
and
shall
stand
before
him;
then
shall
I
see
his
face
with
pleasure,
and
he
will
say
unto
me:
Come
unto
me,
ye
blessed,
there
is
a
place
prepared
for
you
in
the
mansions
of
my
Father.
Amen.