The Book of HelamanAn account of the Nephites.
Their wars and contentions, and their
dissensions. And also the prophecies of many holy prophets,
before the coming of Christ, according to the
records of Helaman, who was the son of Helaman,
and also according to the records of his sons,
even down to the coming of Christ. And also many
of the Lamanites are converted. An account of
their conversion. An account of the righteousness
of the Lamanites, and the wickedness and
abominations of the Nephites, according to the record of
Helaman and his sons, even down to the coming
of Christ, which is called the book of Helaman,
and so forth.Chapter 1 Pahoran the second becomes
chief judge and is murdered by
Kishkumen—Pacumeni fills the judgment seat—Coriantumr leads the
Lamanite armies, takes Zarahemla, and slays
Pacumeni—Moronihah defeats the Lamanites and retakes
Zarahemla, and Coriantumr is slain. About 52–50 B.C.
1 And now behold, it came to pass in the
commencement of the fortieth year of
the reign of the judges over the people of
Nephi, there began to be a serious
difficulty among the people of the Nephites.
2 For behold, Pahoran had died, and
gone the way of all the earth;
therefore there began to be a serious
contention concerning who should
have the judgment-seat among the
brethren, who were the sons of Pahoran.
3 Now these are their names who did
contend for the judgment-seat, who
did also cause the people to
contend: Pahoran, Paanchi, and Pacumeni.
4 Now these are not all the
sons of Pahoran (for he had
many), but these are they who did
contend for the judgment-seat;
therefore, they did cause
three divisions among the people.
5 Nevertheless, it came to
pass that Pahoran was
appointed by the voice of the
people to be chief judge and a
governor over the people of Nephi.
6 And it came to pass that
Pacumeni, when he saw that
he could not obtain the
judgment-seat, he did unite
with the voice of the people.
7 But behold, Paanchi,
and that part of the people
that were desirous that
he should be their
governor, was exceedingly
wroth; therefore, he was about
to flatter away those
people to rise up in
rebellion against their brethren.
8 And it came to pass
as he was about to do
this, behold, he was
taken, and was tried
according to the voice of the
people, and condemned
unto death; for he had
raised up in rebellion
and sought to destroy
the liberty of the people.
9 Now when those
people who were desirous
that he should be their
governor saw that he
was condemned unto
death, therefore they were
angry, and behold,
they sent forth one
Kishkumen, even to the
judgment-seat of Pahoran,
and murdered Pahoran
as he sat upon the judgment-seat.
10 And he was pursued
by the servants of
Pahoran; but behold,
so speedy was the
flight of Kishkumen that
no man could overtake him.
11 And he went unto
those that sent him,
and they all
entered into a covenant,
yea, swearing by
their everlasting Maker,
that they would
tell no man that
Kishkumen had murdered Pahoran.
12 Therefore,
Kishkumen was not
known among the people
of Nephi, for he
was in disguise at
the time that he
murdered Pahoran.
And Kishkumen and
his band, who had
covenanted with
him, did mingle
themselves among the
people, in a manner
that they all
could not be found;
but as many as were
found were condemned unto death.
13 And now
behold, Pacumeni was
appointed,
according to the voice of
the people, to
be a chief judge
and a governor
over the people, to
reign in the
stead of his brother
Pahoran; and it
was according to
his right. And all
this was done in
the fortieth
year of the reign of
the judges; and it had an end.
14 And it came
to pass in the
forty and first
year of the reign
of the judges,
that the
Lamanites had gathered
together an
innumerable army of
men, and armed
them with swords,
and with
cimeters and with bows,
arrows, and with
head-plates, and with
breastplates,
and with all
manner of shields of every kind.
15 And they
came down again
that they might
pitch battle
against the
Nephites. And they
were led by a man
whose name was
Coriantumr;
and he was a
descendant of
Zarahemla; and he
was a dissenter
from among the
Nephites; and he
was a large and a mighty man.
16 Therefore,
the king of
the Lamanites,
whose name was
Tubaloth, who
was the son of
Ammoron,
supposing that
Coriantumr, being
a mighty man,
could stand
against the
Nephites, with
his strength and
also with his
great wisdom,
insomuch that
by sending
him forth he
should gain power over the Nephites—
17 Therefore
he did stir
them up to
anger, and he
did gather
together his
armies, and he
did appoint
Coriantumr to be
their
leader, and did
cause that they
should march
down to the
land of
Zarahemla to battle
against the Nephites.
18 And it
came to pass
that because
of so much
contention
and so much
difficulty in
the
government, that
they had not
kept
sufficient guards in
the land of
Zarahemla;
for they had
supposed
that the
Lamanites durst
not come into
the heart of
their lands
to attack
that great city Zarahemla.
19 But it
came to pass
that
Coriantumr did
march forth
at the head
of his
numerous host,
and came
upon the
inhabitants of
the city,
and their
march was
with such
exceedingly
great speed
that there
was no time
for the
Nephites to
gather together their armies.
Therefore
Coriantumr did
cut down the
watch by
the
entrance of the
city, and
did march
forth with
his whole
army into
the city,
and they
did slay
every one
who did
oppose them,
insomuch
that they
did take
possession of the whole city.
21 And it
came to
pass that
Pacumeni, who was
the
chief judge,
did flee
before
Coriantumr,
even to
the walls
of the
city. And
it came
to pass
that
Coriantumr did
smite him
against
the wall,
insomuch
that he
died. And
thus ended the days of Pacumeni.
22 And
now when
Coriantumr saw
that he
was in
possession
of the
city of
Zarahemla, and
saw that
the
Nephites had
fled
before
them, and
were
slain, and
taken, and
were cast
into
prison,
and that
he had
obtained
the
possession of
strongest
hold in
all the
land, his
heart
took
courage
insomuch
that he was
about to go forth against all the land.
23 And
now he
did not
tarry
in the
land of
Zarahemla,
but he
did march
forth
with a
large
army,
even
towards the
city
of
Bountiful;
for it
was his
determination
to go
forth
and cut
his way
through
with
the
sword, that
he
might obtain the north parts of the land.
And,
supposing
that
their
greatest
strength
was in
the
center
of the
land,
therefore he
did
march
forth,
giving
them
no
time to
assemble
themselves
together
save it
were
in
small
bodies;
and in
this
manner
they
did fall
upon them and cut them down to the earth.
But
behold,
this
march
of
Coriantumr
through
the
center
of the
land
gave
Moronihah
great
advantage
over
them,
notwithstanding
the
greatness of
number of the Nephites who were slain.
For
behold,
Moronihah
had
supposed
that
the
Lamanites
durst
not
come
into
the
center
of
the
land,
but
that
they
would
attack
the
cities
round
about
in
the
borders as
they
had
hitherto
done;
therefore
Moronihah
had
caused
that
their
strong armies should maintain those parts round about by the borders.
But
behold,
the
Lamanites
were
not
frightened
according
to
his
desire,
but
they
had
come
into
the
center
of
the
land,
and
had
taken
the
capital
city
which
was
the
city
of
Zarahemla,
and
were
marching
through
the
most
capital
parts
of
the
land,
slaying
the
people
with
a
great
slaughter, both men, women, and children, taking possession of many cities and of many strongholds.
But
when
Moronihah
had
discovered
this,
he
immediately
sent
forth
Lehi
with
an
army
round
about
to
head them before they should come to the land Bountiful.
29 And thus he did; and he did head them before they came to the land Bountiful, and gave unto them battle, insomuch that they began to retreat back towards the land of
And
thus
he
did;
and
he
did
head
them
before
they
came
to
the
land
Bountiful,
and
gave
unto them battle, insomuch that they began to retreat back towards the land of Zarahemla.
30 And it came to pass that Moronihah did head them in their retreat, and did give unto them battle, insomuch that it became an exceedingly bloody battle; yea, many were slain, and among the number who were slain Coriantumr was also
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Moronihah
did
head
them
in
their
retreat,
and
did
give
unto
them
battle,
insomuch
that
it
became
an
exceedingly
bloody
battle;
yea,
many
were
slain,
and
among
the
number
who
were
slain
Coriantumr
was
also
found.
31 And now, behold, the Lamanites could not retreat either way, neither on the north, nor on the south, nor on the east, nor on the west, for they were surrounded on every hand by the
And
now,
behold,
the
Lamanites
could
not
retreat
either
way,
neither
on
the
north,
nor
on
the
south,
nor
on
the
east,
nor
on
the
west,
for
they
were
surrounded
on
every
hand
by
the
Nephites.
32 And thus had Coriantumr plunged the Lamanites into the midst of the Nephites, insomuch that they were in the power of the Nephites, and he himself was slain, and the Lamanites did yield themselves into the hands of the
And
thus
had
Coriantumr
plunged
the
Lamanites
into
the
midst
of
the
Nephites,
insomuch
that
they
were
in
the
power
of
the
Nephites,
and
he
himself
was
slain,
and
the
Lamanites
did
yield
themselves
into
the
hands
of
the
Nephites.
33 And it came to pass that Moronihah took possession of the city of Zarahemla again, and caused that the Lamanites who had been taken prisoners should depart out of the land in
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Moronihah
took
possession
of
the
city
of
Zarahemla
again,
and
caused
that
the
Lamanites
who
had
been
taken
prisoners
should
depart
out
of
the
land
in
peace.
34 And thus ended the forty and first year of the reign of the judges.
And
thus
ended
the
forty
and
first
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges.