Chapter 15 The Lord chastened the Nephites
because He loved them—Converted Lamanites are firm and
steadfast in the faith—The Lord will be merciful
unto the Lamanites in the latter days. About 6 B.C.
1 And now, my beloved brethren, behold, I
declare unto you that except ye shall repent
your houses shall be left unto you desolate.
2 Yea, except ye repent, your women
shall have great cause to mourn in the day
that they shall give suck; for ye shall
attempt to flee and there shall be no
place for refuge; yea, and wo unto them
which are with child, for they shall be
heavy and cannot flee; therefore, they
shall be trodden down and shall be left to perish.
3 Yea, wo unto this people who are
called the people of Nephi except they
shall repent, when they shall see all
these signs and wonders which shall be
showed unto them; for behold, they have
been a chosen people of the Lord;
yea, the people of Nephi hath he loved,
and also hath he chastened them; yea,
in the days of their iniquities hath he
chastened them because he loveth them.
4 But behold my brethren, the
Lamanites hath he hated because their
deeds have been evil continually,
and this because of the iniquity
of the tradition of their fathers.
But behold, salvation hath come
unto them through the preaching of
the Nephites; and for this intent
hath the Lord prolonged their days.
5 And I would that ye should
behold that the more part of
them are in the path of their
duty, and they do walk
circumspectly before God, and they do
observe to keep his
commandments and his statutes and his
judgments according to the law of Moses.
6 Yea, I say unto you, that
the more part of them are
doing this, and they are
striving with unwearied diligence
that they may bring the
remainder of their brethren to
the knowledge of the truth;
therefore there are many who
do add to their numbers daily.
7 And behold, ye do know of
yourselves, for ye have
witnessed it, that as many of
them as are brought to the
knowledge of the truth,
and to know of the wicked and
abominable traditions of
their fathers, and are led
to believe the holy
scriptures, yea, the prophecies of
the holy prophets, which
are written, which leadeth
them to faith on the Lord,
and unto repentance, which
faith and repentance bringeth
a change of heart unto them—
8 Therefore, as many as
have come to this, ye know
of yourselves are firm
and steadfast in the
faith, and in the thing
wherewith they have been made free.
9 And ye know also that
they have buried their
weapons of war, and they
fear to take them up
lest by any means they
should sin; yea, ye can see
that they fear to
sin—for behold they will
suffer themselves that they
be trodden down and slain
by their enemies, and
will not lift their
swords against them, and this
because of their faith in Christ.
10 And now, because of
their steadfastness
when they do believe in
that thing which they
do believe, for
because of their firmness
when they are once
enlightened, behold, the
Lord shall bless them
and prolong their days,
notwithstanding their iniquity—
11 Yea, even if they
should dwindle in
unbelief the Lord shall
prolong their days,
until the time shall
come which hath been
spoken of by our
fathers, and also by the
prophet Zenos, and
many other prophets,
concerning the
restoration of our brethren,
the Lamanites, again
to the knowledge of the truth—
12 Yea, I say unto
you, that in the
latter times the
promises of the Lord have
been extended to our
brethren, the
Lamanites; and
notwithstanding the many
afflictions which they
shall have, and
notwithstanding they shall
be driven to and fro
upon the face of
the earth, and be
hunted, and shall be
smitten and scattered
abroad, having no
place for refuge, the
Lord shall be merciful unto them.
13 And this is
according to the
prophecy, that they
shall again be
brought to the true
knowledge, which is
the knowledge of
their Redeemer, and
their great and
true shepherd, and
be numbered among his sheep.
14 Therefore I
say unto you, it
shall be better for
them than for
you except ye repent.
15 For behold,
had the mighty
works been shown
unto them which
have been shown
unto you, yea,
unto them who have
dwindled in
unbelief because of
the traditions
of their
fathers, ye can see of
yourselves that
they never would
again have
dwindled in unbelief.
16 Therefore,
saith the Lord:
I will not
utterly destroy
them, but I will
cause that in
the day of my
wisdom they shall
return again
unto me, saith the Lord.
17 And now
behold, saith the
Lord,
concerning the people
of the
Nephites: If they
will not repent,
and observe
to do my will,
I will utterly
destroy them,
saith the
Lord, because of
their unbelief
notwithstanding the many
mighty works
which I have done
among them;
and as surely
as the Lord
liveth shall
these things be, saith the Lord.