The prophecy of Samuel, the Lamanite, to the
Nephites. Comprising chapters 13 through 15.Chapter
13 Samuel the Lamanite prophesies the
destruction of the Nephites unless they repent—They and
their riches are cursed—They reject and stone the
prophets, are encircled about by demons, and
seek for happiness in doing iniquity. About 6 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass in the eighty and
sixth year, the Nephites did still remain in
wickedness, yea, in great wickedness, while the
Lamanites did observe strictly to keep the
commandments of God, according to the law of Moses.
2 And it came to pass that in this year
there was one Samuel, a Lamanite, came
into the land of Zarahemla, and began to
preach unto the people. And it came to pass
that he did preach, many days, repentance
unto the people, and they did cast him
out, and he was about to return to his own land.
3 But behold, the voice of the Lord
came unto him, that he should return
again, and prophesy unto the people
whatsoever things should come into his heart.
4 And it came to pass that they
would not suffer that he should
enter into the city; therefore he
went and got upon the wall
thereof, and stretched forth his hand
and cried with a loud voice, and
prophesied unto the people
whatsoever things the Lord put into his heart.
5 And he said unto them: Behold,
I, Samuel, a Lamanite, do speak
the words of the Lord which he
doth put into my heart; and
behold he hath put it into my heart
to say unto this people that the
sword of justice hangeth over
this people; and four hundred
years pass not away save the sword
of justice falleth upon this people.
6 Yea, heavy destruction
awaiteth this people, and it surely
cometh unto this people, and
nothing can save this people
save it be repentance and faith
on the Lord Jesus Christ, who
surely shall come into the
world, and shall suffer many
things and shall be slain for his people.
7 And behold, an angel of the
Lord hath declared it unto
me, and he did bring glad
tidings to my soul. And behold, I
was sent unto you to declare
it unto you also, that ye
might have glad tidings; but
behold ye would not receive me.
8 Therefore, thus saith
the Lord: Because of the
hardness of the hearts of the
people of the Nephites,
except they repent I will
take away my word from
them, and I will withdraw my
Spirit from them, and I
will suffer them no longer,
and I will turn the hearts
of their brethren against them.
9 And four hundred
years shall not pass away
before I will cause that
they shall be smitten;
yea, I will visit them
with the sword and
with famine and with pestilence.
10 Yea, I will visit
them in my fierce
anger, and there shall be
those of the fourth
generation who shall
live, of your enemies, to
behold your utter
destruction; and this
shall surely come except
ye repent, saith the
Lord; and those of the
fourth generation shall
visit your destruction.
11 But if ye will
repent and return unto
the Lord your God I
will turn away mine
anger, saith the Lord;
yea, thus saith the
Lord, blessed are they
who will repent and
turn unto me, but wo
unto him that repenteth not.
12 Yea, wo unto this
great city of
Zarahemla; for behold, it
is because of those
who are righteous
that it is saved;
yea, wo unto this great
city, for I
perceive, saith the Lord,
that there are many,
yea, even the more
part of this great
city, that will harden
their hearts
against me, saith the Lord.
13 But blessed are
they who will
repent, for them will I
spare. But behold,
if it were not for
the righteous who
are in this great
city, behold, I would
cause that fire
should come down out
of heaven and destroy it.
14 But behold, it
is for the
righteous’ sake that it
is spared. But
behold, the time
cometh, saith the Lord,
that when ye
shall cast out the
righteous from among
you, then shall ye
be ripe for
destruction; yea, wo be
unto this great
city, because of
the wickedness and
abominations which are in her.
15 Yea, and wo
be unto the city
of Gideon, for
the wickedness
and abominations
which are in her.
16 Yea, and wo
be unto all the
cities which
are in the land
round about,
which are
possessed by the
Nephites, because of
the wickedness
and
abominations which are in them.
17 And behold,
a curse shall
come upon the
land, saith
the Lord of
Hosts, because of
the people’s
sake who are
upon the land,
yea, because
of their
wickedness and their
abominations.
18 And it
shall come to
pass, saith the
Lord of
Hosts, yea, our
great and true
God, that
whoso shall
hide up
treasures in the
earth shall find
them again no
more,
because of the
great curse of
the land, save
he be a
righteous man and
shall hide it up unto the Lord.
19 For I
will, saith the
Lord, that
they shall
hide up their
treasures
unto me; and
cursed be
they who hide
not up their
treasures
unto me; for
none hideth
up their
treasures unto
me save it
be the
righteous; and he
that hideth
not up his
treasures
unto me, cursed
is he, and
also the
treasure, and
none shall
redeem it
because of the curse of the land.
20 And the
day shall
come that
they shall
hide up their
treasures,
because
they have set
their
hearts upon
riches; and
because they
have set
their hearts
upon their
riches, and
will hide
up their
treasures
when they
shall flee
before their
enemies;
because they
will not hide
them up
unto me,
cursed be they
and also
their
treasures; and in
that day
shall they be smitten, saith the Lord.
21 Behold
ye, the
people of
this great
city, and
hearken
unto my
words; yea,
hearken unto
the words
which the
Lord
saith; for
behold, he
saith that ye
are
cursed because
of your
riches, and
also are
your riches
cursed
because ye
have set
your hearts
upon them,
and have
not
hearkened unto
the words of him who gave them unto you.
22 Ye do
not
remember the
Lord your
God in
the things
with
which he hath
blessed
you, but
ye do
always
remember your
riches,
not to
thank the
Lord your
God for
them; yea,
your
hearts are
not drawn
out unto
the Lord,
but they
do swell
with
great pride,
unto
boasting, and
great
swelling,
envyings,
strifes,
malice,
persecutions,
and murders, and all manner of iniquities.
23 For
this
cause hath
the Lord
God
caused that
a curse
should
come upon
the
land, and
also upon
your
riches,
and this
because
of your iniquities.
24 Yea,
wo
unto this
people,
because of
this time
which
has
arrived,
that ye
do cast
out
the
prophets,
and do
mock
them, and
cast
stones at
them,
and do
slay
them, and
do all
manner
of
iniquity
unto
them, even as they did of old time.
25 And
now
when ye
talk,
ye
say: If
our
days had
been
in the
days
of our
fathers of
old,
we
would not
have
slain
the
prophets;
we
would
not have
stoned them, and cast them out.
Behold
ye
are
worse
than
they;
for as
the
Lord
liveth, if
a
prophet
come
among you
and
declareth
unto
you
the
word of
Lord,
which
testifieth of
your
sins
and
iniquities, ye
are
angry
with
him,
and
cast
him
out and
seek
all
manner of
ways
to
destroy
him;
yea,
you
will
say
that
he is
a
false
prophet, and
that
he
is a
sinner, and of the devil, because he testifieth that your deeds are evil.
But
behold,
if a
man
shall
come
among
you
and
shall
say:
Do
this,
and
there
is no
iniquity;
do
that
and
ye
shall
not
suffer;
yea,
he
will
say:
Walk
after
the
pride
of
your
own
hearts;
yea,
walk
after
the
pride
of
your
eyes,
and
do
whatsoever
your
heart
desireth—and
if
a
man
shall
come
among you and say this, ye will receive him, and say that he is a prophet.
Yea,
ye
will
lift
him
up,
and
ye
will
give
unto
him
of
your
substance;
ye
will
give
unto
him
of
your
gold,
and
of
your
silver,
and
ye
will
clothe
him
with
costly
apparel;
and
because
he
speaketh
flattering
words
unto
you, and he saith that all is well, then ye will not find fault with him.
O
ye
wicked
and
ye
perverse
generation;
ye
hardened
and
ye
stiffnecked
people,
how
long
will
ye
suppose
that
the
Lord
will
suffer
you?
Yea,
how
long
will
ye
suffer
yourselves
to
be
led
by
foolish
and
blind
guides?
Yea,
how
long
will
ye
choose
darkness
rather
than
light?
Yea,
behold,
the
anger
of
the
Lord
is
already
kindled
against
you;
behold,
he
hath cursed the land because of your iniquity.
31 And behold, the time cometh that he curseth your riches, that they become slippery, that ye cannot hold them; and in the days of your poverty ye cannot retain
And
behold,
the
time
cometh
that
he
curseth
your
riches,
that
they
become
slippery, that ye cannot hold them; and in the days of your poverty ye cannot retain them.
32 And in the days of your poverty ye shall cry unto the Lord; and in vain shall ye cry, for your desolation is already come upon you, and your destruction is made sure; and then shall ye weep and howl in that day, saith the Lord of Hosts. And then shall ye lament, and
And
in
the
days
of
your
poverty
ye
shall
cry
unto
the
Lord;
and
in
vain
shall
ye
cry,
for
your
desolation
is
already
come
upon
you,
and
your
destruction
is
made
sure;
and
then
shall
ye
weep
and
howl
in
that
day,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts.
And
then
shall
ye
lament,
and
say:
33 O that I had repented, and had not killed the prophets, and stoned them, and cast them out. Yea, in that day ye shall say: O that we had remembered the Lord our God in the day that he gave us our riches, and then they would not have become slippery that we should lose them; for behold, our riches are gone from
O
that
I
had
repented,
and
had
not
killed
the
prophets,
and
stoned
them,
and
cast
them
out.
Yea,
in
that
day
ye
shall
say:
O
that
we
had
remembered
the
Lord
that
he
gave
us
our
riches,
and
then
they
would
not
have
become
slippery
that
we
should
lose
them;
for
behold,
our
riches
are
gone
from
us.
34 Behold, we lay a tool here and on the morrow it is gone; and behold, our swords are taken from us in the day we have sought them for
Behold,
we
lay
a
tool
here
and
on
the
morrow
it
is
gone;
and
behold,
our
swords
are
taken
from
have
sought
them
for
battle.
35 Yea, we have hid up our treasures and they have slipped away from us, because of the curse of the
Yea,
we
have
hid
up
our
treasures
and
they
have
slipped
away
from
us,
because
of
the
curse
of
the
land.
36 O that we had repented in the day that the word of the Lord came unto us; for behold the land is cursed, and all things are become slippery, and we cannot hold
O
that
we
had
repented
in
the
day
that
the
word
of
the
Lord
came
unto
us;
for
behold
the
land
is
cursed,
and
all
things
are
become
slippery,
and
we
cannot
hold
them.
37 Behold, we are surrounded by demons, yea, we are encircled about by the angels of him who hath sought to destroy our souls. Behold, our iniquities are great. O Lord, canst thou not turn away thine anger from us? And this shall be your language in those
Behold,
we
are
surrounded
by
demons,
yea,
we
are
encircled
about
by
the
angels
of
him
who
hath
sought
to
destroy
our
souls.
Behold,
our
iniquities
are
great.
O
Lord,
canst
thou
not
turn
away
thine
anger
from
us?
And
this
shall
be
your
language
in
those
days.
38 But behold, your days of probation are past; ye have procrastinated the day of your salvation until it is everlastingly too late, and your destruction is made sure; yea, for ye have sought all the days of your lives for that which ye could not obtain; and ye have sought for happiness in doing iniquity, which thing is contrary to the nature of that righteousness which is in our great and Eternal
But
behold,
your
days
of
probation
are
past;
ye
have
procrastinated
the
day
of
your
salvation
until
it
is
everlastingly
too
late,
and
your
destruction
is
made
sure;
yea,
for
ye
have
sought
all
the
days
of
your
lives
for
that
which
ye
could
not
obtain;
and
ye
have
sought
for
happiness
in
doing
iniquity,
which
thing
is
contrary
to
the
nature
of
that
righteousness
which
is
in
our
great
and
Eternal
Head.
39 O ye people of the land, that ye would hear my words! And I pray that the anger of the Lord be turned away from you, and that ye would repent and be saved.
O
ye
people
of
the
land,
that
ye
would
hear
my
words!
And
I
pray
that
the
anger
of
the
Lord
be
turned
away
from
you,
and
that
ye
would
repent
and
be
saved.