Chapter 10 The Lord gives Nephi the sealing
power—He is empowered to bind and loose on earth and in
heaven—He commands the people to repent or
perish—The Spirit carries him from multitude to
multitude. About 21–20 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that there arose a division
among the people, insomuch that they divided
hither and thither and went their ways, leaving Nephi
alone, as he was standing in the midst of them
2 And it came to pass that Nephi went his way
towards his own house, pondering upon the things which
the Lord had shown unto him
3 And it came to pass as he was thus
pondering—being much cast down because of the wickedness of the
people of the Nephites, their secret works of
darkness, and their murderings, and their
plunderings, and all manner of iniquities—and it came to pass
as he was thus pondering in his heart, behold, a
voice came unto him saying
4 Blessed art thou, Nephi, for those things which
thou hast done; for I have beheld how thou hast
with unwearyingness declared the word, which I have
given unto thee, unto this people. And thou hast
not feared them, and hast not sought thine own
life, but hast sought my will, and to keep my
commandments
5 And now, because thou hast done this with such
unwearyingness, behold, I will bless thee forever;
and I will make thee mighty in word and in deed,
in faith and in works; yea, even that all things
shall be done unto thee according to thy word, for
thou shalt not ask that which is contrary to my
will
6 Behold, thou art Nephi, and I am God. Behold, I
declare it unto thee in the presence of mine
angels, that ye shall have power over this people, and
shall smite the earth with famine, and with
pestilence, and destruction, according to the wickedness
of this people
7 Behold, I give unto you power, that whatsoever
ye shall seal on earth shall be sealed in heaven;
and whatsoever ye shall loose on earth shall be
loosed in heaven; and thus shall ye have power among
this people
8 And thus, if ye shall say unto this temple it
shall be rent in twain, it shall be done
9 And if ye shall say unto this mountain, Be thou
cast down and become smooth, it shall be done
10 And behold, if ye shall say that God shall
smite this people, it shall come to pass
11 And now behold, I command you, that ye shall go
and declare unto this people, that thus saith the
Lord God, who is the Almighty: Except ye repent
ye shall be smitten, even unto destruction
12 And behold, now it came to pass that when the
Lord had spoken these words unto Nephi, he did stop
and did not go unto his own house, but did return
unto the multitudes who were scattered about upon
the face of the land, and began to declare unto
them the word of the Lord which had been spoken
unto him, concerning their destruction if they did
not repent
13 Now behold, notwithstanding that great miracle
which Nephi had done in telling them concerning
the death of the chief judge, they did harden their
hearts and did not hearken unto the words of the
Lord
14 Therefore Nephi did declare unto them the word
of the Lord, saying: Except ye repent, thus saith
the Lord, ye shall be smitten even unto
destruction
15 And it came to pass that when Nephi had
declared unto them the word, behold, they did still
harden their hearts and would not hearken unto his
words; therefore they did revile against him, and did
seek to lay their hands upon him that they might
cast him into prison
16 But behold, the power of God was with him, and
they could not take him to cast him into prison,
for he was taken by the Spirit and conveyed away
out of the midst of them
17 And it came to pass that thus he did go forth
in the Spirit, from multitude to multitude,
declaring the word of God, even until he had declared it
unto them all, or sent it forth among all the
people