Chapter 14 Samuel predicts light during the
night and a new star at Christ’s
birth—Christ redeems men from temporal and spiritual
death—The signs of His death include three
days of darkness, the rending of the
rocks, and great upheavals of nature. About 6 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that Samuel,
the Lamanite, did prophesy a great
many more things which cannot be written.
2 And behold, he said unto them:
Behold, I give unto you a sign; for
five years more cometh, and behold,
then cometh the Son of God to redeem
all those who shall believe on his name.
3 And behold, this will I give
unto you for a sign at the time
of his coming; for behold, there
shall be great lights in heaven,
insomuch that in the night
before he cometh there shall be no
darkness, insomuch that it shall
appear unto man as if it was day.
4 Therefore, there shall be one
day and a night and a day, as
if it were one day and there
were no night; and this shall be
unto you for a sign; for ye
shall know of the rising of the
sun and also of its setting;
therefore they shall know of a
surety that there shall be two days
and a night; nevertheless the
night shall not be darkened;
and it shall be the night before he is born.
5 And behold, there shall a
new star arise, such an one as
ye never have beheld; and this
also shall be a sign unto you.
6 And behold this is not
all, there shall be many
signs and wonders in heaven.
7 And it shall come to
pass that ye shall
all be amazed, and
wonder, insomuch that ye
shall fall to the earth.
8 And it shall
come to pass that
whosoever shall
believe on the Son of
God, the same shall
have everlasting life.
9 And behold,
thus hath the Lord
commanded me, by
his angel, that I
should come and
tell this thing
unto you; yea, he
hath commanded
that I should
prophesy these things
unto you; yea, he
hath said unto
me: Cry unto this
people, repent and
prepare the way of the Lord.
10 And now,
because I am a
Lamanite, and have
spoken unto you
the words which
the Lord hath
commanded me, and
because it was
hard against you,
ye are angry with
me and do seek
to destroy me,
and have cast me
out from among you.
11 And ye shall
hear my words,
for, for this
intent have I
come up upon the
walls of this
city, that ye
might hear and
know of the
judgments of God
which do await
you because of
your iniquities,
and also that
ye might know
the conditions of repentance;
12 And also
that ye might
know of the
coming of Jesus
Christ, the Son
of God, the
Father of heaven
and of earth,
the Creator
of all things
from the
beginning; and that
ye might know
of the signs
of his coming,
to the intent
that ye might
believe on his name.
13 And if ye
believe on
his name ye
will repent of
all your sins,
that thereby
ye may have
a remission
of them
through his merits.
14 And
behold, again,
another sign I
give unto
you, yea, a
sign of his death.
15 For
behold, he surely
must die
that salvation
may come;
yea, it
behooveth him and
becometh
expedient that
he dieth,
to bring to
pass the
resurrection of
the dead,
that thereby
men may be
brought into
the presence
of the Lord.
16 Yea,
behold, this
death bringeth
to pass the
resurrection, and
redeemeth all
mankind from the
first
death—that
spiritual death;
for all
mankind, by the
fall of Adam
being cut
off from the
presence of
the Lord, are
considered
as dead,
both as to
things temporal
and to
things spiritual.
17 But
behold, the
resurrection
of Christ
redeemeth
mankind, yea,
even all
mankind, and
bringeth
them back
into the
presence of the Lord.
18 Yea,
and it
bringeth to
pass the
condition of
repentance,
that
whosoever
repenteth the
same is
not hewn
down and cast
into the
fire; but
whosoever
repenteth
not is
hewn down and
cast into
the fire;
and there
cometh
upon them
again a
spiritual
death, yea, a
second
death, for
they are cut
off again
as to
things pertaining to righteousness.
Therefore
repent ye,
lest by
knowing
these things
and not
doing
them ye
shall suffer
yourselves to come
under
condemnation, and ye
are
brought down
unto this second death.
20 But
behold,
as I said
unto
you
concerning
another
sign, a
sign of his
death,
behold,
in that
day that
he
shall suffer
death
the sun
shall be
darkened
and
refuse to
give his
light
unto you;
and also
the
moon and
the stars;
and
there shall
be no
light
upon the
face of
this land,
even
from the
time that
he
shall suffer
death,
for the
space of
three
days, to
the time that he shall rise again from the dead.
21 Yea,
at the
time
that he
shall
yield up
the
ghost
there
shall be
thunderings and
lightnings for
the
space of
many
hours,
and the
earth
shall
shake and
tremble; and
the
rocks which
are
upon the
face of
this
earth,
which
are both
above
the
earth and
beneath,
which
ye know
at
this time
are
solid, or
the
more part of it is one solid mass, shall be broken up;
Yea, they
shall
be
rent in
twain,
and
shall
ever
after be
found
in
seams
and in
cracks,
and
in
broken
fragments
upon
the
face of
whole
earth,
yea,
both above the earth and beneath.
23 And
behold,
there
shall be
great
tempests,
and
there
shall be
many
mountains laid
low,
like
unto a
valley, and
there
shall
be
many
places
which are
now
called
valleys
which
shall
become
mountains,
whose
height is
great.
And
many
highways
shall be
broken up,
and
many
cities
shall
become desolate.
And
many
graves
shall
be
opened,
and
shall
yield
up
many
of
their
dead;
and
many
saints shall appear unto many.
And
behold,
thus
hath
the
angel
spoken
unto
me;
for
he
said
unto
me
that
there
should
be
thunderings
and
lightnings for the space of many hours.
And
he
said
unto
me
that
while
the
thunder
and
the
lightning
lasted,
and
the
tempest,
that
these
things
should
be,
and
that
darkness
should cover the face of the whole earth for the space of three days.
28 And the angel said unto me that many shall see greater things than these, to the intent that they might believe that these signs and these wonders should come to pass upon all the face of this land, to the intent that there should be no cause for unbelief among the children of
And
the
angel
said
unto
me
that
many
shall
see
greater
things
than
these,
to
the
intent
that
they
might
believe
that
these
signs
and
these
wonders should come to pass upon all the face of this land, to the intent that there should be no cause for unbelief among the children of men—
29 And this to the intent that whosoever will believe might be saved, and that whosoever will not believe, a righteous judgment might come upon them; and also if they are condemned they bring upon themselves their own
And
this
to
the
intent
that
whosoever
will
believe
might
be
saved,
and
that
whosoever
will
not
believe,
a
righteous
judgment
might
come
upon
them;
and
also
if
they
are
condemned
they
bring
upon
themselves
their
own
condemnation.
30 And now remember, remember, my brethren, that whosoever perisheth, perisheth unto himself; and whosoever doeth iniquity, doeth it unto himself; for behold, ye are free; ye are permitted to act for yourselves; for behold, God hath given unto you a knowledge and he hath made you
And
now
remember,
my
brethren,
that
whosoever
perisheth,
perisheth
unto
himself;
and
whosoever
doeth
iniquity,
it
unto
himself;
for
behold,
ye
are
free;
ye
are
permitted
to
act
for
yourselves;
behold,
God
hath
given
unto
you
a
knowledge
and
he
hath
made
you
free.
31 He hath given unto you that ye might know good from evil, and he hath given unto you that ye might choose life or death; and ye can do good and be restored unto that which is good, or have that which is good restored unto you; or ye can do evil, and have that which is evil restored unto you.
He
hath
given
unto
you
that
ye
might
know
good
from
evil,
and
he
hath
given
unto
you
that
ye
might
choose
life
or
death;
and
ye
can
do
good
and
be
restored
unto
that
which
is
good,
or
have
that
which
is
good
restored
unto
you;
or
ye
can
do
evil,
and
have
that
which
is
evil
restored
unto
you.