Chapter 12 Men are unstable and foolish and
quick to do evil—The Lord chastens His people—The
nothingness of men is compared with the power of
God—In the day of judgment, men will gain
everlasting life or everlasting damnation. About 6 B.C.
1 And thus we can behold how false, and
also the unsteadiness of the hearts of the
children of men; yea, we can see that the Lord
in his great infinite goodness doth bless
and prosper those who put their trust in him.
2 Yea, and we may see at the very time
when he doth prosper his people, yea, in the
increase of their fields, their flocks and
their herds, and in gold, and in silver,
and in all manner of precious things of
every kind and art; sparing their lives, and
delivering them out of the hands of their
enemies; softening the hearts of their
enemies that they should not declare wars
against them; yea, and in fine, doing all
things for the welfare and happiness of his
people; yea, then is the time that they do
harden their hearts, and do forget the
Lord their God, and do trample under their
feet the Holy One—yea, and this because of
their ease, and their exceedingly great prosperity.
3 And thus we see that except the
Lord doth chasten his people with many
afflictions, yea, except he doth visit
them with death and with terror, and
with famine and with all manner of
pestilence, they will not remember him.
4 O how foolish, and how vain, and
how evil, and devilish, and how quick
to do iniquity, and how slow to do
good, are the children of men; yea,
how quick to hearken unto the words
of the evil one, and to set their
hearts upon the vain things of the world!
5 Yea, how quick to be lifted up
in pride; yea, how quick to boast,
and do all manner of that which is
iniquity; and how slow are they
to remember the Lord their God, and
to give ear unto his counsels,
yea, how slow to walk in wisdom’s paths!
6 Behold, they do not desire
that the Lord their God, who hath
created them, should rule and
reign over them; notwithstanding
his great goodness and his mercy
towards them, they do set at
naught his counsels, and they will
not that he should be their guide.
7 O how great is the
nothingness of the children of
men; yea, even they are less
than the dust of the earth.
8 For behold, the dust
of the earth moveth
hither and thither, to
the dividing asunder,
at the command of our
great and everlasting God.
9 Yea, behold at
his voice do the
hills and the mountains
tremble and quake.
10 And by the
power of his voice
they are broken
up, and become
smooth, yea,
even like unto a valley.
11 Yea, by the
power of his
voice doth the
whole earth shake;
12 Yea, by the
power of his
voice, do the
foundations
rock, even to
the very center.
13 Yea, and
if he say unto
the
earth—Move—it is moved.
14 Yea, if
he say unto
the
earth—Thou shalt go
back, that it
lengthen
out the day
for many
hours—it is done;
15 And
thus, according
to his
word the earth
goeth
back, and it
appeareth
unto man that
the sun
standeth
still; yea, and
behold,
this is so;
for surely it
is the
earth that
moveth and not the sun.
16 And
behold, also,
if he say
unto the
waters of
the great
deep—Be
thou dried
up—it is done.
Behold, if he
say unto
this
mountain—Be
thou raised
up, and
come over
and fall
upon
that city,
that it be
buried
up—behold it is done.
18 And
behold,
if a man
hide up
a
treasure in
the earth,
and the
Lord
shall
say—Let it
be
accursed,
because of
the
iniquity of
him who
hath hid
it
up—behold, it shall be accursed.
19 And
if the
Lord
shall
say—Be
thou
accursed,
that no
man
shall find
thee
from this
time
henceforth and
forever—behold, no
man
getteth it
henceforth and forever.
20 And
behold, if
the
Lord
shall say
unto
a
man—Because of
thine
iniquities,
thou
shalt be
accursed
forever—it shall be done.
And if
the
Lord
shall
say—Because of
thine
iniquities
thou
shalt be
cut
off
from
my
presence—he
will
cause that it shall be so.
And wo
unto
him
to
whom he
shall
say
this,
for
it
shall
be
unto him
that
will
do
iniquity,
and he
cannot be
saved;
therefore,
for
this
cause,
that
men
might
be
saved,
hath
repentance
been
declared.
Therefore,
blessed
are
they
who
will
repent
and
hearken
unto
the
voice of
Lord
their
God;
for
these
are they that shall be saved.
And
may
God
grant,
in
his
great
fulness,
that
men
might
be
brought
unto
repentance
and
good
works,
that
they
might
be
restored
unto grace for grace, according to their works.
And
I
would
that
all
men
might
be
saved.
But
we
read
that
in
the
great
and
last
day
there
are
some
who
shall
be
cast
out, yea, who shall be cast off from the presence of the Lord;
Yea,
who
shall
be
consigned
to
a
state
of
endless
misery,
fulfilling
the
words
which
say:
They
that
have
done
good
shall
have
everlasting
life;
and
they
that
have
done
evil
shall
have
everlasting
damnation.
And
thus
it
is.
Amen.