Chapter 11 Nephi persuades the Lord to
replace their war with a famine—Many people
perish—They repent, and Nephi importunes
the Lord for rain—Nephi and Lehi receive
many revelations—The Gadianton robbers
entrench themselves in the land. About 20–6 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass in the seventy
and second year of the reign of the
judges that the contentions did increase,
insomuch that there were wars throughout
all the land among all the people of Nephi.
2 And it was this secret band of
robbers who did carry on this work of
destruction and wickedness. And this war
did last all that year; and in the
seventy and third year it did also last.
3 And it came to pass
that in this year Nephi did
cry unto the Lord, saying:
4 O Lord, do not suffer
that this people shall
be destroyed by the
sword; but O Lord, rather
let there be a famine
in the land, to stir
them up in remembrance of
the Lord their God,
and perhaps they will
repent and turn unto thee.
5 And so it was done,
according to the words
of Nephi. And there
was a great famine upon
the land, among all
the people of Nephi.
And thus in the seventy
and fourth year the
famine did continue, and
the work of
destruction did cease by the
sword but became sore by famine.
6 And this work of
destruction did also
continue in the seventy
and fifth year. For
the earth was smitten
that it was dry, and
did not yield forth
grain in the season
of grain; and the
whole earth was smitten,
even among the
Lamanites as well as among
the Nephites, so that
they were smitten
that they did perish by
thousands in the
more wicked parts of the land.
7 And it came to
pass that the people
saw that they were
about to perish by
famine, and they
began to remember the
Lord their God;
and they began to
remember the words of Nephi.
8 And the people
began to plead with
their chief
judges and their
leaders, that they would
say unto Nephi:
Behold, we know
that thou art a man
of God, and
therefore cry unto the
Lord our God that he
turn away from us
this famine, lest
all the words
which thou hast
spoken concerning our
destruction be fulfilled.
9 And it came to
pass that the
judges did say unto
Nephi, according
to the words
which had been
desired. And it came to
pass that when
Nephi saw that the
people had
repented and did
humble themselves in
sackcloth, he
cried again unto the Lord, saying:
10 O Lord,
behold this people
repenteth; and
they have swept
away the band of
Gadianton from
amongst them
insomuch that they
have become
extinct, and they have
concealed their
secret plans in the earth.
11 Now, O Lord,
because of
this their
humility wilt thou
turn away thine
anger, and let
thine anger be
appeased in the
destruction of
those wicked men
whom thou hast
already destroyed.
12 O Lord,
wilt thou turn
away thine
anger, yea, thy
fierce anger, and
cause that
this famine may
cease in this land.
13 O Lord,
wilt thou
hearken unto me,
and cause that
it may be
done according
to my words,
and send
forth rain upon
the face of
the earth, that
she may
bring forth her
fruit, and her
grain in the
season of grain.
14 O Lord,
thou didst
hearken unto
my words when
I said, Let
there be a
famine, that
the
pestilence of the
sword might
cease; and I
know that
thou wilt,
even at this
time, hearken
unto my
words, for thou
saidst that:
If this
people repent I will spare them.
15 Yea, O
Lord, and
thou seest
that they
have repented,
because of
the famine
and the
pestilence
and
destruction which
has come unto them.
16 And
now, O Lord,
wilt thou
turn away
thine
anger, and try
again if
they will
serve
thee? And if
so, O Lord,
thou
canst bless
them
according to thy
words
which thou hast said.
17 And it
came to
pass that
in the
seventy
and sixth
year the
Lord did
turn away
his anger
from the
people,
and
caused that
rain should
fall
upon the
earth,
insomuch that
it did
bring forth
her
fruit in the
season of
her
fruit. And it
came to
pass that
it did
bring
forth her grain in the season of her grain.
18 And
behold,
the
people did
rejoice
and
glorify God,
and the
whole
face of the
land
was filled
with
rejoicing;
and
they did no
more
seek to
destroy
Nephi, but
they
did esteem
him as
a great
prophet,
and a
man of
God,
having great
power
and authority given unto him from God.
19 And
behold,
Lehi,
his
brother,
was not
a whit
behind
him as
to
things
pertaining
to righteousness.
20 And
thus it
did
come to
pass
that the
people
of Nephi
began
to
prosper
again in
the
land, and
began to
build
up
their waste
places, and
began to
multiply and
spread,
even
until
they did
cover
the
whole face
of the
land,
both on
the
northward
and on
the
southward,
from
the sea
west to
the
sea east.
21 And
it
came to
pass
that
the
seventy
and
sixth year
did
end in
peace.
And
the
seventy
and
seventh
year
began in
peace; and
the
church
did
spread
throughout the
face
of all
the
land;
and the
more
part
of the
people, both
the
Nephites and
Lamanites, did
belong to
the
church;
and
they did
have
exceedingly
great
peace
in the land; and thus ended the seventy and seventh year.
And
also
they had
peace in
the
seventy and
eighth
year,
save
it
were a
few
contentions
concerning
the
points of
doctrine
which
had
been laid down by the prophets.
And
in
the
seventy
and
ninth
year
there
began
to
be
much
strife.
But
it
came
to
pass
that
Nephi
and
Lehi,
many of
their
brethren
who
knew
concerning
the
true
points
of
doctrine,
having
many
revelations
daily,
therefore
they
did
preach
unto
the
people,
insomuch that they did put an end to their strife in that same year.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
in
the
eightieth
year of
the
reign
of
the
judges
over
the
people
of
Nephi,
there
were a
certain
number
of
the
dissenters
from
the
people
of
Nephi,
who
had
some
years
before
gone
over
unto
the
Lamanites,
and
taken
upon
themselves
the
name of
Lamanites,
and
also
a
certain
number
who
were
real
descendants
of
the
Lamanites,
being
stirred
up
to
anger
by
them,
or
by
those
dissenters,
therefore
they
commenced a
war
with
their
brethren.
And
they
did
commit
murder
and
plunder;
then
they
would
retreat
back
into
the
mountains,
and
into
the
wilderness
and
secret
places,
hiding
themselves
that
they
could
not
be
discovered,
receiving
daily
an
addition
to
their numbers, inasmuch as there were dissenters that went forth unto them.
And
thus
in
time,
yea,
even
in
the
space
of
not
many
years,
they
became
an
exceedingly
great
band
of
robbers;
and
they
did
search
out
all
the secret plans of Gadianton; and thus they became robbers of Gadianton.
27 Now behold, these robbers did make great havoc, yea, even great destruction among the people of Nephi, and also among the people of the
Now
behold,
these
robbers
did
make
great
havoc,
yea,
even
great
destruction among the people of Nephi, and also among the people of the Lamanites.
28 And it came to pass that it was expedient that there should be a stop put to this work of destruction; therefore they sent an army of strong men into the wilderness and upon the mountains to search out this band of robbers, and to destroy
And
it
came
to
pass
that
it
was
expedient
that
there
should
be
a
stop
put
to
this
work
of
destruction;
therefore
they
sent
an
army
of
strong
men
into
the
wilderness
and
upon
the
mountains
to
search
out
this
band
of
robbers,
and
to
destroy
them.
29 But behold, it came to pass that in that same year they were driven back even into their own lands. And thus ended the eightieth year of the reign of the judges over the people of
But
behold,
it
came
to
pass
that
in
same
year
they
were
driven
back
even
into
their
own
lands.
And
thus
ended
the
eightieth
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges
over
the
people
of
Nephi.
30 And it came to pass in the commencement of the eighty and first year they did go forth again against this band of robbers, and did destroy many; and they were also visited with much
And
it
came
to
pass
in
the
commencement
of
the
eighty
and
first
year
they
did
go
forth
again
against
this
band
of
robbers,
and
did
destroy
many;
and
they
were
also
visited
with
much
destruction.
31 And they were again obliged to return out of the wilderness and out of the mountains unto their own lands, because of the exceeding greatness of the numbers of those robbers who infested the mountains and the
And
they
were
again
obliged
to
return
out
of
the
wilderness
and
out
of
the
mountains
unto
their
own
lands,
because
of
the
exceeding
greatness
of
the
numbers
of
those
robbers
who
infested
the
mountains
and
the
wilderness.
32 And it came to pass that thus ended this year. And the robbers did still increase and wax strong, insomuch that they did defy the whole armies of the Nephites, and also of the Lamanites; and they did cause great fear to come unto the people upon all the face of the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
thus
ended
this
year.
And
the
robbers
did
still
increase
and
wax
strong,
insomuch
that
they
did
defy
the
whole
armies
of
the
Nephites,
and
also
of
the
Lamanites;
and
they
did
cause
great
fear
to
come
unto
the
people
upon
all
the
face
of
the
land.
33 Yea, for they did visit many parts of the land, and did do great destruction unto them; yea, did kill many, and did carry away others captive into the wilderness, yea, and more especially their women and their
Yea,
for
they
did
visit
many
parts
of
the
land,
and
did
do
great
destruction
unto
them;
yea,
did
kill
many,
and
did
carry
away
others
captive
into
the
wilderness,
yea,
and
more
especially
their
women
and
their
children.
34 Now this great evil, which came unto the people because of their iniquity, did stir them up again in remembrance of the Lord their
Now
this
great
evil,
which
came
unto
the
people
because
of
their
iniquity,
did
stir
them
up
again
in
remembrance
of
the
Lord
their
God.
35 And thus ended the eighty and first year of the reign of the
And
thus
ended
the
eighty
and
first
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges.
36 And in the eighty and second year they began again to forget the Lord their God. And in the eighty and third year they began to wax strong in iniquity. And in the eighty and fourth year they did not mend their
And
in
the
eighty
and
second
year
they
began
again
to
forget
the
Lord
their
God.
And
in
the
eighty
and
third
year
they
began
to
wax
strong
in
iniquity.
And
in
the
eighty
and
fourth
year
they
did
not
mend
their
ways.
37 And it came to pass in the eighty and fifth year they did wax stronger and stronger in their pride, and in their wickedness; and thus they were ripening again for
And
it
came
to
pass
in
the
eighty
and
fifth
year
they
did
wax
stronger
and
in
their
pride,
and
in
their
wickedness;
and
thus
they
were
ripening
again
for
destruction.
38 And thus ended the eighty and fifth year.
And
thus
ended
the
eighty
and
fifth
year.