Chapter 16 The Nephites who believe Samuel are
baptized by Nephi—Samuel cannot be slain with the
arrows and stones of the unrepentant Nephites—Some
harden their hearts, and others see angels—The
unbelievers say it is not reasonable to believe in
Christ and His coming in Jerusalem. About 6–1 B.C.
1 And now, it came to pass that there were many
who heard the words of Samuel, the Lamanite, which
he spake upon the walls of the city. And as many as
believed on his word went forth and sought for
Nephi; and when they had come forth and found him
they confessed unto him their sins and denied not,
desiring that they might be baptized unto the Lord
2 But as many as there were who did not believe in
the words of Samuel were angry with him; and they
cast stones at him upon the wall, and also many
shot arrows at him as he stood upon the wall; but
the Spirit of the Lord was with him, insomuch that
they could not hit him with their stones neither
with their arrows
3 Now when they saw that they could not hit him,
there were many more who did believe on his words,
insomuch that they went away unto Nephi to be
baptized
4 For behold, Nephi was baptizing, and
prophesying, and preaching, crying repentance unto the
people, showing signs and wonders, working miracles
among the people, that they might know that the Christ
must shortly come
5 Telling them of things which must shortly come,
that they might know and remember at the time of
their coming that they had been made known unto
them beforehand, to the intent that they might
believe; therefore as many as believed on the words of
Samuel went forth unto him to be baptized, for they
came repenting and confessing their sins
6 But the more part of them did not believe in the
words of Samuel; therefore when they saw that
they could not hit him with their stones and their
arrows, they cried unto their captains, saying: Take
this fellow and bind him, for behold he hath a
devil; and because of the power of the devil which
is in him we cannot hit him with our stones and our
arrows; therefore take him and bind him, and away
with him
7 And as they went forth to lay their hands on
him, behold, he did cast himself down from the wall,
and did flee out of their lands, yea, even unto
his own country, and began to preach and to prophesy
among his own people
8 And behold, he was never heard of more among the
Nephites; and thus were the affairs of the
people
9 And thus ended the eighty and sixth year of the
reign of the judges over the people of Nephi
10 And thus ended also the eighty and seventh year
of the reign of the judges, the more part of the
people remaining in their pride and wickedness,
and the lesser part walking more circumspectly
before God
11 And these were the conditions also, in the
eighty and eighth year of the reign of the judges
12 And there was but little alteration in the
affairs of the people, save it were the people began
to be more hardened in iniquity, and do more and
more of that which was contrary to the commandments
of God, in the eighty and ninth year of the reign
of the judges
13 But it came to pass in the ninetieth year of
the reign of the judges, there were great signs
given unto the people, and wonders; and the words of
the prophets began to be fulfilled
14 And angels did appear unto men, wise men, and
did declare unto them glad tidings of great joy;
thus in this year the scriptures began to be
fulfilled
15 Nevertheless, the people began to harden their
hearts, all save it were the most believing part
of them, both of the Nephites and also of the
Lamanites, and began to depend upon their own strength
and upon their own wisdom, saying
16 Some things they may have guessed right, among
so many; but behold, we know that all these great
and marvelous works cannot come to pass, of which
has been spoken
17 And they began to reason and to contend among
themselves, saying
18 That it is not reasonable that such a being as
a Christ shall come; if so, and he be the Son of
God, the Father of heaven and of earth, as it has
been spoken, why will he not show himself unto us
as well as unto them who shall be at Jerusalem
19 Yea, why will he not show himself in this land
as well as in the land of Jerusalem
20 But behold, we know that this is a wicked
tradition, which has been handed down unto us by our
fathers, to cause us that we should believe in some
great and marvelous thing which should come to
pass, but not among us, but in a land which is far
distant, a land which we know not; therefore they
can keep us in ignorance, for we cannot witness with
our own eyes that they are true
21 And they will, by the cunning and the
mysterious arts of the evil one, work some great mystery
which we cannot understand, which will keep us down
to be servants to their words, and also servants
unto them, for we depend upon them to teach us the
word; and thus will they keep us in ignorance if
we will yield ourselves unto them, all the days of
our lives
22 And many more things did the people imagine up
in their hearts, which were foolish and vain; and
they were much disturbed, for Satan did stir them
up to do iniquity continually; yea, he did go
about spreading rumors and contentions upon all the
face of the land, that he might harden the hearts of
the people against that which was good and
against that which should come
23 And notwithstanding the signs and the wonders
which were wrought among the people of the Lord,
and the many miracles which they did, Satan did get
great hold upon the hearts of the people upon all
the face of the land
24 And thus ended the ninetieth year of the reign
of the judges over the people of Nephi
25 And thus ended the book of Helaman, according
to the record of Helaman and his sons.