Chapter 2 Helaman, the son of Helaman, becomes
chief judge—Gadianton leads the band of
Kishkumen—Helaman’s servant slays Kishkumen, and the Gadianton
band flees into the wilderness. About 50–49 B.C.
1 And it came to pass in the forty and second year
of the reign of the judges, after Moronihah had
established again peace between the Nephites and
the Lamanites, behold there was no one to fill the
judgment-seat; therefore there began to be a
contention again among the people concerning who should
fill the judgment-seat
2 And it came to pass that Helaman, who was the
son of Helaman, was appointed to fill the
judgment-seat, by the voice of the people
3 But behold, Kishkumen, who had murdered Pahoran,
did lay wait to destroy Helaman also; and he was
upheld by his band, who had entered into a
covenant that no one should know his wickedness
4 For there was one Gadianton, who was exceedingly
expert in many words, and also in his craft, to
carry on the secret work of murder and of robbery;
therefore he became the leader of the band of
Kishkumen
5 Therefore he did flatter them, and also
Kishkumen, that if they would place him in the
judgment-seat he would grant unto those who belonged to his
band that they should be placed in power and
authority among the people; therefore Kishkumen sought
to destroy Helaman
6 And it came to pass as he went forth towards the
judgment-seat to destroy Helaman, behold one of
the servants of Helaman, having been out by night,
and having obtained, through disguise, a knowledge
of those plans which had been laid by this band
to destroy Helaman
7 And it came to pass that he met Kishkumen, and
he gave unto him a sign; therefore Kishkumen made
known unto him the object of his desire, desiring
that he would conduct him to the judgment-seat that
he might murder Helaman
8 And when the servant of Helaman had known all
the heart of Kishkumen, and how that it was his
object to murder, and also that it was the object of
all those who belonged to his band to murder, and
to rob, and to gain power, (and this was their
secret plan, and their combination) the servant of
Helaman said unto Kishkumen: Let us go forth unto the
judgment-seat
9 Now this did please Kishkumen exceedingly, for
he did suppose that he should accomplish his
design; but behold, the servant of Helaman, as they were
going forth unto the judgment-seat, did stab
Kishkumen even to the heart, that he fell dead without
a groan. And he ran and told Helaman all the
things which he had seen, and heard, and done
10 And it came to pass that Helaman did send forth
to take this band of robbers and secret
murderers, that they might be executed according to the
law
11 But behold, when Gadianton had found that
Kishkumen did not return he feared lest that he should
be destroyed; therefore he caused that his band
should follow him. And they took their flight out of
the land, by a secret way, into the wilderness;
and thus when Helaman sent forth to take them they
could nowhere be found
12 And more of this Gadianton shall be spoken
hereafter. And thus ended the forty and second year of
the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi