Chapter 3 Many Nephites migrate to the
land northward—They build houses of cement
and keep many records—Tens of thousands are
converted and baptized—The word of God
leads men to salvation—Nephi the son of
Helaman fills the judgment seat. About 49–39 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass in the forty
and third year of the reign of the
judges, there was no contention among the
people of Nephi save it were a little
pride which was in the church, which did
cause some little dissensions among the
people, which affairs were settled in
the ending of the forty and third year.
2 And there was no contention
among the people in the forty and
fourth year; neither was there much
contention in the forty and fifth year.
3 And it came to pass in the
forty and sixth, yea, there was
much contention and many
dissensions; in the which there were
an exceedingly great many who
departed out of the land of
Zarahemla, and went forth unto the
land northward to inherit the land.
4 And they did travel to an
exceedingly great distance,
insomuch that they came to large
bodies of water and many rivers.
5 Yea, and even they did
spread forth into all parts of
the land, into whatever parts
it had not been rendered
desolate and without timber,
because of the many inhabitants
who had before inherited the land.
6 And now no part of the
land was desolate, save it
were for timber; but
because of the greatness of the
destruction of the people
who had before inhabited
the land it was called desolate.
7 And there being but
little timber upon the face
of the land, nevertheless
the people who went
forth became exceedingly
expert in the working of
cement; therefore they did
build houses of cement, in
the which they did dwell.
8 And it came to pass
that they did multiply and
spread, and did go
forth from the land
southward to the land northward,
and did spread insomuch
that they began to
cover the face of the whole
earth, from the sea
south to the sea north, from
the sea west to the sea east.
9 And the people who
were in the land
northward did dwell in tents,
and in houses of cement,
and they did suffer
whatsoever tree should
spring up upon the face
of the land that it
should grow up, that in
time they might have
timber to build their
houses, yea, their cities,
and their temples, and
their synagogues, and
their sanctuaries, and all
manner of their buildings.
10 And it came to
pass as timber was
exceedingly scarce in the
land northward, they
did send forth much
by the way of shipping.
11 And thus they did
enable the people
in the land northward
that they might
build many cities, both
of wood and of cement.
12 And it came to
pass that there
were many of the
people of Ammon, who
were Lamanites by
birth, did also go
forth into this land.
13 And now there
are many
records kept of the
proceedings of
this people, by
many of this
people, which are
particular and very
large, concerning them.
14 But behold,
a hundredth
part of the
proceedings of this
people, yea, the
account of the
Lamanites and
of the
Nephites, and their
wars, and
contentions, and
dissensions, and
their preaching,
and their
prophecies, and their
shipping and
their building of
ships, and
temples, and of
synagogues and
their
sanctuaries, and their
righteousness,
and their
wickedness, and
their murders, and
their robbings,
and their
plundering, and all
manner of
abominations and
whoredoms, cannot be contained in this work.
15 But behold,
there are
many books and
many records of
every kind,
and they have
been kept
chiefly by the Nephites.
16 And they
have been
handed down from
one
generation to another
by the
Nephites, even
until they have
fallen into
transgression
and have been
murdered,
plundered, and
hunted, and
driven forth,
and slain, and
scattered
upon the face
of the earth,
and mixed
with the
Lamanites until they
are no more
called the
Nephites,
becoming wicked,
and wild, and
ferocious, yea, even becoming Lamanites.
17 And now I
return again
to mine
account;
therefore, what I have
spoken had
passed after
there had been
great
contentions, and
disturbances,
and wars, and
dissensions,
among the
people of Nephi.
18 The forty
and sixth
year of the
reign of the
judges ended;
19 And it
came to pass
that there
was still
great
contention in
the land,
yea, even in
the forty
and seventh
year, and
also in the
forty and eighth year.
Nevertheless
Helaman did
fill the
judgment-seat
with
justice and
equity; yea,
he did
observe to
keep the
statutes,
and the
judgments, and
the
commandments of
God; and
he did do
that which
was right
in the
sight of God
continually; and he
did walk
after the
ways of
his father,
insomuch
that he did prosper in the land.
21 And it
came to
pass that
he had
two sons.
He gave
unto the
eldest the
name of
Nephi,
and unto
the
youngest, the
name of
Lehi. And
they began
to grow up unto the Lord.
22 And
it came
to pass
that the
wars and
contentions
began to
cease, in
a small
degree,
among
the people
of the
Nephites, in the
latter
end of
the forty
and
eighth year
of the
reign of
the
judges over the people of Nephi.
23 And
it came
to pass
in the
forty and
ninth
year of
the reign
of the
judges,
there was
continual peace
established in
the
land, all
save it
were the
secret
combinations which
Gadianton the
robber
had
established in
the
more
settled parts
of the
land,
which at
that time
were not
known
unto
those who
were at
the head
of
government;
therefore
they
were not
destroyed
out of
the land.
24 And
it came
to
pass that
in this
same
year
there was
exceedingly
great
prosperity
in the
church,
insomuch
that there
were
thousands who
did join
themselves
unto the
church
and
were baptized unto repentance.
25 And
so
great
was the
prosperity
of the
church, and
so
many the
blessings
which
were
poured
out upon
the
people,
that
even
the
high
priests
and the
teachers
were
themselves astonished beyond measure.
And it
came
to
pass
that
the
work of
Lord
did
prosper
unto
the
baptizing
and
uniting to
the
church
of
God,
many
souls,
yea, even tens of thousands.
Thus
we
may
see
that
the
Lord
is
merciful
unto
all
who
will,
in
the
sincerity
of
their
hearts, call upon his holy name.
Yea,
thus
we
see
that
the
gate of
heaven
is
open
unto
all,
even
to
those
who
will
believe
on
the
name
of
Jesus
Christ,
who is
the
Son
of
God.
Yea,
we
see
that
whosoever
will
may
lay
hold
upon
the
word of
God,
which
is
quick
and
powerful,
which
shall
divide
asunder
all
the
cunning
and
the
snares
and
the
wiles
of
the
devil,
and
lead
the
man of
Christ
in a
strait
and
narrow
course
across
that
everlasting
gulf
of
misery
which
is
prepared
to
engulf
the
wicked—
And
land
their
souls,
yea,
their
immortal
souls,
at
the
right
hand
of
God
in
the
kingdom
of
heaven,
to
sit
down
with
Abraham,
and
Isaac,
with
Jacob, and with all our holy fathers, to go no more out.
And
in
this
year
there
was
continual
rejoicing
in
the
land
of
Zarahemla,
and
in
all
the
regions
round
about,
even in all the land which was possessed by the Nephites.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
there
was
peace
and
exceedingly
great
joy
in
the
remainder
of
the
forty
and
ninth
year;
yea,
and
also
there
was
continual
peace
and
great
joy
in
the
fiftieth
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges.
33 And in the fifty and first year of the reign of the judges there was peace also, save it were the pride which began to enter into the church—not into the church of God, but into the hearts of the people who professed to belong to the church of
And
in
the
fifty
and
first
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges
there
was
peace
also,
save
it
were
the
pride
which
began
to
enter into the church—not into the church of God, but into the hearts of the people who professed to belong to the church of God—
34 And they were lifted up in pride, even to the persecution of many of their brethren. Now this was a great evil, which did cause the more humble part of the people to suffer great persecutions, and to wade through much
And
they
were
lifted
up
in
pride,
even
to
the
persecution
of
many
their
brethren.
Now
this
was
a
great
evil,
which
did
cause
the
more
humble
part
of
the
people
to
suffer
great
persecutions,
and
to
wade
through
much
affliction.
35 Nevertheless they did fast and pray oft, and did wax stronger and stronger in their humility, and firmer and firmer in the faith of Christ, unto the filling their souls with joy and consolation, yea, even to the purifying and the sanctification of their hearts, which sanctification cometh because of their yielding their hearts unto
Nevertheless
they
did
fast
and
pray
oft,
and
did
wax
stronger
and
in
their
humility,
and
firmer
in
the
faith
of
Christ,
unto
the
filling
their
souls
with
joy
and
consolation,
yea,
even
to
the
purifying
and
the
sanctification
of
their
hearts,
which
sanctification
cometh
because
of
their
yielding
hearts
unto
God.
36 And it came to pass that the fifty and second year ended in peace also, save it were the exceedingly great pride which had gotten into the hearts of the people; and it was because of their exceedingly great riches and their prosperity in the land; and it did grow upon them from day to
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
fifty
and
second
year
ended
in
peace
also,
save
it
were
the
exceedingly
great
pride
which
had
gotten
into
the
hearts
of
the
people;
and
it
was
because
of
their
exceedingly
great
riches
and
their
prosperity
in
the
land;
and
it
did
grow
upon
them
from
day
to
day.
37 And it came to pass in the fifty and third year of the reign of the judges, Helaman died, and his eldest son Nephi began to reign in his stead. And it came to pass that he did fill the judgment-seat with justice and equity; yea, he did keep the commandments of God, and did walk in the ways of his father.
And
it
came
to
pass
in
the
fifty
and
third
year
of
the
reign
of
the
judges,
Helaman
died,
and
his
eldest
son
Nephi
began
to
reign
in
his
stead.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
he
did
fill
the
judgment-seat
with
justice
and
equity;
yea,
he
did
keep
the
commandments
of
God,
and
did
walk
in
the
ways
of
his
father.