Chapter 4 Nephite dissenters and the Lamanites
join forces and take the land of
Zarahemla—The Nephites’ defeats come because of their
wickedness—The Church dwindles, and the people
become weak like the Lamanites. About 38–30 B.C.
1 And it came to pass in the fifty and fourth
year there were many dissensions in the
church, and there was also a contention among the
people, insomuch that there was much bloodshed.
2 And the rebellious part were slain
and driven out of the land, and they
did go unto the king of the Lamanites.
3 And it came to pass that they did
endeavor to stir up the Lamanites to
war against the Nephites; but
behold, the Lamanites were exceedingly
afraid, insomuch that they would not
hearken to the words of those dissenters.
4 But it came to pass in the fifty
and sixth year of the reign of the
judges, there were dissenters who
went up from the Nephites unto the
Lamanites; and they succeeded with
those others in stirring them up to
anger against the Nephites; and
they were all that year preparing for war.
5 And in the fifty and seventh year
they did come down against the
Nephites to battle, and they did
commence the work of death; yea,
insomuch that in the fifty and eighth year
of the reign of the judges they
succeeded in obtaining possession of
the land of Zarahemla; yea, and
also all the lands, even unto the land
which was near the land Bountiful.
6 And the Nephites and the
armies of Moronihah were driven
even into the land of Bountiful;
7 And there they did fortify
against the Lamanites, from
the west sea, even unto the
east; it being a day’s
journey for a Nephite, on the
line which they had fortified
and stationed their armies
to defend their north country.
8 And thus those
dissenters of the Nephites, with
the help of a numerous army
of the Lamanites, had
obtained all the possession of
the Nephites which was in
the land southward. And
all this was done in the
fifty and eighth and ninth
years of the reign of the judges.
9 And it came to pass in
the sixtieth year of the
reign of the judges,
Moronihah did succeed with
his armies in obtaining
many parts of the land; yea,
they regained many
cities which had fallen into
the hands of the Lamanites.
10 And it came to pass
in the sixty and first
year of the reign of the
judges they succeeded in
regaining even the half
of all their possessions.
11 Now this great loss
of the Nephites, and
the great slaughter
which was among them,
would not have happened
had it not been for
their wickedness and
their abomination which
was among them; yea,
and it was among those
also who professed to
belong to the church of God.
12 And it was because
of the pride of
their hearts, because of
their exceeding
riches, yea, it was
because of their oppression
to the poor,
withholding their food from
the hungry,
withholding their clothing
from the naked, and
smiting their humble
brethren upon the cheek,
making a mock of that
which was sacred,
denying the spirit of
prophecy and of
revelation, murdering,
plundering, lying,
stealing, committing
adultery, rising up in
great contentions, and
deserting away into the
land of Nephi, among the Lamanites—
13 And because of
this their great
wickedness, and their
boastings in their own
strength, they were
left in their own
strength; therefore
they did not prosper,
but were afflicted
and smitten, and
driven before the
Lamanites, until they had
lost possession of
almost all their lands.
14 But behold,
Moronihah did preach
many things unto the
people because of
their iniquity, and
also Nephi and
Lehi, who were the sons
of Helaman, did
preach many things
unto the people, yea,
and did prophesy
many things unto
them concerning their
iniquities, and
what should come unto
them if they did
not repent of their sins.
15 And it came to
pass that they
did repent, and
inasmuch as they
did repent they did
begin to prosper.
16 For when
Moronihah saw that
they did repent he
did venture to
lead them forth from
place to place,
and from city to
city, even until
they had regained
the one-half of
their property
and the one-half of
all their lands.
17 And thus
ended the sixty
and first year
of the reign
of the judges.
18 And it
came to pass in
the sixty and
second year
of the reign
of the
judges, that
Moronihah could
obtain no more
possessions
over the Lamanites.
19 Therefore
they did
abandon their
design to
obtain the
remainder of
their lands,
for so
numerous were the
Lamanites
that it became
impossible
for the
Nephites to
obtain more
power over them;
therefore
Moronihah did
employ all
his armies
in
maintaining those parts which he had taken.
20 And it
came to
pass, because
of the
greatness of the
number of
the
Lamanites the
Nephites were
in great
fear, lest
they should be
overpowered, and
trodden down,
and slain, and destroyed.
21 Yea,
they began
to remember
the
prophecies of
Alma, and
also the
words of
Mosiah; and
they saw
that they
had been a
stiffnecked
people,
and that
they had set
at naught
the commandments of God;
22 And
that they
had
altered and
trampled
under their
feet the
laws of
Mosiah, or
that
which the
Lord
commanded him
to give
unto the
people; and
they saw
that
their laws
had become
corrupted, and
that they
had become
a wicked
people,
insomuch
that they
were
wicked even like unto the Lamanites.
23 And
because
of their
iniquity
the
church had
begun to
dwindle; and
they began
to
disbelieve
in the
spirit of
prophecy
and in
the
spirit of
revelation; and
the
judgments of
God did stare them in the face.
24 And
they
saw that
had
become weak,
like
unto
their
brethren,
the
Lamanites,
and
that the
Spirit
of the
Lord did
no
more
preserve
them; yea,
it had
withdrawn
from them
because
the
Spirit of
Lord doth not dwell in unholy temples—
Therefore
the
Lord
did
cease to
preserve them
by
his
miraculous
and
matchless
power,
for they
had
fallen
into a
state
of
unbelief
and
awful
wickedness;
and
they saw
that
the
Lamanites
were
exceedingly
more
numerous than
they,
and
except
they
should
cleave
unto
the Lord their God they must unavoidably perish.
For
behold,
they
saw
that
the
strength of
Lamanites
was as
great as
their
strength,
even
man
for
man.
And
thus
had
they
fallen
into
this
great
transgression;
yea,
thus
had
they
become
weak,
because
of
their
transgression, in the space of not many years.