Chapter 5 Nephi and Lehi devote themselves to
preaching—Their names invite them to pattern their
lives after their forebears—Christ redeems those who
repent—Nephi and Lehi make many converts and are
imprisoned, and fire encircles them—A cloud of
darkness overshadows three hundred people—The earth
shakes, and a voice commands men to repent—Nephi and
Lehi converse with angels, and the multitude is
encircled by fire. About 30 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that in this same year,
behold, Nephi delivered up the judgment-seat to a man
whose name was Cezoram
2 For as their laws and their governments were
established by the voice of the people, and they who
chose evil were more numerous than they who chose
good, therefore they were ripening for
destruction, for the laws had become corrupted
3 Yea, and this was not all; they were a
stiffnecked people, insomuch that they could not be
governed by the law nor justice, save it were to their
destruction
4 And it came to pass that Nephi had become weary
because of their iniquity; and he yielded up the
judgment-seat, and took it upon him to preach the
word of God all the remainder of his days, and his
brother Lehi also, all the remainder of his days
5 For they remembered the words which their father
Helaman spake unto them. And these are the words
which he spake
6 Behold, my sons, I desire that ye should
remember to keep the commandments of God; and I would
that ye should declare unto the people these words.
Behold, I have given unto you the names of our
first parents who came out of the land of Jerusalem;
and this I have done that when you remember your
names ye may remember them; and when ye remember
them ye may remember their works; and when ye
remember their works ye may know how that it is said, and
also written, that they were good
7 Therefore, my sons, I would that ye should do
that which is good, that it may be said of you, and
also written, even as it has been said and written
of them
8 And now my sons, behold I have somewhat more to
desire of you, which desire is, that ye may not do
these things that ye may boast, but that ye may
do these things to lay up for yourselves a treasure
in heaven, yea, which is eternal, and which
fadeth not away; yea, that ye may have that precious
gift of eternal life, which we have reason to
suppose hath been given to our fathers
9 O remember, remember, my sons, the words which
king Benjamin spake unto his people; yea, remember
that there is no other way nor means whereby man
can be saved, only through the atoning blood of
Jesus Christ, who shall come; yea, remember that he
cometh to redeem the world
10 And remember also the words which Amulek spake
unto Zeezrom, in the city of Ammonihah; for he
said unto him that the Lord surely should come to
redeem his people, but that he should not come to
redeem them in their sins, but to redeem them from
their sins
11 And he hath power given unto him from the
Father to redeem them from their sins because of
repentance; therefore he hath sent his angels to declare
the tidings of the conditions of repentance,
which bringeth unto the power of the Redeemer, unto
the salvation of their souls
12 And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is
upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the
Son of God, that ye must build your foundation;
that when the devil shall send forth his mighty
winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when
all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon
you, it shall have no power over you to drag you
down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of
the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure
foundation, a foundation whereon if men build
they cannot fall
13 And it came to pass that these were the words
which Helaman taught to his sons; yea, he did teach
them many things which are not written, and also
many things which are written
14 And they did remember his words; and therefore
they went forth, keeping the commandments of God,
to teach the word of God among all the people of
Nephi, beginning at the city Bountiful
15 And from thenceforth to the city of Gid; and
from the city of Gid to the city of Mulek
16 And even from one city to another, until they
had gone forth among all the people of Nephi who
were in the land southward; and from thence into the
land of Zarahemla, among the Lamanites
17 And it came to pass that they did preach with
great power, insomuch that they did confound many
of those dissenters who had gone over from the
Nephites, insomuch that they came forth and did
confess their sins and were baptized unto repentance,
and immediately returned to the Nephites to endeavor
to repair unto them the wrongs which they had
done
18 And it came to pass that Nephi and Lehi did
preach unto the Lamanites with such great power and
authority, for they had power and authority given
unto them that they might speak, and they also had
what they should speak given unto them
19 Therefore they did speak unto the great
astonishment of the Lamanites, to the convincing them,
insomuch that there were eight thousand of the
Lamanites who were in the land of Zarahemla and round
about baptized unto repentance, and were convinced
of the wickedness of the traditions of their
fathers
20 And it came to pass that Nephi and Lehi did
proceed from thence to go to the land of Nephi
21 And it came to pass that they were taken by an
army of the Lamanites and cast into prison; yea,
even in that same prison in which Ammon and his
brethren were cast by the servants of Limhi
22 And after they had been cast into prison many
days without food, behold, they went forth into the
prison to take them that they might slay them
23 And it came to pass that Nephi and Lehi were
encircled about as if by fire, even insomuch that
they durst not lay their hands upon them for fear
lest they should be burned. Nevertheless, Nephi and
Lehi were not burned; and they were as standing in
the midst of fire and were not burned
24 And when they saw that they were encircled
about with a pillar of fire, and that it burned them
not, their hearts did take courage
25 For they saw that the Lamanites durst not lay
their hands upon them; neither durst they come near
unto them, but stood as if they were struck dumb
with amazement
26 And it came to pass that Nephi and Lehi did
stand forth and began to speak unto them, saying:
Fear not, for behold, it is God that has shown unto
you this marvelous thing, in the which is shown
unto you that ye cannot lay your hands on us to slay
us
27 And behold, when they had said these words, the
earth shook exceedingly, and the walls of the
prison did shake as if they were about to tumble to
the earth; but behold, they did not fall. And
behold, they that were in the prison were Lamanites and
Nephites who were dissenters
28 And it came to pass that they were overshadowed
with a cloud of darkness, and an awful solemn
fear came upon them
29 And it came to pass that there came a voice as
if it were above the cloud of darkness, saying:
Repent ye, repent ye, and seek no more to destroy my
servants whom I have sent unto you to declare
good tidings
30 And it came to pass when they heard this voice,
and beheld that it was not a voice of thunder,
neither was it a voice of a great tumultuous noise,
but behold, it was a still voice of perfect
mildness, as if it had been a whisper, and it did pierce
even to the very soul
31 And notwithstanding the mildness of the voice,
behold the earth shook exceedingly, and the walls
of the prison trembled again, as if it were about
to tumble to the earth; and behold the cloud of
darkness, which had overshadowed them, did not
disperse
32 And behold the voice came again, saying: Repent
ye, repent ye, for the kingdom of heaven is at
hand; and seek no more to destroy my servants. And
it came to pass that the earth shook again, and the
walls trembled
33 And also again the third time the voice came,
and did speak unto them marvelous words which
cannot be uttered by man; and the walls did tremble
again, and the earth shook as if it were about to
divide asunder
34 And it came to pass that the Lamanites could
not flee because of the cloud of darkness which did
overshadow them; yea, and also they were immovable
because of the fear which did come upon them
35 Now there was one among them who was a Nephite
by birth, who had once belonged to the church of
God but had dissented from them
36 And it came to pass that he turned him about,
and behold, he saw through the cloud of darkness
the faces of Nephi and Lehi; and behold, they did
shine exceedingly, even as the faces of angels. And
he beheld that they did lift their eyes to heaven;
and they were in the attitude as if talking or
lifting their voices to some being whom they beheld
37 And it came to pass that this man did cry unto
the multitude, that they might turn and look. And
behold, there was power given unto them that they
did turn and look; and they did behold the faces
of Nephi and Lehi
38 And they said unto the man: Behold, what do all
these things mean, and who is it with whom these
men do converse
39 Now the man’s name was Aminadab. And Aminadab
said unto them: They do converse with the angels of
God
40 And it came to pass that the Lamanites said
unto him: What shall we do, that this cloud of
darkness may be removed from overshadowing us
41 And Aminadab said unto them: You must repent,
and cry unto the voice, even until ye shall have
faith in Christ, who was taught unto you by Alma,
and Amulek, and Zeezrom; and when ye shall do this,
the cloud of darkness shall be removed from
overshadowing you
42 And it came to pass that they all did begin to
cry unto the voice of him who had shaken the
earth; yea, they did cry even until the cloud of
darkness was dispersed
43 And it came to pass that when they cast their
eyes about, and saw that the cloud of darkness was
dispersed from overshadowing them, behold, they
saw that they were encircled about, yea every soul,
by a pillar of fire
44 And Nephi and Lehi were in the midst of them;
yea, they were encircled about; yea, they were as
if in the midst of a flaming fire, yet it did harm
them not, neither did it take hold upon the walls
of the prison; and they were filled with that joy
which is unspeakable and full of glory
45 And behold, the Holy Spirit of God did come
down from heaven, and did enter into their hearts,
and they were filled as if with fire, and they could
speak forth marvelous words
46 And it came to pass that there came a voice
unto them, yea, a pleasant voice, as if it were a
whisper, saying
47 Peace, peace be unto you, because of your faith
in my Well Beloved, who was from the foundation
of the world
48 And now, when they heard this they cast up
their eyes as if to behold from whence the voice came;
and behold, they saw the heavens open; and angels
came down out of heaven and ministered unto them
49 And there were about three hundred souls who
saw and heard these things; and they were bidden to
go forth and marvel not, neither should they
doubt
50 And it came to pass that they did go forth, and
did minister unto the people, declaring
throughout all the regions round about all the things which
they had heard and seen, insomuch that the more
part of the Lamanites were convinced of them,
because of the greatness of the evidences which they
had received
51 And as many as were convinced did lay down
their weapons of war, and also their hatred and the
tradition of their fathers
52 And it came to pass that they did yield up unto
the Nephites the lands of their possession.