Chapter 6 The righteous Lamanites preach to the
wicked Nephites—Both peoples prosper during an era
of peace and plenty—Lucifer, the author of sin,
stirs up the hearts of the wicked and the Gadianton
robbers in murder and wickedness—The robbers take
over the Nephite government. About 29–23 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that when the sixty and
second year of the reign of the judges had ended, all
these things had happened and the Lamanites had
become, the more part of them, a righteous people,
insomuch that their righteousness did exceed that
of the Nephites, because of their firmness and
their steadiness in the faith
2 For behold, there were many of the Nephites who
had become hardened and impenitent and grossly
wicked, insomuch that they did reject the word of God
and all the preaching and prophesying which did
come among them
3 Nevertheless, the people of the church did have
great joy because of the conversion of the
Lamanites, yea, because of the church of God, which had
been established among them. And they did
fellowship one with another, and did rejoice one with
another, and did have great joy
4 And it came to pass that many of the Lamanites
did come down into the land of Zarahemla, and did
declare unto the people of the Nephites the manner
of their conversion, and did exhort them to faith
and repentance
5 Yea, and many did preach with exceedingly great
power and authority, unto the bringing down many
of them into the depths of humility, to be the
humble followers of God and the Lamb
6 And it came to pass that many of the Lamanites
did go into the land northward; and also Nephi and
Lehi went into the land northward, to preach unto
the people. And thus ended the sixty and third
year
7 And behold, there was peace in all the land,
insomuch that the Nephites did go into whatsoever
part of the land they would, whether among the
Nephites or the Lamanites
8 And it came to pass that the Lamanites did also
go whithersoever they would, whether it were among
the Lamanites or among the Nephites; and thus
they did have free intercourse one with another, to
buy and to sell, and to get gain, according to
their desire
9 And it came to pass that they became exceedingly
rich, both the Lamanites and the Nephites; and
they did have an exceeding plenty of gold, and of
silver, and of all manner of precious metals, both
in the land south and in the land north
10 Now the land south was called Lehi, and the
land north was called Mulek, which was after the son
of Zedekiah; for the Lord did bring Mulek into the
land north, and Lehi into the land south
11 And behold, there was all manner of gold in
both these lands, and of silver, and of precious ore
of every kind; and there were also curious
workmen, who did work all kinds of ore and did refine it;
and thus they did become rich
12 They did raise grain in abundance, both in the
north and in the south; and they did flourish
exceedingly, both in the north and in the south. And
they did multiply and wax exceedingly strong in the
land. And they did raise many flocks and herds,
yea, many fatlings
13 Behold their women did toil and spin, and did
make all manner of cloth, of fine-twined linen and
cloth of every kind, to clothe their nakedness.
And thus the sixty and fourth year did pass away in
peace
14 And in the sixty and fifth year they did also
have great joy and peace, yea, much preaching and
many prophecies concerning that which was to come.
And thus passed away the sixty and fifth year
15 And it came to pass that in the sixty and sixth
year of the reign of the judges, behold, Cezoram
was murdered by an unknown hand as he sat upon the
judgment-seat. And it came to pass that in the
same year, that his son, who had been appointed by
the people in his stead, was also murdered. And
thus ended the sixty and sixth year
16 And in the commencement of the sixty and
seventh year the people began to grow exceedingly wicked
again
17 For behold, the Lord had blessed them so long
with the riches of the world that they had not been
stirred up to anger, to wars, nor to bloodshed;
therefore they began to set their hearts upon their
riches; yea, they began to seek to get gain that
they might be lifted up one above another;
therefore they began to commit secret murders, and to rob
and to plunder, that they might get gain
18 And now behold, those murderers and plunderers
were a band who had been formed by Kishkumen and
Gadianton. And now it had come to pass that there
were many, even among the Nephites, of Gadianton’s
band. But behold, they were more numerous among
the more wicked part of the Lamanites. And they were
called Gadianton’s robbers and murderers
19 And it was they who did murder the chief judge
Cezoram, and his son, while in the judgment-seat;
and behold, they were not found
20 And now it came to pass that when the Lamanites
found that there were robbers among them they
were exceedingly sorrowful; and they did use every
means in their power to destroy them off the face of
the earth
21 But behold, Satan did stir up the hearts of the
more part of the Nephites, insomuch that they did
unite with those bands of robbers, and did enter
into their covenants and their oaths, that they
would protect and preserve one another in whatsoever
difficult circumstances they should be placed,
that they should not suffer for their murders, and
their plunderings, and their stealings
22 And it came to pass that they did have their
signs, yea, their secret signs, and their secret
words; and this that they might distinguish a brother
who had entered into the covenant, that
whatsoever wickedness his brother should do he should not
be injured by his brother, nor by those who did
belong to his band, who had taken this covenant
23 And thus they might murder, and plunder, and
steal, and commit whoredoms and all manner of
wickedness, contrary to the laws of their country and
also the laws of their God
24 And whosoever of those who belonged to their
band should reveal unto the world of their
wickedness and their abominations, should be tried, not
according to the laws of their country, but according
to the laws of their wickedness, which had been
given by Gadianton and Kishkumen
25 Now behold, it is these secret oaths and
covenants which Alma commanded his son should not go
forth unto the world, lest they should be a means of
bringing down the people unto destruction
26 Now behold, those secret oaths and covenants
did not come forth unto Gadianton from the records
which were delivered unto Helaman; but behold, they
were put into the heart of Gadianton by that same
being who did entice our first parents to partake
of the forbidden fruit
27 Yea, that same being who did plot with Cain,
that if he would murder his brother Abel it should
not be known unto the world. And he did plot with
Cain and his followers from that time forth
28 And also it is that same being who put it into
the hearts of the people to build a tower
sufficiently high that they might get to heaven. And it
was that same being who led on the people who came
from that tower into this land; who spread the
works of darkness and abominations over all the face
of the land, until he dragged the people down to an
entire destruction, and to an everlasting hell
29 Yea, it is that same being who put it into the
heart of Gadianton to still carry on the work of
darkness, and of secret murder; and he has brought
it forth from the beginning of man even down to
this time
30 And behold, it is he who is the author of all
sin. And behold, he doth carry on his works of
darkness and secret murder, and doth hand down their
plots, and their oaths, and their covenants, and
their plans of awful wickedness, from generation to
generation according as he can get hold upon the
hearts of the children of men
31 And now behold, he had got great hold upon the
hearts of the Nephites; yea, insomuch that they
had become exceedingly wicked; yea, the more part of
them had turned out of the way of righteousness,
and did trample under their feet the commandments
of God, and did turn unto their own ways, and did
build up unto themselves idols of their gold and
their silver
32 And it came to pass that all these iniquities
did come unto them in the space of not many years,
insomuch that a more part of it had come unto them
in the sixty and seventh year of the reign of the
judges over the people of Nephi
33 And they did grow in their iniquities in the
sixty and eighth year also, to the great sorrow and
lamentation of the righteous
34 And thus we see that the Nephites did begin to
dwindle in unbelief, and grow in wickedness and
abominations, while the Lamanites began to grow
exceedingly in the knowledge of their God; yea, they
did begin to keep his statutes and commandments,
and to walk in truth and uprightness before him
35 And thus we see that the Spirit of the Lord
began to withdraw from the Nephites, because of the
wickedness and the hardness of their hearts
36 And thus we see that the Lord began to pour out
his Spirit upon the Lamanites, because of their
easiness and willingness to believe in his words
37 And it came to pass that the Lamanites did hunt
the band of robbers of Gadianton; and they did
preach the word of God among the more wicked part of
them, insomuch that this band of robbers was
utterly destroyed from among the Lamanites
38 And it came to pass on the other hand, that the
Nephites did build them up and support them,
beginning at the more wicked part of them, until they
had overspread all the land of the Nephites, and
had seduced the more part of the righteous until
they had come down to believe in their works and
partake of their spoils, and to join with them in
their secret murders and combinations
39 And thus they did obtain the sole management of
the government, insomuch that they did trample
under their feet and smite and rend and turn their
backs upon the poor and the meek, and the humble
followers of God
40 And thus we see that they were in an awful
state, and ripening for an everlasting destruction
41 And it came to pass that thus ended the sixty
and eighth year of the reign of the judges over the
people of Nephi.