The Prophecy of Nephi, the Son of Helaman—God
threatens the people of Nephi that he will visit them
in his anger, to their utter destruction except
they repent of their wickedness. God smiteth the
people of Nephi with pestilence; they repent and turn
unto him. Samuel, a Lamanite, prophesies unto the
Nephites. Comprising chapters 7
through 16.Chapter 7 Nephi is rejected in the north and returns to
Zarahemla—He prays upon his garden tower and then
calls upon the people to repent or perish. About
23–21 B.C.
1 Behold, now it came to pass in the sixty and
ninth year of the reign of the judges over the people
of the Nephites, that Nephi, the son of Helaman,
returned to the land of Zarahemla from the land
northward
2 For he had been forth among the people who were
in the land northward, and did preach the word of
God unto them, and did prophesy many things unto
them
3 And they did reject all his words, insomuch that
he could not stay among them, but returned again
unto the land of his nativity
4 And seeing the people in a state of such awful
wickedness, and those Gadianton robbers filling the
judgment-seats—having usurped the power and
authority of the land; laying aside the commandments of
God, and not in the least aright before him;
doing no justice unto the children of men
5 Condemning the righteous because of their
righteousness; letting the guilty and the wicked go
unpunished because of their money; and moreover to be
held in office at the head of government, to rule
and do according to their wills, that they might
get gain and glory of the world, and, moreover,
that they might the more easily commit adultery, and
steal, and kill, and do according to their own
wills
6 Now this great iniquity had come upon the
Nephites, in the space of not many years; and when Nephi
saw it, his heart was swollen with sorrow within
his breast; and he did exclaim in the agony of his
soul
7 Oh, that I could have had my days in the days
when my father Nephi first came out of the land of
Jerusalem, that I could have joyed with him in the
promised land; then were his people easy to be
entreated, firm to keep the commandments of God, and
slow to be led to do iniquity; and they were quick
to hearken unto the words of the Lord
8 Yea, if my days could have been in those days,
then would my soul have had joy in the
righteousness of my brethren
9 But behold, I am consigned that these are my
days, and that my soul shall be filled with sorrow
because of this the wickedness of my brethren
10 And behold, now it came to pass that it was
upon a tower, which was in the garden of Nephi, which
was by the highway which led to the chief market,
which was in the city of Zarahemla; therefore,
Nephi had bowed himself upon the tower which was in
his garden, which tower was also near unto the
garden gate by which led the highway
11 And it came to pass that there were certain men
passing by and saw Nephi as he was pouring out
his soul unto God upon the tower; and they ran and
told the people what they had seen, and the people
came together in multitudes that they might know
the cause of so great mourning for the wickedness
of the people
12 And now, when Nephi arose he beheld the
multitudes of people who had gathered together
13 And it came to pass that he opened his mouth
and said unto them: Behold, why have ye gathered
yourselves together? That I may tell you of your
iniquities
14 Yea, because I have got upon my tower that I
might pour out my soul unto my God, because of the
exceeding sorrow of my heart, which is because of
your iniquities
15 And because of my mourning and lamentation ye
have gathered yourselves together, and do marvel;
yea, and ye have great need to marvel; yea, ye
ought to marvel because ye are given away that the
devil has got so great hold upon your hearts
16 Yea, how could you have given way to the
enticing of him who is seeking to hurl away your souls
down to everlasting misery and endless wo
17 O repent ye, repent ye! Why will ye die? Turn
ye, turn ye unto the Lord your God. Why has he
forsaken you
18 It is because you have hardened your hearts;
yea, ye will not hearken unto the voice of the good
shepherd; yea, ye have provoked him to anger
against you
19 And behold, instead of gathering you, except ye
will repent, behold, he shall scatter you forth
that ye shall become meat for dogs and wild beasts
20 O, how could you have forgotten your God in the
very day that he has delivered you
21 But behold, it is to get gain, to be praised of
men, yea, and that ye might get gold and silver.
And ye have set your hearts upon the riches and
the vain things of this world, for the which ye do
murder, and plunder, and steal, and bear false
witness against your neighbor, and do all manner of
iniquity
22 And for this cause wo shall come unto you
except ye shall repent. For if ye will not repent,
behold, this great city, and also all those great
cities which are round about, which are in the land of
our possession, shall be taken away that ye shall
have no place in them; for behold, the Lord will
not grant unto you strength, as he has hitherto
done, to withstand against your enemies
23 For behold, thus saith the Lord: I will not
show unto the wicked of my strength, to one more than
the other, save it be unto those who repent of
their sins, and hearken unto my words. Now
therefore, I would that ye should behold, my brethren, that
it shall be better for the Lamanites than for you
except ye shall repent
24 For behold, they are more righteous than you,
for they have not sinned against that great
knowledge which ye have received; therefore the Lord will
be merciful unto them; yea, he will lengthen out
their days and increase their seed, even when thou
shalt be utterly destroyed except thou shalt
repent
25 Yea, wo be unto you because of that great
abomination which has come among you; and ye have
united yourselves unto it, yea, to that secret band
which was established by Gadianton
26 Yea, wo shall come unto you because of that
pride which ye have suffered to enter your hearts,
which has lifted you up beyond that which is good
because of your exceedingly great riches
27 Yea, wo be unto you because of your wickedness
and abominations