Chapter 8 Corrupt judges seek to incite the people
against Nephi—Abraham, Moses, Zenos, Zenock,
Ezias, Isaiah, Jeremiah, Lehi, and Nephi all testified
of Christ—By inspiration Nephi announces the
murder of the chief judge. About 23–21 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that when Nephi had said
these words, behold, there were men who were
judges, who also belonged to the secret band of
Gadianton, and they were angry, and they cried out
against him, saying unto the people: Why do ye not
seize upon this man and bring him forth, that he may
be condemned according to the crime which he has
done
2 Why seest thou this man, and hearest him revile
against this people and against our law
3 For behold, Nephi had spoken unto them
concerning the corruptness of their law; yea, many things
did Nephi speak which cannot be written; and
nothing did he speak which was contrary to the
commandments of God
4 And those judges were angry with him because he
spake plainly unto them concerning their secret
works of darkness; nevertheless, they durst not lay
their own hands upon him, for they feared the
people lest they should cry out against them
5 Therefore they did cry unto the people, saying:
Why do you suffer this man to revile against us?
For behold he doth condemn all this people, even
unto destruction; yea, and also that these our great
cities shall be taken from us, that we shall have
no place in them
6 And now we know that this is impossible, for
behold, we are powerful, and our cities great,
therefore our enemies can have no power over us
7 And it came to pass that thus they did stir up
the people to anger against Nephi, and raised
contentions among them; for there were some who did cry
out: Let this man alone, for he is a good man,
and those things which he saith will surely come to
pass except we repent
8 Yea, behold, all the judgments will come upon us
which he has testified unto us; for we know that
he has testified aright unto us concerning our
iniquities. And behold they are many, and he knoweth
as well all things which shall befall us as he
knoweth of our iniquities
9 Yea, and behold, if he had not been a prophet he
could not have testified concerning those things
10 And it came to pass that those people who
sought to destroy Nephi were compelled because of their
fear, that they did not lay their hands on him;
therefore he began again to speak unto them, seeing
that he had gained favor in the eyes of some,
insomuch that the remainder of them did fear
11 Therefore he was constrained to speak more unto
them saying: Behold, my brethren, have ye not
read that God gave power unto one man, even Moses, to
smite upon the waters of the Red Sea, and they
parted hither and thither, insomuch that the
Israelites, who were our fathers, came through upon dry
ground, and the waters closed upon the armies of
the Egyptians and swallowed them up
12 And now behold, if God gave unto this man such
power, then why should ye dispute among
yourselves, and say that he hath given unto me no power
whereby I may know concerning the judgments that shall
come upon you except ye repent
13 But, behold, ye not only deny my words, but ye
also deny all the words which have been spoken by
our fathers, and also the words which were spoken
by this man, Moses, who had such great power given
unto him, yea, the words which he hath spoken
concerning the coming of the Messiah
14 Yea, did he not bear record that the Son of God
should come? And as he lifted up the brazen
serpent in the wilderness, even so shall he be lifted
up who should come
15 And as many as should look upon that serpent
should live, even so as many as should look upon the
Son of God with faith, having a contrite spirit,
might live, even unto that life which is eternal
16 And now behold, Moses did not only testify of
these things, but also all the holy prophets, from
his days even to the days of Abraham
17 Yea, and behold, Abraham saw of his coming, and
was filled with gladness and did rejoice
18 Yea, and behold I say unto you, that Abraham
not only knew of these things, but there were many
before the days of Abraham who were called by the
order of God; yea, even after the order of his Son;
and this that it should be shown unto the people,
a great many thousand years before his coming,
that even redemption should come unto them
19 And now I would that ye should know, that even
since the days of Abraham there have been many
prophets that have testified these things; yea,
behold, the prophet Zenos did testify boldly; for the
which he was slain
20 And behold, also Zenock, and also Ezias, and
also Isaiah, and Jeremiah, (Jeremiah being that same
prophet who testified of the destruction of
Jerusalem) and now we know that Jerusalem was destroyed
according to the words of Jeremiah. O then why
not the Son of God come, according to his prophecy
21 And now will you dispute that Jerusalem was
destroyed? Will ye say that the sons of Zedekiah were
not slain, all except it were Mulek? Yea, and do
ye not behold that the seed of Zedekiah are with
us, and they were driven out of the land of
Jerusalem? But behold, this is not all
22 Our father Lehi was driven out of Jerusalem
because he testified of these things. Nephi also
testified of these things, and also almost all of our
fathers, even down to this time; yea, they have
testified of the coming of Christ, and have looked
forward, and have rejoiced in his day which is to
come
23 And behold, he is God, and he is with them, and
he did manifest himself unto them, that they were
redeemed by him; and they gave unto him glory,
because of that which is to come
24 And now, seeing ye know these things and cannot
deny them except ye shall lie, therefore in this
ye have sinned, for ye have rejected all these
things, notwithstanding so many evidences which ye
have received; yea, even ye have received all
things, both things in heaven, and all things which are
in the earth, as a witness that they are true
25 But behold, ye have rejected the truth, and
rebelled against your holy God; and even at this
time, instead of laying up for yourselves treasures in
heaven, where nothing doth corrupt, and where
nothing can come which is unclean, ye are heaping up
for yourselves wrath against the day of judgment
26 Yea, even at this time ye are ripening, because
of your murders and your fornication and
wickedness, for everlasting destruction; yea, and except
ye repent it will come unto you soon
27 Yea, behold it is now even at your doors; yea,
go ye in unto the judgment-seat, and search; and
behold, your judge is murdered, and he lieth in his
blood; and he hath been murdered by his brother,
who seeketh to sit in the judgment-seat
28 And behold, they both belong to your secret
band, whose author is Gadianton and the evil one who
seeketh to destroy the souls of men.