Chapter 9 Messengers find the chief judge
dead at the judgment seat—They are imprisoned
and later released—By inspiration Nephi
identifies Seantum as the murderer—Nephi is
accepted by some as a prophet. About 23–21 B.C.
1 Behold, now it came to pass that when
Nephi had spoken these words, certain men
who were among them ran to the
judgment-seat; yea, even there were five who went,
and they said among themselves, as they went:
2 Behold, now we will know of a surety
whether this man be a prophet and God
hath commanded him to prophesy such
marvelous things unto us. Behold, we do not
believe that he hath; yea, we do not
believe that he is a prophet;
nevertheless, if this thing which he has said
concerning the chief judge be true, that
he be dead, then will we believe that
the other words which he has spoken are true.
3 And it came to pass that they
ran in their might, and came in
unto the judgment-seat; and behold,
the chief judge had fallen to
the earth, and did lie in his blood.
4 And now behold, when they saw
this they were astonished
exceedingly, insomuch that they fell
to the earth; for they had not
believed the words which Nephi had
spoken concerning the chief judge.
5 But now, when they saw
they believed, and fear came
upon them lest all the
judgments which Nephi had
spoken should come upon the
people; therefore they did
quake, and had fallen to the earth.
6 Now, immediately when
the judge had been
murdered—he being stabbed by
his brother by a garb of
secrecy, and he fled,
and the servants ran and
told the people, raising
the cry of murder among them;
7 And behold the
people did gather
themselves together unto the
place of the
judgment-seat—and behold, to
their astonishment they
saw those five men who
had fallen to the earth.
8 And now behold, the
people knew nothing
concerning the
multitude who had gathered
together at the
garden of Nephi; therefore
they said among
themselves: These men are
they who have
murdered the judge, and God
has smitten them
that they could not flee from us.
9 And it came to
pass that they laid
hold on them, and bound
them and cast them
into prison. And
there was a
proclamation sent abroad that
the judge was slain,
and that the
murderers had been taken
and were cast into prison.
10 And it came to
pass that on the
morrow the people
did assemble
themselves together to
mourn and to fast,
at the burial of
the great chief
judge who had been slain.
11 And thus also
those judges who
were at the garden
of Nephi, and heard
his words, were
also gathered
together at the burial.
12 And it came to
pass that they
inquired among the
people, saying:
Where are the
five who were sent
to inquire
concerning the chief
judge whether he was
dead? And they
answered and said:
Concerning this
five whom ye say
ye have sent, we
know not; but
there are five who
are the murderers,
whom we have cast into prison.
13 And it came
to pass that the
judges desired
that they should
be brought; and
they were
brought, and behold
they were the five
who were sent;
and behold the
judges inquired
of them to know
concerning the
matter, and they
told them all
that they had done, saying:
14 We ran and
came to the
place of the
judgment-seat, and
when we saw all
things even as
Nephi had
testified, we were
astonished
insomuch that we fell
to the earth;
and when we
were recovered
from our
astonishment, behold
they cast us into prison.
15 Now, as for
the murder of
this man, we
know not who
has done it;
and only this
much we know, we
ran and came
according as
ye desired, and
behold he was
dead,
according to the words of Nephi.
16 And now it
came to pass
that the
judges did
expound the matter
unto the
people, and did
cry out
against Nephi,
saying: Behold,
we know that
this Nephi
must have
agreed with some
one to slay
the judge, and
then he might
declare it
unto us, that
he might
convert us unto
his faith,
that he might
raise himself
to be a great
man, chosen of God, and a prophet.
17 And now
behold, we will
detect this
man, and he
shall confess
his fault and
make known
unto us the
true murderer
of this judge.
18 And it
came to pass
that the five
were
liberated on the
day of the
burial.
Nevertheless, they
did rebuke
the judges
in the words
which they
had spoken
against Nephi,
and did
contend with
them one by
one, insomuch
that they did confound them.
Nevertheless, they
caused that
Nephi
should be taken
and bound
and brought
before the
multitude,
and they
began to
question him
in divers
ways that
they might
cross him,
that they
might accuse him to death—
20 Saying
unto him:
Thou art
confederate; who is
this man
that hath
done this
murder? Now
tell us,
and
acknowledge thy
fault;
saying, Behold
here is
money; and
also we
will grant
unto thee
thy life if
thou wilt
tell us,
and
acknowledge the
agreement
which thou hast made with him.
21 But
Nephi said
unto
them: O ye
fools, ye
uncircumcised of
heart, ye
blind, and
ye
stiffnecked
people, do
ye know
how long
the Lord
your God
will
suffer you
that ye
shall go on
in this your way of sin?
22 O ye
ought to
begin
to howl
and
mourn,
because of the
great
destruction which
at this
time
doth await
you,
except ye shall repent.
Behold ye
say that
I have
agreed
with a
man
that he
should
murder
Seezoram, our
chief
judge.
But
behold, I
say unto
you,
that this
is
because I
have
testified
unto
you that
ye
might know
concerning
this
thing; yea,
even
for a
witness
unto
you, that
I did
know of
the
wickedness and abominations which are among you.
24 And
because I
have
done
this, ye
say
that I
have
agreed
with a
man
that he
should
do
this
thing;
yea,
because I
showed unto
you
this
sign ye
are
angry
with me,
and seek to destroy my life.
And now
behold, I
will
show
unto
you
another
sign,
and
see if
ye
will in
this
thing seek to destroy me.
Behold I
say
unto
you: Go
to
the
house of
Seantum,
who is
the
brother
of
Seezoram, and say unto him—
Has
Nephi,
the
pretended
prophet,
who
doth
prophesy
so
much
evil
concerning
this
people,
agreed
with
thee,
in
the
which
ye
have murdered Seezoram, who is your brother?
And
behold,
he
shall
say
unto
you,
Nay.
And
ye
shall
say
unto
him:
Have
ye
murdered
your
brother?
And
he
shall
stand
with
fear,
and
wist
not
what
to
say.
And
behold,
he
shall
deny
unto
you;
and
he
shall
make
as
if
he
were
astonished; nevertheless, he shall declare unto you that he is innocent.
But
behold,
ye
shall
examine
him,
and
ye
shall
find
blood
upon
the
skirts
of
his
cloak.
And
when
ye
have
seen
this,
ye
shall
say:
From
whence
cometh
this
blood?
Do
we
not
know
that
it
is
the
blood
of
your
brother?
And
then
shall
he
tremble,
and
shall
look
pale,
even
as
if
death
had
come
upon
him.
34 And then shall ye say: Because of this fear and this paleness which has come upon your face, behold, we know that thou art
And
then
shall
ye
say:
Because
of
this
fear
and
this
paleness
which has come upon your face, behold, we know that thou art guilty.
35 And then shall greater fear come upon him; and then shall he confess unto you, and deny no more that he has done this
And
then
shall
greater
fear
come
upon
him;
and
then
shall
he
confess
unto
you,
and
deny
no
more
that
he
has
done
this
murder.
36 And then shall he say unto you, that I, Nephi, know nothing concerning the matter save it were given unto me by the power of God. And then shall ye know that I am an honest man, and that I am sent unto you from
And
then
shall
he
say
unto
you,
that
I,
Nephi,
know
nothing
concerning
the
matter
save
it
were
given
unto
me
by
the
power
of
God.
And
then
shall
ye
know
that
I
am
an
honest
man,
and
that
I
am
sent
unto
you
from
God.
37 And it came to pass that they went and did, even according as Nephi had said unto them. And behold, the words which he had said were true; for according to the words he did deny; and also according to the words he did
And
it
came
to
pass
that
they
went
and
did,
even
according
as
Nephi
had
said
unto
them.
And
behold,
the
words
which
he
had
said
were
true;
for
according
to
the
words
he
did
deny;
and
also
according
to
the
words
he
did
confess.
38 And he was brought to prove that he himself was the very murderer, insomuch that the five were set at liberty, and also was
And
he
was
brought
to
prove
that
he
himself
was
the
very
murderer,
insomuch
that
the
five
were
set
at
liberty,
and
also
was
Nephi.
39 And there were some of the Nephites who believed on the words of Nephi; and there were some also, who believed because of the testimony of the five, for they had been converted while they were in
And
there
were
some
of
the
Nephites
who
believed
on
the
words
of
Nephi;
and
there
were
some
also,
who
believed
because
of
the
testimony
of
the
five,
for
they
had
been
converted
while
they
were
in
prison.
40 And now there were some among the people, who said that Nephi was a
And
now
there
were
some
among
the
people,
who
said
that
Nephi
was
a
prophet.
41 And there were others who said: Behold, he is a god, for except he was a god he could not know of all things. For behold, he has told us the thoughts of our hearts, and also has told us things; and even he has brought unto our knowledge the true murderer of our chief judge.
And
there
were
others
who
said:
Behold,
he
is
a
god,
for
except
could
not
know
of
all
things.
For
behold,
he
has
told
us
the
thoughts
of
our
hearts,
and
also
has
told
us
things;
and
even
he
has
brought
unto
our
knowledge
the
true
murderer
of
our
chief
judge.