Chapter 12 The prophet Ether exhorts the
people to believe in God—Moroni recounts the
wonders and marvels done by faith—Faith
enabled the brother of Jared to see Christ—The
Lord gives men weakness that they may be
humble—The brother of Jared moved Mount Zerin by
faith—Faith, hope, and charity are essential
to salvation—Moroni saw Jesus face to face.
1 And it came to pass that the days of
Ether were in the days of Coriantumr;
and Coriantumr was king over all the land.
2 And Ether was a prophet of the
Lord; wherefore Ether came forth in
the days of Coriantumr, and began to
prophesy unto the people, for he
could not be restrained because of
the Spirit of the Lord which was in him.
3 For he did cry from the
morning, even until the going down
of the sun, exhorting the
people to believe in God unto
repentance lest they should be
destroyed, saying unto them that
by faith all things are fulfilled—
4 Wherefore, whoso believeth
in God might with surety
hope for a better world, yea,
even a place at the right
hand of God, which hope cometh
of faith, maketh an anchor
to the souls of men, which
would make them sure and
steadfast, always abounding in
good works, being led to glorify God.
5 And it came to pass
that Ether did prophesy
great and marvelous things
unto the people, which
they did not believe,
because they saw them not.
6 And now, I, Moroni,
would speak somewhat
concerning these things; I
would show unto the
world that faith is
things which are hoped for
and not seen; wherefore,
dispute not because ye
see not, for ye
receive no witness until
after the trial of your faith.
7 For it was by faith
that Christ showed
himself unto our fathers,
after he had risen
from the dead; and he
showed not himself unto
them until after they
had faith in him;
wherefore, it must needs
be that some had faith
in him, for he showed
himself not unto the world.
8 But because of the
faith of men he has
shown himself unto the
world, and glorified
the name of the
Father, and prepared a
way that thereby others
might be partakers
of the heavenly gift,
that they might hope
for those things
which they have not seen.
9 Wherefore, ye
may also have hope,
and be partakers
of the gift, if ye
will but have faith.
10 Behold it was
by faith that
they of old were
called after the
holy order of God.
11 Wherefore,
by faith was the
law of Moses
given. But in
the gift of his
Son hath God
prepared a more
excellent way;
and it is by
faith that it hath
been fulfilled.
12 For if
there be no faith
among the
children of men
God can do no
miracle among
them; wherefore,
he showed not
himself until
after their faith.
13 Behold, it
was the
faith of Alma and
Amulek that
caused the
prison to
tumble to the earth.
14 Behold,
it was the
faith of Nephi
and Lehi
that wrought
the change
upon the
Lamanites, that
they were
baptized with
fire and with
the Holy Ghost.
15 Behold,
it was the
faith of
Ammon and his
brethren
which
wrought so great
a miracle
among the Lamanites.
16 Yea,
and even all
they who
wrought
miracles
wrought them
by faith,
even those
who were
before
Christ and
also those
who were after.
17 And it
was by
faith that
the
three
disciples
obtained a
promise that
they
should not
taste of
death; and
they
obtained not
the
promise until
after their faith.
18 And
neither at
any time
hath any
wrought
miracles
until
after their
faith;
wherefore
they first
believed
in the
Son of God.
19 And
there
were many
whose
faith was
so
exceedingly
strong,
even
before Christ
came,
who could
not be
kept
from within
the
veil, but
truly saw
with
their eyes
the
things
which they
had
beheld with
an eye of
faith, and they were glad.
20 And
behold,
we have
seen in
this
record that
one of
these was
the
brother of
Jared;
for so
great was
his
faith in
God, that
when God
put
forth his
finger he
could
not hide
it from
the sight
of the
brother
of
Jared,
because of his
word
which he
had
spoken unto
him,
which word
he had
obtained
by faith.
21 And
after
the
brother of
Jared
had
beheld the
finger
of the
Lord,
because
of the
promise
which
the
brother of
Jared
had
obtained
by
faith, the
Lord
could not
withhold
anything
from his
sight;
wherefore he
showed
him all
things,
for he
could no longer be kept without the veil.
22 And
it is
by
faith
that my
fathers have
obtained
the
promise
that
these
things
should
come
unto
their
brethren
through the
Gentiles;
therefore the
Lord
hath
commanded me, yea, even Jesus Christ.
And I
said
unto
him:
Lord,
the
Gentiles
will
mock at
these
things,
because of
our
weakness
in
writing;
for
Lord
thou
hast
made
us
mighty
in
word by
faith,
but
thou
hast not
made
us
mighty
in
writing;
for
thou
hast
made all
this
people
that
they
could
speak
much,
because of the Holy Ghost which thou hast given them;
And
thou
hast
made us
that we
could
write
but
little,
because
of
the
awkwardness
of
our
hands.
Behold,
thou
hast
not
made
us
mighty
in
writing
like
unto
the
brother
of
Jared,
for
thou
madest
him
that
the
things
which
he
wrote
were
mighty
even as thou art, unto the overpowering of man to read them.
Thou
hast
also
made
our
words
powerful
and
great,
even
that
we
cannot
write
them;
wherefore,
when
we
write we
behold
our
weakness,
and
stumble
because of
the
placing
of
our
words;
and I
fear
lest
the
Gentiles
shall
mock
at
our
words.
And
when
I
had
said
this,
the
Lord
spake
unto
me,
saying:
Fools
mock,
but
they
shall
mourn;
and
my
grace
is
sufficient
for
the
meek,
that they shall take no advantage of your weakness;
And
if
men
come
unto
me
I
will
show
unto
them
their
weakness.
I
give
unto
men
weakness
that
they
may
be
humble;
and
my
grace
is
sufficient
for
all
men
that
humble
themselves
before
me;
for
if
they
humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.
28 Behold, I will show unto the Gentiles their weakness, and I will show unto them that faith, hope and charity bringeth unto me—the fountain of all
Behold,
I
will
show
unto
the
Gentiles
their
weakness,
and
I
will
show
unto
them that faith, hope and charity bringeth unto me—the fountain of all righteousness.
29 And I, Moroni, having heard these words, was comforted, and said: O Lord, thy righteous will be done, for I know that thou workest unto the children of men according to their
And
I,
Moroni,
having
heard
these
words,
was
comforted,
and
said:
O
Lord,
thy
righteous
will
be
done,
for
I
know
that
thou
workest
unto
the
children
of
men
according
to
their
faith;
30 For the brother of Jared said unto the mountain Zerin, Remove—and it was removed. And if he had not had faith it would not have moved; wherefore thou workest after men have
For
the
brother
of
Jared
said
unto
the
mountain
Zerin,
Remove—and
it
was
removed.
faith
it
would
not
have
moved;
wherefore
thou
workest
after
men
have
faith.
31 For thus didst thou manifest thyself unto thy disciples; for after they had faith, and did speak in thy name, thou didst show thyself unto them in great
For
thus
didst
thou
manifest
thyself
unto
thy
disciples;
for
after
they
had
faith,
and
did
speak
in
thy
name,
thou
didst
show
thyself
unto
them
in
great
power.
32 And I also remember that thou hast said that thou hast prepared a house for man, yea, even among the mansions of thy Father, in which man might have a more excellent hope; wherefore man must hope, or he cannot receive an inheritance in the place which thou hast
And
I
also
remember
that
thou
hast
said
that
thou
hast
prepared
a
house
for
man,
yea,
even
among
the
mansions
of
thy
Father,
in
which
man
might
have
a
more
excellent
hope;
wherefore
man
must
hope,
or
he
cannot
receive
an
inheritance
in
the
place
which
thou
hast
prepared.
33 And again, I remember that thou hast said that thou hast loved the world, even unto the laying down of thy life for the world, that thou mightest take it again to prepare a place for the children of
And
again,
I
remember
that
thou
hast
said
that
thou
hast
loved
the
world,
even
unto
the
laying
down
of
thy
life
for
the
world,
that
thou
mightest
take
it
again
to
prepare
a
place
for
the
children
of
men.
34 And now I know that this love which thou hast had for the children of men is charity; wherefore, except men shall have charity they cannot inherit that place which thou hast prepared in the mansions of thy
And
now
I
know
that
this
love
which
thou
hast
had
for
the
children
of
men
is
charity;
wherefore,
except
men
shall
have
charity
they
cannot
inherit
that
place
which
thou
hast
prepared
in
the
mansions
of
thy
Father.
35 Wherefore, I know by this thing which thou hast said, that if the Gentiles have not charity, because of our weakness, that thou wilt prove them, and take away their talent, yea, even that which they have received, and give unto them who shall have more
Wherefore,
I
know
by
this
thing
which
thou
hast
said,
that
if
the
Gentiles
have
not
charity,
because
of
our
weakness,
that
thou
wilt
prove
them,
and
take
away
their
talent,
yea,
even
that
which
they
have
received,
and
give
unto
them
who
shall
have
more
abundantly.
36 And it came to pass that I prayed unto the Lord that he would give unto the Gentiles grace, that they might have
And
it
came
to
pass
that
I
prayed
unto
the
Lord
that
he
would
give
unto
the
Gentiles
grace,
that
they
might
have
charity.
37 And it came to pass that the Lord said unto me: If they have not charity it mattereth not unto thee, thou hast been faithful; wherefore, thy garments shall be made clean. And because thou hast seen thy weakness thou shalt be made strong, even unto the sitting down in the place which I have prepared in the mansions of my
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
Lord
said
unto
me:
If
they
have
not
charity
it
mattereth
not
unto
thee,
thou
hast
been
faithful;
wherefore,
thy
garments
shall
be
made
clean.
And
because
thou
hast
seen
thy
weakness
thou
shalt
be
made
strong,
even
unto
the
sitting
down
in
the
place
which
I
have
prepared
in
the
mansions
of
my
Father.
38 And now I, Moroni, bid farewell unto the Gentiles, yea, and also unto my brethren whom I love, until we shall meet before the judgment-seat of Christ, where all men shall know that my garments are not spotted with your
And
now
I,
Moroni,
bid
farewell
unto
the
Gentiles,
yea,
and
also
unto
my
brethren
whom
I
love,
until
we
shall
meet
before
the
judgment-seat
of
Christ,
where
all
men
shall
know
that
my
garments
are
not
spotted
with
your
blood.
39 And then shall ye know that I have seen Jesus, and that he hath talked with me face to face, and that he told me in plain humility, even as a man telleth another in mine own language, concerning these
And
then
shall
ye
know
that
I
have
seen
Jesus,
and
that
he
hath
talked
with
me
face
to
face,
and
that
he
told
me
in
plain
humility,
even
as
a
man
telleth
another
in
mine
own
language,
concerning
these
things;
40 And only a few have I written, because of my weakness in
And
only
a
few
have
I
written,
because
of
my
weakness
in
writing.
41 And now, I would commend you to seek this Jesus of whom the prophets and apostles have written, that the grace of God the Father, and also the Lord Jesus Christ, and the Holy Ghost, which beareth record of them, may be and abide in you forever. Amen.
And
now,
I
would
commend
you
to
seek
this
Jesus
of
whom
the
prophets
and
apostles
have
written,
that
the
grace
of
God
the
Father,
and
also
the
Lord
Jesus
Christ,
and
the
Holy
Ghost,
which
beareth
record
of
them,
may
be
and
abide
in
you
forever.
Amen.