Chapter 15 Millions of the Jaredites are slain in
battle—Shiz and Coriantumr assemble all the people
to mortal combat—The Spirit of the Lord ceases to
strive with them—The Jaredite nation is utterly
destroyed—Only Coriantumr remains.
1 And it came to pass when Coriantumr had
recovered of his wounds, he began to remember the words
which Ether had spoken unto him
2 He saw that there had been slain by the sword
already nearly two millions of his people, and he
began to sorrow in his heart; yea, there had been
slain two millions of mighty men, and also their
wives and their children
3 He began to repent of the evil which he had
done; he began to remember the words which had been
spoken by the mouth of all the prophets, and he saw
them that they were fulfilled thus far, every
whit; and his soul mourned and refused to be
comforted
4 And it came to pass that he wrote an epistle
unto Shiz, desiring him that he would spare the
people, and he would give up the kingdom for the sake
of the lives of the people
5 And it came to pass that when Shiz had received
his epistle he wrote an epistle unto Coriantumr,
that if he would give himself up, that he might
slay him with his own sword, that he would spare the
lives of the people
6 And it came to pass that the people repented not
of their iniquity; and the people of Coriantumr
were stirred up to anger against the people of
Shiz; and the people of Shiz were stirred up to anger
against the people of Coriantumr; wherefore, the
people of Shiz did give battle unto the people of
Coriantumr
7 And when Coriantumr saw that he was about to
fall he fled again before the people of Shiz
8 And it came to pass that he came to the waters
of Ripliancum, which, by interpretation, is large,
or to exceed all; wherefore, when they came to
these waters they pitched their tents; and Shiz also
pitched his tents near unto them; and therefore on
the morrow they did come to battle
9 And it came to pass that they fought an
exceedingly sore battle, in which Coriantumr was wounded
again, and he fainted with the loss of blood
10 And it came to pass that the armies of
Coriantumr did press upon the armies of Shiz that they
beat them, that they caused them to flee before them;
and they did flee southward, and did pitch their
tents in a place which was called Ogath
11 And it came to pass that the army of Coriantumr
did pitch their tents by the hill Ramah; and it
was that same hill where my father Mormon did hide
up the records unto the Lord, which were sacred
12 And it came to pass that they did gather
together all the people upon all the face of the land,
who had not been slain, save it was Ether
13 And it came to pass that Ether did behold all
the doings of the people; and he beheld that the
people who were for Coriantumr were gathered
together to the army of Coriantumr; and the people who
were for Shiz were gathered together to the army of
Shiz
14 Wherefore, they were for the space of four
years gathering together the people, that they might
get all who were upon the face of the land, and
that they might receive all the strength which it was
possible that they could receive
15 And it came to pass that when they were all
gathered together, every one to the army which he
would, with their wives and their children—both men,
women and children being armed with weapons of
war, having shields, and breastplates, and
head-plates, and being clothed after the manner of war—they
did march forth one against another to battle; and
they fought all that day, and conquered not
16 And it came to pass that when it was night they
were weary, and retired to their camps; and after
they had retired to their camps they took up a
howling and a lamentation for the loss of the slain
of their people; and so great were their cries,
their howlings and lamentations, that they did rend
the air exceedingly
17 And it came to pass that on the morrow they did
go again to battle, and great and terrible was
that day; nevertheless, they conquered not, and when
the night came again they did rend the air with
their cries, and their howlings, and their
mournings, for the loss of the slain of their people
18 And it came to pass that Coriantumr wrote again
an epistle unto Shiz, desiring that he would not
come again to battle, but that he would take the
kingdom, and spare the lives of the people
19 But behold, the Spirit of the Lord had ceased
striving with them, and Satan had full power over
the hearts of the people; for they were given up
unto the hardness of their hearts, and the blindness
of their minds that they might be destroyed;
wherefore they went again to battle
20 And it came to pass that they fought all that
day, and when the night came they slept upon their
swords
21 And on the morrow they fought even until the
night came
22 And when the night came they were drunken with
anger, even as a man who is drunken with wine; and
they slept again upon their swords
23 And on the morrow they fought again; and when
the night came they had all fallen by the sword
save it were fifty and two of the people of
Coriantumr, and sixty and nine of the people of Shiz
24 And it came to pass that they slept upon their
swords that night, and on the morrow they fought
again, and they contended in their might with their
swords and with their shields, all that day
25 And when the night came there were thirty and
two of the people of Shiz, and twenty and seven of
the people of Coriantumr
26 And it came to pass that they ate and slept,
and prepared for death on the morrow. And they were
large and mighty men as to the strength of men
27 And it came to pass that they fought for the
space of three hours, and they fainted with the loss
of blood
28 And it came to pass that when the men of
Coriantumr had received sufficient strength that they
could walk, they were about to flee for their lives;
but behold, Shiz arose, and also his men, and he
swore in his wrath that he would slay Coriantumr
or he would perish by the sword
29 Wherefore, he did pursue them, and on the
morrow he did overtake them; and they fought again with
the sword. And it came to pass that when they had
all fallen by the sword, save it were Coriantumr
and Shiz, behold Shiz had fainted with the loss of
blood
30 And it came to pass that when Coriantumr had
leaned upon his sword, that he rested a little, he
smote off the head of Shiz
31 And it came to pass that after he had smitten
off the head of Shiz, that Shiz raised up on his
hands and fell; and after that he had struggled for
breath, he died
32 And it came to pass that Coriantumr fell to the
earth, and became as if he had no life
33 And the Lord spake unto Ether, and said unto
him: Go forth. And he went forth, and beheld that
the words of the Lord had all been fulfilled; and he
finished his record; (and the hundredth part I
have not written) and he hid them in a manner that
the people of Limhi did find them
34 Now the last words which are written by Ether
are these: Whether the Lord will that I be
translated, or that I suffer the will of the Lord in the
flesh, it mattereth not, if it so be that I am
saved in the kingdom of God. Amen.