Chapter 11 Wars, dissensions, and wickedness
dominate Jaredite life—Prophets predict the utter
destruction of the Jaredites unless they repent—The
people reject the words of the prophets.
1 And there came also in the days of Com many
prophets, and prophesied of the destruction of that
great people except they should repent, and turn
unto the Lord, and forsake their murders and
wickedness
2 And it came to pass that the prophets were
rejected by the people, and they fled unto Com for
protection, for the people sought to destroy them
3 And they prophesied unto Com many things; and he
was blessed in all the remainder of his days
4 And he lived to a good old age, and begat
Shiblom; and Shiblom reigned in his stead. And the
brother of Shiblom rebelled against him, and there
began to be an exceedingly great war in all the land
5 And it came to pass that the brother of Shiblom
caused that all the prophets who prophesied of the
destruction of the people should be put to death
6 And there was great calamity in all the land,
for they had testified that a great curse should
come upon the land, and also upon the people, and
that there should be a great destruction among them,
such an one as never had been upon the face of the
earth, and their bones should become as heaps of
earth upon the face of the land except they should
repent of their wickedness
7 And they hearkened not unto the voice of the
Lord, because of their wicked combinations;
wherefore, there began to be wars and contentions in all
the land, and also many famines and pestilences,
insomuch that there was a great destruction, such an
one as never had been known upon the face of the
earth; and all this came to pass in the days of
Shiblom
8 And the people began to repent of their
iniquity; and inasmuch as they did the Lord did have mercy
on them
9 And it came to pass that Shiblom was slain, and
Seth was brought into captivity, and did dwell in
captivity all his days
10 And it came to pass that Ahah, his son, did
obtain the kingdom; and he did reign over the people
all his days. And he did do all manner of iniquity
in his days, by which he did cause the shedding
of much blood; and few were his days
11 And Ethem, being a descendant of Ahah, did
obtain the kingdom; and he also did do that which was
wicked in his days
12 And it came to pass that in the days of Ethem
there came many prophets, and prophesied again unto
the people; yea, they did prophesy that the Lord
would utterly destroy them from off the face of
the earth except they repented of their iniquities
13 And it came to pass that the people hardened
their hearts, and would not hearken unto their
words; and the prophets mourned and withdrew from among
the people
14 And it came to pass that Ethem did execute
judgment in wickedness all his days; and he begat
Moron. And it came to pass that Moron did reign in his
stead; and Moron did that which was wicked before
the Lord
15 And it came to pass that there arose a
rebellion among the people, because of that secret
combination which was built up to get power and gain; and
there arose a mighty man among them in iniquity,
and gave battle unto Moron, in which he did
overthrow the half of the kingdom; and he did maintain
the half of the kingdom for many years
16 And it came to pass that Moron did overthrow
him, and did obtain the kingdom again
17 And it came to pass that there arose another
mighty man; and he was a descendant of the brother
of Jared
18 And it came to pass that he did overthrow Moron
and obtain the kingdom; wherefore, Moron dwelt in
captivity all the remainder of his days; and he
begat Coriantor
19 And it came to pass that Coriantor dwelt in
captivity all his days
20 And in the days of Coriantor there also came
many prophets, and prophesied of great and marvelous
things, and cried repentance unto the people, and
except they should repent the Lord God would
execute judgment against them to their utter
destruction
21 And that the Lord God would send or bring forth
another people to possess the land, by his power,
after the manner by which he brought their
fathers
22 And they did reject all the words of the
prophets, because of their secret society and wicked
abominations
23 And it came to pass that Coriantor begat Ether,
and he died, having dwelt in captivity all his
days.