Chapter 3 The brother of Jared sees the finger
of the Lord as He touches sixteen
stones—Christ shows His spirit body to the brother of
Jared—Those who have a perfect knowledge cannot
be kept from within the veil—Interpreters are
provided to bring the Jaredite record to light.
1 And it came to pass that the brother of
Jared, (now the number of the vessels
which had been prepared was eight) went forth
unto the mount, which they called the
mount Shelem, because of its exceeding height,
and did molten out of a rock sixteen
small stones; and they were white and clear,
even as transparent glass; and he did carry
them in his hands upon the top of the
mount, and cried again unto the Lord, saying:
2 O Lord, thou hast said that we must
be encompassed about by the floods.
Now behold, O Lord, and do not be angry
with thy servant because of his
weakness before thee; for we know that thou
art holy and dwellest in the heavens,
and that we are unworthy before thee;
because of the fall our natures have
become evil continually; nevertheless,
O Lord, thou hast given us a
commandment that we must call upon thee, that
from thee we may receive according to our desires.
3 Behold, O Lord, thou hast smitten
us because of our iniquity, and hast
driven us forth, and for these many
years we have been in the wilderness;
nevertheless, thou hast been merciful
unto us. O Lord, look upon me in
pity, and turn away thine anger from this
thy people, and suffer not that they
shall go forth across this raging
deep in darkness; but behold these
things which I have molten out of the rock.
4 And I know, O Lord, that thou
hast all power, and can do
whatsoever thou wilt for the benefit of
man; therefore touch these stones, O
Lord, with thy finger, and prepare
them that they may shine forth in
darkness; and they shall shine
forth unto us in the vessels which
we have prepared, that we may have
light while we shall cross the sea.
5 Behold, O Lord, thou canst
do this. We know that thou
art able to show forth great
power, which looks small
unto the understanding of men.
6 And it came to pass that
when the brother of Jared
had said these words,
behold, the Lord stretched forth
his hand and touched the
stones one by one with his
finger. And the veil was
taken from off the eyes of the
brother of Jared, and he
saw the finger of the Lord;
and it was as the finger of
a man, like unto flesh and
blood; and the brother of
Jared fell down before the
Lord, for he was struck with fear.
7 And the Lord saw that
the brother of Jared had
fallen to the earth; and
the Lord said unto him:
Arise, why hast thou fallen?
8 And he saith unto the
Lord: I saw the finger
of the Lord, and I feared
lest he should smite
me; for I knew not that
the Lord had flesh and blood.
9 And the Lord said
unto him: Because of thy
faith thou hast seen
that I shall take upon me
flesh and blood; and
never has man come before
me with such exceeding
faith as thou hast;
for were it not so ye
could not have seen my
finger. Sawest thou more than this?
10 And he
answered: Nay; Lord,
show thyself unto me.
11 And the Lord
said unto him:
Believest thou
the words
which I shall speak?
12 And he
answered: Yea,
Lord, I know that
thou speakest
the truth,
for thou art a
God of truth,
and canst not lie.
13 And when
he had said
these words,
behold, the
Lord showed
himself unto him,
and said:
Because thou
knowest these
things ye are
redeemed from
the fall;
therefore ye
are brought
back into my
presence;
therefore I show myself unto you.
14 Behold, I
am he who
was prepared
from the
foundation of
the world to
redeem my
people.
Behold, I am Jesus
Christ. I
am the Father
and the
Son. In me
shall all
mankind have life,
and that
eternally,
even they who
shall believe
on my name;
and they
shall become
my sons and my daughters.
15 And
never have I
showed myself
unto man
whom I have
created,
for never has
man
believed in me as
thou hast.
Seest thou
that ye
are created
after mine
own image?
Yea, even
all men were
created in
the
beginning after mine own image.
16 Behold,
this
body, which ye
now
behold, is the
body of my
spirit;
and man
have I
created after
the body of
my spirit;
and even
as I
appear unto
thee to be in
the
spirit will I
appear unto
my people in the flesh.
17 And
now, as I,
Moroni,
said I
could not
make a full
account
of these
things
which are
written,
therefore
it
sufficeth me to
say that
Jesus
showed
himself unto
this man
in the
spirit,
even after
the manner
and in
the
likeness of the
same
body even as
he showed himself unto the Nephites.
18 And
he
ministered
unto him
even as he
ministered unto
the
Nephites;
and all
this,
that this
man might
know
that he
was God,
because
of the
many great
works
which the
Lord had showed unto him.
19 And
because
of the
knowledge of
this
man he
could not
be
kept from
beholding
within the
veil;
and he
saw the
finger
of
Jesus,
which, when
he
saw, he
fell with
fear;
for he
knew
that it
was the
finger
of the
Lord;
and he
had
faith no
longer, for he knew, nothing doubting.
Wherefore,
having
this
perfect
knowledge of
God, he
could
not
be kept
from
within
the
veil;
therefore he
saw
Jesus;
and he
did minister unto him.
And it
came
to
pass
that
the
Lord
said
unto the
brother
of
Jared:
Behold,
thou
shalt
not
suffer
these
things
which ye
have
seen
and
heard
to
go
forth
unto
the
world,
until
the
time
cometh
that
I
shall
glorify my
name
in
the
flesh;
wherefore,
ye
shall
treasure up
the
things which ye have seen and heard, and show it to no man.
And
behold,
when
ye
shall
come
unto
me,
ye
shall
write
them
and
shall
seal
them
up,
that
no
one
can
interpret
them;
for
ye
shall
write
them
in a language that they cannot be read.
And
behold,
these
two
stones
will
I
give
unto
thee,
and
ye
shall
seal
them
up
also
with
the things which ye shall write.
For
behold,
the
language
which
ye
shall
write
I
have
confounded;
wherefore
I
will
cause
in
my
own
due
time
that
these
stones
shall
magnify
to
the
eyes
of
men
these
things
which
ye
shall
write.
And
when
the
Lord
had
said
these
words,
he
showed
unto
the
brother
of
Jared
all
the
inhabitants
of
the
earth
which
had
been,
and
also
all
that
would
be; and he withheld them not from his sight, even unto the ends of the earth.
For
he
had
said
unto
him
in
times
before,
that
if
he
would
believe
in
him
that
he
could
show
unto
him
all
things—it
should
be
shown
unto
him;
therefore
the
Lord
could
not
withhold
anything
from
him,
for
he
knew
that
the
Lord
could
show
him
all
things.
27 And the Lord said unto him: Write these things and seal them up; and I will show them in mine own due time unto the children of
And
the
Lord
said
unto
him:
Write
these
things
and
seal
them
up;
and I will show them in mine own due time unto the children of men.
28 And it came to pass that the Lord commanded him that he should seal up the two stones which he had received, and show them not, until the Lord should show them unto the children of men.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
Lord
commanded
him
that
he
should
seal
up
the
two
stones
which
he
had
received,
and
show
them
not,
until
the
Lord
should
show
them
unto
the
children
of
men.