Chapter 10 One king succeeds another—Some
of the kings are righteous; others are
wicked—When righteousness prevails, the
people are blessed and prospered by the Lord.
1 And it came to pass that Shez, who
was a descendant of Heth—for Heth had
perished by the famine, and all his
household save it were Shez—wherefore, Shez
began to build up again a broken people.
2 And it came to pass that Shez did
remember the destruction of his
fathers, and he did build up a
righteous kingdom; for he remembered what
the Lord had done in bringing
Jared and his brother across the deep;
and he did walk in the ways of the
Lord; and he begat sons and daughters.
3 And his eldest son, whose name
was Shez, did rebel against
him; nevertheless, Shez was smitten
by the hand of a robber,
because of his exceeding riches, which
brought peace again unto his father.
4 And it came to pass that his
father did build up many
cities upon the face of the land,
and the people began again to
spread over all the face of
the land. And Shez did live to
an exceedingly old age; and he
begat Riplakish. And he died,
and Riplakish reigned in his stead.
5 And it came to pass that
Riplakish did not do that
which was right in the sight
of the Lord, for he did
have many wives and
concubines, and did lay that upon
men’s shoulders which was
grievous to be borne; yea, he
did tax them with heavy
taxes; and with the taxes he
did build many spacious buildings.
6 And he did erect him an
exceedingly beautiful
throne; and he did build many
prisons, and whoso would
not be subject unto taxes
he did cast into prison;
and whoso was not able to
pay taxes he did cast into
prison; and he did cause
that they should labor
continually for their support;
and whoso refused to labor
he did cause to be put to death.
7 Wherefore he did
obtain all his fine work,
yea, even his fine gold he
did cause to be refined
in prison; and all
manner of fine workmanship he
did cause to be wrought
in prison. And it came
to pass that he did
afflict the people with his
whoredoms and abominations.
8 And when he had
reigned for the space of
forty and two years
the people did rise
up in rebellion
against him; and there
began to be war again in
the land, insomuch
that Riplakish was
killed, and his
descendants were driven out of the land.
9 And it came to
pass after the space of
many years,
Morianton, (he being a
descendant of Riplakish)
gathered together
an army of outcasts,
and went forth and
gave battle unto the
people; and he
gained power over many
cities; and the war
became exceedingly
sore, and did last for
the space of many
years; and he did gain
power over all the
land, and did
establish himself king over all the land.
10 And after that
he had established
himself king he
did ease the burden
of the people, by
which he did gain
favor in the eyes
of the people,
and they did anoint
him to be their king.
11 And he did do
justice unto
the people, but
not unto himself
because of his
many whoredoms;
wherefore he was
cut off from the
presence of the Lord.
12 And it came
to pass that
Morianton built
up many cities,
and the people
became
exceedingly rich under
his reign, both
in buildings,
and in gold and
silver, and in
raising grain,
and in flocks,
and herds, and
such things
which had been
restored unto them.
13 And
Morianton did live to
an
exceedingly great age,
and then he
begat Kim; and
Kim did reign in
the stead of
his father;
and he did reign
eight years,
and his father
died. And it
came to pass
that Kim did
not reign in
righteousness,
wherefore he was
not favored of the Lord.
14 And his
brother did
rise up in
rebellion against
him, by which
he did bring
him into
captivity; and
he did remain
in captivity
all his days;
and he begat
sons and
daughters in
captivity, and
in his old age
he begat Levi; and he died.
15 And it
came to pass
that Levi did
serve in
captivity
after the death
of his
father, for the
space of
forty and two
years. And he
did make war
against the
king of the
land, by
which he did
obtain unto
himself the kingdom.
16 And
after he had
obtained unto
himself
the kingdom
he did that
which was
right in the
sight of
the Lord;
and the
people did
prosper in the
land; and he
did live
to a good
old age, and
begat sons
and
daughters; and he
also begat
Corom, whom
he anointed king in his stead.
17 And it
came to pass
that Corom
did that
which was
good in the
sight of the
Lord all
his days;
and he begat
many sons
and
daughters; and
after he had
seen many
days he did
pass away,
even like
unto the rest
of the
earth; and Kish
reigned in
his stead.
18 And it
came to
pass that
Kish passed
away also,
and Lib
reigned in
his stead.
19 And it
came to
pass that
Lib also
did that
which
was good in
the
sight of the
Lord. And
in the
days of
Lib the
poisonous
serpents
were
destroyed.
Wherefore
they did go
into the
land
southward, to
hunt
food for the
people
of the
land, for
the land
was covered
with
animals of
the
forest. And Lib
also himself became a great hunter.
20 And
they
built a
great city
by the
narrow
neck of
land, by
the place
where
the sea
divides the land.
21 And
they
did
preserve the
land
southward for a
wilderness,
to get
game.
And the
whole
face of
the land
northward was
covered with inhabitants.
22 And
they
were
exceedingly
industrious,
and
they did
buy
and
sell and
traffic one
with
another, that
they might get gain.
And
they did
work
in
all
manner
of
ore,
and
they did
make
gold, and
silver,
and
iron,
brass,
and
all
manner
of
metals;
and
they
did
dig it
out
of
the
earth;
wherefore,
they
did
cast
up
mighty
heaps
of
earth
to get
ore,
of
gold,
and
of
silver,
and
of
iron,
and of copper. And they did work all manner of fine work.
And
they did
have
silks,
and
fine-twined
linen;
and
they
did
work
all
manner
of
cloth,
that
they
might
clothe
themselves
from
their
nakedness.
And
they
did
make
all
manner
of
tools
to
till
the
earth,
both
to
plow
and
to
sow,
reap
and
to hoe, and also to thrash.
And
they
did
make
all
manner
of
tools
with
which
they
did work their beasts.
And
they
did
make
all
manner
of
weapons
war.
And
they
did
work
all
manner
of
work
exceedingly
curious
workmanship.
And
never
could
be
a
people
more
blessed
than
were
they,
and
more
prospered
by
the
hand
of
the
Lord.
And
they
were
in
a
land that was choice above all lands, for the Lord had spoken it.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Lib
did
live
many
years,
and
begat
sons
and
daughters;
he
also
begat
Hearthom.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Hearthom
reigned
in
the
stead
of
his
father.
And
when
Hearthom
had
reigned
twenty
and
four
years,
behold,
the
kingdom
was
taken
away
from
him.
And
he
served
many
years
in
captivity,
yea,
even
all
the
remainder
of
his
days.
31 And he begat Heth, and Heth lived in captivity all his days. And Heth begat Aaron, and Aaron dwelt in captivity all his days; and he begat Amnigaddah, and Amnigaddah also dwelt in captivity all his days; and he begat Coriantum, and Coriantum dwelt in captivity all his days; and he begat
And
he
begat
Heth,
and
Heth
lived
in
captivity
all
his
days.
And
Heth
begat
Aaron,
and
Aaron
dwelt
in
captivity
all
his
days;
and
he
begat
Amnigaddah, and Amnigaddah also dwelt in captivity all his days; and he begat Coriantum, and Coriantum dwelt in captivity all his days; and he begat Com.
32 And it came to pass that Com drew away the half of the kingdom. And he reigned over the half of the kingdom forty and two years; and he went to battle against the king, Amgid, and they fought for the space of many years, during which time Com gained power over Amgid, and obtained power over the remainder of the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Com
drew
away
the
half
of
the
kingdom.
And
he
reigned
over
the
half
of
the
kingdom
forty
and
two
years;
and
he
went
to
battle
against
the
king,
Amgid,
and
they
fought
for
the
space
of
many
years,
during
which
time
Com
gained
power
over
Amgid,
and
obtained
power
over
the
remainder
of
the
kingdom.
33 And in the days of Com there began to be robbers in the land; and they adopted the old plans, and administered oaths after the manner of the ancients, and sought again to destroy the
And
in
the
days
of
Com
there
began
to
be
robbers
in
the
land;
and
they
adopted
the
old
plans,
and
administered
oaths
after
the
manner
of
the
ancients,
and
sought
again
to
destroy
the
kingdom.
34 Now Com did fight against them much; nevertheless, he did not prevail against them.
Now
Com
did
fight
against
them
much;
nevertheless,
he
did
not
prevail
against
them.