Chapter 13 Ether speaks of a New Jerusalem
to be built in America by the seed of
Joseph—He prophesies, is cast out, writes the
Jaredite history, and foretells the destruction
of the Jaredites—War rages over all the land.
1 And now I, Moroni, proceed to finish
my record concerning the destruction of
the people of whom I have been writing.
2 For behold, they rejected all the
words of Ether; for he truly told
them of all things, from the
beginning of man; and that after the
waters had receded from off the face of
this land it became a choice land
above all other lands, a chosen
land of the Lord; wherefore the Lord
would have that all men should serve
him who dwell upon the face thereof;
3 And that it was the place of
the New Jerusalem, which
should come down out of heaven,
and the holy sanctuary of the Lord.
4 Behold, Ether saw the
days of Christ, and he
spake concerning a New
Jerusalem upon this land.
5 And he spake also
concerning the house of
Israel, and the
Jerusalem from whence Lehi
should come—after it
should be destroyed it
should be built up
again, a holy city unto
the Lord; wherefore, it
could not be a new
Jerusalem for it had been
in a time of old; but
it should be built up
again, and become a
holy city of the Lord;
and it should be built
unto the house of Israel—
6 And that a New
Jerusalem should be
built up upon this
land, unto the remnant
of the seed of
Joseph, for which things
there has been a type.
7 For as Joseph
brought his father
down into the land of
Egypt, even so he
died there;
wherefore, the Lord brought
a remnant of the
seed of Joseph out
of the land of
Jerusalem, that he might
be merciful unto
the seed of Joseph
that they should
perish not, even as he
was merciful unto
the father of
Joseph that he should perish not.
8 Wherefore, the
remnant of the
house of Joseph shall
be built upon this
land; and it
shall be a land of
their inheritance;
and they shall build
up a holy city
unto the Lord, like
unto the Jerusalem
of old; and they
shall no more be
confounded, until
the end come when
the earth shall pass away.
9 And there
shall be a new
heaven and a new
earth; and they
shall be like unto
the old save the
old have passed
away, and all
things have become new.
10 And then
cometh the New
Jerusalem; and
blessed are they
who dwell
therein, for it is
they whose
garments are white
through the blood
of the Lamb;
and they are
they who are
numbered among the
remnant of the
seed of Joseph,
who were of the
house of Israel.
11 And then
also cometh the
Jerusalem of
old; and the
inhabitants
thereof, blessed
are they, for
they have been
washed in the
blood of the
Lamb; and they
are they who
were scattered
and gathered
in from the
four quarters of
the earth, and
from the
north countries,
and are
partakers of the
fulfilling of the
covenant which
God made with their father, Abraham.
12 And when
these things
come, bringeth
to pass the
scripture
which saith,
there are they
who were
first, who shall
be last; and
there are they
who were
last, who shall be first.
13 And I was
about to
write more,
but I am
forbidden; but
great and
marvelous were
the
prophecies of Ether;
but they
esteemed him as
naught, and
cast him
out; and he
hid himself in
the cavity
of a rock by
day, and by
night he
went forth
viewing the
things which
should come upon the people.
14 And as
he dwelt in
the cavity
of a rock
he made the
remainder
of this
record, viewing
the
destructions
which came upon
the people, by night.
15 And it
came to
pass that in
that same
year in
which he
was cast out
from
among the
people there
began to be
a great
war among
the people,
for there
were many
who rose
up, who
were mighty
men, and
sought to
destroy
Coriantumr by
their
secret plans
of
wickedness, of which hath been spoken.
16 And
now
Coriantumr,
having
studied,
himself, in all
the arts
of war
and all
the cunning
of the
world,
wherefore he
gave
battle unto
them who
sought to destroy him.
17 But
he
repented not,
neither
his fair
sons
nor
daughters;
neither the
fair
sons and
daughters
of
Cohor;
neither the
fair sons
and
daughters
of
Corihor; and
in fine,
there
were none
of the
fair sons
and
daughters
upon the
face of
the
whole earth who repented of their sins.
Wherefore,
it came
to
pass that
in the
first
year
that Ether
dwelt
in the
cavity
of a
rock,
there were
many
people
who were
slain
by the
sword
of those
secret
combinations,
fighting
against
Coriantumr
that they might obtain the kingdom.
19 And
it came
to
pass that
the
sons of
Coriantumr
fought much
and
bled much.
20 And
in
the
second
year the
word
of the
Lord
came to
Ether, that
he
should
go and
prophesy
unto
Coriantumr
that,
if he
would
repent, and
all
his
household, the
Lord
would
give
unto him
his kingdom and spare the people—
Otherwise
they
should
be
destroyed,
and
all his
household
save
it
were
himself.
And he
should
only
live to
see
the
fulfilling
of the
prophecies
which
had
been
spoken
concerning
another
people
receiving
the
land
for
their
inheritance; and
Coriantumr
should
receive a
burial
by
them;
and every soul should be destroyed save it were Coriantumr.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Coriantumr
repented
not,
neither
his
household,
neither
the
people;
and
the
wars
ceased
not;
and
they
sought
to
kill
Ether,
but
he
fled
from
before
them and hid again in the cavity of the rock.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
there
arose
up
Shared,
and
he
also
gave
battle
unto
Coriantumr;
and
he
did
beat
him,
insomuch
that
in
the third year he did bring him into captivity.
And
the
sons
of
Coriantumr,
in
the
fourth
year,
did
beat
Shared,
and
did
obtain the kingdom again unto their father.
25 Now there began to be a war upon all the face of the land, every man with his band fighting for that which he
Now
there
began
to
be
a
war
upon
all
the
face
of
the
land, every man with his band fighting for that which he desired.
26 And there were robbers, and in fine, all manner of wickedness upon all the face of the
And
there
were
robbers,
and
in
fine,
all
manner
of
wickedness
upon
all
the
face
of
the
land.
27 And it came to pass that Coriantumr was exceedingly angry with Shared, and he went against him with his armies to battle; and they did meet in great anger, and they did meet in the valley of Gilgal; and the battle became exceedingly
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Coriantumr
was
exceedingly
angry
with
Shared,
and
he
went
against
him
with
his
armies
to
battle;
and
they
did
meet
in
great
anger,
and
they
did
meet
in
the
valley
of
Gilgal;
and
the
battle
became
exceedingly
sore.
28 And it came to pass that Shared fought against him for the space of three days. And it came to pass that Coriantumr beat him, and did pursue him until he came to the plains of
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Shared
fought
against
him
for
the
space
of
three
days.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Coriantumr
beat
him,
and
did
pursue
him
until
he
came
to
the
plains
of
Heshlon.
29 And it came to pass that Shared gave him battle again upon the plains; and behold, he did beat Coriantumr, and drove him back again to the valley of
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Shared
gave
him
battle
again
upon
the
plains;
and
behold,
he
did
beat
Coriantumr,
and
drove
him
back
again
to
the
valley
of
Gilgal.
30 And Coriantumr gave Shared battle again in the valley of Gilgal, in which he beat Shared and slew
And
Coriantumr
gave
Shared
battle
again
in
the
valley
of
Gilgal,
in
which
he
beat
Shared
and
slew
him.
31 And Shared wounded Coriantumr in his thigh, that he did not go to battle again for the space of two years, in which time all the people upon the face of the land were shedding blood, and there was none to restrain them.
And
Shared
wounded
Coriantumr
in
his
thigh,
that
battle
again
for
the
space
of
two
years,
in
which
time
all
the
people
upon
the
face
of
the
land
were
shedding
blood,
and
there
was
none
to
restrain
them.