Chapter 6 The Jaredite barges are driven by the
winds to the promised land—The people praise the
Lord for His goodness—Orihah is appointed king over
them—Jared and his brother die.
1 And now I, Moroni, proceed to give the record of
Jared and his brother
2 For it came to pass after the Lord had prepared
the stones which the brother of Jared had carried
up into the mount, the brother of Jared came down
out of the mount, and he did put forth the stones
into the vessels which were prepared, one in each
end thereof; and behold, they did give light unto
the vessels
3 And thus the Lord caused stones to shine in
darkness, to give light unto men, women, and children,
that they might not cross the great waters in
darkness
4 And it came to pass that when they had prepared
all manner of food, that thereby they might
subsist upon the water, and also food for their flocks
and herds, and whatsoever beast or animal or fowl
that they should carry with them—and it came to
pass that when they had done all these things they
got aboard of their vessels or barges, and set forth
into the sea, commending themselves unto the Lord
their God
5 And it came to pass that the Lord God caused
that there should be a furious wind blow upon the
face of the waters, towards the promised land; and
thus they were tossed upon the waves of the sea
before the wind
6 And it came to pass that they were many times
buried in the depths of the sea, because of the
mountain waves which broke upon them, and also the
great and terrible tempests which were caused by the
fierceness of the wind
7 And it came to pass that when they were buried
in the deep there was no water that could hurt
them, their vessels being tight like unto a dish, and
also they were tight like unto the ark of Noah;
therefore when they were encompassed about by many
waters they did cry unto the Lord, and he did bring
them forth again upon the top of the waters
8 And it came to pass that the wind did never
cease to blow towards the promised land while they
were upon the waters; and thus they were driven forth
before the wind
9 And they did sing praises unto the Lord; yea,
the brother of Jared did sing praises unto the Lord,
and he did thank and praise the Lord all the day
long; and when the night came, they did not cease
to praise the Lord
10 And thus they were driven forth; and no monster
of the sea could break them, neither whale that
could mar them; and they did have light
continually, whether it was above the water or under the
water
11 And thus they were driven forth, three hundred
and forty and four days upon the water
12 And they did land upon the shore of the
promised land. And when they had set their feet upon the
shores of the promised land they bowed themselves
down upon the face of the land, and did humble
themselves before the Lord, and did shed tears of joy
before the Lord, because of the multitude of his
tender mercies over them
13 And it came to pass that they went forth upon
the face of the land, and began to till the earth
14 And Jared had four sons; and they were called
Jacom, and Gilgah, and Mahah, and Orihah
15 And the brother of Jared also begat sons and
daughters
16 And the friends of Jared and his brother were
in number about twenty and two souls; and they also
begat sons and daughters before they came to the
promised land; and therefore they began to be
many
17 And they were taught to walk humbly before the
Lord; and they were also taught from on high
18 And it came to pass that they began to spread
upon the face of the land, and to multiply and to
till the earth; and they did wax strong in the
land
19 And the brother of Jared began to be old, and
saw that he must soon go down to the grave;
wherefore he said unto Jared: Let us gather together our
people that we may number them, that we may know
of them what they will desire of us before we go
down to our graves
20 And accordingly the people were gathered
together. Now the number of the sons and the daughters
of the brother of Jared were twenty and two souls;
and the number of sons and daughters of Jared were
twelve, he having four sons
21 And it came to pass that they did number their
people; and after that they had numbered them,
they did desire of them the things which they would
that they should do before they went down to their
graves
22 And it came to pass that the people desired of
them that they should anoint one of their sons to
be a king over them
23 And now behold, this was grievous unto them.
And the brother of Jared said unto them: Surely this
thing leadeth into captivity
24 But Jared said unto his brother: Suffer them
that they may have a king. And therefore he said
unto them: Choose ye out from among our sons a king,
even whom ye will
25 And it came to pass that they chose even the
firstborn of the brother of Jared; and his name was
Pagag. And it came to pass that he refused and
would not be their king. And the people would that
his father should constrain him, but his father
would not; and he commanded them that they should
constrain no man to be their king
26 And it came to pass that they chose all the
brothers of Pagag, and they would not
27 And it came to pass that neither would the sons
of Jared, even all save it were one; and Orihah
was anointed to be king over the people
28 And he began to reign, and the people began to
prosper; and they became exceedingly rich
29 And it came to pass that Jared died, and his
brother also
30 And it came to pass that Orihah did walk humbly
before the Lord, and did remember how great
things the Lord had done for his father, and also
taught his people how great things the Lord had done
for their fathers.