Chapter 5 Three witnesses and the work
itself will stand as a testimony of
the truthfulness of the Book of Mormon.
1 And now I, Moroni, have written
the words which were commanded me,
according to my memory; and I have
told you the things which I have
sealed up; therefore touch them not in
order that ye may translate; for
that thing is forbidden you, except
by and by it shall be wisdom in God.
2 And behold, ye may be
privileged that ye may show the
plates unto those who shall
assist to bring forth this work;
3 And unto three shall
they be shown by the
power of God; wherefore they
shall know of a surety
that these things are true.
4 And in the mouth of
three witnesses shall
these things be
established; and the testimony
of three, and this work,
in the which shall be
shown forth the power
of God and also his
word, of which the Father,
and the Son, and the
Holy Ghost bear
record—and all this shall stand
as a testimony against
the world at the last day.
5 And if it so be
that they repent and
come unto the Father in
the name of Jesus,
they shall be received
into the kingdom of God.
6 And now, if I
have no authority for
these things, judge
ye; for ye shall
know that I have
authority when ye
shall see me, and we
shall stand before
God at the last day. Amen.