Chapter 8 There is strife and contention over
the kingdom—Akish forms an oath-bound secret
combination to slay the king—Secret combinations
are of the devil and result in the destruction
of nations—Modern Gentiles are warned against
the secret combination that will seek to
overthrow the freedom of all lands, nations, and countries.
1 And it came to pass that he begat Omer,
and Omer reigned in his stead. And Omer
begat Jared; and Jared begat sons and daughters.
2 And Jared rebelled against his father,
and came and dwelt in the land of Heth.
And it came to pass that he did flatter
many people, because of his cunning words,
until he had gained the half of the kingdom.
3 And when he had gained the half
of the kingdom he gave battle
unto his father, and he did carry
away his father into captivity,
and did make him serve in captivity;
4 And now, in the days of the
reign of Omer he was in
captivity the half of his days.
And it came to pass that he
begat sons and daughters, among
whom were Esrom and Coriantumr;
5 And they were
exceedingly angry because of the
doings of Jared their
brother, insomuch that they did
raise an army and gave
battle unto Jared. And it came
to pass that they did
give battle unto him by night.
6 And it came to pass
that when they had slain the
army of Jared they were
about to slay him also;
and he pled with them that
they would not slay him,
and he would give up the
kingdom unto his father.
And it came to pass that
they did grant unto him his life.
7 And now Jared became
exceedingly sorrowful
because of the loss
of the kingdom, for he
had set his heart upon
the kingdom and upon
the glory of the world.
8 Now the daughter of
Jared being
exceedingly expert, and
seeing the sorrows of her
father, thought to
devise a plan whereby
she could redeem the
kingdom unto her father.
9 Now the daughter
of Jared was
exceedingly fair. And it
came to pass that she
did talk with her
father, and said unto
him: Whereby hath my
father so much
sorrow? Hath he not read
the record which our
fathers brought
across the great deep?
Behold, is there not
an account
concerning them of old, that
they by their
secret plans did obtain
kingdoms and great glory?
10 And now,
therefore, let my father
send for Akish, the
son of Kimnor; and
behold, I am fair,
and I will dance
before him, and I
will please him, that
he will desire me
to wife; wherefore
if he shall desire
of thee that ye
shall give unto him me
to wife, then shall
ye say: I will
give her if ye will
bring unto me the
head of my father, the king.
11 And now Omer
was a friend to
Akish; wherefore,
when Jared had
sent for Akish, the
daughter of Jared
danced before
him that she
pleased him, insomuch
that he desired
her to wife. And it
came to pass
that he said unto
Jared: Give her unto me to wife.
12 And Jared
said unto him: I
will give her
unto you, if ye
will bring unto
me the head of
my father, the king.
13 And it came
to pass that
Akish gathered
in unto the
house of Jared
all his
kinsfolk, and said
unto them: Will
ye swear unto
me that ye
will be faithful
unto me in
the thing which
I shall desire of you?
14 And it
came to pass
that they all
sware unto him,
by the God
of heaven, and
also by the
heavens, and
earth, and by
their heads,
that whoso
should vary
from the
assistance which
Akish desired
should lose his
head; and
whoso should
divulge
whatsoever thing
Akish made known
unto them,
the same should lose his life.
15 And it
came to pass
that thus
they did agree
with Akish.
And Akish
did administer
unto them
the oaths
which were
given by them of
old who
also sought
power, which
had been
handed down even
from Cain,
who was a
murderer from the beginning.
16 And they
were kept
up by the
power of the
devil to
administer
these oaths
unto the
people, to
keep them in
darkness,
to help such
as sought
power to
gain power,
and to
murder, and to
plunder, and
to lie,
and to commit
all manner
of wickedness and whoredoms.
17 And it
was the
daughter of
Jared who
put it
into his
heart to
search up these
things of
old; and
Jared put
it into
the heart of
Akish;
wherefore,
Akish
administered it
unto his
kindred
and friends,
leading
them away
by fair
promises to
do whatsoever thing he desired.
18 And it
came to
pass that
they
formed a
secret
combination,
even as
they of
old; which
combination is most
abominable and
wicked
above all, in
the sight of God;
19 For
the Lord
worketh
not in
secret
combinations,
neither doth
he will
that
man should
shed
blood, but
in all
things
hath
forbidden
it, from
the beginning of man.
20 And
now I,
Moroni,
do not
write
the
manner of
their
oaths
and
combinations, for
it hath
been
made
known unto
me that
they
are had
among
all
people, and
they
are had among the Lamanites.
21 And
they
have
caused
the
destruction of
this
people
of
whom I
am now
speaking,
and also
the
destruction
of the people of Nephi.
22 And
whatsoever
nation
shall
uphold such
secret
combinations, to
get
power
and
gain,
until
they
shall
spread
over the
nation,
behold,
they
shall be
destroyed;
for the
Lord
will
not
suffer
that the
blood
of
his
saints,
which
shall be
shed
by
them,
shall
always
cry unto
him
from
the
ground for
vengeance
upon
them and
yet
he
avenge
them not.
Wherefore, O
ye
Gentiles,
it is
wisdom in
God
that
these
things
should
be
shown
unto
you,
that
thereby
ye
may
repent
of
your
sins,
and
suffer
not
that
these
murderous
combinations
shall
get
above
you,
which
are
built
up to
get
power
and
gain—and
the
work,
yea,
even
the
work of
destruction
come
upon
you,
yea,
even
the
sword of
justice of
the
Eternal
God
shall
fall
upon you, to your overthrow and destruction if ye shall suffer these things to be.
Wherefore,
the
Lord
commandeth
you,
when
ye
shall
see
these
things
come
among
you
that ye
shall
awake
to
a
sense
of
your
awful
situation,
because
of
this
secret
combination
which
shall
be
among
you; or
wo
be
unto
it,
because
of
the
blood
of
them
who
have
been
slain;
for
they
cry
from the dust for vengeance upon it, and also upon those who built it up.
For
it
cometh
to
pass
that
whoso
buildeth
it
up
seeketh
to
overthrow
the
freedom
of
all
lands,
nations,
and
countries;
it
bringeth
to
pass
the
destruction
of
all
people,
for
it
is
built
up
by
the
devil,
who
is
the
father
of
all
lies;
even
that
same
liar
who
beguiled
our
first
parents,
yea,
even
that
same
liar
who
hath
caused
man
to
commit
murder
from
the
beginning;
who hath hardened the hearts of men that they have murdered the prophets, and stoned them, and cast them out from the beginning.
Wherefore,
I,
Moroni,
am
commanded
to
write
these
things
that
evil
may
be
done
away,
and
that
the
time
may
come
that
Satan
may
have
no
power
upon
the
hearts
of
the
children
of
men,
but
that
they
may
be
persuaded to do good continually, that they may come unto the fountain of all righteousness and be saved.