The Book of Ether The record of the Jaredites,
taken from the twenty-four plates found by the people
of Limhi in the days of King Mosiah.Chapter 1
Moroni abridges the writings of Ether—Ether’s
genealogy is set forth—The language of the Jaredites is
not confounded at the Tower of Babel—The Lord
promises to lead them to a choice land and make them a
great nation.
1 And now I, Moroni, proceed to give an account of
those ancient inhabitants who were destroyed by
the hand of the Lord upon the face of this north
country
2 And I take mine account from the twenty and four
plates which were found by the people of Limhi,
which is called the Book of Ether
3 And as I suppose that the first part of this
record, which speaks concerning the creation of the
world, and also of Adam, and an account from that
time even to the great tower, and whatsoever things
transpired among the children of men until that
time, is had among the Jews
4 Therefore I do not write those things which
transpired from the days of Adam until that time; but
they are had upon the plates; and whoso findeth
them, the same will have power that he may get the
full account
5 But behold, I give not the full account, but a
part of the account I give, from the tower down
until they were destroyed
6 And on this wise do I give the account. He that
wrote this record was Ether, and he was a
descendant of Coriantor
7 Coriantor was the son of Moron
8 And Moron was the son of Ethem
9 And Ethem was the son of Ahah
10 And Ahah was the son of Seth
11 And Seth was the son of Shiblon
12 And Shiblon was the son of Com
13 And Com was the son of Coriantum
14 And Coriantum was the son of Amnigaddah
15 And Amnigaddah was the son of Aaron
16 And Aaron was a descendant of Heth, who was the
son of Hearthom
17 And Hearthom was the son of Lib
18 And Lib was the son of Kish
19 And Kish was the son of Corom
20 And Corom was the son of Levi
21 And Levi was the son of Kim
22 And Kim was the son of Morianton
23 And Morianton was a descendant of Riplakish
24 And Riplakish was the son of Shez
25 And Shez was the son of Heth
26 And Heth was the son of Com
27 And Com was the son of Coriantum
28 And Coriantum was the son of Emer
29 And Emer was the son of Omer
30 And Omer was the son of Shule
31 And Shule was the son of Kib
32 And Kib was the son of Orihah, who was the son
of Jared
33 Which Jared came forth with his brother and
their families, with some others and their families,
from the great tower, at the time the Lord
confounded the language of the people, and swore in his
wrath that they should be scattered upon all the
face of the earth; and according to the word of the
Lord the people were scattered
34 And the brother of Jared being a large and
mighty man, and a man highly favored of the Lord,
Jared, his brother, said unto him: Cry unto the Lord,
that he will not confound us that we may not
understand our words
35 And it came to pass that the brother of Jared
did cry unto the Lord, and the Lord had compassion
upon Jared; therefore he did not confound the
language of Jared; and Jared and his brother were not
confounded
36 Then Jared said unto his brother: Cry again
unto the Lord, and it may be that he will turn away
his anger from them who are our friends, that he
confound not their language
37 And it came to pass that the brother of Jared
did cry unto the Lord, and the Lord had compassion
upon their friends and their families also, that
they were not confounded
38 And it came to pass that Jared spake again unto
his brother, saying: Go and inquire of the Lord
whether he will drive us out of the land, and if he
will drive us out of the land, cry unto him
whither we shall go. And who knoweth but the Lord will
carry us forth into a land which is choice above
all the earth? And if it so be, let us be faithful
unto the Lord, that we may receive it for our
inheritance
39 And it came to pass that the brother of Jared
did cry unto the Lord according to that which had
been spoken by the mouth of Jared
40 And it came to pass that the Lord did hear the
brother of Jared, and had compassion upon him, and
said unto him
41 Go to and gather together thy flocks, both male
and female, of every kind; and also of the seed
of the earth of every kind; and thy families; and
also Jared thy brother and his family; and also thy
friends and their families, and the friends of
Jared and their families
42 And when thou hast done this thou shalt go at
the head of them down into the valley which is
northward. And there will I meet thee, and I will go
before thee into a land which is choice above all
the lands of the earth
43 And there will I bless thee and thy seed, and
raise up unto me of thy seed, and of the seed of
thy brother, and they who shall go with thee, a
great nation. And there shall be none greater than the
nation which I will raise up unto me of thy seed,
upon all the face of the earth. And thus I will
do unto thee because this long time ye have cried
unto me.