Chapter 7 Orihah reigns in righteousness—Amid
usurpation and strife, the rival kingdoms of Shule
and Cohor are set up—Prophets condemn the
wickedness and idolatry of the people, who then repent.
1 And it came to pass that Orihah did
execute judgment upon the land in righteousness
all his days, whose days were exceedingly many.
2 And he begat sons and daughters;
yea, he begat thirty and one,
among whom were twenty and three sons.
3 And it came to pass that he
also begat Kib in his old age. And
it came to pass that Kib reigned
in his stead; and Kib begat Corihor.
4 And when Corihor was thirty
and two years old he rebelled
against his father, and went
over and dwelt in the land of
Nehor; and he begat sons and
daughters, and they became
exceedingly fair; wherefore Corihor
drew away many people after him.
5 And when he had gathered
together an army he came up
unto the land of Moron
where the king dwelt, and took
him captive, which brought
to pass the saying of the
brother of Jared that they
would be brought into captivity.
6 Now the land of Moron,
where the king dwelt, was
near the land which is called
Desolation by the Nephites.
7 And it came to pass
that Kib dwelt in
captivity, and his people under
Corihor his son, until
he became exceedingly
old; nevertheless Kib begat
Shule in his old age,
while he was yet in captivity.
8 And it came to pass
that Shule was angry
with his brother; and
Shule waxed strong, and
became mighty as to the
strength of a man; and he
was also mighty in judgment.
9 Wherefore, he came
to the hill Ephraim,
and he did molten out of
the hill, and made
swords out of steel for
those whom he had
drawn away with him; and
after he had armed them
with swords he
returned to the city Nehor,
and gave battle unto
his brother Corihor, by
which means he
obtained the kingdom and
restored it unto his father Kib.
10 And now because of
the thing which
Shule had done, his
father bestowed upon him
the kingdom; therefore
he began to reign in
the stead of his father.
11 And it came to
pass that he did
execute judgment in
righteousness; and he
did spread his
kingdom upon all the
face of the land,
for the people had
become exceedingly numerous.
12 And it came to
pass that Shule
also begat many
sons and daughters.
13 And Corihor
repented of the
many evils
which he had done;
wherefore
Shule gave him
power in his kingdom.
14 And it came
to pass that
Corihor had
many sons and
daughters. And
among the sons
of Corihor
there was one
whose name was Noah.
15 And it
came to pass
that Noah
rebelled against
Shule, the
king, and also
his father
Corihor, and drew
away Cohor
his brother,
and also all
his brethren
and many of the people.
16 And he
gave battle
unto Shule,
the king, in
which he did
obtain the
land of their
first
inheritance; and
he became a
king over
that part of the land.
17 And it
came to pass
that he
gave battle
again unto
Shule, the
king; and he
took
Shule, the king,
and
carried him away
captive into Moron.
18 And it
came to
pass as he
was about
to put him
to death,
the sons
of Shule
crept into
the house
of Noah by
night and
slew him,
and broke
down the
door of the
prison
and brought
out their
father,
and placed
him upon
his throne in his own kingdom.
Wherefore, the
son of
Noah did
build up
his kingdom
in his
stead;
nevertheless
they did
not gain
power
any more
over Shule
the king,
and the
people
who were
under the
reign of
Shule the
king did
prosper
exceedingly and wax great.
20 And
the
country was
divided;
and
there were
two
kingdoms, the
kingdom
of
Shule, and
the
kingdom of
Cohor, the son of Noah.
21 And
Cohor,
the son
of
Noah,
caused that
his
people
should
give
battle unto
Shule,
in
which
Shule did
beat
them and did slay Cohor.
22 And
now
Cohor had
a son
who was
called
Nimrod;
and
Nimrod
gave up
the
kingdom of
Cohor
unto
Shule, and
he did
gain
favor in
the
eyes of
Shule;
wherefore Shule
did
bestow
great
favors
upon him,
and he
did do
in the
kingdom
of
Shule
according
to his
desires.
23 And
also
in the
reign
of
Shule
there
came
prophets
among
the
people,
who
were
sent from
the
Lord,
prophesying
that
the
wickedness
and
idolatry of
the
people
was
bringing a
curse
upon
the
land,
and they
should be destroyed if they did not repent.
And it
came
to
pass
that
the
people
did
revile
against
the
prophets, and
did
mock
them.
And
it
came to
pass
that
king
Shule did
execute
judgment
against
all
those
who did revile against the prophets.
And
he
did
execute a
law
throughout
all
the
land,
which
gave
power
unto
the
prophets
that
they
should
go
whithersoever
they
would;
and by
this
cause
the people were brought unto repentance.
And
because
the
people
did
repent
of
their
iniquities
and
idolatries
the
Lord
did
spare
them,
and
they
began
to
prosper
again
in
the
land.
And
it
came
to
pass that Shule begat sons and daughters in his old age.
And
there
were
no
more
wars
in
the
days
of
Shule;
and
he
remembered
the
great
things
that
the
Lord
had
done
for
his
fathers
in
bringing
them
across
the
great
deep
into
the
promised
land;
wherefore
he
did
execute
judgment
in
righteousness
all
his
days.