Chapter 14 The iniquity of the people
brings a curse upon the land—Coriantumr
engages in warfare against Gilead, then Lib, and
then Shiz—Blood and carnage cover the land.
1 And now there began to be a great
curse upon all the land because of
the iniquity of the people, in which,
if a man should lay his tool or his
sword upon his shelf, or upon the
place whither he would keep it,
behold, upon the morrow, he could not
find it, so great was the curse upon the land.
2 Wherefore every man did cleave
unto that which was his own,
with his hands, and would not
borrow neither would he lend; and
every man kept the hilt of his
sword in his right hand, in the
defence of his property and his own
life and of his wives and children.
3 And now, after the space
of two years, and after the
death of Shared, behold,
there arose the brother of
Shared and he gave battle unto
Coriantumr, in which
Coriantumr did beat him and did
pursue him to the wilderness of Akish.
4 And it came to pass
that the brother of Shared
did give battle unto him
in the wilderness of
Akish; and the battle became
exceedingly sore, and many
thousands fell by the sword.
5 And it came to pass
that Coriantumr did lay
siege to the
wilderness; and the brother of
Shared did march forth
out of the wilderness by
night, and slew a part
of the army of
Coriantumr, as they were drunken.
6 And he came forth to
the land of Moron,
and placed himself upon
the throne of Coriantumr.
7 And it came to
pass that Coriantumr
dwelt with his army
in the wilderness
for the space of
two years, in which
he did receive great
strength to his army.
8 Now the brother
of Shared, whose
name was Gilead,
also received
great strength to
his army, because
of secret combinations.
9 And it came to
pass that his
high priest
murdered him as he
sat upon his throne.
10 And it came
to pass that
one of the secret
combinations
murdered him in
a secret pass,
and obtained
unto himself the
kingdom; and
his name was Lib;
and Lib was a
man of great
stature, more
than any other man
among all the people.
11 And it
came to pass
that in the
first year of
Lib, Coriantumr
came up unto
the land of
Moron, and
gave battle unto Lib.
12 And it
came to pass
that he
fought with Lib,
in which Lib
did smite
upon his arm
that he was
wounded;
nevertheless,
the army of
Coriantumr
did press
forward upon
Lib, that he
fled to the
borders upon the seashore.
13 And it
came to pass
that
Coriantumr
pursued him; and
Lib gave
battle unto
him upon
the seashore.
14 And it
came to
pass that
Lib did
smite the army
of
Coriantumr, that
they fled
again to
the
wilderness of Akish.
15 And it
came to
pass that
Lib did
pursue him
until he came
to the
plains of
Agosh. And
Coriantumr
had taken
all the
people with
him as he
fled
before Lib in
that
quarter of the
land
whither he fled.
16 And
when he had
come to
the
plains of
Agosh he gave
battle
unto Lib,
and he
smote upon
him until
he died;
nevertheless, the
brother
of Lib
did come
against
Coriantumr
in the
stead
thereof, and
the battle
became
exceedingly
sore, in
the
which
Coriantumr fled
again
before the army of the brother of Lib.
17 Now
the name
of the
brother
of Lib
was called
Shiz.
And it
came to
pass that
Shiz
pursued
after
Coriantumr,
and he
did
overthrow many
cities,
and he
did slay
both
women and
children, and he did burn the cities.
18 And
there
went a
fear of
Shiz
throughout all
the
land; yea,
a cry
went
forth
throughout
the
land—Who
can
stand
before the
army of
Shiz?
Behold,
he
sweepeth the earth before him!
19 And
it
came to
pass
that
the
people
began to
flock
together in
armies,
throughout
all
the face of the land.
And
they
were
divided;
and
a
part of
them
fled
to
the
army of
Shiz,
and
a
part of
them
fled
to
the army of Coriantumr.
And so
great
and
lasting
had
been the
war,
and
so
long
had
been the
scene of
bloodshed
and
carnage,
that
the
whole
face of
the
land
was
covered
with the
bodies of
the
dead.
And so
swift
and
speedy was
the
war
that
there
was
none
left
to
bury the
dead, but
they
did
march
forth
from the
shedding
of
blood
to the
shedding
of
blood,
leaving
the
bodies
of
both
men,
women,
and
children
strewed
upon
the
face
of the
land, to
become a
prey
to the
worms of
the
flesh.
And
the
scent
thereof
went
forth
upon
the
face of
land,
even
upon
all
the
face of
land;
wherefore
the
people
became
troubled
by
day
and
by night, because of the scent thereof.
Nevertheless,
Shiz
did
not
cease
to
pursue
Coriantumr;
for he
had
sworn
to
avenge
himself
upon
Coriantumr
of
the
blood of
his
brother,
who
had
been
slain,
and
the
word
of
the
Lord
which
came to
Ether
that
Coriantumr
should
not
fall
by
the
sword.
And
thus
we
see
that
the
Lord
did
visit
them
in
the
fulness
of
his
wrath,
and
their
wickedness
and
abominations
had
prepared
a
way
for
their
everlasting
destruction.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Shiz
did
pursue
Coriantumr
eastward,
even
to
the
borders
by
the
seashore,
and
there
he
gave
battle unto Shiz for the space of three days.
And
so
terrible
was
the
destruction
among
the
armies
of
Shiz
that
the
people
began
to
be
frightened,
and
began
to
flee
before
the
armies
of
Coriantumr;
and
they
fled
to
the
land
of
Corihor,
and
swept
off
the
inhabitants
before
them,
all
them
that
would
not
join
them.
And
they
pitched
their
tents
in
the
valley
of
Corihor;
and
Coriantumr
pitched
his
tents
in
the
valley
of
Shurr.
Now
the
valley
of
Shurr
was
near
the
hill
Comnor;
wherefore,
Coriantumr
did
gather
his
armies
together upon the hill Comnor, and did sound a trumpet unto the armies of Shiz to invite them forth to battle.
29 And it came to pass that they came forth, but were driven again; and they came the second time, and they were driven again the second time. And it came to pass that they came again the third time, and the battle became exceedingly
And
it
came
to
pass
that
they
came
forth,
but
were
driven
again;
and
they
came
the
second
time,
and
they
were
driven
again the second time. And it came to pass that they came again the third time, and the battle became exceedingly sore.
30 And it came to pass that Shiz smote upon Coriantumr that he gave him many deep wounds; and Coriantumr, having lost his blood, fainted, and was carried away as though he were
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Shiz
smote
upon
Coriantumr
that
he
gave
him
many
deep
wounds;
and
Coriantumr,
having
lost
his
blood,
fainted,
and
was
carried
away
as
though
he
were
dead.
31 Now the loss of men, women and children on both sides was so great that Shiz commanded his people that they should not pursue the armies of Coriantumr; wherefore, they returned to their camp.
Now
the
loss
of
men,
women
and
children
on
both
sides
was
so
great
that
Shiz
commanded
his
people
that
they
should
not
pursue
the
armies
of
Coriantumr;
wherefore,
they
returned
to
their
camp.