Chapter 9 The kingdom passes from one to another
by descent, intrigue, and murder—Emer saw the Son
of Righteousness—Many prophets cry repentance—A
famine and poisonous serpents plague the people.
1 And now I, Moroni, proceed with my record.
Therefore, behold, it came to pass that because of
the secret combinations of Akish and his
friends, behold, they did overthrow the kingdom of Omer.
2 Nevertheless, the Lord was merciful
unto Omer, and also to his sons and to his
daughters who did not seek his destruction.
3 And the Lord warned Omer in a dream
that he should depart out of the land;
wherefore Omer departed out of the land
with his family, and traveled many
days, and came over and passed by the hill
of Shim, and came over by the place
where the Nephites were destroyed, and
from thence eastward, and came to a place
which was called Ablom, by the
seashore, and there he pitched his tent, and
also his sons and his daughters, and all
his household, save it were Jared and his family.
4 And it came to pass that Jared
was anointed king over the people,
by the hand of wickedness; and he
gave unto Akish his daughter to wife.
5 And it came to pass that
Akish sought the life of his
father-in-law; and he applied unto
those whom he had sworn by the
oath of the ancients, and they
obtained the head of his
father-in-law, as he sat upon his
throne, giving audience to his people.
6 For so great had been the
spreading of this wicked and
secret society that it had
corrupted the hearts of all
the people; therefore Jared
was murdered upon his
throne, and Akish reigned in his stead.
7 And it came to pass that
Akish began to be jealous
of his son, therefore he
shut him up in prison, and
kept him upon little or no
food until he had suffered death.
8 And now the brother of
him that suffered death,
(and his name was Nimrah)
was angry with his father
because of that which his
father had done unto his brother.
9 And it came to pass
that Nimrah gathered
together a small number
of men, and fled out
of the land, and came
over and dwelt with Omer.
10 And it came to
pass that Akish begat
other sons, and they
won the hearts of the
people,
notwithstanding they had sworn unto
him to do all manner
of iniquity
according to that which he desired.
11 Now the people of
Akish were desirous
for gain, even as
Akish was desirous
for power; wherefore,
the sons of Akish
did offer them money,
by which means they
drew away the more
part of the people after them.
12 And there began
to be a war between
the sons of Akish and
Akish, which lasted
for the space of
many years, yea, unto
the destruction of
nearly all the people
of the kingdom,
yea, even all, save it
were thirty souls,
and they who fled
with the house of Omer.
13 Wherefore,
Omer was restored
again to the land
of his inheritance.
14 And it came
to pass that Omer
began to be
old; nevertheless,
in his old age
he begat Emer;
and he anointed
Emer to be king to
reign in his stead.
15 And after
that he had
anointed Emer to be
king he saw
peace in the land
for the space
of two years,
and he died,
having seen
exceedingly many days,
which were
full of sorrow.
And it came to
pass that Emer
did reign in his
stead, and did
fill the steps of his father.
16 And the Lord
began again to
take the curse
from off the
land, and the
house of Emer did
prosper
exceedingly under the
reign of Emer;
and in the
space of sixty and
two years they
had become
exceedingly
strong, insomuch that
they became
exceedingly rich—
17 Having all
manner of
fruit, and of
grain, and of
silks, and of fine
linen, and of
gold, and of
silver, and of
precious things;
18 And also
all manner of
cattle, of
oxen, and cows,
and of
sheep, and of
swine, and of
goats, and also
many other
kinds of
animals which were
useful for
the food of man.
19 And they
also had
horses, and
asses, and
there were
elephants and
cureloms and
cumoms; all of
which were
useful unto
man, and
more especially
the
elephants and
cureloms and cumoms.
20 And thus
the Lord did
pour out
his blessings
upon this
land, which
was choice
above all other
lands; and
he commanded
that whoso
should
possess the land
possess it unto
the Lord, or
they should
be destroyed
when they
were ripened
in iniquity;
for upon
such, saith
the Lord: I
will pour out
the fulness
of my wrath.
21 And Emer
did
execute judgment
in
righteousness all
his days,
and he begat
many sons
and
daughters; and he
begat
Coriantum, and he
anointed
Coriantum to
reign in his stead.
22 And
after he had
anointed
Coriantum
to reign in
his stead
he lived
four
years, and he
saw peace
in the
land; yea, and
he even
saw the Son
of
Righteousness,
and did
rejoice and
glory in
his day; and he died in peace.
23 And it
came to
pass that
Coriantum did
walk in the
steps of
his
father, and
did build
many
mighty cities,
and did
administer that
which was
good unto
his
people in all
his days.
And it
came to
pass that
he had no
children
even until he was exceedingly old.
24 And
it came
to pass
that his
wife
died, being
an
hundred and
two
years old.
And it
came to
pass that
Coriantum took
to wife,
in his
old age,
a young
maid,
and begat
sons and
daughters;
wherefore he
lived
until he
was an
hundred and forty and two years old.
25 And
it came
to
pass that
he
begat Com,
and Com
reigned in
his
stead; and
he
reigned
forty and
nine
years, and
he
begat
Heth; and
he also
begat
other sons and daughters.
26 And
the
people
had
spread
again
over
all the
face
of the
land,
and
there
began
again to
be an
exceedingly
great
wickedness
upon
the
face of
land, and
Heth
began
to
embrace
the
secret
plans
again of old, to destroy his father.
And it
came
to
pass
that he
did
dethrone
his
father,
for
he
slew
him
with his
own
sword; and
he
did reign in his stead.
And
there
came
prophets
in
the
land
again,
crying
repentance
unto
them—that
they
must
prepare
the
way
of
the
Lord
or
there
should
come a
curse
upon
the
face
of
the
land;
yea,
even
there
should
be a
great
famine,
in which they should be destroyed if they did not repent.
But
the
people
believed
not
the
words
of
the
prophets,
but
they
cast
them
out;
and
some
of
them
they
cast
into
pits
and
left
them
to
perish.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
they
did
all these things according to the commandment of the king, Heth.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
there
began
to
be
a
great
dearth
upon
the
land,
and
the
inhabitants
began
to
be
destroyed
exceedingly
fast
because
of
the
dearth,
for
there
was
no
rain
upon
the
face
of
the
earth.
And
there
came
forth
poisonous
serpents
also
upon
the
face
of
the
land,
and
did
poison
many
people.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
their
flocks
began
to
flee
before
the
poisonous serpents, towards the land southward, which was called by the Nephites Zarahemla.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
there
were
many
of
them
which
did
perish
by
the
way;
nevertheless,
there
were
some
which
fled
into
the
land
southward.
33 And it came to pass that the Lord did cause the serpents that they should pursue them no more, but that they should hedge up the way that the people could not pass, that whoso should attempt to pass might fall by the poisonous
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
Lord
did
cause
the
serpents
that
they
should
pursue
them
no
more,
but
that
they
should
hedge up the way that the people could not pass, that whoso should attempt to pass might fall by the poisonous serpents.
34 And it came to pass that the people did follow the course of the beasts, and did devour the carcasses of them which fell by the way, until they had devoured them all. Now when the people saw that they must perish they began to repent of their iniquities and cry unto the
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
people
did
follow
the
course
of
the
beasts,
and
did
devour
the
carcasses
of
them
which
fell
by
the
way,
until
they
had
devoured
them
all.
Now
when
the
people
saw
that
they
must
perish
they
began
to
repent
of
their
iniquities
and
cry
unto
the
Lord.
35 And it came to pass that when they had humbled themselves sufficiently before the Lord he did send rain upon the face of the earth; and the people began to revive again, and there began to be fruit in the north countries, and in all the countries round about. And the Lord did show forth his power unto them in preserving them from famine.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
when
they
had
humbled
themselves
sufficiently
before
the
Lord
he
did
send
rain
upon
the
face
of
the
earth;
and
the
people
began
to
revive
again,
and
there
began
to
be
fruit
in
the
north
countries,
and
in
all
the
countries
round
about.
And
the
Lord
did
show
forth
his
power
unto
them
in
preserving
them
from
famine.