Chapter 2 The Jaredites prepare for their journey
to a promised land—It is a choice land whereon
men must serve Christ or be swept off—The Lord
talks to the brother of Jared for three hours—The
Jaredites build barges—The Lord asks the brother of
Jared to propose how the barges will be lighted.
1 And it came to pass that Jared and his
brother, and their families, and also the
friends of Jared and his brother and their
families, went down into the valley which was
northward, (and the name of the valley was
Nimrod, being called after the mighty
hunter) with their flocks which they had
gathered together, male and female, of every kind.
2 And they did also lay snares and
catch fowls of the air; and they did also
prepare a vessel, in which they did
carry with them the fish of the waters.
3 And they did also carry with them
deseret, which, by interpretation,
is a honey bee; and thus they did
carry with them swarms of bees, and all
manner of that which was upon the
face of the land, seeds of every kind.
4 And it came to pass that when
they had come down into the
valley of Nimrod the Lord came down
and talked with the brother of
Jared; and he was in a cloud, and
the brother of Jared saw him not.
5 And it came to pass that the
Lord commanded them that they
should go forth into the
wilderness, yea, into that quarter
where there never had man
been. And it came to pass that
the Lord did go before them, and
did talk with them as he
stood in a cloud, and gave
directions whither they should travel.
6 And it came to pass that
they did travel in the
wilderness, and did build barges,
in which they did cross many
waters, being directed
continually by the hand of the Lord.
7 And the Lord would not
suffer that they should
stop beyond the sea in the
wilderness, but he would
that they should come
forth even unto the land of
promise, which was
choice above all other lands,
which the Lord God had
preserved for a righteous people.
8 And he had sworn in
his wrath unto the brother
of Jared, that whoso
should possess this land
of promise, from that
time henceforth and
forever, should serve him, the
true and only God, or
they should be swept off
when the fulness of his
wrath should come upon them.
9 And now, we can
behold the decrees of God
concerning this land,
that it is a land of
promise; and whatsoever
nation shall possess it
shall serve God, or they
shall be swept off when
the fulness of his
wrath shall come upon them.
And the fulness of his
wrath cometh upon them
when they are ripened in iniquity.
10 For behold, this
is a land which is
choice above all other
lands; wherefore he
that doth possess it
shall serve God or
shall be swept off; for
it is the everlasting
decree of God. And it
is not until the
fulness of iniquity
among the children of the
land, that they are swept off.
11 And this cometh
unto you, O ye
Gentiles, that ye may
know the decrees of
God—that ye may
repent, and not
continue in your
iniquities until the
fulness come, that ye may
not bring down the
fulness of the
wrath of God upon you
as the inhabitants
of the land have hitherto done.
12 Behold, this is
a choice land,
and whatsoever
nation shall possess it
shall be free
from bondage, and
from captivity, and
from all other
nations under heaven,
if they will but
serve the God of
the land, who is
Jesus Christ, who
hath been manifested
by the things
which we have written.
13 And now I
proceed with my
record; for behold, it
came to pass
that the Lord did
bring Jared and his
brethren forth
even to that great
sea which
divideth the lands. And
as they came to
the sea they
pitched their tents;
and they called
the name of the
place Moriancumer;
and they dwelt in
tents, and dwelt
in tents upon
the seashore for
the space of four years.
14 And it came
to pass at the
end of four years
that the Lord
came again unto
the brother of
Jared, and stood in
a cloud and
talked with him.
And for the space
of three hours
did the Lord talk
with the
brother of Jared, and
chastened him
because he
remembered not to call
upon the name of the Lord.
15 And the
brother of Jared
repented of the
evil which he
had done, and did
call upon the
name of the
Lord for his
brethren who were
with him. And the
Lord said unto
him: I will
forgive thee and
thy brethren of
their sins;
but thou shalt
not sin any more,
for ye shall
remember that my
Spirit will
not always strive
with man;
wherefore, if ye
will sin until ye
are fully ripe
ye shall be
cut off from the
presence of the
Lord. And
these are my
thoughts upon the
land which I shall
give you for
your
inheritance; for it shall
be a land choice above all other lands.
16 And the
Lord said: Go to
work and
build, after the
manner of barges
which ye have
hitherto
built. And it came
to pass that
the brother of
Jared did go
to work, and
also his
brethren, and built
barges after
the manner
which they had
built, according
to the
instructions of the
Lord. And they
were small,
and they were
light upon the
water, even
like unto the
lightness of a fowl upon the water.
17 And they
were built
after a manner
that they were
exceedingly
tight, even
that they
would hold water
like unto a
dish; and the
bottom
thereof was tight
like unto a
dish; and the
sides thereof
were tight
like unto a
dish; and the
ends thereof
were peaked;
and the top
thereof was
tight like unto a
dish; and
the length
thereof was the
length of a
tree; and the
door thereof,
when it was
shut, was tight like unto a dish.
18 And it
came to pass
that the
brother of Jared
cried unto
the Lord,
saying: O
Lord, I have
performed the
work which
thou hast
commanded me,
and I have
made the barges
according
as thou hast directed me.
19 And
behold, O Lord,
in them
there is no
light;
whither shall we
steer? And
also we
shall perish,
for in
them we cannot
breathe,
save it is
the air
which is in
them;
therefore we shall perish.
20 And the
Lord said
unto the
brother of
Jared:
Behold, thou
shalt
make a hole
in the top,
and also
in the
bottom; and
when thou
shalt
suffer for air
thou shalt
unstop
the hole and
receive
air. And if
it be so
that the
water come
in upon
thee,
behold, ye shall
stop the
hole, that
ye may not perish in the flood.
21 And it
came to
pass that
the
brother of
Jared did
so,
according as
the Lord
had commanded.
22 And he
cried
again unto
the Lord
saying: O
Lord,
behold I
have done
even as
thou hast
commanded
me; and I
have
prepared the
vessels
for my
people, and
behold
there is
no light
in them.
Behold, O
Lord,
wilt thou
suffer that
we shall
cross
this great
water in
darkness?
23 And
the Lord
said
unto the
brother of
Jared:
What
will ye
that I
should do
that ye
may have
light in
your
vessels?
For
behold, ye
cannot have
windows, for
they will
be
dashed in
pieces;
neither
shall ye
take fire
with
you, for ye
shall not go by the light of fire.
24 For
behold,
ye
shall be
as a
whale in
the
midst of
the sea;
for the
mountain
waves shall
dash
upon
you.
Nevertheless, I
will bring
you up
again
out of
the
depths of
sea; for
the
winds have
gone
forth out
of my
mouth,
and
also the
rains and the floods have I sent forth.
25 And
behold, I
prepare
you
against
these
things; for
ye
cannot
cross
this
great
deep
save I
prepare
you
against
the
waves of
sea,
and the
winds
which
have
gone
forth,
and the
floods
which
shall
come.
Therefore
what
will ye
that
I
should
prepare
for you
that
ye may
have
light
when ye are swallowed up in the depths of the sea?