Chapter 4 Moroni is commanded to seal up the
writings of the brother of Jared—They will not be
revealed until men have faith even as the
brother of Jared—Christ commands men to believe His
words and those of His disciples—Men are
commanded to repent, believe the gospel, and be saved.
1 And the Lord commanded the brother of
Jared to go down out of the mount from the
presence of the Lord, and write the things which
he had seen; and they were forbidden to come
unto the children of men until after that
he should be lifted up upon the cross; and
for this cause did king Mosiah keep them, that
they should not come unto the world until
after Christ should show himself unto his people.
2 And after Christ truly had showed
himself unto his people he
commanded that they should be made manifest.
3 And now, after that, they
have all dwindled in unbelief; and
there is none save it be the
Lamanites, and they have
rejected the gospel of Christ;
therefore I am commanded that I should
hide them up again in the earth.
4 Behold, I have written upon
these plates the very things
which the brother of Jared
saw; and there never were
greater things made manifest than
those which were made
manifest unto the brother of Jared.
5 Wherefore the Lord hath
commanded me to write them; and
I have written them. And he
commanded me that I should
seal them up; and he also hath
commanded that I should seal
up the interpretation thereof;
wherefore I have sealed up
the interpreters, according to
the commandment of the Lord.
6 For the Lord said unto
me: They shall not go forth
unto the Gentiles until
the day that they shall
repent of their iniquity, and
become clean before the Lord.
7 And in that day that
they shall exercise faith
in me, saith the Lord,
even as the brother of Jared
did, that they may
become sanctified in me, then
will I manifest unto them
the things which the
brother of Jared saw, even
to the unfolding unto them
all my revelations,
saith Jesus Christ, the Son
of God, the Father of the
heavens and of the earth,
and all things that in them are.
8 And he that will
contend against the word
of the Lord, let him
be accursed; and he
that shall deny these
things, let him be
accursed; for unto them will
I show no greater
things, saith Jesus
Christ; for I am he who speaketh.
9 And at my command
the heavens are opened
and are shut; and at
my word the earth
shall shake; and at my
command the
inhabitants thereof shall pass
away, even so as by fire.
10 And he that
believeth not my words
believeth not my
disciples; and if it
so be that I do not
speak, judge ye;
for ye shall know
that it is I that
speaketh, at the last day.
11 But he that
believeth these
things which I have
spoken, him will
I visit with the
manifestations of
my Spirit, and
he shall know and
bear record. For
because of my
Spirit he shall know
that these
things are true; for
it persuadeth men to do good.
12 And
whatsoever thing
persuadeth men to do
good is of me; for
good cometh of
none save it be
of me. I am the
same that leadeth
men to all
good; he that will
not believe my
words will not
believe me—that I
am; and he that
will not believe
me will not
believe the Father
who sent me. For
behold, I am the
Father, I am
the light, and the
life, and the truth of the world.
13 Come unto
me, O ye
Gentiles, and I will
show unto you the
greater
things, the knowledge
which is hid
up because of unbelief.
14 Come unto
me, O ye house
of Israel, and
it shall be
made manifest
unto you how
great things the
Father hath
laid up for
you, from the
foundation of the
world; and it
hath not come
unto you,
because of unbelief.
15 Behold,
when ye shall
rend that veil
of unbelief
which doth
cause you to
remain in your
awful state
of wickedness,
and hardness
of heart,
and blindness
of mind, then
shall the
great and
marvelous things
which have been
hid up from
the
foundation of the
world from
you—yea, when ye
shall call upon
the Father
in my name,
with a broken
heart and a
contrite
spirit, then shall
ye know that
the Father
hath remembered
the covenant
which he
made unto your fathers, O house of Israel.
16 And then
shall my
revelations
which I have
caused to be
written by my
servant
John be
unfolded in the
eyes of all the
people.
Remember, when
ye see these
things, ye
shall know
that the time
is at hand
that they
shall be made
manifest in very deed.
Therefore, when ye
shall receive
this record
ye may know
that the
work of the
Father has
commenced upon
all the face
of the land.
Therefore, repent
all ye ends
of the
earth, and come
unto me,
and believe
in my
gospel, and be
baptized in
my name;
for he that
believeth
and is
baptized shall be
saved; but
he that
believeth not
shall be
damned; and
signs shall
follow
them that believe in my name.
19 And
blessed is he
that is
found
faithful unto
my name at
the last
day, for he
shall be
lifted up
to dwell
in the
kingdom
prepared for him
from the
foundation
of the
world. And
behold it
is I that
hath spoken it. Amen.