Chapter 22 Israel will be scattered upon all the
face of the earth—The Gentiles will nurse and
nourish Israel with the gospel in the last days—Israel
will be gathered and saved, and the wicked will
burn as stubble—The kingdom of the devil will be
destroyed, and Satan will be bound. About
588–570 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that after I, Nephi, had
read these things which were engraven upon the
plates of brass, my brethren came unto me and said
unto me: What meaneth these things which ye have
read? Behold, are they to be understood according to
things which are spiritual, which shall come to
pass according to the spirit and not the flesh
2 And I, Nephi, said unto them: Behold they were
manifest unto the prophet by the voice of the
Spirit; for by the Spirit are all things made known
unto the prophets, which shall come upon the children
of men according to the flesh
3 Wherefore, the things of which I have read are
things pertaining to things both temporal and
spiritual; for it appears that the house of Israel,
sooner or later, will be scattered upon all the face
of the earth, and also among all nations
4 And behold, there are many who are already lost
from the knowledge of those who are at Jerusalem.
Yea, the more part of all the tribes have been led
away; and they are scattered to and fro upon the
isles of the sea; and whither they are none of us
knoweth, save that we know that they have been led
away
5 And since they have been led away, these things
have been prophesied concerning them, and also
concerning all those who shall hereafter be scattered
and be confounded, because of the Holy One of
Israel; for against him will they harden their
hearts; wherefore, they shall be scattered among all
nations and shall be hated of all men
6 Nevertheless, after they shall be nursed by the
Gentiles, and the Lord has lifted up his hand upon
the Gentiles and set them up for a standard, and
their children have been carried in their arms,
and their daughters have been carried upon their
shoulders, behold these things of which are spoken
are temporal; for thus are the covenants of the Lord
with our fathers; and it meaneth us in the days
to come, and also all our brethren who are of the
house of Israel
7 And it meaneth that the time cometh that after
all the house of Israel have been scattered and
confounded, that the Lord God will raise up a mighty
nation among the Gentiles, yea, even upon the face
of this land; and by them shall our seed be
scattered
8 And after our seed is scattered the Lord God
will proceed to do a marvelous work among the
Gentiles, which shall be of great worth unto our seed;
wherefore, it is likened unto their being nourished
by the Gentiles and being carried in their arms
and upon their shoulders
9 And it shall also be of worth unto the Gentiles;
and not only unto the Gentiles but unto all the
house of Israel, unto the making known of the
covenants of the Father of heaven unto Abraham, saying:
In thy seed shall all the kindreds of the earth
be blessed
10 And I would, my brethren, that ye should know
that all the kindreds of the earth cannot be
blessed unless he shall make bare his arm in the eyes of
the nations
11 Wherefore, the Lord God will proceed to make
bare his arm in the eyes of all the nations, in
bringing about his covenants and his gospel unto those
who are of the house of Israel
12 Wherefore, he will bring them again out of
captivity, and they shall be gathered together to the
lands of their inheritance; and they shall be
brought out of obscurity and out of darkness; and they
shall know that the Lord is their Savior and
their Redeemer, the Mighty One of Israel
13 And the blood of that great and abominable
church, which is the whore of all the earth, shall
turn upon their own heads; for they shall war among
themselves, and the sword of their own hands shall
fall upon their own heads, and they shall be
drunken with their own blood
14 And every nation which shall war against thee,
O house of Israel, shall be turned one against
another, and they shall fall into the pit which they
digged to ensnare the people of the Lord. And all
that fight against Zion shall be destroyed, and
that great whore, who hath perverted the right ways
of the Lord, yea, that great and abominable
church, shall tumble to the dust and great shall be the
fall of it
15 For behold, saith the prophet, the time cometh
speedily that Satan shall have no more power over
the hearts of the children of men; for the day
soon cometh that all the proud and they who do
wickedly shall be as stubble; and the day cometh that
they must be burned
16 For the time soon cometh that the fulness of
the wrath of God shall be poured out upon all the
children of men; for he will not suffer that the
wicked shall destroy the righteous
17 Wherefore, he will preserve the righteous by
his power, even if it so be that the fulness of his
wrath must come, and the righteous be preserved,
even unto the destruction of their enemies by fire.
Wherefore, the righteous need not fear; for thus
saith the prophet, they shall be saved, even if it
so be as by fire
18 Behold, my brethren, I say unto you, that these
things must shortly come; yea, even blood, and
fire, and vapor of smoke must come; and it must
needs be upon the face of this earth; and it cometh
unto men according to the flesh if it so be that
they will harden their hearts against the Holy One of
Israel
19 For behold, the righteous shall not perish; for
the time surely must come that all they who fight
against Zion shall be cut off
20 And the Lord will surely prepare a way for his
people, unto the fulfilling of the words of Moses,
which he spake, saying: A prophet shall the Lord
your God raise up unto you, like unto me; him
shall ye hear in all things whatsoever he shall say
unto you. And it shall come to pass that all those
who will not hear that prophet shall be cut off
from among the people
21 And now I, Nephi, declare unto you, that this
prophet of whom Moses spake was the Holy One of
Israel; wherefore, he shall execute judgment in
righteousness
22 And the righteous need not fear, for they are
those who shall not be confounded. But it is the
kingdom of the devil, which shall be built up among
the children of men, which kingdom is established
among them which are in the flesh
23 For the time speedily shall come that all
churches which are built up to get gain, and all those
who are built up to get power over the flesh, and
those who are built up to become popular in the
eyes of the world, and those who seek the lusts of
the flesh and the things of the world, and to do
all manner of iniquity; yea, in fine, all those who
belong to the kingdom of the devil are they who
need fear, and tremble, and quake; they are those
who must be brought low in the dust; they are those
who must be consumed as stubble; and this is
according to the words of the prophet
24 And the time cometh speedily that the righteous
must be led up as calves of the stall, and the
Holy One of Israel must reign in dominion, and
might, and power, and great glory
25 And he gathereth his children from the four
quarters of the earth; and he numbereth his sheep,
and they know him; and there shall be one fold and
one shepherd; and he shall feed his sheep, and in
him they shall find pasture
26 And because of the righteousness of his people,
Satan has no power; wherefore, he cannot be
loosed for the space of many years; for he hath no
power over the hearts of the people, for they dwell in
righteousness, and the Holy One of Israel
reigneth
27 And now behold, I, Nephi, say unto you that all
these things must come according to the flesh
28 But, behold, all nations, kindreds, tongues,
and people shall dwell safely in the Holy One of
Israel if it so be that they will repent
29 And now I, Nephi, make an end; for I durst not
speak further as yet concerning these things
30 Wherefore, my brethren, I would that ye should
consider that the things which have been written
upon the plates of brass are true; and they testify
that a man must be obedient to the commandments
of God
31 Wherefore, ye need not suppose that I and my
father are the only ones that have testified, and
also taught them. Wherefore, if ye shall be obedient
to the commandments, and endure to the end, ye
shall be saved at the last day. And thus it is.
Amen.