The First Book of NephiHis Reign and MinistryAn account of
Lehi and his wife Sariah, and his four sons, being
called, (beginning at the eldest) Laman, Lemuel, Sam, and Nephi.
The Lord warns Lehi to depart out of the land
of Jerusalem, because he prophesieth unto the people concerning their
iniquity and they seek to destroy his life. He taketh
three days’ journey into the wilderness with his family. Nephi
taketh his brethren and returneth to the land of Jerusalem
after the record of the Jews. The account of their
sufferings. They take the daughters of Ishmael to wife. They
take their families and depart into the wilderness. Their sufferings
and afflictions in the wilderness. The course of their travels.
They come to the large waters. Nephi’s brethren rebel against
him. He confoundeth them, and buildeth a ship. They call
the name of the place Bountiful. They cross the large
waters into the promised land, and so forth. This is
according to the account of Nephi; or in other words,
I, Nephi, wrote this record.Chapter 1 Nephi begins the record
of his people—Lehi sees in vision a pillar of fire
and reads from a book of prophecy—He praises God, foretells
the coming of the Messiah, and prophesies the destruction of
Jerusalem—He is persecuted by the Jews. About 600 B.C.
1 I, Nephi, having been born of goodly parents, therefore
I was taught somewhat in all the learning of my
father; and having seen many afflictions in the course of
my days, nevertheless, having been highly favored of the Lord
in all my days; yea, having had a great knowledge
of the goodness and the mysteries of God, therefore I
make a record of my proceedings in my days.
2 Yea, I make a record in the language of
my father, which consists of the learning of the Jews
and the language of the Egyptians.
3 And I know that the record which I make
is true; and I make it with mine own hand;
and I make it according to my knowledge.
4 For it came to pass in the commencement of
the first year of the reign of Zedekiah, king of
Judah, (my father, Lehi, having dwelt at Jerusalem in all
his days); and in that same year there came many
prophets, prophesying unto the people that they must repent, or
the great city Jerusalem must be destroyed.
5 Wherefore it came to pass that my father, Lehi,
as he went forth prayed unto the Lord, yea, even
with all his heart, in behalf of his people.
6 And it came to pass as he prayed unto
the Lord, there came a pillar of fire and dwelt
upon a rock before him; and he saw and heard
much; and because of the things which he saw and
heard he did quake and tremble exceedingly.
7 And it came to pass that he returned to
his own house at Jerusalem; and he cast himself upon
his bed, being overcome with the Spirit and the things
which he had seen.
8 And being thus overcome with the Spirit, he was
carried away in a vision, even that he saw the
heavens open, and he thought he saw God sitting upon
his throne, surrounded with numberless concourses of angels in the
attitude of singing and praising their God.
9 And it came to pass that he saw One
descending out of the midst of heaven, and he beheld
that his luster was above that of the sun at
noon-day.
10 And he also saw twelve others following him, and
their brightness did exceed that of the stars in the
firmament.
11 And they came down and went forth upon the
face of the earth; and the first came and stood
before my father, and gave unto him a book, and
bade him that he should read.
12 And it came to pass that as he read,
he was filled with the Spirit of the Lord.
13 And he read, saying: Wo, wo, unto Jerusalem, for
I have seen thine abominations! Yea, and many things did
my father read concerning Jerusalem—that it should be destroyed, and
the inhabitants thereof; many should perish by the sword, and
many should be carried away captive into Babylon.
14 And it came to pass that when my father
had read and seen many great and marvelous things, he
did exclaim many things unto the Lord; such as: Great
and marvelous are thy works, O Lord God Almighty! Thy
throne is high in the heavens, and thy power, and
goodness, and mercy are over all the inhabitants of the
earth; and, because thou art merciful, thou wilt not suffer
those who come unto thee that they shall perish!
15 And after this manner was the language of my
father in the praising of his God; for his soul
did rejoice, and his whole heart was filled, because of
the things which he had seen, yea, which the Lord
had shown unto him.
16 And now I, Nephi, do not make a full
account of the things which my father hath written, for
he hath written many things which he saw in visions
and in dreams; and he also hath written many things
which he prophesied and spake unto his children, of which
I shall not make a full account.
17 But I shall make an account of my proceedings
in my days. Behold, I make an abridgment of the
record of my father, upon plates which I have made
with mine own hands; wherefore, after I have abridged the
record of my father then will I make an account
of mine own life.
18 Therefore, I would that ye should know, that after
the Lord had shown so many marvelous things unto my
father, Lehi, yea, concerning the destruction of Jerusalem, behold he
went forth among the people, and began to prophesy and
to declare unto them concerning the things which he had
both seen and heard.
19 And it came to pass that the Jews did
mock him because of the things which he testified of
them; for he truly testified of their wickedness and their
abominations; and he testified that the things which he saw
and heard, and also the things which he read in
the book, manifested plainly of the coming of a Messiah,
and also the redemption of the world.
20 And when the Jews heard these things they were
angry with him; yea, even as with the prophets of
old, whom they had cast out, and stoned, and slain;
and they also sought his life, that they might take
it away. But behold, I, Nephi, will show unto you
that the tender mercies of the Lord are over all
those whom he hath chosen, because of their faith, to
make them mighty even unto the power of deliverance.