Chapter 17 Nephi is commanded to build a ship—His
brethren oppose him—He exhorts them by recounting
the history of God’s dealings with Israel—Nephi is
filled with the power of God—His brethren are
forbidden to touch him, lest they wither as a dried
reed. About 592–591 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that we did again take our
journey in the wilderness; and we did travel nearly
eastward from that time forth. And we did travel
and wade through much affliction in the
wilderness; and our women did bear children in the
wilderness
2 And so great were the blessings of the Lord upon
us, that while we did live upon raw meat in the
wilderness, our women did give plenty of suck for
their children, and were strong, yea, even like
unto the men; and they began to bear their
journeyings without murmurings
3 And thus we see that the commandments of God
must be fulfilled. And if it so be that the children
of men keep the commandments of God he doth
nourish them, and strengthen them, and provide means
whereby they can accomplish the thing which he has
commanded them; wherefore, he did provide means for
us while we did sojourn in the wilderness
4 And we did sojourn for the space of many years,
yea, even eight years in the wilderness
5 And we did come to the land which we called
Bountiful, because of its much fruit and also wild
honey; and all these things were prepared of the Lord
that we might not perish. And we beheld the sea,
which we called Irreantum, which, being
interpreted, is many waters
6 And it came to pass that we did pitch our tents
by the seashore; and notwithstanding we had
suffered many afflictions and much difficulty, yea, even
so much that we cannot write them all, we were
exceedingly rejoiced when we came to the seashore;
and we called the place Bountiful, because of its
much fruit
7 And it came to pass that after I, Nephi, had
been in the land of Bountiful for the space of many
days, the voice of the Lord came unto me, saying:
Arise, and get thee into the mountain. And it came
to pass that I arose and went up into the
mountain, and cried unto the Lord
8 And it came to pass that the Lord spake unto me,
saying: Thou shalt construct a ship, after the
manner which I shall show thee, that I may carry thy
people across these waters
9 And I said: Lord, whither shall I go that I may
find ore to molten, that I may make tools to
construct the ship after the manner which thou hast
shown unto me
10 And it came to pass that the Lord told me
whither I should go to find ore, that I might make
tools
11 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did make a
bellows wherewith to blow the fire, of the skins of
beasts; and after I had made a bellows, that I
might have wherewith to blow the fire, I did smite
two stones together that I might make fire
12 For the Lord had not hitherto suffered that we
should make much fire, as we journeyed in the
wilderness; for he said: I will make thy food become
sweet, that ye cook it not
13 And I will also be your light in the
wilderness; and I will prepare the way before you, if it so
be that ye shall keep my commandments; wherefore,
inasmuch as ye shall keep my commandments ye shall
be led towards the promised land; and ye shall
know that it is by me that ye are led
14 Yea, and the Lord said also that: After ye have
arrived in the promised land, ye shall know that
I, the Lord, am God; and that I, the Lord, did
deliver you from destruction; yea, that I did bring
you out of the land of Jerusalem
15 Wherefore, I, Nephi, did strive to keep the
commandments of the Lord, and I did exhort my
brethren to faithfulness and diligence
16 And it came to pass that I did make tools of
the ore which I did molten out of the rock
17 And when my brethren saw that I was about to
build a ship, they began to murmur against me,
saying: Our brother is a fool, for he thinketh that he
can build a ship; yea, and he also thinketh that
he can cross these great waters
18 And thus my brethren did complain against me,
and were desirous that they might not labor, for
they did not believe that I could build a ship;
neither would they believe that I was instructed of
the Lord
19 And now it came to pass that I, Nephi, was
exceedingly sorrowful because of the hardness of their
hearts; and now when they saw that I began to be
sorrowful they were glad in their hearts, insomuch
that they did rejoice over me, saying: We knew
that ye could not construct a ship, for we knew that
ye were lacking in judgment; wherefore, thou
canst not accomplish so great a work
20 And thou art like unto our father, led away by
the foolish imaginations of his heart; yea, he
hath led us out of the land of Jerusalem, and we have
wandered in the wilderness for these many years;
and our women have toiled, being big with child;
and they have borne children in the wilderness and
suffered all things, save it were death; and it
would have been better that they had died before
they came out of Jerusalem than to have suffered
these afflictions
21 Behold, these many years we have suffered in
the wilderness, which time we might have enjoyed our
possessions and the land of our inheritance; yea,
and we might have been happy
22 And we know that the people who were in the
land of Jerusalem were a righteous people; for they
kept the statutes and judgments of the Lord, and
all his commandments, according to the law of Moses;
wherefore, we know that they are a righteous
people; and our father hath judged them, and hath led
us away because we would hearken unto his words;
yea, and our brother is like unto him. And after
this manner of language did my brethren murmur and
complain against us
23 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, spake unto
them, saying: Do ye believe that our fathers, who
were the children of Israel, would have been led
away out of the hands of the Egyptians if they had
not hearkened unto the words of the Lord
24 Yea, do ye suppose that they would have been
led out of bondage, if the Lord had not commanded
Moses that he should lead them out of bondage
25 Now ye know that the children of Israel were in
bondage; and ye know that they were laden with
tasks, which were grievous to be borne; wherefore,
ye know that it must needs be a good thing for
them, that they should be brought out of bondage
26 Now ye know that Moses was commanded of the
Lord to do that great work; and ye know that by his
word the waters of the Red Sea were divided hither
and thither, and they passed through on dry
ground
27 But ye know that the Egyptians were drowned in
the Red Sea, who were the armies of Pharaoh
28 And ye also know that they were fed with manna
in the wilderness
29 Yea, and ye also know that Moses, by his word
according to the power of God which was in him,
smote the rock, and there came forth water, that the
children of Israel might quench their thirst
30 And notwithstanding they being led, the Lord
their God, their Redeemer, going before them,
leading them by day and giving light unto them by night,
and doing all things for them which were
expedient for man to receive, they hardened their hearts
and blinded their minds, and reviled against Moses
and against the true and living God
31 And it came to pass that according to his word
he did destroy them; and according to his word he
did lead them; and according to his word he did do
all things for them; and there was not any thing
done save it were by his word
32 And after they had crossed the river Jordan he
did make them mighty unto the driving out of the
children of the land, yea, unto the scattering them
to destruction
33 And now, do ye suppose that the children of
this land, who were in the land of promise, who were
driven out by our fathers, do ye suppose that they
were righteous? Behold, I say unto you, Nay
34 Do ye suppose that our fathers would have been
more choice than they if they had been righteous?
I say unto you, Nay
35 Behold, the Lord esteemeth all flesh in one; he
that is righteous is favored of God. But behold,
this people had rejected every word of God, and
they were ripe in iniquity; and the fulness of the
wrath of God was upon them; and the Lord did curse
the land against them, and bless it unto our
fathers; yea, he did curse it against them unto their
destruction, and he did bless it unto our fathers
unto their obtaining power over it
36 Behold, the Lord hath created the earth that it
should be inhabited; and he hath created his
children that they should possess it
37 And he raiseth up a righteous nation, and
destroyeth the nations of the wicked
38 And he leadeth away the righteous into precious
lands, and the wicked he destroyeth, and curseth
the land unto them for their sakes
39 He ruleth high in the heavens, for it is his
throne, and this earth is his footstool
40 And he loveth those who will have him to be
their God. Behold, he loved our fathers, and he
covenanted with them, yea, even Abraham, Isaac, and
Jacob; and he remembered the covenants which he had
made; wherefore, he did bring them out of the land
of Egypt
41 And he did straiten them in the wilderness with
his rod; for they hardened their hearts, even as
ye have; and the Lord straitened them because of
their iniquity. He sent fiery flying serpents among
them; and after they were bitten he prepared a
way that they might be healed; and the labor which
they had to perform was to look; and because of the
simpleness of the way, or the easiness of it,
there were many who perished
42 And they did harden their hearts from time to
time, and they did revile against Moses, and also
against God; nevertheless, ye know that they were
led forth by his matchless power into the land of
promise
43 And now, after all these things, the time has
come that they have become wicked, yea, nearly unto
ripeness; and I know not but they are at this day
about to be destroyed; for I know that the day
must surely come that they must be destroyed, save a
few only, who shall be led away into captivity
44 Wherefore, the Lord commanded my father that he
should depart into the wilderness; and the Jews
also sought to take away his life; yea, and ye also
have sought to take away his life; wherefore, ye
are murderers in your hearts and ye are like unto
them
45 Ye are swift to do iniquity but slow to
remember the Lord your God. Ye have seen an angel, and he
spake unto you; yea, ye have heard his voice from
time to time; and he hath spoken unto you in a
still small voice, but ye were past feeling, that ye
could not feel his words; wherefore, he has
spoken unto you like unto the voice of thunder, which
did cause the earth to shake as if it were to
divide asunder
46 And ye also know that by the power of his
almighty word he can cause the earth that it shall pass
away; yea, and ye know that by his word he can
cause the rough places to be made smooth, and smooth
places shall be broken up. O, then, why is it,
that ye can be so hard in your hearts
47 Behold, my soul is rent with anguish because of
you, and my heart is pained; I fear lest ye shall
be cast off forever. Behold, I am full of the
Spirit of God, insomuch that my frame has no
strength
48 And now it came to pass that when I had spoken
these words they were angry with me, and were
desirous to throw me into the depths of the sea; and
as they came forth to lay their hands upon me I
spake unto them, saying: In the name of the Almighty
God, I command you that ye touch me not, for I am
filled with the power of God, even unto the
consuming of my flesh; and whoso shall lay his hands
upon me shall wither even as a dried reed; and he
shall be as naught before the power of God, for God
shall smite him
49 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, said unto
them that they should murmur no more against their
father; neither should they withhold their labor
from me, for God had commanded me that I should
build a ship
50 And I said unto them: If God had commanded me
to do all things I could do them. If he should
command me that I should say unto this water, be thou
earth, it should be earth; and if I should say it,
it would be done
51 And now, if the Lord has such great power, and
has wrought so many miracles among the children of
men, how is it that he cannot instruct me, that I
should build a ship
52 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, said many
things unto my brethren, insomuch that they were
confounded and could not contend against me; neither
durst they lay their hands upon me nor touch me
with their fingers, even for the space of many days.
Now they durst not do this lest they should
wither before me, so powerful was the Spirit of God;
and thus it had wrought upon them
53 And it came to pass that the Lord said unto me:
Stretch forth thine hand again unto thy brethren,
and they shall not wither before thee, but I will
shock them, saith the Lord, and this will I do,
that they may know that I am the Lord their God
54 And it came to pass that I stretched forth my
hand unto my brethren, and they did not wither
before me; but the Lord did shake them, even according
to the word which he had spoken
55 And now, they said: We know of a surety that
the Lord is with thee, for we know that it is the
power of the Lord that has shaken us. And they fell
down before me, and were about to worship me, but
I would not suffer them, saying: I am thy brother,
yea, even thy younger brother; wherefore, worship
the Lord thy God, and honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long in the land which
the Lord thy God shall give thee.