Chapter 16 The wicked take the truth to be
hard—Lehi’s sons marry the daughters of Ishmael—The
Liahona guides their course in the wilderness—Messages
from the Lord are written on the Liahona from time
to time—Ishmael dies; his family murmurs because
of afflictions. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that after I, Nephi, had
made an end of speaking to my brethren, behold
they said unto me: Thou hast declared unto us hard
things, more than we are able to bear
2 And it came to pass that I said unto them that I
knew that I had spoken hard things against the
wicked, according to the truth; and the righteous
have I justified, and testified that they should be
lifted up at the last day; wherefore, the guilty
taketh the truth to be hard, for it cutteth them to
the very center
3 And now my brethren, if ye were righteous and
were willing to hearken to the truth, and give heed
unto it, that ye might walk uprightly before God,
then ye would not murmur because of the truth, and
say: Thou speakest hard things against us
4 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did exhort my
brethren, with all diligence, to keep the
commandments of the Lord
5 And it came to pass that they did humble
themselves before the Lord; insomuch that I had joy and
great hopes of them, that they would walk in the
paths of righteousness
6 Now, all these things were said and done as my
father dwelt in a tent in the valley which he
called Lemuel
7 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, took one of
the daughters of Ishmael to wife; and also, my
brethren took of the daughters of Ishmael to wife; and
also Zoram took the eldest daughter of Ishmael to
wife
8 And thus my father had fulfilled all the
commandments of the Lord which had been given unto him.
And also, I, Nephi, had been blessed of the Lord
exceedingly
9 And it came to pass that the voice of the Lord
spake unto my father by night, and commanded him
that on the morrow he should take his journey into
the wilderness
10 And it came to pass that as my father arose in
the morning, and went forth to the tent door, to
his great astonishment he beheld upon the ground a
round ball of curious workmanship; and it was of
fine brass. And within the ball were two spindles;
and the one pointed the way whither we should go
into the wilderness
11 And it came to pass that we did gather together
whatsoever things we should carry into the
wilderness, and all the remainder of our provisions
which the Lord had given unto us; and we did take seed
of every kind that we might carry into the
wilderness
12 And it came to pass that we did take our tents
and depart into the wilderness, across the river
Laman
13 And it came to pass that we traveled for the
space of four days, nearly a south-southeast
direction, and we did pitch our tents again; and we did
call the name of the place Shazer
14 And it came to pass that we did take our bows
and our arrows, and go forth into the wilderness to
slay food for our families; and after we had
slain food for our families we did return again to our
families in the wilderness, to the place of
Shazer. And we did go forth again in the wilderness,
following the same direction, keeping in the most
fertile parts of the wilderness, which were in the
borders near the Red Sea
15 And it came to pass that we did travel for the
space of many days, slaying food by the way, with
our bows and our arrows and our stones and our
slings
16 And we did follow the directions of the ball,
which led us in the more fertile parts of the
wilderness
17 And after we had traveled for the space of many
days, we did pitch our tents for the space of a
time, that we might again rest ourselves and obtain
food for our families
18 And it came to pass that as I, Nephi, went
forth to slay food, behold, I did break my bow, which
was made of fine steel; and after I did break my
bow, behold, my brethren were angry with me because
of the loss of my bow, for we did obtain no food
19 And it came to pass that we did return without
food to our families, and being much fatigued,
because of their journeying, they did suffer much for
the want of food
20 And it came to pass that Laman and Lemuel and
the sons of Ishmael did begin to murmur
exceedingly, because of their sufferings and afflictions in
the wilderness; and also my father began to murmur
against the Lord his God; yea, and they were all
exceedingly sorrowful, even that they did murmur
against the Lord
21 Now it came to pass that I, Nephi, having been
afflicted with my brethren because of the loss of
my bow, and their bows having lost their springs,
it began to be exceedingly difficult, yea,
insomuch that we could obtain no food
22 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did speak
much unto my brethren, because they had hardened
their hearts again, even unto complaining against the
Lord their God
23 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did make out
of wood a bow, and out of a straight stick, an
arrow; wherefore, I did arm myself with a bow and an
arrow, with a sling and with stones. And I said
unto my father: Whither shall I go to obtain food
24 And it came to pass that he did inquire of the
Lord, for they had humbled themselves because of
my words; for I did say many things unto them in
the energy of my soul
25 And it came to pass that the voice of the Lord
came unto my father; and he was truly chastened
because of his murmuring against the Lord, insomuch
that he was brought down into the depths of
sorrow
26 And it came to pass that the voice of the Lord
said unto him: Look upon the ball, and behold the
things which are written
27 And it came to pass that when my father beheld
the things which were written upon the ball, he
did fear and tremble exceedingly, and also my
brethren and the sons of Ishmael and our wives
28 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, beheld the
pointers which were in the ball, that they did work
according to the faith and diligence and heed
which we did give unto them
29 And there was also written upon them a new
writing, which was plain to be read, which did give us
understanding concerning the ways of the Lord;
and it was written and changed from time to time,
according to the faith and diligence which we gave
unto it. And thus we see that by small means the
Lord can bring about great things
30 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did go forth
up into the top of the mountain, according to the
directions which were given upon the ball
31 And it came to pass that I did slay wild
beasts, insomuch that I did obtain food for our
families
32 And it came to pass that I did return to our
tents, bearing the beasts which I had slain; and now
when they beheld that I had obtained food, how
great was their joy! And it came to pass that they
did humble themselves before the Lord, and did give
thanks unto him
33 And it came to pass that we did again take our
journey, traveling nearly the same course as in
the beginning; and after we had traveled for the
space of many days we did pitch our tents again, that
we might tarry for the space of a time
34 And it came to pass that Ishmael died, and was
buried in the place which was called Nahom
35 And it came to pass that the daughters of
Ishmael did mourn exceedingly, because of the loss of
their father, and because of their afflictions in
the wilderness; and they did murmur against my
father, because he had brought them out of the land of
Jerusalem, saying: Our father is dead; yea, and
we have wandered much in the wilderness, and we
have suffered much affliction, hunger, thirst, and
fatigue; and after all these sufferings we must
perish in the wilderness with hunger
36 And thus they did murmur against my father, and
also against me; and they were desirous to return
again to Jerusalem
37 And Laman said unto Lemuel and also unto the
sons of Ishmael: Behold, let us slay our father, and
also our brother Nephi, who has taken it upon him
to be our ruler and our teacher, who are his
elder brethren
38 Now, he says that the Lord has talked with him,
and also that angels have ministered unto him.
But behold, we know that he lies unto us; and he
tells us these things, and he worketh many things by
his cunning arts, that he may deceive our eyes,
thinking, perhaps, that he may lead us away into
some strange wilderness; and after he has led us
away, he has thought to make himself a king and a
ruler over us, that he may do with us according to his
will and pleasure. And after this manner did my
brother Laman stir up their hearts to anger
39 And it came to pass that the Lord was with us,
yea, even the voice of the Lord came and did speak
many words unto them, and did chasten them
exceedingly; and after they were chastened by the voice
of the Lord they did turn away their anger, and
did repent of their sins, insomuch that the Lord did
bless us again with food, that we did not perish.