Chapter 15 Lehi’s seed are to receive the gospel
from the Gentiles in the latter days—The gathering
of Israel is likened unto an olive tree whose
natural branches will be grafted in again—Nephi
interprets the vision of the tree of life and speaks of
the justice of God in dividing the wicked from the
righteous. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that after I, Nephi, had
been carried away in the Spirit, and seen all these
things, I returned to the tent of my father
2 And it came to pass that I beheld my brethren,
and they were disputing one with another concerning
the things which my father had spoken unto them
3 For he truly spake many great things unto them,
which were hard to be understood, save a man
should inquire of the Lord; and they being hard in
their hearts, therefore they did not look unto the
Lord as they ought
4 And now I, Nephi, was grieved because of the
hardness of their hearts, and also, because of the
things which I had seen, and knew they must
unavoidably come to pass because of the great wickedness
of the children of men
5 And it came to pass that I was overcome because
of my afflictions, for I considered that mine
afflictions were great above all, because of the
destruction of my people, for I had beheld their fall
6 And it came to pass that after I had received
strength I spake unto my brethren, desiring to know
of them the cause of their disputations
7 And they said: Behold, we cannot understand the
words which our father hath spoken concerning the
natural branches of the olive tree, and also
concerning the Gentiles
8 And I said unto them: Have ye inquired of the
Lord
9 And they said unto me: We have not; for the Lord
maketh no such thing known unto us
10 Behold, I said unto them: How is it that ye do
not keep the commandments of the Lord? How is it
that ye will perish, because of the hardness of
your hearts
11 Do ye not remember the things which the Lord
hath said?—If ye will not harden your hearts, and
ask me in faith, believing that ye shall receive,
with diligence in keeping my commandments, surely
these things shall be made known unto you
12 Behold, I say unto you, that the house of
Israel was compared unto an olive tree, by the Spirit
of the Lord which was in our father; and behold are
we not broken off from the house of Israel, and
are we not a branch of the house of Israel
13 And now, the thing which our father meaneth
concerning the grafting in of the natural branches
through the fulness of the Gentiles, is, that in the
latter days, when our seed shall have dwindled in
unbelief, yea, for the space of many years, and
many generations after the Messiah shall be
manifested in body unto the children of men, then shall
the fulness of the gospel of the Messiah come unto
the Gentiles, and from the Gentiles unto the
remnant of our seed
14 And at that day shall the remnant of our seed
know that they are of the house of Israel, and that
they are the covenant people of the Lord; and
then shall they know and come to the knowledge of
their forefathers, and also to the knowledge of the
gospel of their Redeemer, which was ministered unto
their fathers by him; wherefore, they shall come
to the knowledge of their Redeemer and the very
points of his doctrine, that they may know how to
come unto him and be saved
15 And then at that day will they not rejoice and
give praise unto their everlasting God, their rock
and their salvation? Yea, at that day, will they
not receive the strength and nourishment from the
true vine? Yea, will they not come unto the true
fold of God
16 Behold, I say unto you, Yea; they shall be
remembered again among the house of Israel; they shall
be grafted in, being a natural branch of the
olive tree, into the true olive tree
17 And this is what our father meaneth; and he
meaneth that it will not come to pass until after
they are scattered by the Gentiles; and he meaneth
that it shall come by way of the Gentiles, that the
Lord may show his power unto the Gentiles, for the
very cause that he shall be rejected of the Jews,
or of the house of Israel
18 Wherefore, our father hath not spoken of our
seed alone, but also of all the house of Israel,
pointing to the covenant which should be fulfilled in
the latter days; which covenant the Lord made to
our father Abraham, saying: In thy seed shall all
the kindreds of the earth be blessed
19 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, spake much
unto them concerning these things; yea, I spake
unto them concerning the restoration of the Jews in
the latter days
20 And I did rehearse unto them the words of
Isaiah, who spake concerning the restoration of the
Jews, or of the house of Israel; and after they were
restored they should no more be confounded,
neither should they be scattered again. And it came to
pass that I did speak many words unto my brethren,
that they were pacified and did humble themselves
before the Lord
21 And it came to pass that they did speak unto me
again, saying: What meaneth this thing which our
father saw in a dream? What meaneth the tree which
he saw
22 And I said unto them: It was a representation
of the tree of life
23 And they said unto me: What meaneth the rod of
iron which our father saw, that led to the tree
24 And I said unto them that it was the word of
God; and whoso would hearken unto the word of God,
and would hold fast unto it, they would never
perish; neither could the temptations and the fiery
darts of the adversary overpower them unto blindness,
to lead them away to destruction
25 Wherefore, I, Nephi, did exhort them to give
heed unto the word of the Lord; yea, I did exhort
them with all the energies of my soul, and with all
the faculty which I possessed, that they would
give heed to the word of God and remember to keep his
commandments always in all things
26 And they said unto me: What meaneth the river
of water which our father saw
27 And I said unto them that the water which my
father saw was filthiness; and so much was his mind
swallowed up in other things that he beheld not
the filthiness of the water
28 And I said unto them that it was an awful gulf,
which separated the wicked from the tree of life,
and also from the saints of God
29 And I said unto them that it was a
representation of that awful hell, which the angel said unto
me was prepared for the wicked
30 And I said unto them that our father also saw
that the justice of God did also divide the wicked
from the righteous; and the brightness thereof was
like unto the brightness of a flaming fire, which
ascendeth up unto God forever and ever, and hath
no end
31 And they said unto me: Doth this thing mean the
torment of the body in the days of probation, or
doth it mean the final state of the soul after the
death of the temporal body, or doth it speak of
the things which are temporal
32 And it came to pass that I said unto them that
it was a representation of things both temporal
and spiritual; for the day should come that they
must be judged of their works, yea, even the works
which were done by the temporal body in their days
of probation
33 Wherefore, if they should die in their
wickedness they must be cast off also, as to the things
which are spiritual, which are pertaining to
righteousness; wherefore, they must be brought to stand
before God, to be judged of their works; and if
their works have been filthiness they must needs be
filthy; and if they be filthy it must needs be that
they cannot dwell in the kingdom of God; if so,
the kingdom of God must be filthy also
34 But behold, I say unto you, the kingdom of God
is not filthy, and there cannot any unclean thing
enter into the kingdom of God; wherefore there
must needs be a place of filthiness prepared for that
which is filthy
35 And there is a place prepared, yea, even that
awful hell of which I have spoken, and the devil is
the preparator of it; wherefore the final state
of the souls of men is to dwell in the kingdom of
God, or to be cast out because of that justice of
which I have spoken
36 Wherefore, the wicked are rejected from the
righteous, and also from that tree of life, whose
fruit is most precious and most desirable above all
other fruits; yea, and it is the greatest of all
the gifts of God. And thus I spake unto my brethren.
Amen.