Chapter 20 The Lord reveals His purposes to
Israel—Israel has been chosen in the furnace of
affliction and is to go forth from Babylon—Compare
Isaiah
48. About 588–570 B.C.
1 Hearken and hear this, O house of Jacob, who are
called by the name of Israel, and are come forth
out of the waters of Judah, or out of the waters
of baptism, who swear by the name of the Lord, and
make mention of the God of Israel, yet they swear
not in truth nor in righteousness
2 Nevertheless, they call themselves of the holy
city, but they do not stay themselves upon the God
of Israel, who is the Lord of Hosts; yea, the Lord
of Hosts is his name
3 Behold, I have declared the former things from
the beginning; and they went forth out of my mouth,
and I showed them. I did show them suddenly
4 And I did it because I knew that thou art
obstinate, and thy neck is an iron sinew, and thy brow
brass
5 And I have even from the beginning declared to
thee; before it came to pass I showed them thee;
and I showed them for fear lest thou shouldst
say—Mine idol hath done them, and my graven image, and
my molten image hath commanded them
6 Thou hast seen and heard all this; and will ye
not declare them? And that I have showed thee new
things from this time, even hidden things, and thou
didst not know them
7 They are created now, and not from the
beginning, even before the day when thou heardest them not
they were declared unto thee, lest thou shouldst
say—Behold I knew them
8 Yea, and thou heardest not; yea, thou knewest
not; yea, from that time thine ear was not opened;
for I knew that thou wouldst deal very
treacherously, and wast called a transgressor from the womb
9 Nevertheless, for my name’s sake will I defer
mine anger, and for my praise will I refrain from
thee, that I cut thee not off
10 For, behold, I have refined thee, I have chosen
thee in the furnace of affliction
11 For mine own sake, yea, for mine own sake will
I do this, for I will not suffer my name to be
polluted, and I will not give my glory unto another
12 Hearken unto me, O Jacob, and Israel my called,
for I am he; I am the first, and I am also the
last
13 Mine hand hath also laid the foundation of the
earth, and my right hand hath spanned the heavens.
I call unto them and they stand up together
14 All ye, assemble yourselves, and hear; who
among them hath declared these things unto them? The
Lord hath loved him; yea, and he will fulfil his
word which he hath declared by them; and he will do
his pleasure on Babylon, and his arm shall come
upon the Chaldeans
15 Also, saith the Lord; I the Lord, yea, I have
spoken; yea, I have called him to declare, I have
brought him, and he shall make his way prosperous
16 Come ye near unto me; I have not spoken in
secret; from the beginning, from the time that it was
declared have I spoken; and the Lord God, and his
Spirit, hath sent me
17 And thus saith the Lord, thy Redeemer, the Holy
One of Israel; I have sent him, the Lord thy God
who teacheth thee to profit, who leadeth thee by
the way thou shouldst go, hath done it
18 O that thou hadst hearkened to my
commandments—then had thy peace been as a river, and thy
righteousness as the waves of the sea
19 Thy seed also had been as the sand; the
offspring of thy bowels like the gravel thereof; his name
should not have been cut off nor destroyed from
before me
20 Go ye forth of Babylon, flee ye from the
Chaldeans, with a voice of singing declare ye, tell
this, utter to the end of the earth; say ye: The Lord
hath redeemed his servant Jacob
21 And they thirsted not; he led them through the
deserts; he caused the waters to flow out of the
rock for them; he clave the rock also and the
waters gushed out
22 And notwithstanding he hath done all this, and
greater also, there is no peace, saith the Lord,
unto the wicked.