Chapter 11 Nephi sees the Spirit of the Lord and
is shown in vision the tree of life—He sees the
mother of the Son of God and learns of the
condescension of God—He sees the baptism, ministry, and
crucifixion of the Lamb of God—He sees also the call
and ministry of the Twelve Apostles of the Lamb.
About 600–592 B.C.
1 For it came to pass after I had desired to know
the things that my father had seen, and believing
that the Lord was able to make them known unto me,
as I sat pondering in mine heart I was caught
away in the Spirit of the Lord, yea, into an
exceedingly high mountain, which I never had before seen,
and upon which I never had before set my foot
2 And the Spirit said unto me: Behold, what
desirest thou
3 And I said: I desire to behold the things which
my father saw
4 And the Spirit said unto me: Believest thou that
thy father saw the tree of which he hath spoken
5 And I said: Yea, thou knowest that I believe all
the words of my father
6 And when I had spoken these words, the Spirit
cried with a loud voice, saying: Hosanna to the
Lord, the most high God; for he is God over all the
earth, yea, even above all. And blessed art thou,
Nephi, because thou believest in the Son of the most
high God; wherefore, thou shalt behold the things
which thou hast desired
7 And behold this thing shall be given unto thee
for a sign, that after thou hast beheld the tree
which bore the fruit which thy father tasted, thou
shalt also behold a man descending out of heaven,
and him shall ye witness; and after ye have
witnessed him ye shall bear record that it is the Son of
God
8 And it came to pass that the Spirit said unto
me: Look! And I looked and beheld a tree; and it was
like unto the tree which my father had seen; and
the beauty thereof was far beyond, yea, exceeding
of all beauty; and the whiteness thereof did
exceed the whiteness of the driven snow
9 And it came to pass after I had seen the tree, I
said unto the Spirit: I behold thou hast shown
unto me the tree which is precious above all
10 And he said unto me: What desirest thou
11 And I said unto him: To know the interpretation
thereof—for I spake unto him as a man speaketh;
for I beheld that he was in the form of a man; yet
nevertheless, I knew that it was the Spirit of the
Lord; and he spake unto me as a man speaketh with
another
12 And it came to pass that he said unto me: Look!
And I looked as if to look upon him, and I saw
him not; for he had gone from before my presence
13 And it came to pass that I looked and beheld
the great city of Jerusalem, and also other cities.
And I beheld the city of Nazareth; and in the city
of Nazareth I beheld a virgin, and she was
exceedingly fair and white
14 And it came to pass that I saw the heavens
open; and an angel came down and stood before me; and
he said unto me: Nephi, what beholdest thou
15 And I said unto him: A virgin, most beautiful
and fair above all other virgins
16 And he said unto me: Knowest thou the
condescension of God
17 And I said unto him: I know that he loveth his
children; nevertheless, I do not know the meaning
of all things
18 And he said unto me: Behold, the virgin whom
thou seest is the mother of the Son of God, after
the manner of the flesh
19 And it came to pass that I beheld that she was
carried away in the Spirit; and after she had been
carried away in the Spirit for the space of a
time the angel spake unto me, saying: Look
20 And I looked and beheld the virgin again,
bearing a child in her arms
21 And the angel said unto me: Behold the Lamb of
God, yea, even the Son of the Eternal Father!
Knowest thou the meaning of the tree which thy father
saw
22 And I answered him, saying: Yea, it is the love
of God, which sheddeth itself abroad in the
hearts of the children of men; wherefore, it is the
most desirable above all things
23 And he spake unto me, saying: Yea, and the most
joyous to the soul
24 And after he had said these words, he said unto
me: Look! And I looked, and I beheld the Son of
God going forth among the children of men; and I
saw many fall down at his feet and worship him
25 And it came to pass that I beheld that the rod
of iron, which my father had seen, was the word of
God, which led to the fountain of living waters,
or to the tree of life; which waters are a
representation of the love of God; and I also beheld that
the tree of life was a representation of the love
of God
26 And the angel said unto me again: Look and
behold the condescension of God
27 And I looked and beheld the Redeemer of the
world, of whom my father had spoken; and I also
beheld the prophet who should prepare the way before
him. And the Lamb of God went forth and was baptized
of him; and after he was baptized, I beheld the
heavens open, and the Holy Ghost come down out of
heaven and abide upon him in the form of a dove
28 And I beheld that he went forth ministering
unto the people, in power and great glory; and the
multitudes were gathered together to hear him; and I
beheld that they cast him out from among them
29 And I also beheld twelve others following him.
And it came to pass that they were carried away in
the Spirit from before my face, and I saw them
not
30 And it came to pass that the angel spake unto
me again, saying: Look! And I looked, and I beheld
the heavens open again, and I saw angels
descending upon the children of men; and they did minister
unto them
31 And he spake unto me again, saying: Look! And I
looked, and I beheld the Lamb of God going forth
among the children of men. And I beheld multitudes
of people who were sick, and who were afflicted
with all manner of diseases, and with devils and
unclean spirits; and the angel spake and showed all
these things unto me. And they were healed by the
power of the Lamb of God; and the devils and the
unclean spirits were cast out
32 And it came to pass that the angel spake unto
me again, saying: Look! And I looked and beheld the
Lamb of God, that he was taken by the people;
yea, the Son of the everlasting God was judged of the
world; and I saw and bear record
33 And I, Nephi, saw that he was lifted up upon
the cross and slain for the sins of the world
34 And after he was slain I saw the multitudes of
the earth, that they were gathered together to
fight against the apostles of the Lamb; for thus were
the twelve called by the angel of the Lord
35 And the multitude of the earth was gathered
together; and I beheld that they were in a large and
spacious building, like unto the building which my
father saw. And the angel of the Lord spake unto
me again, saying: Behold the world and the wisdom
thereof; yea, behold the house of Israel hath
gathered together to fight against the twelve apostles
of the Lamb
36 And it came to pass that I saw and bear record,
that the great and spacious building was the
pride of the world; and it fell, and the fall thereof
was exceedingly great. And the angel of the Lord
spake unto me again, saying: Thus shall be the
destruction of all nations, kindreds, tongues, and
people, that shall fight against the twelve apostles
of the Lamb.