Chapter 7 Lehi’s sons return to Jerusalem and
invite Ishmael and his household to join them in their
journey—Laman and others rebel—Nephi exhorts his
brethren to have faith in the Lord—They bind him
with cords and plan his destruction—He is freed by
the power of faith—His brethren ask
forgiveness—Lehi and his company offer sacrifice and burnt
offerings. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And now I would that ye might know, that after
my father, Lehi, had made an end of prophesying
concerning his seed, it came to pass that the Lord
spake unto him again, saying that it was not meet
for him, Lehi, that he should take his family into
the wilderness alone; but that his sons should take
daughters to wife, that they might raise up seed
unto the Lord in the land of promise
2 And it came to pass that the Lord commanded him
that I, Nephi, and my brethren, should again
return unto the land of Jerusalem, and bring down
Ishmael and his family into the wilderness
3 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did again,
with my brethren, go forth into the wilderness to go
up to Jerusalem
4 And it came to pass that we went up unto the
house of Ishmael, and we did gain favor in the sight
of Ishmael, insomuch that we did speak unto him
the words of the Lord
5 And it came to pass that the Lord did soften the
heart of Ishmael, and also his household,
insomuch that they took their journey with us down into
the wilderness to the tent of our father
6 And it came to pass that as we journeyed in the
wilderness, behold Laman and Lemuel, and two of
the daughters of Ishmael, and the two sons of
Ishmael and their families, did rebel against us; yea,
against me, Nephi, and Sam, and their father,
Ishmael, and his wife, and his three other daughters
7 And it came to pass in the which rebellion, they
were desirous to return unto the land of
Jerusalem
8 And now I, Nephi, being grieved for the hardness
of their hearts, therefore I spake unto them,
saying, yea, even unto Laman and unto Lemuel: Behold
ye are mine elder brethren, and how is it that ye
are so hard in your hearts, and so blind in your
minds, that ye have need that I, your younger
brother, should speak unto you, yea, and set an example
for you
9 How is it that ye have not hearkened unto the
word of the Lord
10 How is it that ye have forgotten that ye have
seen an angel of the Lord
11 Yea, and how is it that ye have forgotten what
great things the Lord hath done for us, in
delivering us out of the hands of Laban, and also that we
should obtain the record
12 Yea, and how is it that ye have forgotten that
the Lord is able to do all things according to his
will, for the children of men, if it so be that
they exercise faith in him? Wherefore, let us be
faithful to him
13 And if it so be that we are faithful to him, we
shall obtain the land of promise; and ye shall
know at some future period that the word of the Lord
shall be fulfilled concerning the destruction of
Jerusalem; for all things which the Lord hath
spoken concerning the destruction of Jerusalem must be
fulfilled
14 For behold, the Spirit of the Lord ceaseth soon
to strive with them; for behold, they have
rejected the prophets, and Jeremiah have they cast into
prison. And they have sought to take away the life
of my father, insomuch that they have driven him
out of the land
15 Now behold, I say unto you that if ye will
return unto Jerusalem ye shall also perish with them.
And now, if ye have choice, go up to the land, and
remember the words which I speak unto you, that
if ye go ye will also perish; for thus the Spirit
of the Lord constraineth me that I should speak
16 And it came to pass that when I, Nephi, had
spoken these words unto my brethren, they were angry
with me. And it came to pass that they did lay
their hands upon me, for behold, they were
exceedingly wroth, and they did bind me with cords, for they
sought to take away my life, that they might
leave me in the wilderness to be devoured by wild
beasts
17 But it came to pass that I prayed unto the
Lord, saying: O Lord, according to my faith which is
in thee, wilt thou deliver me from the hands of my
brethren; yea, even give me strength that I may
burst these bands with which I am bound
18 And it came to pass that when I had said these
words, behold, the bands were loosed from off my
hands and feet, and I stood before my brethren, and
I spake unto them again
19 And it came to pass that they were angry with
me again, and sought to lay hands upon me; but
behold, one of the daughters of Ishmael, yea, and also
her mother, and one of the sons of Ishmael, did
plead with my brethren, insomuch that they did
soften their hearts; and they did cease striving to
take away my life
20 And it came to pass that they were sorrowful,
because of their wickedness, insomuch that they did
bow down before me, and did plead with me that I
would forgive them of the thing that they had done
against me
21 And it came to pass that I did frankly forgive
them all that they had done, and I did exhort them
that they would pray unto the Lord their God for
forgiveness. And it came to pass that they did so.
And after they had done praying unto the Lord we
did again travel on our journey towards the tent
of our father
22 And it came to pass that we did come down unto
the tent of our father. And after I and my
brethren and all the house of Ishmael had come down unto
the tent of my father, they did give thanks unto
the Lord their God; and they did offer sacrifice
and burnt offerings unto him.