Chapter 4 Nephi slays Laban at the Lord’s command
and then secures the plates of brass by
stratagem—Zoram chooses to join Lehi’s family in the
wilderness. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that I spake unto my
brethren, saying: Let us go up again unto Jerusalem, and
let us be faithful in keeping the commandments of
the Lord; for behold he is mightier than all the
earth, then why not mightier than Laban and his
fifty, yea, or even than his tens of thousands
2 Therefore let us go up; let us be strong like
unto Moses; for he truly spake unto the waters of
the Red Sea and they divided hither and thither, and
our fathers came through, out of captivity, on
dry ground, and the armies of Pharaoh did follow and
were drowned in the waters of the Red Sea
3 Now behold ye know that this is true; and ye
also know that an angel hath spoken unto you;
wherefore can ye doubt? Let us go up; the Lord is able to
deliver us, even as our fathers, and to destroy
Laban, even as the Egyptians
4 Now when I had spoken these words, they were yet
wroth, and did still continue to murmur;
nevertheless they did follow me up until we came without
the walls of Jerusalem
5 And it was by night; and I caused that they
should hide themselves without the walls. And after
they had hid themselves, I, Nephi, crept into the
city and went forth towards the house of Laban
6 And I was led by the Spirit, not knowing
beforehand the things which I should do
7 Nevertheless I went forth, and as I came near
unto the house of Laban I beheld a man, and he had
fallen to the earth before me, for he was drunken
with wine
8 And when I came to him I found that it was
Laban
9 And I beheld his sword, and I drew it forth from
the sheath thereof; and the hilt thereof was of
pure gold, and the workmanship thereof was
exceedingly fine, and I saw that the blade thereof was of
the most precious steel
10 And it came to pass that I was constrained by
the Spirit that I should kill Laban; but I said in
my heart: Never at any time have I shed the blood
of man. And I shrunk and would that I might not
slay him
11 And the Spirit said unto me again: Behold the
Lord hath delivered him into thy hands. Yea, and I
also knew that he had sought to take away mine own
life; yea, and he would not hearken unto the
commandments of the Lord; and he also had taken away
our property
12 And it came to pass that the Spirit said unto
me again: Slay him, for the Lord hath delivered him
into thy hands
13 Behold the Lord slayeth the wicked to bring
forth his righteous purposes. It is better that one
man should perish than that a nation should dwindle
and perish in unbelief
14 And now, when I, Nephi, had heard these words,
I remembered the words of the Lord which he spake
unto me in the wilderness, saying that: Inasmuch
as thy seed shall keep my commandments, they shall
prosper in the land of promise
15 Yea, and I also thought that they could not
keep the commandments of the Lord according to the
law of Moses, save they should have the law
16 And I also knew that the law was engraven upon
the plates of brass
17 And again, I knew that the Lord had delivered
Laban into my hands for this cause—that I might
obtain the records according to his commandments
18 Therefore I did obey the voice of the Spirit,
and took Laban by the hair of the head, and I smote
off his head with his own sword
19 And after I had smitten off his head with his
own sword, I took the garments of Laban and put
them upon mine own body; yea, even every whit; and I
did gird on his armor about my loins
20 And after I had done this, I went forth unto
the treasury of Laban. And as I went forth towards
the treasury of Laban, behold, I saw the servant of
Laban who had the keys of the treasury. And I
commanded him in the voice of Laban, that he should
go with me into the treasury
21 And he supposed me to be his master, Laban, for
he beheld the garments and also the sword girded
about my loins
22 And he spake unto me concerning the elders of
the Jews, he knowing that his master, Laban, had
been out by night among them
23 And I spake unto him as if it had been Laban
24 And I also spake unto him that I should carry
the engravings, which were upon the plates of
brass, to my elder brethren, who were without the
walls
25 And I also bade him that he should follow me
26 And he, supposing that I spake of the brethren
of the church, and that I was truly that Laban
whom I had slain, wherefore he did follow me
27 And he spake unto me many times concerning the
elders of the Jews, as I went forth unto my
brethren, who were without the walls
28 And it came to pass that when Laman saw me he
was exceedingly frightened, and also Lemuel and
Sam. And they fled from before my presence; for they
supposed it was Laban, and that he had slain me
and had sought to take away their lives also
29 And it came to pass that I called after them,
and they did hear me; wherefore they did cease to
flee from my presence
30 And it came to pass that when the servant of
Laban beheld my brethren he began to tremble, and
was about to flee from before me and return to the
city of Jerusalem
31 And now I, Nephi, being a man large in stature,
and also having received much strength of the
Lord, therefore I did seize upon the servant of
Laban, and held him, that he should not flee
32 And it came to pass that I spake with him, that
if he would hearken unto my words, as the Lord
liveth, and as I live, even so that if he would
hearken unto our words, we would spare his life
33 And I spake unto him, even with an oath, that
he need not fear; that he should be a free man like
unto us if he would go down in the wilderness
with us
34 And I also spake unto him, saying: Surely the
Lord hath commanded us to do this thing; and shall
we not be diligent in keeping the commandments of
the Lord? Therefore, if thou wilt go down into the
wilderness to my father thou shalt have place
with us
35 And it came to pass that Zoram did take courage
at the words which I spake. Now Zoram was the
name of the servant; and he promised that he would go
down into the wilderness unto our father. Yea,
and he also made an oath unto us that he would tarry
with us from that time forth
36 Now we were desirous that he should tarry with
us for this cause, that the Jews might not know
concerning our flight into the wilderness, lest they
should pursue us and destroy us
37 And it came to pass that when Zoram had made an
oath unto us, our fears did cease concerning him
38 And it came to pass that we took the plates of
brass and the servant of Laban, and departed into
the wilderness, and journeyed unto the tent of our
father.