Chapter 19 Nephi makes plates of ore and records
the history of his people—The God of Israel will
come six hundred years from the time Lehi left
Jerusalem—Nephi tells of His sufferings and
crucifixion—The Jews will be despised and scattered until the
latter days, when they will return unto the Lord.
About 588–570 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that the Lord commanded me,
wherefore I did make plates of ore that I might
engraven upon them the record of my people. And upon
the plates which I made I did engraven the record
of my father, and also our journeyings in the
wilderness, and the prophecies of my father; and also
many of mine own prophecies have I engraven upon
them
2 And I knew not at the time when I made them that
I should be commanded of the Lord to make these
plates; wherefore, the record of my father, and the
genealogy of his fathers, and the more part of
all our proceedings in the wilderness are engraven
upon those first plates of which I have spoken;
wherefore, the things which transpired before I made
these plates are, of a truth, more particularly
made mention upon the first plates
3 And after I had made these plates by way of
commandment, I, Nephi, received a commandment that the
ministry and the prophecies, the more plain and
precious parts of them, should be written upon
these plates; and that the things which were written
should be kept for the instruction of my people,
who should possess the land, and also for other wise
purposes, which purposes are known unto the Lord
4 Wherefore, I, Nephi, did make a record upon the
other plates, which gives an account, or which
gives a greater account of the wars and contentions
and destructions of my people. And this have I
done, and commanded my people what they should do
after I was gone; and that these plates should be
handed down from one generation to another, or from
one prophet to another, until further commandments
of the Lord
5 And an account of my making these plates shall
be given hereafter; and then, behold, I proceed
according to that which I have spoken; and this I do
that the more sacred things may be kept for the
knowledge of my people
6 Nevertheless, I do not write anything upon
plates save it be that I think it be sacred. And now,
if I do err, even did they err of old; not that I
would excuse myself because of other men, but
because of the weakness which is in me, according to
the flesh, I would excuse myself
7 For the things which some men esteem to be of
great worth, both to the body and soul, others set
at naught and trample under their feet. Yea, even
the very God of Israel do men trample under their
feet; I say, trample under their feet but I would
speak in other words—they set him at naught, and
hearken not to the voice of his counsels
8 And behold he cometh, according to the words of
the angel, in six hundred years from the time my
father left Jerusalem
9 And the world, because of their iniquity, shall
judge him to be a thing of naught; wherefore they
scourge him, and he suffereth it; and they smite
him, and he suffereth it. Yea, they spit upon him,
and he suffereth it, because of his loving
kindness and his long-suffering towards the children of
men
10 And the God of our fathers, who were led out of
Egypt, out of bondage, and also were preserved in
the wilderness by him, yea, the God of Abraham,
and of Isaac, and the God of Jacob, yieldeth
himself, according to the words of the angel, as a man,
into the hands of wicked men, to be lifted up,
according to the words of Zenock, and to be
crucified, according to the words of Neum, and to be buried
in a sepulchre, according to the words of Zenos,
which he spake concerning the three days of
darkness, which should be a sign given of his death unto
those who should inhabit the isles of the sea,
more especially given unto those who are of the
house of Israel
11 For thus spake the prophet: The Lord God surely
shall visit all the house of Israel at that day,
some with his voice, because of their
righteousness, unto their great joy and salvation, and others
with the thunderings and the lightnings of his
power, by tempest, by fire, and by smoke, and vapor
of darkness, and by the opening of the earth, and
by mountains which shall be carried up
12 And all these things must surely come, saith
the prophet Zenos. And the rocks of the earth must
rend; and because of the groanings of the earth,
many of the kings of the isles of the sea shall be
wrought upon by the Spirit of God, to exclaim: The
God of nature suffers
13 And as for those who are at Jerusalem, saith
the prophet, they shall be scourged by all people,
because they crucify the God of Israel, and turn
their hearts aside, rejecting signs and wonders, and
the power and glory of the God of Israel
14 And because they turn their hearts aside, saith
the prophet, and have despised the Holy One of
Israel, they shall wander in the flesh, and perish,
and become a hiss and a byword, and be hated among
all nations
15 Nevertheless, when that day cometh, saith the
prophet, that they no more turn aside their hearts
against the Holy One of Israel, then will he
remember the covenants which he made to their fathers
16 Yea, then will he remember the isles of the
sea; yea, and all the people who are of the house of
Israel, will I gather in, saith the Lord,
according to the words of the prophet Zenos, from the four
quarters of the earth
17 Yea, and all the earth shall see the salvation
of the Lord, saith the prophet; every nation,
kindred, tongue and people shall be blessed
18 And I, Nephi, have written these things unto my
people, that perhaps I might persuade them that
they would remember the Lord their Redeemer
19 Wherefore, I speak unto all the house of
Israel, if it so be that they should obtain these
things
20 For behold, I have workings in the spirit,
which doth weary me even that all my joints are weak,
for those who are at Jerusalem; for had not the
Lord been merciful, to show unto me concerning them,
even as he had prophets of old, I should have
perished also
21 And he surely did show unto the prophets of old
all things concerning them; and also he did show
unto many concerning us; wherefore, it must needs
be that we know concerning them for they are
written upon the plates of brass
22 Now it came to pass that I, Nephi, did teach my
brethren these things; and it came to pass that I
did read many things to them, which were engraven
upon the plates of brass, that they might know
concerning the doings of the Lord in other lands,
among people of old
23 And I did read many things unto them which were
written in the books of Moses; but that I might
more fully persuade them to believe in the Lord
their Redeemer I did read unto them that which was
written by the prophet Isaiah; for I did liken all
scriptures unto us, that it might be for our profit
and learning
24 Wherefore I spake unto them, saying: Hear ye
the words of the prophet, ye who are a remnant of
the house of Israel, a branch who have been broken
off; hear ye the words of the prophet, which were
written unto all the house of Israel, and liken
them unto yourselves, that ye may have hope as well
as your brethren from whom ye have been broken off;
for after this manner has the prophet written.