Chapter 14 An angel tells Nephi of the blessings
and cursings to fall upon the Gentiles—There are
only two churches: the Church of the Lamb of God and
the church of the devil—The Saints of God in all
nations are persecuted by the great and abominable
church—The Apostle John will write concerning the
end of the world. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And it shall come to pass, that if the Gentiles
shall hearken unto the Lamb of God in that day
that he shall manifest himself unto them in word, and
also in power, in very deed, unto the taking away
of their stumbling blocks
2 And harden not their hearts against the Lamb of
God, they shall be numbered among the seed of thy
father; yea, they shall be numbered among the
house of Israel; and they shall be a blessed people
upon the promised land forever; they shall be no
more brought down into captivity; and the house of
Israel shall no more be confounded
3 And that great pit, which hath been digged for
them by that great and abominable church, which was
founded by the devil and his children, that he
might lead away the souls of men down to hell—yea,
that great pit which hath been digged for the
destruction of men shall be filled by those who digged
it, unto their utter destruction, saith the Lamb
of God; not the destruction of the soul, save it be
the casting of it into that hell which hath no
end
4 For behold, this is according to the captivity
of the devil, and also according to the justice of
God, upon all those who will work wickedness and
abomination before him
5 And it came to pass that the angel spake unto
me, Nephi, saying: Thou hast beheld that if the
Gentiles repent it shall be well with them; and thou
also knowest concerning the covenants of the Lord
unto the house of Israel; and thou also hast heard
that whoso repenteth not must perish
6 Therefore, wo be unto the Gentiles if it so be
that they harden their hearts against the Lamb of
God
7 For the time cometh, saith the Lamb of God, that
I will work a great and a marvelous work among
the children of men; a work which shall be
everlasting, either on the one hand or on the other—either
to the convincing of them unto peace and life
eternal, or unto the deliverance of them to the
hardness of their hearts and the blindness of their
minds unto their being brought down into captivity,
and also into destruction, both temporally and
spiritually, according to the captivity of the devil,
of which I have spoken
8 And it came to pass that when the angel had
spoken these words, he said unto me: Rememberest thou
the covenants of the Father unto the house of
Israel? I said unto him, Yea
9 And it came to pass that he said unto me: Look,
and behold that great and abominable church, which
is the mother of abominations, whose founder is
the devil
10 And he said unto me: Behold there are save two
churches only; the one is the church of the Lamb
of God, and the other is the church of the devil;
wherefore, whoso belongeth not to the church of the
Lamb of God belongeth to that great church, which
is the mother of abominations; and she is the
whore of all the earth
11 And it came to pass that I looked and beheld
the whore of all the earth, and she sat upon many
waters; and she had dominion over all the earth,
among all nations, kindreds, tongues, and people
12 And it came to pass that I beheld the church of
the Lamb of God, and its numbers were few,
because of the wickedness and abominations of the whore
who sat upon many waters; nevertheless, I beheld
that the church of the Lamb, who were the saints of
God, were also upon all the face of the earth;
and their dominions upon the face of the earth were
small, because of the wickedness of the great
whore whom I saw
13 And it came to pass that I beheld that the
great mother of abominations did gather together
multitudes upon the face of all the earth, among all
the nations of the Gentiles, to fight against the
Lamb of God
14 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, beheld the
power of the Lamb of God, that it descended upon
the saints of the church of the Lamb, and upon the
covenant people of the Lord, who were scattered
upon all the face of the earth; and they were armed
with righteousness and with the power of God in
great glory
15 And it came to pass that I beheld that the
wrath of God was poured out upon that great and
abominable church, insomuch that there were wars and
rumors of wars among all the nations and kindreds of
the earth
16 And as there began to be wars and rumors of
wars among all the nations which belonged to the
mother of abominations, the angel spake unto me,
saying: Behold, the wrath of God is upon the mother of
harlots; and behold, thou seest all these things
17 And when the day cometh that the wrath of God
is poured out upon the mother of harlots, which is
the great and abominable church of all the earth,
whose founder is the devil, then, at that day, the
work of the Father shall commence, in preparing
the way for the fulfilling of his covenants, which
he hath made to his people who are of the house of
Israel
18 And it came to pass that the angel spake unto
me, saying: Look
19 And I looked and beheld a man, and he was
dressed in a white robe
20 And the angel said unto me: Behold one of the
twelve apostles of the Lamb
21 Behold, he shall see and write the remainder of
these things; yea, and also many things which
have been
22 And he shall also write concerning the end of
the world
23 Wherefore, the things which he shall write are
just and true; and behold they are written in the
book which thou beheld proceeding out of the mouth
of the Jew; and at the time they proceeded out of
the mouth of the Jew, or, at the time the book
proceeded out of the mouth of the Jew, the things
which were written were plain and pure, and most
precious and easy to the understanding of all men
24 And behold, the things which this apostle of
the Lamb shall write are many things which thou hast
seen; and behold, the remainder shalt thou see
25 But the things which thou shalt see hereafter
thou shalt not write; for the Lord God hath
ordained the apostle of the Lamb of God that he should
write them
26 And also others who have been, to them hath he
shown all things, and they have written them; and
they are sealed up to come forth in their purity,
according to the truth which is in the Lamb, in
the own due time of the Lord, unto the house of
Israel
27 And I, Nephi, heard and bear record, that the
name of the apostle of the Lamb was John, according
to the word of the angel
28 And behold, I, Nephi, am forbidden that I
should write the remainder of the things which I saw
and heard; wherefore the things which I have written
sufficeth me; and I have written but a small part
of the things which I saw
29 And I bear record that I saw the things which
my father saw, and the angel of the Lord did make
them known unto me
30 And now I make an end of speaking concerning
the things which I saw while I was carried away in
the Spirit; and if all the things which I saw are
not written, the things which I have written are
true. And thus it is. Amen.