Chapter 10 Lehi predicts that the Jews will be
taken captive by the Babylonians—He tells of the
coming among the Jews of a Messiah, a Savior, a
Redeemer—Lehi tells also of the coming of the one who
should baptize the Lamb of God—Lehi tells of the
death and resurrection of the Messiah—He compares the
scattering and gathering of Israel to an olive
tree—Nephi speaks of the Son of God, of the gift of
the Holy Ghost, and of the need for righteousness.
About 600–592 B.C.
1 And now I, Nephi, proceed to give an account
upon these plates of my proceedings, and my reign and
ministry; wherefore, to proceed with mine
account, I must speak somewhat of the things of my
father, and also of my brethren
2 For behold, it came to pass after my father had
made an end of speaking the words of his dream,
and also of exhorting them to all diligence, he
spake unto them concerning the Jews
3 That after they should be destroyed, even that
great city Jerusalem, and many be carried away
captive into Babylon, according to the own due time of
the Lord, they should return again, yea, even be
brought back out of captivity; and after they
should be brought back out of captivity they should
possess again the land of their inheritance
4 Yea, even six hundred years from the time that
my father left Jerusalem, a prophet would the Lord
God raise up among the Jews—even a Messiah, or, in
other words, a Savior of the world
5 And he also spake concerning the prophets, how
great a number had testified of these things,
concerning this Messiah, of whom he had spoken, or this
Redeemer of the world
6 Wherefore, all mankind were in a lost and in a
fallen state, and ever would be save they should
rely on this Redeemer
7 And he spake also concerning a prophet who
should come before the Messiah, to prepare the way of
the Lord
8 Yea, even he should go forth and cry in the
wilderness: Prepare ye the way of the Lord, and make
his paths straight; for there standeth one among
you whom ye know not; and he is mightier than I,
whose shoe’s latchet I am not worthy to unloose. And
much spake my father concerning this thing
9 And my father said he should baptize in
Bethabara, beyond Jordan; and he also said he should
baptize with water; even that he should baptize the
Messiah with water
10 And after he had baptized the Messiah with
water, he should behold and bear record that he had
baptized the Lamb of God, who should take away the
sins of the world
11 And it came to pass after my father had spoken
these words he spake unto my brethren concerning
the gospel which should be preached among the Jews,
and also concerning the dwindling of the Jews in
unbelief. And after they had slain the Messiah,
who should come, and after he had been slain he
should rise from the dead, and should make himself
manifest, by the Holy Ghost, unto the Gentiles
12 Yea, even my father spake much concerning the
Gentiles, and also concerning the house of Israel,
that they should be compared like unto an olive
tree, whose branches should be broken off and should
be scattered upon all the face of the earth
13 Wherefore, he said it must needs be that we
should be led with one accord into the land of
promise, unto the fulfilling of the word of the Lord,
that we should be scattered upon all the face of the
earth
14 And after the house of Israel should be
scattered they should be gathered together again; or, in
fine, after the Gentiles had received the fulness
of the Gospel, the natural branches of the olive
tree, or the remnants of the house of Israel,
should be grafted in, or come to the knowledge of the
true Messiah, their Lord and their Redeemer
15 And after this manner of language did my father
prophesy and speak unto my brethren, and also
many more things which I do not write in this book;
for I have written as many of them as were
expedient for me in mine other book
16 And all these things, of which I have spoken,
were done as my father dwelt in a tent, in the
valley of Lemuel
17 And it came to pass after I, Nephi, having
heard all the words of my father, concerning the
things which he saw in a vision, and also the things
which he spake by the power of the Holy Ghost, which
power he received by faith on the Son of God—and
the Son of God was the Messiah who should come—I,
Nephi, was desirous also that I might see, and
hear, and know of these things, by the power of the
Holy Ghost, which is the gift of God unto all those
who diligently seek him, as well in times of old
as in the time that he should manifest himself
unto the children of men
18 For he is the same yesterday, today, and
forever; and the way is prepared for all men from the
foundation of the world, if it so be that they
repent and come unto him
19 For he that diligently seeketh shall find; and
the mysteries of God shall be unfolded unto them,
by the power of the Holy Ghost, as well in these
times as in times of old, and as well in times of
old as in times to come; wherefore, the course of
the Lord is one eternal round
20 Therefore remember, O man, for all thy doings
thou shalt be brought into judgment
21 Wherefore, if ye have sought to do wickedly in
the days of your probation, then ye are found
unclean before the judgment-seat of God; and no
unclean thing can dwell with God; wherefore, ye must be
cast off forever
22 And the Holy Ghost giveth authority that I
should speak these things, and deny them not.