Chapter 12 Nephi sees in vision the land of
promise; the righteousness, iniquity, and downfall of
its inhabitants; the coming of the Lamb of God among
them; how the Twelve Disciples and the Twelve
Apostles will judge Israel; and the loathsome and
filthy state of those who dwindle in unbelief. About
600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that the angel said unto me:
Look, and behold thy seed, and also the seed of
thy brethren. And I looked and beheld the land of
promise; and I beheld multitudes of people, yea,
even as it were in number as many as the sand of the
sea
2 And it came to pass that I beheld multitudes
gathered together to battle, one against the other;
and I beheld wars, and rumors of wars, and great
slaughters with the sword among my people
3 And it came to pass that I beheld many
generations pass away, after the manner of wars and
contentions in the land; and I beheld many cities, yea,
even that I did not number them
4 And it came to pass that I saw a mist of
darkness on the face of the land of promise; and I saw
lightnings, and I heard thunderings, and
earthquakes, and all manner of tumultuous noises; and I saw
the earth and the rocks, that they rent; and I saw
mountains tumbling into pieces; and I saw the
plains of the earth, that they were broken up; and I
saw many cities that they were sunk; and I saw many
that they were burned with fire; and I saw many
that did tumble to the earth, because of the
quaking thereof
5 And it came to pass after I saw these things, I
saw the vapor of darkness, that it passed from off
the face of the earth; and behold, I saw
multitudes who had not fallen because of the great and
terrible judgments of the Lord
6 And I saw the heavens open, and the Lamb of God
descending out of heaven; and he came down and
showed himself unto them
7 And I also saw and bear record that the Holy
Ghost fell upon twelve others; and they were ordained
of God, and chosen
8 And the angel spake unto me, saying: Behold the
twelve disciples of the Lamb, who are chosen to
minister unto thy seed
9 And he said unto me: Thou rememberest the twelve
apostles of the Lamb? Behold they are they who
shall judge the twelve tribes of Israel; wherefore,
the twelve ministers of thy seed shall be judged
of them; for ye are of the house of Israel
10 And these twelve ministers whom thou beholdest
shall judge thy seed. And, behold, they are
righteous forever; for because of their faith in the
Lamb of God their garments are made white in his
blood
11 And the angel said unto me: Look! And I looked,
and beheld three generations pass away in
righteousness; and their garments were white even like
unto the Lamb of God. And the angel said unto me:
These are made white in the blood of the Lamb,
because of their faith in him
12 And I, Nephi, also saw many of the fourth
generation who passed away in righteousness
13 And it came to pass that I saw the multitudes
of the earth gathered together
14 And the angel said unto me: Behold thy seed,
and also the seed of thy brethren
15 And it came to pass that I looked and beheld
the people of my seed gathered together in
multitudes against the seed of my brethren; and they were
gathered together to battle
16 And the angel spake unto me, saying: Behold the
fountain of filthy water which thy father saw;
yea, even the river of which he spake; and the
depths thereof are the depths of hell
17 And the mists of darkness are the temptations
of the devil, which blindeth the eyes, and
hardeneth the hearts of the children of men, and leadeth
them away into broad roads, that they perish and
are lost
18 And the large and spacious building, which thy
father saw, is vain imaginations and the pride of
the children of men. And a great and a terrible
gulf divideth them; yea, even the word of the
justice of the Eternal God, and the Messiah who is the
Lamb of God, of whom the Holy Ghost beareth record,
from the beginning of the world until this time,
and from this time henceforth and forever
19 And while the angel spake these words, I beheld
and saw that the seed of my brethren did contend
against my seed, according to the word of the
angel; and because of the pride of my seed, and the
temptations of the devil, I beheld that the seed of
my brethren did overpower the people of my seed
20 And it came to pass that I beheld, and saw the
people of the seed of my brethren that they had
overcome my seed; and they went forth in multitudes
upon the face of the land
21 And I saw them gathered together in multitudes;
and I saw wars and rumors of wars among them; and
in wars and rumors of wars I saw many generations
pass away
22 And the angel said unto me: Behold these shall
dwindle in unbelief
23 And it came to pass that I beheld, after they
had dwindled in unbelief they became a dark, and
loathsome, and a filthy people, full of idleness and
all manner of abominations.