Chapter 3 Lehi’s sons return to Jerusalem to
obtain the plates of brass—Laban refuses to give
the plates up—Nephi exhorts and encourages his
brethren—Laban steals their property and attempts
to slay them—Laman and Lemuel smite Nephi and Sam
and are reproved by an angel. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that I,
Nephi, returned from speaking with
the Lord, to the tent of my father.
2 And it came to pass that he
spake unto me, saying:
Behold I have dreamed a dream, in
the which the Lord hath
commanded me that thou and thy
brethren shall return to Jerusalem.
3 For behold, Laban hath
the record of the Jews and
also a genealogy of my
forefathers, and they are
engraven upon plates of brass.
4 Wherefore, the Lord
hath commanded me that
thou and thy brothers
should go unto the house of
Laban, and seek the
records, and bring them down
hither into the wilderness.
5 And now, behold thy
brothers murmur,
saying it is a hard
thing which I have
required of them; but
behold I have not required
it of them, but it
is a commandment of the Lord.
6 Therefore go, my
son, and thou
shalt be favored of
the Lord, because
thou hast not murmured.
7 And it came to
pass that I, Nephi,
said unto my
father: I will go and
do the things
which the Lord hath
commanded, for I
know that the Lord
giveth no
commandments unto the
children of men, save he
shall prepare a
way for them that
they may accomplish
the thing which
he commandeth them.
8 And it came to
pass that when my
father had heard
these words he
was exceedingly
glad, for he knew
that I had been
blessed of the Lord.
9 And I, Nephi,
and my brethren
took our journey
in the
wilderness, with our
tents, to go up to
the land of Jerusalem.
10 And it came
to pass that
when we had gone
up to the land
of Jerusalem, I
and my
brethren did consult
one with another.
11 And we cast
lots—who of
us should go in
unto the
house of Laban.
And it came to
pass that the
lot fell upon
Laman; and
Laman went in unto
the house of
Laban, and he
talked with
him as he sat in his house.
12 And he
desired of
Laban the
records which
were engraven
upon the
plates of brass,
which
contained the
genealogy of my father.
13 And
behold, it came
to pass
that Laban
was angry,
and thrust
him out from
his
presence; and he
would not
that he
should have the
records.
Wherefore, he
said unto
him: Behold
thou art a
robber,
and I will slay thee.
14 But
Laman fled
out of his
presence,
and told
the things
which Laban
had done,
unto us.
And we
began to be
exceedingly
sorrowful, and my
brethren
were about
to return
unto my
father in the wilderness.
15 But
behold I
said unto
them that:
As the
Lord
liveth, and as
we live,
we will
not go
down unto
our father
in the
wilderness
until we
have
accomplished
the
thing which
the Lord hath commanded us.
Wherefore,
let us be
faithful
in
keeping the
commandments of
the
Lord;
therefore let
us go
down to
the land
of our
father’s
inheritance, for
behold
he left
gold and
silver,
and all
manner
of
riches. And
all this
he hath
done
because of the commandments of the Lord.
17 For
he knew
that
Jerusalem must
be
destroyed,
because
of the
wickedness of
the people.
18 For
behold,
they have
rejected
the
words of
prophets.
Wherefore,
if my
father
should
dwell in
the
land
after he
hath
been
commanded
to
flee out
of
the
land,
behold, he
would
also
perish.
Wherefore,
it
must needs be that he flee out of the land.
And
behold,
it is
wisdom in
God
that
we
should
obtain
these
records,
that we
may
preserve
unto
our
children
the
language of our fathers;
And
also
that
we
may
preserve
unto
them
the
words
which
have
been
spoken
by
the
mouth
of
all
the
holy
prophets,
which
have
been
delivered
unto
them
by
the
Spirit
and
power
of
God,
since
the world began, even down unto this present time.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
after
this
manner
of
language
did I
persuade
my
brethren,
that
they
might
be
faithful in keeping the commandments of God.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
went
down
to
the
land
of
our
inheritance,
and
we
did
gather
together
our
gold,
and
our
silver,
and
our
precious
things.
And
after
we
had
gathered
these
things
together,
we
went
up
again
unto
the
house
of
Laban.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
went
in
unto
Laban,
and
desired
him
that
he
would
give
unto
us
the
records
which
were
engraven
upon
the
plates
of
brass,
for
which we would give unto him our gold, and our silver, and all our precious things.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
when
Laban
saw
our
property,
and
that
it
was
exceedingly
great,
he
did
lust
after
it,
insomuch
that
he
thrust
us
out,
and
sent
his
servants
to
slay
us,
that
he
might
obtain
our
property.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
did
flee
before
the
servants
of
Laban,
and
we
were
obliged
to
leave
behind
our
property,
and
it
fell
into
the
hands
of
Laban.
27 And it came to pass that we fled into the wilderness, and the servants of Laban did not overtake us, and we hid ourselves in the cavity of a
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
fled
into
the
wilderness,
and
the
servants
of Laban did not overtake us, and we hid ourselves in the cavity of a rock.
28 And it came to pass that Laman was angry with me, and also with my father; and also was Lemuel, for he hearkened unto the words of Laman. Wherefore Laman and Lemuel did speak many hard words unto us, their younger brothers, and they did smite us even with a
And
it
came
to
pass
that
Laman
was
angry
with
me,
and
also
with
my
father;
and
also
was
Lemuel,
for
he
hearkened
unto
the
words
of
Laman.
Wherefore
Laman
and
Lemuel
did
speak
many
hard
words
unto
us,
their
younger
brothers,
and
they
did
smite
us
even
with
a
rod.
29 And it came to pass as they smote us with a rod, behold, an angel of the Lord came and stood before them, and he spake unto them, saying: Why do ye smite your younger brother with a rod? Know ye not that the Lord hath chosen him to be a ruler over you, and this because of your iniquities? Behold ye shall go up to Jerusalem again, and the Lord will deliver Laban into your
And
it
came
to
pass
as
they
smote
us
with
a
rod,
behold,
an
angel
of
the
Lord
came
and
stood
before
them,
and
he
spake
unto
them,
saying:
Why
do
ye
smite
your
younger
brother
with
a
rod?
Know
ye
not
that
the
Lord
hath
chosen
him
to
be
a
ruler
over
you,
and
this
because
of
your
iniquities?
Behold
ye
shall
go
up
to
Jerusalem
again,
and
the
Lord
will
deliver
Laban
into
your
hands.
30 And after the angel had spoken unto us, he
And
after
the
angel
had
spoken
unto
us,
he
departed.
31 And after the angel had departed, Laman and Lemuel again began to murmur, saying: How is it possible that the Lord will deliver Laban into our hands? Behold, he is a mighty man, and he can command fifty, yea, even he can slay fifty; then why not us?
And
after
the
angel
had
departed,
Laman
and
Lemuel
again
began
to
murmur,
saying:
How
is
it
possible
that
the
Lord
will
deliver
Laban
into
our
hands?
Behold,
he
is
a
mighty
man,
and
he
can
command
fifty,
yea,
even
he
can
slay
fifty;
then
why
not
us?