Chapter 9 Nephi makes two sets of records—Each is
called the plates of Nephi—The larger plates
contain a secular history; the smaller ones deal
primarily with sacred things. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And all these things did my father see, and
hear, and speak, as he dwelt in a tent, in the valley
of Lemuel, and also a great many more things,
which cannot be written upon these plates
2 And now, as I have spoken concerning these
plates, behold they are not the plates upon which I
make a full account of the history of my people; for
the plates upon which I make a full account of my
people I have given the name of Nephi; wherefore,
they are called the plates of Nephi, after mine
own name; and these plates also are called the
plates of Nephi
3 Nevertheless, I have received a commandment of
the Lord that I should make these plates, for the
special purpose that there should be an account
engraven of the ministry of my people
6 But the Lord knoweth all things from the
beginning; wherefore, he prepareth a way to accomplish
all his works among the children of men; for behold,
he hath all power unto the fulfilling of all his
words. And thus it is. Amen.