Chapter 18 The ship is finished—The births of
Jacob and Joseph are mentioned—The company embarks for
the promised land—The sons of Ishmael and their
wives join in revelry and rebellion—Nephi is bound,
and the ship is driven back by a terrible
tempest—Nephi is freed, and by his prayer the storm
ceases—The people arrive in the promised land. About
591–589 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that they did worship the
Lord, and did go forth with me; and we did work
timbers of curious workmanship. And the Lord did show
me from time to time after what manner I should
work the timbers of the ship
2 Now I, Nephi, did not work the timbers after the
manner which was learned by men, neither did I
build the ship after the manner of men; but I did
build it after the manner which the Lord had shown
unto me; wherefore, it was not after the manner of
men
3 And I, Nephi, did go into the mount oft, and I
did pray oft unto the Lord; wherefore the Lord
showed unto me great things
4 And it came to pass that after I had finished
the ship, according to the word of the Lord, my
brethren beheld that it was good, and that the
workmanship thereof was exceedingly fine; wherefore, they
did humble themselves again before the Lord
5 And it came to pass that the voice of the Lord
came unto my father, that we should arise and go
down into the ship
6 And it came to pass that on the morrow, after we
had prepared all things, much fruits and meat
from the wilderness, and honey in abundance, and
provisions according to that which the Lord had
commanded us, we did go down into the ship, with all our
loading and our seeds, and whatsoever thing we
had brought with us, every one according to his age;
wherefore, we did all go down into the ship, with
our wives and our children
7 And now, my father had begat two sons in the
wilderness; the elder was called Jacob and the
younger Joseph
8 And it came to pass after we had all gone down
into the ship, and had taken with us our provisions
and things which had been commanded us, we did
put forth into the sea and were driven forth before
the wind towards the promised land
9 And after we had been driven forth before the
wind for the space of many days, behold, my brethren
and the sons of Ishmael and also their wives
began to make themselves merry, insomuch that they
began to dance, and to sing, and to speak with much
rudeness, yea, even that they did forget by what
power they had been brought thither; yea, they were
lifted up unto exceeding rudeness
10 And I, Nephi, began to fear exceedingly lest
the Lord should be angry with us, and smite us
because of our iniquity, that we should be swallowed up
in the depths of the sea; wherefore, I, Nephi,
began to speak to them with much soberness; but
behold they were angry with me, saying: We will not
that our younger brother shall be a ruler over us
11 And it came to pass that Laman and Lemuel did
take me and bind me with cords, and they did treat
me with much harshness; nevertheless, the Lord did
suffer it that he might show forth his power,
unto the fulfilling of his word which he had spoken
concerning the wicked
12 And it came to pass that after they had bound
me insomuch that I could not move, the compass,
which had been prepared of the Lord, did cease to
work
13 Wherefore, they knew not whither they should
steer the ship, insomuch that there arose a great
storm, yea, a great and terrible tempest, and we
were driven back upon the waters for the space of
three days; and they began to be frightened
exceedingly lest they should be drowned in the sea;
nevertheless they did not loose me
14 And on the fourth day, which we had been driven
back, the tempest began to be exceedingly sore
15 And it came to pass that we were about to be
swallowed up in the depths of the sea. And after we
had been driven back upon the waters for the space
of four days, my brethren began to see that the
judgments of God were upon them, and that they must
perish save that they should repent of their
iniquities; wherefore, they came unto me, and loosed
the bands which were upon my wrists, and behold
they had swollen exceedingly; and also mine ankles
were much swollen, and great was the soreness
thereof
16 Nevertheless, I did look unto my God, and I did
praise him all the day long; and I did not murmur
against the Lord because of mine afflictions
17 Now my father, Lehi, had said many things unto
them, and also unto the sons of Ishmael; but,
behold, they did breathe out much threatenings against
anyone that should speak for me; and my parents
being stricken in years, and having suffered much
grief because of their children, they were brought
down, yea, even upon their sick-beds
18 Because of their grief and much sorrow, and the
iniquity of my brethren, they were brought near
even to be carried out of this time to meet their
God; yea, their grey hairs were about to be brought
down to lie low in the dust; yea, even they were
near to be cast with sorrow into a watery grave
19 And Jacob and Joseph also, being young, having
need of much nourishment, were grieved because of
the afflictions of their mother; and also my wife
with her tears and prayers, and also my children,
did not soften the hearts of my brethren that they
would loose me
20 And there was nothing save it were the power of
God, which threatened them with destruction,
could soften their hearts; wherefore, when they saw
that they were about to be swallowed up in the
depths of the sea they repented of the thing which they
had done, insomuch that they loosed me
21 And it came to pass after they had loosed me,
behold, I took the compass, and it did work whither
I desired it. And it came to pass that I prayed
unto the Lord; and after I had prayed the winds did
cease, and the storm did cease, and there was a
great calm
22 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did guide
the ship, that we sailed again towards the promised
land
23 And it came to pass that after we had sailed
for the space of many days we did arrive at the
promised land; and we went forth upon the land, and
did pitch our tents; and we did call it the promised
land
24 And it came to pass that we did begin to till
the earth, and we began to plant seeds; yea, we did
put all our seeds into the earth, which we had
brought from the land of Jerusalem. And it came to
pass that they did grow exceedingly; wherefore, we
were blessed in abundance
25 And it came to pass that we did find upon the
land of promise, as we journeyed in the wilderness,
that there were beasts in the forests of every
kind, both the cow and the ox, and the ass and the
horse, and the goat and the wild goat, and all
manner of wild animals, which were for the use of men.
And we did find all manner of ore, both of gold,
and of silver, and of copper.