Chapter 2 Lehi takes his family into the
wilderness by the Red Sea—They leave their
property—Lehi offers a sacrifice to the Lord and teaches his
sons to keep the commandments—Laman and Lemuel
murmur against their father—Nephi is obedient
and prays in faith; the Lord speaks to him, and he
is chosen to rule over his brethren. About 600 B.C.
1 For behold, it came to pass that the Lord
spake unto my father, yea, even in a dream,
and said unto him: Blessed art thou Lehi,
because of the things which thou hast done; and
because thou hast been faithful and declared
unto this people the things which I commanded
thee, behold, they seek to take away thy life.
2 And it came to pass that the
Lord commanded my father, even in a
dream, that he should take his
family and depart into the wilderness.
3 And it came to pass that
he was obedient unto the word
of the Lord, wherefore he
did as the Lord commanded him.
4 And it came to pass
that he departed into the
wilderness. And he left his
house, and the land of
his inheritance, and his
gold, and his silver, and
his precious things, and
took nothing with him,
save it were his family,
and provisions, and tents,
and departed into the wilderness.
5 And he came down by
the borders near the shore
of the Red Sea; and he
traveled in the
wilderness in the borders which
are nearer the Red Sea;
and he did travel in the
wilderness with his
family, which consisted of
my mother, Sariah, and
my elder brothers, who
were Laman, Lemuel, and Sam.
6 And it came to pass
that when he had
traveled three days in the
wilderness, he pitched his
tent in a valley by
the side of a river of water.
7 And it came to pass
that he built an
altar of stones, and
made an offering unto
the Lord, and gave
thanks unto the Lord our God.
8 And it came to
pass that he called
the name of the
river, Laman, and it
emptied into the Red
Sea; and the valley
was in the borders
near the mouth thereof.
9 And when my
father saw that the
waters of the
river emptied into
the fountain of
the Red Sea, he
spake unto Laman,
saying: O that thou
mightest be like
unto this river,
continually
running into the
fountain of all righteousness!
10 And he also
spake unto
Lemuel: O that thou
mightest be
like unto this
valley, firm and
steadfast, and
immovable in
keeping the
commandments of the Lord!
11 Now this he
spake because
of the
stiffneckedness of
Laman and
Lemuel; for behold
they did
murmur in many
things against
their father,
because he was a
visionary man,
and had led
them out of the
land of
Jerusalem, to leave
the land of
their
inheritance, and their
gold, and
their silver, and
their precious
things, to
perish in the
wilderness. And
this they said
he had done
because of the
foolish imaginations of his heart.
12 And thus
Laman and
Lemuel, being the
eldest, did
murmur
against their
father. And they
did murmur
because they
knew not the
dealings of that
God who had
created them.
13 Neither
did they
believe that
Jerusalem, that
great city,
could be
destroyed
according to the
words of
the prophets.
And they
were like unto
the Jews who
were at
Jerusalem, who
sought to
take away the
life of my father.
14 And it
came to pass
that my
father did
speak unto
them in the
valley of
Lemuel, with
power,
being filled
with the
Spirit, until
their frames
did shake
before him.
And he did
confound
them, that
they durst
not utter
against him;
wherefore,
they did as he commanded them.
15 And my
father dwelt
in a tent.
16 And it
came to
pass that I,
Nephi,
being
exceedingly
young,
nevertheless
being large in
stature,
and also
having
great desires
to know of
the
mysteries of
God,
wherefore, I did
cry unto
the Lord;
and behold
he did
visit me, and
did
soften my heart
that I
did believe
all the
words which
had been
spoken by
my father;
wherefore,
I did not
rebel against him like unto my brothers.
17 And I
spake
unto Sam,
making
known unto
him the
things which
the Lord
had
manifested
unto me by
his Holy
Spirit.
And it
came to pass
that he
believed in my words.
18 But,
behold,
Laman
and Lemuel
would
not
hearken unto
my
words; and
being
grieved
because of
the
hardness of
their
hearts I
cried unto
the Lord for them.
19 And
it came
to
pass that
the
Lord spake
unto
me,
saying:
Blessed
art thou,
Nephi,
because of
thy
faith, for
thou
hast
sought me
diligently, with lowliness of heart.
20 And
inasmuch as
ye
shall
keep my
commandments, ye
shall
prosper, and
be led
to a
land
of
promise;
yea,
even a
land
which I
have
prepared for
you;
yea, a
land
which
is choice above all other lands.
And
inasmuch
as
thy
brethren
shall
rebel
against
thee,
they
shall
be cut
off
from
the
presence of the Lord.
And
inasmuch
as
thou
shalt
keep
my
commandments,
thou
shalt
be
made a
ruler
and a
teacher over thy brethren.
For
behold,
in
that
day
they
shall
rebel
against
me,
I
will
curse
them
even
with a
sore
curse,
and
they
shall
have
no
power
over
thy seed except they shall rebel against me also.
that
they
rebel
against
me,
they
shall
be
a
scourge
unto
thy
seed,
to stir them up in the ways of remembrance.