Chapter 13 Nephi sees in vision the church of the
devil set up among the Gentiles, the discovery and
colonizing of America, the loss of many plain and
precious parts of the Bible, the resultant state
of gentile apostasy, the restoration of the
gospel, the coming forth of latter-day scripture, and
the building up of Zion. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that the angel spake unto
me, saying: Look! And I looked and beheld many
nations and kingdoms
2 And the angel said unto me: What beholdest thou?
And I said: I behold many nations and kingdoms
3 And he said unto me: These are the nations and
kingdoms of the Gentiles
4 And it came to pass that I saw among the nations
of the Gentiles the formation of a great church
5 And the angel said unto me: Behold the formation
of a church which is most abominable above all
other churches, which slayeth the saints of God,
yea, and tortureth them and bindeth them down, and
yoketh them with a yoke of iron, and bringeth them
down into captivity
6 And it came to pass that I beheld this great and
abominable church; and I saw the devil that he
was the founder of it
7 And I also saw gold, and silver, and silks, and
scarlets, and fine-twined linen, and all manner of
precious clothing; and I saw many harlots
8 And the angel spake unto me, saying: Behold the
gold, and the silver, and the silks, and the
scarlets, and the fine-twined linen, and the precious
clothing, and the harlots, are the desires of this
great and abominable church
9 And also for the praise of the world do they
destroy the saints of God, and bring them down into
captivity
10 And it came to pass that I looked and beheld
many waters; and they divided the Gentiles from the
seed of my brethren
11 And it came to pass that the angel said unto
me: Behold the wrath of God is upon the seed of thy
brethren
12 And I looked and beheld a man among the
Gentiles, who was separated from the seed of my brethren
by the many waters; and I beheld the Spirit of
God, that it came down and wrought upon the man; and
he went forth upon the many waters, even unto the
seed of my brethren, who were in the promised
land
13 And it came to pass that I beheld the Spirit of
God, that it wrought upon other Gentiles; and
they went forth out of captivity, upon the many
waters
14 And it came to pass that I beheld many
multitudes of the Gentiles upon the land of promise; and I
beheld the wrath of God, that it was upon the
seed of my brethren; and they were scattered before
the Gentiles and were smitten
15 And I beheld the Spirit of the Lord, that it
was upon the Gentiles, and they did prosper and
obtain the land for their inheritance; and I beheld
that they were white, and exceedingly fair and
beautiful, like unto my people before they were slain
16 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, beheld that
the Gentiles who had gone forth out of captivity
did humble themselves before the Lord; and the
power of the Lord was with them
17 And I beheld that their mother Gentiles were
gathered together upon the waters, and upon the land
also, to battle against them
18 And I beheld that the power of God was with
them, and also that the wrath of God was upon all
those that were gathered together against them to
battle
19 And I, Nephi, beheld that the Gentiles that had
gone out of captivity were delivered by the power
of God out of the hands of all other nations
20 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, beheld that
they did prosper in the land; and I beheld a book,
and it was carried forth among them
21 And the angel said unto me: Knowest thou the
meaning of the book
22 And I said unto him: I know not
23 And he said: Behold it proceedeth out of the
mouth of a Jew. And I, Nephi, beheld it; and he said
unto me: The book that thou beholdest is a record
of the Jews, which contains the covenants of the
Lord, which he hath made unto the house of Israel;
and it also containeth many of the prophecies of
the holy prophets; and it is a record like unto
the engravings which are upon the plates of brass,
save there are not so many; nevertheless, they
contain the covenants of the Lord, which he hath made
unto the house of Israel; wherefore, they are of
great worth unto the Gentiles
24 And the angel of the Lord said unto me: Thou
hast beheld that the book proceeded forth from the
mouth of a Jew; and when it proceeded forth from
the mouth of a Jew it contained the fulness of the
gospel of the Lord, of whom the twelve apostles
bear record; and they bear record according to the
truth which is in the Lamb of God
25 Wherefore, these things go forth from the Jews
in purity unto the Gentiles, according to the
truth which is in God
26 And after they go forth by the hand of the
twelve apostles of the Lamb, from the Jews unto the
Gentiles, thou seest the formation of that great and
abominable church, which is most abominable above
all other churches; for behold, they have taken
away from the gospel of the Lamb many parts which
are plain and most precious; and also many
covenants of the Lord have they taken away
27 And all this have they done that they might
pervert the right ways of the Lord, that they might
blind the eyes and harden the hearts of the
children of men
28 Wherefore, thou seest that after the book hath
gone forth through the hands of the great and
abominable church, that there are many plain and
precious things taken away from the book, which is the
book of the Lamb of God
29 And after these plain and precious things were
taken away it goeth forth unto all the nations of
the Gentiles; and after it goeth forth unto all
the nations of the Gentiles, yea, even across the
many waters which thou hast seen with the Gentiles
which have gone forth out of captivity, thou
seest—because of the many plain and precious things
which have been taken out of the book, which were
plain unto the understanding of the children of men,
according to the plainness which is in the Lamb of
God—because of these things which are taken away
out of the gospel of the Lamb, an exceedingly great
many do stumble, yea, insomuch that Satan hath
great power over them
30 Nevertheless, thou beholdest that the Gentiles
who have gone forth out of captivity, and have
been lifted up by the power of God above all other
nations, upon the face of the land which is choice
above all other lands, which is the land that the
Lord God hath covenanted with thy father that his
seed should have for the land of their inheritance;
wherefore, thou seest that the Lord God will not
suffer that the Gentiles will utterly destroy the
mixture of thy seed, which are among thy brethren
31 Neither will he suffer that the Gentiles shall
destroy the seed of thy brethren
32 Neither will the Lord God suffer that the
Gentiles shall forever remain in that awful state of
blindness, which thou beholdest they are in, because
of the plain and most precious parts of the
gospel of the Lamb which have been kept back by that
abominable church, whose formation thou hast seen
33 Wherefore saith the Lamb of God: I will be
merciful unto the Gentiles, unto the visiting of the
remnant of the house of Israel in great judgment
34 And it came to pass that the angel of the Lord
spake unto me, saying: Behold, saith the Lamb of
God, after I have visited the remnant of the house
of Israel—and this remnant of whom I speak is the
seed of thy father—wherefore, after I have visited
them in judgment, and smitten them by the hand of
the Gentiles, and after the Gentiles do stumble
exceedingly, because of the most plain and precious
parts of the gospel of the Lamb which have been
kept back by that abominable church, which is the
mother of harlots, saith the Lamb—I will be
merciful unto the Gentiles in that day, insomuch that I
will bring forth unto them, in mine own power, much
of my gospel, which shall be plain and precious,
saith the Lamb
35 For, behold, saith the Lamb: I will manifest
myself unto thy seed, that they shall write many
things which I shall minister unto them, which shall
be plain and precious; and after thy seed shall be
destroyed, and dwindle in unbelief, and also the
seed of thy brethren, behold, these things shall
be hid up, to come forth unto the Gentiles, by the
gift and power of the Lamb
36 And in them shall be written my gospel, saith
the Lamb, and my rock and my salvation
37 And blessed are they who shall seek to bring
forth my Zion at that day, for they shall have the
gift and the power of the Holy Ghost; and if they
endure unto the end they shall be lifted up at the
last day, and shall be saved in the everlasting
kingdom of the Lamb; and whoso shall publish peace,
yea, tidings of great joy, how beautiful upon the
mountains shall they be
38 And it came to pass that I beheld the remnant
of the seed of my brethren, and also the book of
the Lamb of God, which had proceeded forth from the
mouth of the Jew, that it came forth from the
Gentiles unto the remnant of the seed of my brethren
39 And after it had come forth unto them I beheld
other books, which came forth by the power of the
Lamb, from the Gentiles unto them, unto the
convincing of the Gentiles and the remnant of the seed
of my brethren, and also the Jews who were
scattered upon all the face of the earth, that the records
of the prophets and of the twelve apostles of the
Lamb are true
40 And the angel spake unto me, saying: These last
records, which thou hast seen among the Gentiles,
shall establish the truth of the first, which are
of the twelve apostles of the Lamb, and shall
make known the plain and precious things which have
been taken away from them; and shall make known to
all kindreds, tongues, and people, that the Lamb
of God is the Son of the Eternal Father, and the
Savior of the world; and that all men must come unto
him, or they cannot be saved
41 And they must come according to the words which
shall be established by the mouth of the Lamb;
and the words of the Lamb shall be made known in the
records of thy seed, as well as in the records of
the twelve apostles of the Lamb; wherefore they
both shall be established in one; for there is one
God and one Shepherd over all the earth
42 And the time cometh that he shall manifest
himself unto all nations, both unto the Jews and also
unto the Gentiles; and after he has manifested
himself unto the Jews and also unto the Gentiles,
then he shall manifest himself unto the Gentiles and
also unto the Jews, and the last shall be first,
and the first shall be last.