Chapter 8 Lehi sees a vision of the tree of
life—He partakes of its fruit and desires his family to
do likewise—He sees a rod of iron, a strait and
narrow path, and the mists of darkness that enshroud
men—Sariah, Nephi, and Sam partake of the fruit,
but Laman and Lemuel refuse. About 600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that we had gathered
together all manner of seeds of every kind, both of grain
of every kind, and also of the seeds of fruit of
every kind
2 And it came to pass that while my father tarried
in the wilderness he spake unto us, saying:
Behold, I have dreamed a dream; or, in other words, I
have seen a vision
3 And behold, because of the thing which I have
seen, I have reason to rejoice in the Lord because
of Nephi and also of Sam; for I have reason to
suppose that they, and also many of their seed, will
be saved
4 But behold, Laman and Lemuel, I fear exceedingly
because of you; for behold, methought I saw in my
dream, a dark and dreary wilderness
5 And it came to pass that I saw a man, and he was
dressed in a white robe; and he came and stood
before me
6 And it came to pass that he spake unto me, and
bade me follow him
7 And it came to pass that as I followed him I
beheld myself that I was in a dark and dreary waste
8 And after I had traveled for the space of many
hours in darkness, I began to pray unto the Lord
that he would have mercy on me, according to the
multitude of his tender mercies
9 And it came to pass after I had prayed unto the
Lord I beheld a large and spacious field
10 And it came to pass that I beheld a tree, whose
fruit was desirable to make one happy
11 And it came to pass that I did go forth and
partake of the fruit thereof; and I beheld that it
was most sweet, above all that I ever before tasted.
Yea, and I beheld that the fruit thereof was
white, to exceed all the whiteness that I had ever
seen
12 And as I partook of the fruit thereof it filled
my soul with exceedingly great joy; wherefore, I
began to be desirous that my family should partake
of it also; for I knew that it was desirable
above all other fruit
13 And as I cast my eyes round about, that perhaps
I might discover my family also, I beheld a river
of water; and it ran along, and it was near the
tree of which I was partaking the fruit
14 And I looked to behold from whence it came; and
I saw the head thereof a little way off; and at
the head thereof I beheld your mother Sariah, and
Sam, and Nephi; and they stood as if they knew not
whither they should go
15 And it came to pass that I beckoned unto them;
and I also did say unto them with a loud voice
that they should come unto me, and partake of the
fruit, which was desirable above all other fruit
16 And it came to pass that they did come unto me
and partake of the fruit also
17 And it came to pass that I was desirous that
Laman and Lemuel should come and partake of the
fruit also; wherefore, I cast mine eyes towards the
head of the river, that perhaps I might see them
18 And it came to pass that I saw them, but they
would not come unto me and partake of the fruit
19 And I beheld a rod of iron, and it extended
along the bank of the river, and led to the tree by
which I stood
20 And I also beheld a strait and narrow path,
which came along by the rod of iron, even to the tree
by which I stood; and it also led by the head of
the fountain, unto a large and spacious field, as
if it had been a world
21 And I saw numberless concourses of people, many
of whom were pressing forward, that they might
obtain the path which led unto the tree by which I
stood
22 And it came to pass that they did come forth,
and commence in the path which led to the tree
23 And it came to pass that there arose a mist of
darkness; yea, even an exceedingly great mist of
darkness, insomuch that they who had commenced in
the path did lose their way, that they wandered off
and were lost
24 And it came to pass that I beheld others
pressing forward, and they came forth and caught hold of
the end of the rod of iron; and they did press
forward through the mist of darkness, clinging to
the rod of iron, even until they did come forth and
partake of the fruit of the tree
25 And after they had partaken of the fruit of the
tree they did cast their eyes about as if they
were ashamed
26 And I also cast my eyes round about, and
beheld, on the other side of the river of water, a great
and spacious building; and it stood as it were in
the air, high above the earth
27 And it was filled with people, both old and
young, both male and female; and their manner of
dress was exceedingly fine; and they were in the
attitude of mocking and pointing their fingers towards
those who had come at and were partaking of the
fruit
28 And after they had tasted of the fruit they
were ashamed, because of those that were scoffing at
them; and they fell away into forbidden paths and
were lost
29 And now I, Nephi, do not speak all the words of
my father
30 But, to be short in writing, behold, he saw
other multitudes pressing forward; and they came and
caught hold of the end of the rod of iron; and
they did press their way forward, continually holding
fast to the rod of iron, until they came forth
and fell down and partook of the fruit of the tree
31 And he also saw other multitudes feeling their
way towards that great and spacious building
32 And it came to pass that many were drowned in
the depths of the fountain; and many were lost from
his view, wandering in strange roads
33 And great was the multitude that did enter into
that strange building. And after they did enter
into that building they did point the finger of
scorn at me and those that were partaking of the
fruit also; but we heeded them not
34 These are the words of my father: For as many
as heeded them, had fallen away
35 And Laman and Lemuel partook not of the fruit,
said my father
36 And it came to pass after my father had spoken
all the words of his dream or vision, which were
many, he said unto us, because of these things
which he saw in a vision, he exceedingly feared for
Laman and Lemuel; yea, he feared lest they should be
cast off from the presence of the Lord
37 And he did exhort them then with all the
feeling of a tender parent, that they would hearken to
his words, that perhaps the Lord would be merciful
to them, and not cast them off; yea, my father did
preach unto them
38 And after he had preached unto them, and also
prophesied unto them of many things, he bade them
to keep the commandments of the Lord; and he did
cease speaking unto them.