Chapter 21 The Messiah will be a light to the
Gentiles and will free the prisoners—Israel will be
gathered with power in the last days—Kings will be
their nursing fathers—Compare
Isaiah 49. About
588–570 B.C.
1 And again: Hearken, O ye house of Israel, all ye
that are broken off and are driven out because of
the wickedness of the pastors of my people; yea,
all ye that are broken off, that are scattered
abroad, who are of my people, O house of Israel.
Listen, O isles, unto me, and hearken ye people from
far; the Lord hath called me from the womb; from
the bowels of my mother hath he made mention of my
name
2 And he hath made my mouth like a sharp sword; in
the shadow of his hand hath he hid me, and made
me a polished shaft; in his quiver hath he hid me
3 And said unto me: Thou art my servant, O Israel,
in whom I will be glorified
4 Then I said, I have labored in vain, I have
spent my strength for naught and in vain; surely my
judgment is with the Lord, and my work with my God
5 And now, saith the Lord—that formed me from the
womb that I should be his servant, to bring Jacob
again to him—though Israel be not gathered, yet
shall I be glorious in the eyes of the Lord, and my
God shall be my strength
6 And he said: It is a light thing that thou
shouldst be my servant to raise up the tribes of Jacob,
and to restore the preserved of Israel. I will
also give thee for a light to the Gentiles, that
thou mayest be my salvation unto the ends of the
earth
7 Thus saith the Lord, the Redeemer of Israel, his
Holy One, to him whom man despiseth, to him whom
the nations abhorreth, to servant of rulers: Kings
shall see and arise, princes also shall worship,
because of the Lord that is faithful
8 Thus saith the Lord: In an acceptable time have
I heard thee, O isles of the sea, and in a day of
salvation have I helped thee; and I will preserve
thee, and give thee my servant for a covenant of
the people, to establish the earth, to cause to
inherit the desolate heritages
9 That thou mayest say to the prisoners: Go forth;
to them that sit in darkness: Show yourselves.
They shall feed in the ways, and their pastures
shall be in all high places
10 They shall not hunger nor thirst, neither shall
the heat nor the sun smite them; for he that hath
mercy on them shall lead them, even by the
springs of water shall he guide them
11 And I will make all my mountains a way, and my
highways shall be exalted
12 And then, O house of Israel, behold, these
shall come from far; and lo, these from the north and
from the west; and these from the land of Sinim
13 Sing, O heavens; and be joyful, O earth; for
the feet of those who are in the east shall be
established; and break forth into singing, O mountains;
for they shall be smitten no more; for the Lord
hath comforted his people, and will have mercy upon
his afflicted
14 But, behold, Zion hath said: The Lord hath
forsaken me, and my Lord hath forgotten me—but he will
show that he hath not
15 For can a woman forget her sucking child, that
she should not have compassion on the son of her
womb? Yea, they may forget, yet will I not forget
thee, O house of Israel
16 Behold, I have graven thee upon the palms of my
hands; thy walls are continually before me
17 Thy children shall make haste against thy
destroyers; and they that made thee waste shall go
forth of thee
18 Lift up thine eyes round about and behold; all
these gather themselves together, and they shall
come to thee. And as I live, saith the Lord, thou
shalt surely clothe thee with them all, as with an
ornament, and bind them on even as a bride
19 For thy waste and thy desolate places, and the
land of thy destruction, shall even now be too
narrow by reason of the inhabitants; and they that
swallowed thee up shall be far away
20 The children whom thou shalt have, after thou
hast lost the first, shall again in thine ears say:
The place is too strait for me; give place to me
that I may dwell
21 Then shalt thou say in thine heart: Who hath
begotten me these, seeing I have lost my children,
and am desolate, a captive, and removing to and
fro? And who hath brought up these? Behold, I was
left alone; these, where have they been
22 Thus saith the Lord God: Behold, I will lift up
mine hand to the Gentiles, and set up my standard
to the people; and they shall bring thy sons in
their arms, and thy daughters shall be carried upon
their shoulders
23 And kings shall be thy nursing fathers, and
their queens thy nursing mothers; they shall bow down
to thee with their face towards the earth, and
lick up the dust of thy feet; and thou shalt know
that I am the Lord; for they shall not be ashamed
that wait for me
24 For shall the prey be taken from the mighty, or
the lawful captives delivered
25 But thus saith the Lord, even the captives of
the mighty shall be taken away, and the prey of the
terrible shall be delivered; for I will contend
with him that contendeth with thee, and I will save
thy children
26 And I will feed them that oppress thee with
their own flesh; they shall be drunken with their own
blood as with sweet wine; and all flesh shall
know that I, the Lord, am thy Savior and thy
Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob.