Chapter 5 Sariah complains against Lehi—Both
rejoice over the return of their sons—They offer
sacrifices—The plates of brass contain writings of Moses
and the prophets—The plates identify Lehi as a
descendant of Joseph—Lehi prophesies concerning his
seed and the preservation of the plates. About
600–592 B.C.
1 And it came to pass that after we had come down
into the wilderness unto our father, behold, he
was filled with joy, and also my mother, Sariah, was
exceedingly glad, for she truly had mourned
because of us
2 For she had supposed that we had perished in the
wilderness; and she also had complained against
my father, telling him that he was a visionary man;
saying: Behold thou hast led us forth from the
land of our inheritance, and my sons are no more,
and we perish in the wilderness
3 And after this manner of language had my mother
complained against my father
4 And it had come to pass that my father spake
unto her, saying: I know that I am a visionary man;
for if I had not seen the things of God in a vision
I should not have known the goodness of God, but
had tarried at Jerusalem, and had perished with my
brethren
5 But behold, I have obtained a land of promise,
in the which things I do rejoice; yea, and I know
that the Lord will deliver my sons out of the hands
of Laban, and bring them down again unto us in
the wilderness
6 And after this manner of language did my father,
Lehi, comfort my mother, Sariah, concerning us,
while we journeyed in the wilderness up to the land
of Jerusalem, to obtain the record of the Jews
7 And when we had returned to the tent of my
father, behold their joy was full, and my mother was
comforted
8 And she spake, saying: Now I know of a surety
that the Lord hath commanded my husband to flee into
the wilderness; yea, and I also know of a surety
that the Lord hath protected my sons, and
delivered them out of the hands of Laban, and given them
power whereby they could accomplish the thing which
the Lord hath commanded them. And after this
manner of language did she speak
9 And it came to pass that they did rejoice
exceedingly, and did offer sacrifice and burnt offerings
unto the Lord; and they gave thanks unto the God
of Israel
10 And after they had given thanks unto the God of
Israel, my father, Lehi, took the records which
were engraven upon the plates of brass, and he did
search them from the beginning
11 And he beheld that they did contain the five
books of Moses, which gave an account of the
creation of the world, and also of Adam and Eve, who were
our first parents
12 And also a record of the Jews from the
beginning, even down to the commencement of the reign of
Zedekiah, king of Judah
13 And also the prophecies of the holy prophets,
from the beginning, even down to the commencement
of the reign of Zedekiah; and also many prophecies
which have been spoken by the mouth of Jeremiah
14 And it came to pass that my father, Lehi, also
found upon the plates of brass a genealogy of his
fathers; wherefore he knew that he was a
descendant of Joseph; yea, even that Joseph who was the son
of Jacob, who was sold into Egypt, and who was
preserved by the hand of the Lord, that he might
preserve his father, Jacob, and all his household
from perishing with famine
15 And they were also led out of captivity and out
of the land of Egypt, by that same God who had
preserved them
16 And thus my father, Lehi, did discover the
genealogy of his fathers. And Laban also was a
descendant of Joseph, wherefore he and his fathers had
kept the records
17 And now when my father saw all these things, he
was filled with the Spirit, and began to prophesy
concerning his seed
18 That these plates of brass should go forth unto
all nations, kindreds, tongues, and people who
were of his seed
19 Wherefore, he said that these plates of brass
should never perish; neither should they be dimmed
any more by time. And he prophesied many things
concerning his seed
22 Wherefore, it was wisdom in the Lord that we
should carry them with us, as we journeyed in the
wilderness towards the land of promise.