The Book of JaromChapter 1 The Nephites
keep the law of Moses, look forward to
the coming of Christ, and prosper in the
land—Many prophets labor to keep the
people in the way of truth. About 399–361 B.C.
1 Now behold, I, Jarom, write
a few words according to the
commandment of my father, Enos,
that our genealogy may be kept.
2 And as these plates are
small, and as these things are
written for the intent of
the benefit of our brethren
the Lamanites, wherefore, it
must needs be that I write a
little; but I shall not
write the things of my
prophesying, nor of my revelations.
For what could I write more
than my fathers have
written? For have not they revealed
the plan of salvation? I
say unto you, Yea; and this sufficeth me.
3 Behold, it is expedient
that much should be done
among this people, because of
the hardness of their
hearts, and the deafness of
their ears, and the blindness
of their minds, and the
stiffness of their necks;
nevertheless, God is exceedingly
merciful unto them, and
has not as yet swept them off
from the face of the land.
4 And there are many
among us who have many
revelations, for they are not
all stiffnecked. And as
many as are not stiffnecked
and have faith, have
communion with the Holy
Spirit, which maketh manifest
unto the children of
men, according to their faith.
5 And now, behold, two
hundred years had
passed away, and the people
of Nephi had waxed
strong in the land. They
observed to keep the law
of Moses and the
sabbath day holy unto the
Lord. And they profaned
not; neither did they
blaspheme. And the laws of
the land were exceedingly strict.
6 And they were
scattered upon much of the
face of the land,
and the Lamanites also.
And they were
exceedingly more numerous
than were they of the
Nephites; and they
loved murder and would
drink the blood of beasts.
7 And it came to
pass that they came
many times against us,
the Nephites, to
battle. But our kings
and our leaders were
mighty men in the
faith of the Lord; and
they taught the
people the ways of the
Lord; wherefore, we
withstood the
Lamanites and swept them
away out of our
lands, and began to
fortify our cities, or
whatsoever place of our inheritance.
8 And we multiplied
exceedingly, and
spread upon the face
of the land, and
became exceedingly
rich in gold, and in
silver, and in
precious things, and
in fine workmanship
of wood, in
buildings, and in
machinery, and also in iron
and copper, and
brass and steel,
making all manner of
tools of every kind
to till the ground,
and weapons of
war—yea, the sharp
pointed arrow, and the
quiver, and the
dart, and the javelin,
and all preparations for war.
9 And thus being
prepared to meet
the Lamanites, they
did not prosper
against us. But the
word of the Lord
was verified, which
he spake unto our
fathers, saying
that: Inasmuch as
ye will keep my
commandments ye shall
prosper in the land.
10 And it came to
pass that the
prophets of the Lord
did threaten the
people of Nephi,
according to the word
of God, that if
they did not keep
the commandments,
but should fall
into transgression,
they should be
destroyed from off the
face of the land.
11 Wherefore, the
prophets, and
the priests, and
the teachers, did
labor diligently,
exhorting with
all long-suffering
the people to
diligence; teaching
the law of Moses,
and the intent
for which it was
given; persuading
them to look
forward unto the
Messiah, and believe
in him to come as
though he
already was. And after
this manner did they teach them.
12 And it came
to pass that by
so doing they
kept them from
being destroyed upon
the face of the
land; for they
did prick their
hearts with the
word,
continually stirring them
up unto repentance.
13 And it came
to pass that
two hundred
and thirty and
eight years had
passed
away—after the
manner of wars, and
contentions,
and
dissensions, for the
space of much of the time.
14 And I,
Jarom, do not
write more, for
the plates
are small. But
behold, my
brethren, ye
can go to the
other plates
of Nephi; for
behold, upon
them the
records of our
wars are
engraven,
according to the
writings of the
kings, or
those which they
caused to be written.
15 And I
deliver these
plates into
the hands of
my son Omni,
that they
may be kept
according to
the
commandments of my fathers.