Chapter 10 Jacob explains that the Jews will
crucify their God—They will be scattered until they
begin to believe in Him—America will be a land of
liberty where no king will rule—Reconcile yourselves
to God and gain salvation through His grace. About
559–545 B.C.
1 And now I, Jacob, speak unto you again, my
beloved brethren, concerning this righteous branch of
which I have spoken
2 For behold, the promises which we have obtained
are promises unto us according to the flesh;
wherefore, as it has been shown unto me that many of
our children shall perish in the flesh because of
unbelief, nevertheless, God will be merciful unto
many; and our children shall be restored, that they
may come to that which will give them the true
knowledge of their Redeemer
3 Wherefore, as I said unto you, it must needs be
expedient that Christ—for in the last night the
angel spake unto me that this should be his
name—should come among the Jews, among those who are the
more wicked part of the world; and they shall
crucify him—for thus it behooveth our God, and there is
none other nation on earth that would crucify
their God
4 For should the mighty miracles be wrought among
other nations they would repent, and know that he
be their God
5 But because of priestcrafts and iniquities, they
at Jerusalem will stiffen their necks against
him, that he be crucified
6 Wherefore, because of their iniquities,
destructions, famines, pestilences, and bloodshed shall
come upon them; and they who shall not be destroyed
shall be scattered among all nations
7 But behold, thus saith the Lord God: When the
day cometh that they shall believe in me, that I am
Christ, then have I covenanted with their fathers
that they shall be restored in the flesh, upon the
earth, unto the lands of their inheritance
8 And it shall come to pass that they shall be
gathered in from their long dispersion, from the
isles of the sea, and from the four parts of the
earth; and the nations of the Gentiles shall be great
in the eyes of me, saith God, in carrying them
forth to the lands of their inheritance
9 Yea, the kings of the Gentiles shall be nursing
fathers unto them, and their queens shall become
nursing mothers; wherefore, the promises of the
Lord are great unto the Gentiles, for he hath spoken
it, and who can dispute
10 But behold, this land, said God, shall be a
land of thine inheritance, and the Gentiles shall be
blessed upon the land
11 And this land shall be a land of liberty unto
the Gentiles, and there shall be no kings upon the
land, who shall raise up unto the Gentiles
12 And I will fortify this land against all other
nations
13 And he that fighteth against Zion shall perish,
saith God
14 For he that raiseth up a king against me shall
perish, for I, the Lord, the king of heaven, will
be their king, and I will be a light unto them
forever, that hear my words
15 Wherefore, for this cause, that my covenants
may be fulfilled which I have made unto the children
of men, that I will do unto them while they are
in the flesh, I must needs destroy the secret works
of darkness, and of murders, and of abominations
16 Wherefore, he that fighteth against Zion, both
Jew and Gentile, both bond and free, both male and
female, shall perish; for they are they who are
the whore of all the earth; for they who are not
for me are against me, saith our God
17 For I will fulfil my promises which I have made
unto the children of men, that I will do unto
them while they are in the flesh
18 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, thus saith our
God: I will afflict thy seed by the hand of the
Gentiles; nevertheless, I will soften the hearts of
the Gentiles, that they shall be like unto a
father to them; wherefore, the Gentiles shall be
blessed and numbered among the house of Israel
19 Wherefore, I will consecrate this land unto thy
seed, and them who shall be numbered among thy
seed, forever, for the land of their inheritance;
for it is a choice land, saith God unto me, above
all other lands, wherefore I will have all men that
dwell thereon that they shall worship me, saith
God
20 And now, my beloved brethren, seeing that our
merciful God has given us so great knowledge
concerning these things, let us remember him, and lay
aside our sins, and not hang down our heads, for we
are not cast off; nevertheless, we have been
driven out of the land of our inheritance; but we have
been led to a better land, for the Lord has made
the sea our path, and we are upon an isle of the
sea
21 But great are the promises of the Lord unto
them who are upon the isles of the sea; wherefore as
it says isles, there must needs be more than this,
and they are inhabited also by our brethren
22 For behold, the Lord God has led away from time
to time from the house of Israel, according to
his will and pleasure. And now behold, the Lord
remembereth all them who have been broken off,
wherefore he remembereth us also
23 Therefore, cheer up your hearts, and remember
that ye are free to act for yourselves—to choose
the way of everlasting death or the way of eternal
life
24 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, reconcile
yourselves to the will of God, and not to the will of
the devil and the flesh; and remember, after ye are
reconciled unto God, that it is only in and
through the grace of God that ye are saved
25 Wherefore, may God raise you from death by the
power of the resurrection, and also from
everlasting death by the power of the atonement, that ye
may be received into the eternal kingdom of God,
that ye may praise him through grace divine. Amen.