The Second Book of NephiAn account of the death
of Lehi. Nephi’s brethren rebel against him. The
Lord warns Nephi to depart into the wilderness.
His journeyings in the wilderness, and so
forth.Chapter 1 Lehi prophesies of a land of liberty—His
seed will be scattered and smitten if they reject
the Holy One of Israel—He exhorts his sons to put
on the armor of righteousness. About 588–570 B.C.
1 And now it came to pass that after I,
Nephi, had made an end of teaching my
brethren, our father, Lehi, also spake many
things unto them, and rehearsed unto them, how
great things the Lord had done for them
in bringing them out of the land of Jerusalem.
2 And he spake unto them concerning
their rebellions upon the waters, and the
mercies of God in sparing their lives,
that they were not swallowed up in the sea.
3 And he also spake unto them
concerning the land of promise, which they
had obtained—how merciful the Lord
had been in warning us that we
should flee out of the land of Jerusalem.
4 For, behold, said he, I have
seen a vision, in which I
know that Jerusalem is destroyed;
and had we remained in
Jerusalem we should also have perished.
5 But, said he,
notwithstanding our afflictions, we
have obtained a land of
promise, a land which is choice
above all other lands; a
land which the Lord God hath
covenanted with me should
be a land for the
inheritance of my seed. Yea, the Lord
hath covenanted this land
unto me, and to my children
forever, and also all
those who should be led out of
other countries by the hand of the Lord.
6 Wherefore, I, Lehi,
prophesy according to the
workings of the Spirit
which is in me, that there
shall none come into this
land save they shall be
brought by the hand of the Lord.
7 Wherefore, this land
is consecrated unto him
whom he shall bring. And
if it so be that they
shall serve him according
to the commandments
which he hath given, it
shall be a land of liberty
unto them; wherefore,
they shall never be brought
down into captivity; if
so, it shall be because
of iniquity; for if
iniquity shall abound
cursed shall be the land for
their sakes, but unto
the righteous it shall be blessed forever.
8 And behold, it is
wisdom that this land
should be kept as yet
from the knowledge of
other nations; for
behold, many nations would
overrun the land, that
there would be no
place for an inheritance.
9 Wherefore, I, Lehi,
have obtained a
promise, that inasmuch as
those whom the Lord
God shall bring out
of the land of
Jerusalem shall keep his
commandments, they shall
prosper upon the
face of this land; and
they shall be kept
from all other nations,
that they may possess
this land unto
themselves. And if it so
be that they shall
keep his commandments
they shall be blessed
upon the face of this
land, and there shall
be none to molest
them, nor to take away
the land of their
inheritance; and they
shall dwell safely forever.
10 But behold, when
the time cometh that
they shall dwindle
in unbelief, after
they have received so
great blessings
from the hand of the
Lord—having a
knowledge of the creation of
the earth, and all
men, knowing the
great and marvelous
works of the Lord from
the creation of the
world; having power
given them to do all
things by faith;
having all the
commandments from the
beginning, and having
been brought by his
infinite goodness into
this precious land
of promise—behold, I
say, if the day
shall come that they
will reject the Holy
One of Israel, the
true Messiah, their
Redeemer and their God,
behold, the
judgments of him that is just shall rest upon them.
11 Yea, he will
bring other nations
unto them, and he
will give unto them
power, and he will
take away from them
the lands of their
possessions, and he
will cause them to
be scattered and smitten.
12 Yea, as one
generation passeth to
another there
shall be bloodsheds,
and great
visitations among them;
wherefore, my sons,
I would that ye
would remember; yea,
would hearken unto my words.
13 O that ye would
awake; awake from
a deep sleep,
yea, even from the
sleep of hell, and
shake off the awful
chains by which
ye are bound, which
are the chains
which bind the
children of men, that
they are carried
away captive down to
the eternal gulf
of misery and woe.
14 Awake! and
arise from the dust,
and hear the
words of a trembling
parent, whose
limbs ye must soon
lay down in the
cold and silent
grave, from whence
no traveler can
return; a few more
days and I go
the way of all the earth.
15 But behold,
the Lord hath
redeemed my soul
from hell; I
have beheld his
glory, and I am
encircled
about eternally in
the arms of his love.
16 And I
desire that ye
should remember to
observe the
statutes and
the judgments of
the Lord;
behold, this hath
been the
anxiety of my soul
from the beginning.
17 My heart
hath been
weighed down with
sorrow from
time to time,
for I have
feared, lest
for the
hardness of your
hearts the Lord
your God
should come out
in the
fulness of his
wrath upon you,
that ye be cut
off and destroyed forever;
18 Or, that
a cursing
should come
upon you for
the space of
many
generations; and ye
are visited
by sword,
and by
famine, and are
hated, and are
led
according to the
will and
captivity of the devil.
19 O my
sons, that
these things
might not
come upon
you, but that
ye might be
a choice
and a
favored people of
the Lord.
But behold,
his will
be done; for
his ways
are righteousness forever.
20 And he
hath said
that:
Inasmuch as ye
shall
keep my
commandments ye
shall
prosper in
the land;
but inasmuch
as ye
will not keep
my
commandments ye
shall be
cut off from my presence.
21 And now
that my
soul might
have joy
in you, and
that my
heart might
leave
this world
with
gladness because
of you,
that I might
not be
brought down
with
grief and
sorrow to the
grave,
arise from
the dust, my
sons, and
be men,
and be
determined in
one mind
and in one
heart,
united in all
things,
that ye may
not come
down into
captivity;
22 That
ye may not
be
cursed with a
sore
cursing; and
also,
that ye may
not incur
the
displeasure
of a just
God upon
you, unto
the
destruction,
yea, the
eternal
destruction of both soul and body.
Awake, my
sons; put
on the
armor of
righteousness.
Shake off
the
chains with
which ye
are
bound, and
come
forth out
of
obscurity, and
arise from the dust.
Rebel no
more
against
your
brother,
whose
views have
been
glorious,
and
who hath
kept
the
commandments
from
the time
that
we left
Jerusalem; and
who
hath been
an
instrument
in the
hands
of God,
in
bringing
us forth
into
the land
of
promise;
for were
it not
for
him, we
must
have
perished
with
hunger in
the
wilderness;
nevertheless,
ye
sought to
take
away his
life; yea, and he hath suffered much sorrow because of you.
25 And
I
exceedingly
fear
and
tremble
because of
you,
lest he
shall
suffer
again;
for
behold, ye
have
accused
him that
he
sought
power and
authority over
you;
but I
know that
he hath
not
sought
for power
nor
authority
over
you, but
he
hath
sought the
glory of
God,
and your
own
eternal
welfare.
26 And
ye
have
murmured
because he
hath
been
plain
unto you.
Ye
say that
he
hath
used
sharpness;
ye
say that
he
hath
been
angry with
you;
but
behold,
his
sharpness was
the
sharpness of
power of
the
word of
God,
which
was in
him;
and
that
which ye
call
anger
was the
truth,
according
to that
which
is in
God,
which
he
could not
restrain, manifesting boldly concerning your iniquities.
And it
must
needs
be
that
the
power
of God
must
be
with
him,
even
unto
his
commanding
you
that ye
must
obey. But
behold,
it was
not
he,
but it
was
the
Spirit
of
the
Lord
which
was in
him,
which
opened
his
mouth to utterance that he could not shut it.
And
now
my
son,
Laman,
and
also
Lemuel
and
Sam,
also
my
sons
who
are
the
sons
of
Ishmael,
behold,
if
ye
will
hearken
unto
the
voice
of
Nephi
ye
shall
not
perish.
And
if
ye
will
hearken
unto
him
I
leave unto you a blessing, yea, even my first blessing.
But
if ye
will
not
hearken
unto
him I
take
away
my
first
blessing,
yea,
even
my
blessing,
and
it
shall
rest
upon
him.
And
now,
Zoram,
I
speak
unto
you:
Behold,
thou
art
the
servant
of
Laban;
nevertheless,
thou
hast
been
brought
out
of
the
land
of
Jerusalem,
and
I
know
that thou art a true friend unto my son, Nephi, forever.
Wherefore,
because
thou
hast
been
faithful
thy
seed
shall
be
blessed
with
his
seed,
that
they
dwell
in
prosperity
long
upon
the
face
of
this
land;
and
nothing,
save
it
shall
be
iniquity among them, shall harm or disturb their prosperity upon the face of this land forever.
32 Wherefore, if ye shall keep the commandments of the Lord, the Lord hath consecrated this land for the security of thy seed with the seed of my son.
Wherefore,
if
ye
shall
keep
the
commandments
of
the
Lord,
Lord
hath
consecrated this land for the security of thy seed with the seed of my son.