Chapter 25 Nephi glories in
plainness—Isaiah’s prophecies will be understood in the last
days—The Jews will return from Babylon,
crucify the Messiah, and be scattered and
scourged—They will be restored when they believe in
the Messiah—He will first come six hundred
years after Lehi left Jerusalem—The Nephites keep
the law of Moses and believe in Christ, who
is the Holy One of Israel. About 559–545 B.C.
1 Now I, Nephi, do speak somewhat
concerning the words which I have written,
which have been spoken by the mouth of
Isaiah. For behold, Isaiah spake many things
which were hard for many of my people
to understand; for they know not
concerning the manner of prophesying among the Jews.
2 For I, Nephi, have not taught
them many things concerning the
manner of the Jews; for their works
were works of darkness, and
their doings were doings of abominations.
3 Wherefore, I write unto my
people, unto all those that shall
receive hereafter these things
which I write, that they may know
the judgments of God, that they
come upon all nations, according
to the word which he hath spoken.
4 Wherefore, hearken, O my
people, which are of the house of
Israel, and give ear unto my
words; for because the words of
Isaiah are not plain unto you,
nevertheless they are plain unto
all those that are filled with
the spirit of prophecy. But I
give unto you a prophecy,
according to the spirit which is in
me; wherefore I shall prophesy
according to the plainness which
hath been with me from the
time that I came out from
Jerusalem with my father; for behold,
my soul delighteth in plainness
unto my people, that they may learn.
5 Yea, and my soul delighteth
in the words of Isaiah, for
I came out from Jerusalem,
and mine eyes hath beheld the
things of the Jews, and I know
that the Jews do understand
the things of the prophets,
and there is none other people
that understand the things
which were spoken unto the
Jews like unto them, save it be
that they are taught after
the manner of the things of the Jews.
6 But behold, I, Nephi,
have not taught my children
after the manner of the Jews;
but behold, I, of myself,
have dwelt at Jerusalem,
wherefore I know concerning
the regions round about; and
I have made mention unto
my children concerning the
judgments of God, which hath
come to pass among the
Jews, unto my children,
according to all that which
Isaiah hath spoken, and I do not write them.
7 But behold, I proceed
with mine own prophecy,
according to my plainness; in
the which I know that no
man can err; nevertheless,
in the days that the
prophecies of Isaiah shall be
fulfilled men shall know of
a surety, at the times
when they shall come to pass.
8 Wherefore, they are of
worth unto the children
of men, and he that
supposeth that they are
not, unto them will I speak
particularly, and
confine the words unto mine
own people; for I know
that they shall be of
great worth unto them in the
last days; for in that
day shall they
understand them; wherefore, for
their good have I written them.
9 And as one
generation hath been destroyed
among the Jews because
of iniquity, even so
have they been
destroyed from generation to
generation according
to their iniquities;
and never hath any of
them been destroyed save
it were foretold them
by the prophets of the Lord.
10 Wherefore, it hath
been told them
concerning the destruction
which should come
upon them, immediately
after my father left
Jerusalem;
nevertheless, they hardened
their hearts; and
according to my prophecy
they have been
destroyed, save it be those
which are carried away
captive into Babylon.
11 And now this I
speak because of the
spirit which is in
me. And
notwithstanding they have been
carried away they shall
return again, and
possess the land of
Jerusalem; wherefore,
they shall be
restored again to the
land of their inheritance.
12 But, behold,
they shall have wars,
and rumors of wars;
and when the day
cometh that the Only
Begotten of the
Father, yea, even the
Father of heaven
and of earth, shall
manifest himself
unto them in the
flesh, behold, they
will reject him,
because of their
iniquities, and the
hardness of their hearts,
and the stiffness of their necks.
13 Behold, they
will crucify him;
and after he is laid
in a sepulchre
for the space of
three days he shall
rise from the dead,
with healing in
his wings; and all
those who shall
believe on his name
shall be saved in
the kingdom of
God. Wherefore, my
soul delighteth to
prophesy concerning
him, for I have
seen his day, and
my heart doth magnify his holy name.
14 And behold it
shall come to
pass that after the
Messiah hath
risen from the dead,
and hath
manifested himself unto
his people, unto
as many as will
believe on his
name, behold,
Jerusalem shall be
destroyed again; for
wo unto them that
fight against God
and the people of his church.
15 Wherefore,
the Jews shall
be scattered
among all nations;
yea, and also
Babylon shall
be destroyed;
wherefore, the
Jews shall be
scattered by other nations.
16 And after
they have been
scattered, and
the Lord God
hath scourged
them by other
nations for
the space of
many generations,
yea, even
down from
generation to
generation until they
shall be
persuaded to
believe in Christ,
the Son of
God, and the
atonement, which
is infinite for
all
mankind—and when that
day shall come
that they
shall believe in
Christ, and
worship the
Father in his name,
with pure
hearts and clean
hands, and
look not forward
any more for
another
Messiah, then, at
that time, the
day will come
that it must
needs be
expedient that they should believe these things.
17 And the
Lord will set
his hand again
the second
time to
restore his people
from their
lost and fallen
state.
Wherefore, he will
proceed to
do a marvelous
work and a
wonder among
the children of men.
Wherefore, he shall
bring forth
his words
unto them,
which words
shall judge them
at the last
day, for
they shall be
given them
for the
purpose of
convincing them of
the true
Messiah, who
was rejected
by them; and
unto the
convincing of
them that
they need not
look forward
any more
for a Messiah
to come, for
there
should not any
come, save it
should be a
false
Messiah which
should deceive
the people;
for there is
save one
Messiah spoken
of by the
prophets, and
that Messiah
is he who should be rejected of the Jews.
19 For
according to
the words of
the
prophets, the
Messiah cometh
in six
hundred years
from the
time that my
father left
Jerusalem;
and
according to the
words of the
prophets,
and also
the word of
the angel of
God, his
name shall
be Jesus Christ, the Son of God.
20 And
now, my
brethren, I
have spoken
plainly
that ye
cannot err. And
as the
Lord God
liveth that
brought
Israel up out
of the
land of
Egypt, and
gave unto
Moses power
that he
should heal
the nations
after
they had been
bitten by
the
poisonous
serpents, if
they would
cast their
eyes unto
the
serpent which he
did raise
up before
them, and
also gave
him power
that he
should
smite the rock
and the
water
should come
forth; yea,
behold I
say unto
you, that as
these
things are
true, and as
the Lord
God liveth,
there is
none other
name
given under
heaven save
it be this
Jesus Christ, of which I have spoken, whereby man can be saved.
Wherefore, for
this
cause hath
the Lord
God
promised unto me
that
these things
which I
write
shall be
kept and
preserved,
and handed
down
unto my
seed, from
generation
to
generation,
that the
promise may
be
fulfilled unto
Joseph,
that his
seed
should never
perish as
long as the earth should stand.
Wherefore,
these
things shall
go from
generation to
generation as
long as the
earth
shall
stand; and
they
shall go
according
to the
will and
pleasure
of God;
and the
nations
who
shall
possess them
shall be
judged
of them
according to the words which are written.
23 For
we labor
diligently to
write, to
persuade
our
children,
and also
our
brethren, to
believe
in
Christ, and
to be
reconciled
to God;
for we
know
that it is
by grace
that we
are
saved,
after all we
can do.
24 And,
notwithstanding we
believe
in
Christ, we
keep
the law
of
Moses, and
look
forward
with
steadfastness unto
Christ, until
the
law shall be fulfilled.
For, for
this
end was
the
law
given;
wherefore the
law
hath
become
dead
unto us,
and we
are
made
alive in
Christ
because of
our
faith;
yet we
keep
the
law because of the commandments.
And we
talk
of
Christ,
we
rejoice in
Christ, we
preach of
Christ,
we
prophesy
of
Christ, and
we
write
according
to
our
prophecies,
that
our
children may
know
to
what
source
they
may look for a remission of their sins.
Wherefore, we
speak
concerning
the
law
that
our
children
may
know
the
deadness of
law;
and
they,
by
knowing
the
deadness
of
the
law,
may
look
forward
unto
that
life
which is
in
Christ,
and
know
for
what
end
the
law
was
given.
And
after
the
law
is
fulfilled
in
Christ,
that
they
need not harden their hearts against him when the law ought to be done away.
And
now
behold,
my
people,
ye
are
a
stiffnecked
people;
wherefore,
I
have
spoken
plainly
unto
you,
that
ye
cannot
misunderstand.
And
the
words
which I
have
spoken
shall
stand
as
a
testimony
against
you;
for
they
are
sufficient
to
teach
any
man
the
right
way;
for
the
right
way
is
to believe in Christ and deny him not; for by denying him ye also deny the prophets and the law.
And
now
behold,
I
say
unto
you
that
the
right
way
is
to
believe
in
Christ,
and
deny
him
not;
and
Christ
is
the
Holy
One
of
Israel;
wherefore
ye
must
bow
down
before
him,
and
worship
him
with
all
your
might,
mind,
and
strength,
your
whole
soul;
and
if
ye
do
this
ye
shall
in
nowise
be
cast
out.
And,
inasmuch
as
it
shall
be
expedient,
ye
must
keep
the
performances
and
ordinances
of
God
until
the
law
shall
be
fulfilled
which
was
given
unto
Moses.