Chapter 24 Israel will be gathered and will
enjoy millennial rest—Lucifer was cast out of heaven
for rebellion—Israel will triumph over Babylon
(the world)—Compare
Isaiah 14. About 559–545 B.C.
1 For the Lord will have mercy on Jacob, and
will yet choose Israel, and set them in their own
land; and the strangers shall be joined with
them, and they shall cleave to the house of Jacob.
2 And the people shall take them and bring
them to their place; yea, from far unto the
ends of the earth; and they shall return to
their lands of promise. And the house of Israel
shall possess them, and the land of the Lord
shall be for servants and handmaids; and they
shall take them captives unto whom they were
captives; and they shall rule over their oppressors.
3 And it shall come to pass in that day
that the Lord shall give thee rest, from thy
sorrow, and from thy fear, and from the
hard bondage wherein thou wast made to serve.
4 And it shall come to pass in
that day, that thou shalt take up
this proverb against the king of
Babylon, and say: How hath the
oppressor ceased, the golden city ceased!
5 The Lord hath broken
the staff of the wicked,
the scepters of the rulers.
6 He who smote the
people in wrath with a
continual stroke, he
that ruled the
nations in anger, is
persecuted, and none hindereth.
7 The whole earth
is at rest, and is
quiet; they break
forth into singing.
8 Yea, the fir
trees rejoice at
thee, and also
the cedars of
Lebanon, saying:
Since thou art
laid down no feller
is come up against us.
9 Hell from
beneath is moved
for thee to meet
thee at thy
coming; it
stirreth up the dead
for thee, even
all the chief
ones of the
earth; it hath
raised up from
their thrones all
the kings of the nations.
10 All they
shall speak and
say unto thee:
Art thou also
become weak as we?
Art thou
become like unto us?
11 Thy pomp is
brought down to
the grave; the
noise of thy
viols is not
heard; the worm is
spread under
thee, and the
worms cover thee.
12 How art
thou fallen from
heaven, O
Lucifer, son of
the morning! Art
thou cut down
to the
ground, which did
weaken the nations!
13 For thou
hast said in
thy heart: I
will ascend
into heaven, I
will exalt my
throne above
the stars of
God; I will
sit also upon
the mount of
the
congregation, in the
sides of the north;
14 I will
ascend above
the
heights of the
clouds; I
will be like
the Most High.
15 Yet
thou shalt
be
brought down to
hell, to
the
sides of the pit.
16 They
that see
thee
shall
narrowly
look upon
thee, and
shall
consider
thee,
and shall
say: Is
this the
man
that made
the earth
to
tremble,
that did shake kingdoms?
17 And
made
the world
as a
wilderness, and
destroyed the
cities
thereof, and
opened
not the
house
of his prisoners?
18 All
the
kings
of the
nations,
yea, all
of
them, lie
in
glory,
every
one of
them
in his own house.
But
thou art
cast
out
of
thy
grave
like an
abominable
branch,
and
the
remnant
of
those
that
are
slain,
thrust
through
with
a
sword,
that
go
down to
the
stones of
pit; as a carcass trodden under feet.
Thou
shalt
not be
joined
with
them in
burial,
because
thou
hast
destroyed thy
land
and
slain
thy
people;
the
seed of
evil-doers
shall
never be
renowned.
Prepare
slaughter
for
his
children
for
the
iniquities
of
their
fathers,
that
they
do
not
rise,
nor
possess
the
land,
nor
fill
the face of the world with cities.
For
I
will
rise
up
against
them,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts,
and
cut
off
from
Babylon
the
name,
and
remnant,
and son, and nephew, saith the Lord.
I
will
also
make
it
a
possession
for
the
bittern,
and
pools
of
water;
and
I
will
sweep
it
with
the besom of destruction, saith the Lord of Hosts.
24 The Lord of Hosts hath sworn, saying: Surely as I have thought, so shall it come to pass; and as I have purposed, so shall it
The
Lord
of
Hosts
hath
sworn,
saying:
Surely
as
I
have
thought,
so shall it come to pass; and as I have purposed, so shall it stand—
25 That I will bring the Assyrian in my land, and upon my mountains tread him under foot; then shall his yoke depart from off them, and his burden depart from off their
That
I
will
bring
the
Assyrian
in
my
land,
and
upon
my
mountains
tread
him
under
foot;
then
shall
his
yoke
depart
from
off
them,
and
his
burden
depart
from
off
their
shoulders.
26 This is the purpose that is purposed upon the whole earth; and this is the hand that is stretched out upon all
This
is
the
purpose
that
is
purposed
upon
the
whole
earth;
and
this
is
the
hand
that
is
stretched
out
upon
all
nations.
27 For the Lord of Hosts hath purposed, and who shall disannul? And his hand is stretched out, and who shall turn it
For
the
Lord
of
Hosts
hath
purposed,
and
who
shall
disannul?
And
his
hand
is
stretched
out,
and
who
shall
turn
it
back?
28 In the year that king Ahaz died was this
In
the
year
that
king
Ahaz
died
was
this
burden.
29 Rejoice not thou, whole Palestina, because the rod of him that smote thee is broken; for out of the serpent’s root shall come forth a cockatrice, and his fruit shall be a fiery flying
Rejoice
not
thou,
whole
Palestina,
because
the
rod
of
him
that
smote
thee
is
broken;
for
out
of
the
serpent’s
root
shall
come
forth
a
cockatrice,
and
his
fruit
shall
be
a
fiery
flying
serpent.
30 And the firstborn of the poor shall feed, and the needy shall lie down in safety; and I will kill thy root with famine, and he shall slay thy
And
the
firstborn
of
the
poor
shall
feed,
and
the
needy
shall
lie
down
in
safety;
and
I
will
kill
thy
root
with
famine,
and
he
shall
slay
thy
remnant.
31 Howl, O gate; cry, O city; thou, whole Palestina, art dissolved; for there shall come from the north a smoke, and none shall be alone in his appointed
Howl,
O
gate;
cry,
O
city;
thou,
whole
Palestina,
art
dissolved;
for
there
shall
come
from
the
north
a
smoke,
and
none
shall
be
alone
in
his
appointed
times.
32 What shall then answer the messengers of the nations? That the Lord hath founded Zion, and the poor of his people shall trust in it.
What
shall
then
answer
the
messengers
of
the
nations?
That
the
Lord
hath
founded
Zion,
and
the
poor
of
his
people
shall
trust
in
it.