Chapter 13 Judah and Jerusalem will be punished
for their disobedience—The Lord pleads for and
judges His people—The daughters of Zion are cursed and
tormented for their worldliness—Compare
Isaiah 3.
About 559–545 B.C.
1 For behold, the Lord, the Lord of Hosts, doth
take away from Jerusalem, and from Judah, the stay
and the staff, the whole staff of bread, and the
whole stay of water
2 The mighty man, and the man of war, the judge,
and the prophet, and the prudent, and the ancient
3 The captain of fifty, and the honorable man, and
the counselor, and the cunning artificer, and the
eloquent orator
4 And I will give children unto them to be their
princes, and babes shall rule over them
5 And the people shall be oppressed, every one by
another, and every one by his neighbor; the child
shall behave himself proudly against the ancient,
and the base against the honorable
6 When a man shall take hold of his brother of the
house of his father, and shall say: Thou hast
clothing, be thou our ruler, and let not this ruin
come under thy hand
7 In that day shall he swear, saying: I will not
be a healer; for in my house there is neither bread
nor clothing; make me not a ruler of the people
8 For Jerusalem is ruined, and Judah is fallen,
because their tongues and their doings have been
against the Lord, to provoke the eyes of his glory
9 The show of their countenance doth witness
against them, and doth declare their sin to be even as
Sodom, and they cannot hide it. Wo unto their
souls, for they have rewarded evil unto themselves
10 Say unto the righteous that it is well with
them; for they shall eat the fruit of their doings
11 Wo unto the wicked, for they shall perish; for
the reward of their hands shall be upon them
12 And my people, children are their oppressors,
and women rule over them. O my people, they who
lead thee cause thee to err and destroy the way of
thy paths
13 The Lord standeth up to plead, and standeth to
judge the people
14 The Lord will enter into judgment with the
ancients of his people and the princes thereof; for ye
have eaten up the vineyard and the spoil of the
poor in your houses
15 What mean ye? Ye beat my people to pieces, and
grind the faces of the poor, saith the Lord God of
Hosts
16 Moreover, the Lord saith: Because the daughters
of Zion are haughty, and walk with
stretched-forth necks and wanton eyes, walking and mincing as
they go, and making a tinkling with their feet
17 Therefore the Lord will smite with a scab the
crown of the head of the daughters of Zion, and the
Lord will discover their secret parts
18 In that day the Lord will take away the bravery
of their tinkling ornaments, and cauls, and round
tires like the moon
19 The chains and the bracelets, and the mufflers
20 The bonnets, and the ornaments of the legs, and
the headbands, and the tablets, and the
ear-rings
21 The rings, and nose jewels
22 The changeable suits of apparel, and the
mantles, and the wimples, and the crisping-pins
23 The glasses, and the fine linen, and hoods, and
the veils
24 And it shall come to pass, instead of sweet
smell there shall be stink; and instead of a girdle,
a rent; and instead of well set hair, baldness;
and instead of a stomacher, a girding of sackcloth;
burning instead of beauty
25 Thy men shall fall by the sword and thy mighty
in the war
26 And her gates shall lament and mourn; and she
shall be desolate, and shall sit upon the ground.