Chapter 15 The Lord’s vineyard (Israel) will
become desolate, and His people will be
scattered—Woes will come upon them in their apostate and
scattered state—The Lord will lift an ensign and
gather Israel—Compare
Isaiah 5. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And then will I sing to my well-beloved a
song of my beloved, touching his vineyard. My
well-beloved hath a vineyard in a very fruitful hill.
2 And he fenced it, and gathered out the
stones thereof, and planted it with the
choicest vine, and built a tower in the midst
of it, and also made a wine-press
therein; and he looked that it should bring forth
grapes, and it brought forth wild grapes.
3 And now, O inhabitants of
Jerusalem, and men of Judah, judge, I
pray you, betwixt me and my vineyard.
4 What could have been done more
to my vineyard that I have not
done in it? Wherefore, when I
looked that it should bring forth
grapes it brought forth wild grapes.
5 And now go to; I will
tell you what I will do to my
vineyard—I will take away
the hedge thereof, and it
shall be eaten up; and I will
break down the wall
thereof, and it shall be trodden down;
6 And I will lay it
waste; it shall not be
pruned nor digged; but
there shall come up briers
and thorns; I will
also command the clouds
that they rain no rain upon it.
7 For the vineyard of
the Lord of Hosts is
the house of Israel,
and the men of Judah
his pleasant plant;
and he looked for
judgment, and behold,
oppression; for
righteousness, but behold, a cry.
8 Wo unto them that
join house to house,
till there can be
no place, that they
may be placed alone
in the midst of the earth!
9 In mine ears,
said the Lord of
Hosts, of a truth
many houses shall be
desolate, and
great and fair cities
without inhabitant.
10 Yea, ten
acres of vineyard
shall yield one
bath, and the seed
of a homer
shall yield an ephah.
11 Wo unto them
that rise up
early in the
morning, that they
may follow
strong drink, that
continue until
night, and
wine inflame them!
12 And the
harp, and the
viol, the tabret,
and pipe, and
wine are in
their feasts;
but they regard
not the work
of the Lord,
neither
consider the
operation of his hands.
13 Therefore,
my people
are gone into
captivity,
because they
have no
knowledge; and their
honorable men
are
famished, and their
multitude
dried up with thirst.
Therefore, hell hath
enlarged
herself, and
opened her
mouth without
measure; and
their glory,
and their
multitude,
pomp, and he
that rejoiceth,
shall descend into it.
15 And the
mean man
shall be
brought down,
and the
mighty man
shall be
humbled, and the
eyes of the
lofty
shall be humbled.
16 But the
Lord of
Hosts shall
be
exalted in
judgment, and
God that is
holy
shall be
sanctified in
righteousness.
17 Then
shall the
lambs
feed after
their
manner, and
the waste
places of
the fat
ones
shall strangers eat.
18 Wo
unto them
that
draw
iniquity with
cords of
vanity,
and sin
as it
were with
a cart rope;
19 That
say:
Let him
make
speed,
hasten
his work,
that
we may
see it;
and let
the
counsel
of the
Holy One
of
Israel
draw nigh
and
come, that we may know it.
20 Wo
unto
them
that
call evil
good,
and
good
evil,
that put
darkness
for
light, and
light
for
darkness,
that put
bitter
for
sweet, and sweet for bitter!
21 Wo
unto
the
wise
in
their
own
eyes
and
prudent
in
their own sight!
22 Wo
unto
the
mighty to
drink
wine, and
men
of
strength to
mingle
strong
drink;
Who
justify
the
wicked
for
reward,
and
take
away
the
righteousness of
righteous from him!
Therefore,
as
the
fire
devoureth
the
stubble,
and
the
flame
consumeth
the
chaff,
their
root
shall
be
rottenness,
and
their
blossoms
shall
go
up
as
dust;
because
they
have
cast
away
the
law
of
the Lord of Hosts, and despised the word of the Holy One of Israel.
Therefore,
is
the
anger
of
the
Lord
kindled
against
his
people,
and
he
hath
stretched
forth
his
hand
against
them,
and
hath
smitten
them;
and
the
hills
did
tremble,
and
their
carcasses
were
torn
in
the
midst
of
the
streets.
For
all
this
his
anger
is
not
turned
away,
but
his
hand
is
stretched
out
still.
And
he
will
lift
up
an
ensign
to
the
nations
from
far,
and
will
hiss
unto
them
from
the
end
of
the
earth;
and
behold,
they
shall
come with speed swiftly; none shall be weary nor stumble among them.
27 None shall slumber nor sleep; neither shall the girdle of their loins be loosed, nor the latchet of their shoes be
None
shall
slumber
nor
sleep;
neither
shall
the
girdle
of
their loins be loosed, nor the latchet of their shoes be broken;
28 Whose arrows shall be sharp, and all their bows bent, and their horses’ hoofs shall be counted like flint, and their wheels like a whirlwind, their roaring like a
Whose
arrows
shall
be
sharp,
and
all
their
bows
bent,
and
their
horses’
hoofs
shall
be
counted
like
flint,
and
their
wheels
like
a
whirlwind,
their
roaring
like
a
lion.
29 They shall roar like young lions; yea, they shall roar, and lay hold of the prey, and shall carry away safe, and none shall
They
shall
roar
like
young
lions;
yea,
they
shall
roar,
and
lay
hold
of
the
prey,
and
shall
carry
away
safe,
and
none
shall
deliver.
30 And in that day they shall roar against them like the roaring of the sea; and if they look unto the land, behold, darkness and sorrow, and the light is darkened in the heavens thereof.
And
in
that
day
they
shall
roar
against
them
like
the
roaring
of
the
sea;
and
if
they
look
unto
the
land,
behold,
darkness
and
sorrow,
the
light
is
darkened
in
the
heavens
thereof.