Chapter 30 Converted Gentiles will be
numbered with the covenant people—Many
Lamanites and Jews will believe the word and
become delightsome—Israel will be restored and
the wicked destroyed. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And now behold, my beloved brethren, I
would speak unto you; for I, Nephi,
would not suffer that ye should suppose
that ye are more righteous than the
Gentiles shall be. For behold, except ye shall
keep the commandments of God ye shall
all likewise perish; and because of the
words which have been spoken ye need not
suppose that the Gentiles are utterly destroyed.
2 For behold, I say unto you that as
many of the Gentiles as will repent
are the covenant people of the
Lord; and as many of the Jews as will
not repent shall be cast off; for the
Lord covenanteth with none save it
be with them that repent and believe
in his Son, who is the Holy One of Israel.
3 And now, I would prophesy
somewhat more concerning the Jews and
the Gentiles. For after the book
of which I have spoken shall come
forth, and be written unto the
Gentiles, and sealed up again unto
the Lord, there shall be many
which shall believe the words which
are written; and they shall
carry them forth unto the remnant of our seed.
4 And then shall the remnant
of our seed know concerning
us, how that we came out
from Jerusalem, and that they
are descendants of the Jews.
5 And the gospel of Jesus
Christ shall be declared
among them; wherefore, they
shall be restored unto
the knowledge of their
fathers, and also to the
knowledge of Jesus Christ, which
was had among their fathers.
6 And then shall they
rejoice; for they shall know
that it is a blessing
unto them from the hand of
God; and their scales of
darkness shall begin to
fall from their eyes; and
many generations shall
not pass away among them,
save they shall be a pure
and a delightsome people.
7 And it shall come to
pass that the Jews which
are scattered also shall
begin to believe in
Christ; and they shall
begin to gather in upon the
face of the land; and as
many as shall believe
in Christ shall also
become a delightsome people.
8 And it shall come to
pass that the Lord
God shall commence his
work among all nations,
kindreds, tongues,
and people, to bring
about the restoration of
his people upon the earth.
9 And with
righteousness shall the Lord
God judge the poor,
and reprove with
equity for the meek of
the earth. And he
shall smite the earth
with the rod of his
mouth; and with the
breath of his lips
shall he slay the wicked.
10 For the time
speedily cometh that
the Lord God
shall cause a great
division among the
people, and the
wicked will he
destroy; and he will
spare his people,
yea, even if it so be
that he must
destroy the wicked by fire.
11 And
righteousness shall be
the girdle of his
loins, and
faithfulness the
girdle of his reins.
12 And then
shall the wolf
dwell with the
lamb; and the
leopard shall lie
down with the
kid, and the
calf, and the young
lion, and the
fatling,
together; and a
little child shall lead them.
13 And the
cow and the
bear shall feed;
their young
ones shall
lie down
together; and the
lion shall eat
straw like the ox.
14 And the
sucking child
shall play
on the hole
of the asp,
and the
weaned child
shall put his
hand on the
cockatrice’s den.
15 They
shall not hurt
nor
destroy in all my
holy
mountain; for
the earth
shall be full
of the
knowledge of
the Lord as
the waters
cover the sea.
Wherefore, the
things of
all nations
shall be
made known;
yea, all
things
shall be made
known
unto the
children of men.
17 There
is
nothing which
is secret
save it
shall be
revealed;
there is
no work
of
darkness save it
shall be
made
manifest in
the
light; and
there is
nothing
which is
sealed upon
the earth
save it shall be loosed.
Wherefore,
all things
which
have been
revealed unto
the
children of
men shall
at that
day be
revealed; and
Satan
shall have
power
over the
hearts of
the
children of
men no
more, for
a long
time.
And now,
my
beloved
brethren, I make an end of my sayings.