Chapter 6 Jacob recounts Jewish history:
The Babylonian captivity and return; the
ministry and crucifixion of the Holy One of
Israel; the help received from the Gentiles;
and the Jews’ latter-day restoration when
they believe in the Messiah. About 559–545 B.C.
1 The words of Jacob, the brother of
Nephi, which he spake unto the people of Nephi:
2 Behold, my beloved brethren, I,
Jacob, having been called of God, and
ordained after the manner of his holy
order, and having been consecrated by my
brother Nephi, unto whom ye look as a
king or a protector, and on whom ye
depend for safety, behold ye know that I
have spoken unto you exceedingly many things.
3 Nevertheless, I speak unto you
again; for I am desirous for the
welfare of your souls. Yea, mine anxiety
is great for you; and ye yourselves
know that it ever has been. For I
have exhorted you with all diligence;
and I have taught you the words of my
father; and I have spoken unto you
concerning all things which are
written, from the creation of the world.
4 And now, behold, I would speak
unto you concerning things which
are, and which are to come;
wherefore, I will read you the words of
Isaiah. And they are the words which
my brother has desired that I
should speak unto you. And I speak
unto you for your sakes, that ye may
learn and glorify the name of your God.
5 And now, the words which I
shall read are they which
Isaiah spake concerning all the
house of Israel; wherefore, they
may be likened unto you, for
ye are of the house of Israel.
And there are many things
which have been spoken by Isaiah
which may be likened unto you,
because ye are of the house of Israel.
6 And now, these are the
words: Thus saith the Lord
God: Behold, I will lift up
mine hand to the Gentiles,
and set up my standard to
the people; and they shall
bring thy sons in their arms,
and thy daughters shall be
carried upon their shoulders.
7 And kings shall be thy
nursing fathers, and their
queens thy nursing
mothers; they shall bow down to
thee with their faces
towards the earth, and lick up
the dust of thy feet; and
thou shalt know that I am
the Lord; for they shall
not be ashamed that wait for me.
8 And now I, Jacob,
would speak somewhat
concerning these words. For
behold, the Lord has shown
me that those who were
at Jerusalem, from whence
we came, have been
slain and carried away captive.
9 Nevertheless, the
Lord has shown unto me
that they should return
again. And he also has
shown unto me that the
Lord God, the Holy One of
Israel, should
manifest himself unto them in
the flesh; and after he
should manifest
himself they should scourge
him and crucify him,
according to the words of
the angel who spake it unto me.
10 And after they
have hardened their
hearts and stiffened
their necks against the
Holy One of Israel,
behold, the judgments
of the Holy One of
Israel shall come upon
them. And the day
cometh that they shall be
smitten and afflicted.
11 Wherefore, after
they are driven to
and fro, for thus
saith the angel, many
shall be afflicted in
the flesh, and
shall not be suffered to
perish, because of
the prayers of the
faithful; they shall
be scattered, and
smitten, and hated;
nevertheless, the Lord
will be merciful
unto them, that when
they shall come to
the knowledge of their
Redeemer, they
shall be gathered
together again to the
lands of their inheritance.
12 And blessed are
the Gentiles, they
of whom the prophet
has written; for
behold, if it so be
that they shall
repent and fight not
against Zion, and do
not unite
themselves to that great
and abominable
church, they shall be
saved; for the Lord
God will fulfil his
covenants which he
has made unto his
children; and for
this cause the prophet
has written these things.
13 Wherefore, they
that fight
against Zion and the
covenant people of
the Lord shall lick
up the dust of
their feet; and the
people of the Lord
shall not be
ashamed. For the people
of the Lord are
they who wait for
him; for they still
wait for the
coming of the Messiah.
14 And behold,
according to the
words of the
prophet, the Messiah
will set himself
again the second
time to recover
them; wherefore, he
will manifest
himself unto them in
power and great
glory, unto the
destruction of
their enemies, when
that day cometh
when they shall
believe in him; and
none will he
destroy that believe in him.
15 And they that
believe not in
him shall be
destroyed, both by
fire, and by
tempest, and by
earthquakes, and by
bloodsheds, and
by pestilence,
and by famine.
And they shall
know that the Lord
is God, the
Holy One of Israel.
16 For shall the
prey be taken
from the mighty,
or the lawful
captive delivered?
17 But thus
saith the Lord:
Even the captives
of the mighty
shall be taken
away, and the
prey of the
terrible shall be
delivered; for
the Mighty God
shall deliver
his covenant
people. For thus
saith the Lord: I
will contend
with them that
contendeth with thee—
18 And I will
feed them that
oppress thee,
with their
own flesh; and
they shall be
drunken with
their own blood
as with sweet
wine; and all
flesh shall
know that I the
Lord am thy
Savior and thy
Redeemer, the
Mighty One of Jacob.