Chapter 17 Ephraim and Syria wage war
against Judah—Christ will be born of a
virgin—Compare
Isaiah 7. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And it came to pass in the days
of Ahaz the son of Jotham, the son
of Uzziah, king of Judah, that
Rezin, king of Syria, and Pekah the son
of Remaliah, king of Israel, went
up toward Jerusalem to war against
it, but could not prevail against it.
2 And it was told the house of
David, saying: Syria is
confederate with Ephraim. And his
heart was moved, and the heart
of his people, as the trees of
the wood are moved with the wind.
3 Then said the Lord unto
Isaiah: Go forth now to meet
Ahaz, thou and Shearjashub
thy son, at the end of the
conduit of the upper pool in
the highway of the fuller’s field;
4 And say unto him: Take
heed, and be quiet; fear not,
neither be faint-hearted for
the two tails of these
smoking firebrands, for the
fierce anger of Rezin with Syria,
and of the son of Remaliah.
5 Because Syria,
Ephraim, and the son of
Remaliah, have taken evil
counsel against thee, saying:
6 Let us go up against
Judah and vex it, and
let us make a breach
therein for us, and set a
king in the midst of
it, yea, the son of Tabeal.
7 Thus saith the
Lord God: It shall
not stand, neither
shall it come to pass.
8 For the head of
Syria is
Damascus, and the head
of Damascus,
Rezin; and within
threescore and five
years shall
Ephraim be broken that
it be not a people.
9 And the head
of Ephraim is
Samaria, and the
head of
Samaria is Remaliah’s
son. If ye
will not believe
surely ye shall
not be established.
10 Moreover,
the Lord
spake again unto
Ahaz, saying:
11 Ask thee
a sign of
the Lord
thy God; ask
it either
in the
depths, or in
the heights above.
12 But
Ahaz said: I
will not
ask,
neither will I
tempt the Lord.
13 And he
said:
Hear ye
now, O house
of
David; is it a
small
thing for
you to
weary men,
but will
ye weary my God also?
Therefore,
the Lord
himself
shall
give you a
sign—Behold, a
virgin
shall
conceive,
and shall
bear a
son, and
shall
call his name Immanuel.
Butter and
honey
shall he
eat,
that he
may
know to
refuse
the evil
and to
choose the good.
16 For
before
the
child
shall know
to
refuse the
evil
and
choose the
good,
the land
that
thou
abhorrest
shall be
forsaken of
both her
kings.
17 The
Lord
shall
bring
upon
thee,
and
upon thy
people, and
upon
thy
father’s
house,
days
that
have
not come
from
the
day that
Ephraim
departed
from
Judah, the king of Assyria.
And it
shall
come
to
pass
in
that day
that
the
Lord
shall
hiss
for
the
fly
that is
in
the
uttermost
part of
Egypt,
and for
the
bee
that is in the land of Assyria.
And
they
shall
come,
and
shall
rest
all
of
them
in
the
desolate
valleys,
and
in
the
holes
of
the
rocks,
and
upon
all thorns, and upon all bushes.
In
the
same
day
shall
the
Lord
shave
with
a
razor
that
is
hired,
by
them
beyond
the
river,
by
the
king
of
Assyria,
the
head,
and
the
hair
of the feet; and it shall also consume the beard.
And
it
shall
come
to
pass
in
that
day,
a
man
shall
nourish a young cow and two sheep;
22 And it shall come to pass, for the abundance of milk they shall give he shall eat butter; for butter and honey shall every one eat that is left in the
And
it
shall
come
to
pass,
for
the
abundance
of
milk
they
shall
give
he
shall eat butter; for butter and honey shall every one eat that is left in the land.
23 And it shall come to pass in that day, every place shall be, where there were a thousand vines at a thousand silverlings, which shall be for briers and
And
it
shall
come
to
pass
in
that
day,
every
place
shall
be,
where
there
were
a
thousand
vines
at
a
thousand
silverlings,
which
shall
be
for
briers
and
thorns.
24 With arrows and with bows shall men come thither, because all the land shall become briers and
With
arrows
and
with
bows
shall
men
come
thither,
because
all
the
land
shall
become
briers
and
thorns.
25 And all hills that shall be digged with the mattock, there shall not come thither the fear of briers and thorns; but it shall be for the sending forth of oxen, and the treading of lesser cattle.
And
all
hills
that
shall
be
digged
with
the
mattock,
there
shall
not
come
thither
the
fear
of
briers
and
thorns;
but
it
shall
be
for
the
sending
forth
of
oxen,
and
the
treading
of
lesser
cattle.