Chapter 7 Jacob continues reading from Isaiah:
Isaiah speaks messianically—The Messiah will have the
tongue of the learned—He will give His back to
the smiters—He will not be confounded—Compare
Isaiah 50. About 559–545 B.C.
1 Yea, for thus saith the Lord: Have I put thee
away, or have I cast thee off forever? For thus
saith the Lord: Where is the bill of your mother’s
divorcement? To whom have I put thee away, or to
which of my creditors have I sold you? Yea, to whom
have I sold you? Behold, for your iniquities have ye
sold yourselves, and for your transgressions is
your mother put away
2 Wherefore, when I came, there was no man; when I
called, yea, there was none to answer. O house of
Israel, is my hand shortened at all that it
cannot redeem, or have I no power to deliver? Behold,
at my rebuke I dry up the sea, I make their rivers
a wilderness and their fish to stink because the
waters are dried up, and they die because of
thirst
3 I clothe the heavens with blackness, and I make
sackcloth their covering
6 I gave my back to the smiter, and my cheeks to
them that plucked off the hair. I hid not my face
from shame and spitting
7 For the Lord God will help me, therefore shall I
not be confounded. Therefore have I set my face
like a flint, and I know that I shall not be
ashamed
8 And the Lord is near, and he justifieth me. Who
will contend with me? Let us stand together. Who
is mine adversary? Let him come near me, and I will
smite him with the strength of my mouth
11 Behold all ye that kindle fire, that compass
yourselves about with sparks, walk in the light of
your fire and in the sparks which ye have kindled.
This shall ye have of mine hand—ye shall lie down
in sorrow.