Chapter 14 Zion and her daughters will be
redeemed and cleansed in the millennial
day—Compare
Isaiah 4. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And in that day, seven women shall
take hold of one man, saying: We
will eat our own bread, and wear our
own apparel; only let us be called by
thy name to take away our reproach.
2 In that day shall the
branch of the Lord be beautiful
and glorious; the fruit of the
earth excellent and comely to
them that are escaped of Israel.
3 And it shall come to
pass, they that are left in
Zion and remain in
Jerusalem shall be called holy,
every one that is written
among the living in Jerusalem—
4 When the Lord shall
have washed away the filth
of the daughters of
Zion, and shall have purged
the blood of Jerusalem
from the midst thereof
by the spirit of judgment
and by the spirit of burning.
5 And the Lord will
create upon every
dwelling-place of mount Zion,
and upon her assemblies,
a cloud and smoke by
day and the shining of a
flaming fire by night;
for upon all the glory
of Zion shall be a defence.
6 And there shall be
a tabernacle for a
shadow in the
daytime from the heat, and
for a place of
refuge, and a covert
from storm and from rain.