Chapter 31 Nephi tells why Christ was
baptized—Men must follow Christ, be baptized, receive the
Holy Ghost, and endure to the end to be
saved—Repentance and baptism are the gate to the strait and
narrow path—Eternal life comes to those who keep
the commandments after baptism. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And now I, Nephi, make an end of my
prophesying unto you, my beloved brethren. And I
cannot write but a few things, which I know
must surely come to pass; neither can I write
but a few of the words of my brother Jacob.
2 Wherefore, the things which I have
written sufficeth me, save it be a
few words which I must speak concerning
the doctrine of Christ; wherefore, I
shall speak unto you plainly,
according to the plainness of my prophesying.
3 For my soul delighteth in
plainness; for after this manner doth
the Lord God work among the children
of men. For the Lord God giveth
light unto the understanding; for
he speaketh unto men according to
their language, unto their understanding.
4 Wherefore, I would that ye
should remember that I have
spoken unto you concerning that
prophet which the Lord showed
unto me, that should baptize
the Lamb of God, which should
take away the sins of the world.
5 And now, if the Lamb of
God, he being holy, should
have need to be baptized by
water, to fulfil all
righteousness, O then, how much more
need have we, being unholy,
to be baptized, yea, even by water!
6 And now, I would ask of
you, my beloved brethren,
wherein the Lamb of God
did fulfil all righteousness
in being baptized by water?
7 Know ye not that he
was holy? But
notwithstanding he being holy, he
showeth unto the children
of men that, according
to the flesh he humbleth
himself before the
Father, and witnesseth unto
the Father that he would
be obedient unto him in
keeping his commandments.
8 Wherefore, after
he was baptized with
water the Holy Ghost
descended upon him
in the form of a dove.
9 And again, it
showeth unto the
children of men the
straitness of the path,
and the narrowness
of the gate, by
which they should
enter, he having set
the example before them.
10 And he said
unto the children
of men: Follow
thou me. Wherefore,
my beloved
brethren, can we follow
Jesus save we
shall be willing to
keep the
commandments of the Father?
11 And the
Father said: Repent
ye, repent ye,
and be
baptized in the name
of my Beloved Son.
12 And also,
the voice of
the Son came
unto me, saying:
He that is
baptized in my
name, to him
will the Father
give the Holy
Ghost, like
unto me;
wherefore, follow me,
and do the
things which ye
have seen me do.
13 Wherefore,
my beloved
brethren, I
know that if ye
shall follow
the Son,
with full
purpose of heart,
acting no
hypocrisy and no
deception
before God, but
with real
intent,
repenting of your
sins, witnessing
unto the
Father that ye
are willing to
take upon
you the name of
Christ, by
baptism—yea,
by following
your Lord and
your Savior
down into the
water,
according to his
word, behold,
then shall ye
receive the
Holy Ghost;
yea, then
cometh the baptism
of fire and
of the Holy
Ghost; and
then can ye
speak with the
tongue of
angels, and shout praises unto the Holy One of Israel.
14 But,
behold, my
beloved brethren,
thus came
the voice of
the Son unto
me, saying:
After ye
have repented
of your
sins, and
witnessed unto the
Father that
ye are
willing to keep
my
commandments, by the
baptism of
water, and
have received
the baptism
of fire and
of the Holy
Ghost, and
can speak
with a new
tongue, yea,
even with the
tongue of
angels, and
after this
should deny me,
it would
have been
better for you that ye had not known me.
15 And I
heard a voice
from the
Father,
saying: Yea,
the words of
my Beloved
are true
and faithful.
He that
endureth to
the end, the
same shall be saved.
16 And now,
my beloved
brethren,
I know by
this that
unless a man
shall
endure to the
end, in
following the
example of
the Son of
the living
God, he
cannot be saved.
Wherefore, do the
things
which I have
told you
I have
seen that
your Lord and
your
Redeemer
should do; for,
for this
cause have
they been
shown
unto me, that
ye might
know the
gate by
which ye
should enter.
For the
gate by
which ye
should enter is
repentance and
baptism by
water; and
then cometh
a
remission of your
sins by fire and by the Holy Ghost.
18 And
then are ye
in this
strait
and narrow
path
which leads
to eternal
life;
yea, ye
have entered
in by
the gate;
ye have
done
according to
the
commandments of
Father and the
Son; and
ye have
received
the Holy
Ghost,
which
witnesses of
the Father
and the
Son, unto
the
fulfilling of
promise which
he hath
made,
that if ye
entered in by the way ye should receive.
19 And
now, my
beloved
brethren,
after
ye have
gotten
into this
strait
and
narrow path,
I would
ask if
all is
done?
Behold, I
say unto
you, Nay;
for ye
have not
come
thus far
save it
were by
the word
of
Christ with
unshaken
faith in
him,
relying
wholly
upon the
merits of him who is mighty to save.
Wherefore,
ye must
press
forward
with a
steadfastness
in
Christ,
having a
perfect
brightness of
hope,
and a
love of
God and
of all
men.
Wherefore, if
ye shall
press
forward,
feasting
upon the
word of
Christ,
and
endure to
the
end,
behold,
thus saith
the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.
21 And
now,
behold, my
beloved
brethren,
this is
the
way;
and
there is
none
other
way nor
name
given
under
heaven
whereby man
can be
saved
in
the
kingdom of
God.
And
now,
behold,
this is
the
doctrine of
Christ,
and
the
only and
true
doctrine of
the
Father,
and of
the
Son, and
of
the Holy Ghost, which is one God, without end. Amen.