Chapter 19 Isaiah speaks messianically—The people
in darkness will see a great light—Unto us a child
is born—He will be the Prince of Peace and will
reign on David’s throne—Compare Isaiah 9. About
559–545 B.C.
1 Nevertheless, the dimness shall not be such as
was in her vexation, when at first he lightly
afflicted the land of Zebulun, and the land of
Naphtali, and afterwards did more grievously afflict by
the way of the Red Sea beyond Jordan in Galilee of
the nations
2 The people that walked in darkness have seen a
great light; they that dwell in the land of the
shadow of death, upon them hath the light shined
3 Thou hast multiplied the nation, and increased
the joy—they joy before thee according to the joy
in harvest, and as men rejoice when they divide the
spoil
4 For thou hast broken the yoke of his burden, and
the staff of his shoulder, the rod of his
oppressor
5 For every battle of the warrior is with confused
noise, and garments rolled in blood; but this
shall be with burning and fuel of fire
6 For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is
given; and the government shall be upon his
shoulder; and his name shall be called, Wonderful,
Counselor, The Mighty God, The Everlasting Father, The
Prince of Peace
7 Of the increase of government and peace there is
no end, upon the throne of David, and upon his
kingdom to order it, and to establish it with
judgment and with justice from henceforth, even forever.
The zeal of the Lord of Hosts will perform this
8 The Lord sent his word unto Jacob and it hath
lighted upon Israel
9 And all the people shall know, even Ephraim and
the inhabitants of Samaria, that say in the pride
and stoutness of heart
10 The bricks are fallen down, but we will build
with hewn stones; the sycamores are cut down, but
we will change them into cedars
11 Therefore the Lord shall set up the adversaries
of Rezin against him, and join his enemies
together
12 The Syrians before and the Philistines behind;
and they shall devour Israel with open mouth. For
all this his anger is not turned away, but his
hand is stretched out still
13 For the people turneth not unto him that
smiteth them, neither do they seek the Lord of Hosts
14 Therefore will the Lord cut off from Israel
head and tail, branch and rush in one day
15 The ancient, he is the head; and the prophet
that teacheth lies, he is the tail
16 For the leaders of this people cause them to
err; and they that are led of them are destroyed
17 Therefore the Lord shall have no joy in their
young men, neither shall have mercy on their
fatherless and widows; for every one of them is a
hypocrite and an evildoer, and every mouth speaketh
folly. For all this his anger is not turned away, but
his hand is stretched out still
18 For wickedness burneth as the fire; it shall
devour the briers and thorns, and shall kindle in
the thickets of the forests, and they shall mount up
like the lifting up of smoke
19 Through the wrath of the Lord of Hosts is the
land darkened, and the people shall be as the fuel
of the fire; no man shall spare his brother
20 And he shall snatch on the right hand and be
hungry; and he shall eat on the left hand and they
shall not be satisfied; they shall eat every man
the flesh of his own arm
21 Manasseh, Ephraim; and Ephraim, Manasseh; they
together shall be against Judah. For all this his
anger is not turned away, but his hand is
stretched out still.