Chapter 18 Christ will be as a stone of
stumbling and a rock of offense—Seek the Lord, not
peeping wizards—Turn to the law and to the testimony
for guidance—Compare
Isaiah 8. About 559–545 B.C.
1 Moreover, the word of the Lord said unto me:
Take thee a great roll, and write in it with
a man’s pen, concerning Maher-shalal-hash-baz.
2 And I took unto me faithful
witnesses to record, Uriah the priest,
and Zechariah the son of Jeberechiah.
3 And I went unto the
prophetess; and she conceived and bare a
son. Then said the Lord to me:
Call his name, Maher-shalal-hash-baz.
4 For behold, the child shall
not have knowledge to cry, My
father, and my mother, before
the riches of Damascus and the
spoil of Samaria shall be
taken away before the king of Assyria.
5 The Lord spake also
unto me again, saying:
6 Forasmuch as this
people refuseth
the waters of Shiloah
that go softly,
and rejoice in Rezin
and Remaliah’s son;
7 Now therefore,
behold, the Lord
bringeth up upon
them the waters
of the river,
strong and many, even
the king of
Assyria and all his
glory; and he
shall come up over
all his channels,
and go over all his banks.
8 And he shall
pass through
Judah; he shall
overflow and go
over, he shall reach
even to the
neck; and the
stretching out of his
wings shall
fill the breadth of
thy land, O Immanuel.
9 Associate
yourselves, O ye
people, and ye
shall be broken
in pieces; and
give ear all ye
of far
countries; gird
yourselves, and ye
shall be broken
in pieces; gird
yourselves, and
ye shall be
broken in pieces.
10 Take
counsel together,
and it shall
come to naught;
speak the word,
and it shall
not stand; for
God is with us.
11 For the
Lord spake
thus to me
with a strong
hand, and
instructed me
that I should
not walk in
the way of
this people, saying:
12 Say ye
not, A
confederacy, to
all to whom
this
people shall
say, A
confederacy;
neither fear ye
their fear,
nor be afraid.
Sanctify the Lord
of Hosts
himself,
and let him
be your
fear, and
let him be
your dread.
14 And he
shall be
for a
sanctuary;
but for a
stone of
stumbling, and
for a rock
of
offense to both
the
houses of
Israel, for
a gin and
a snare
to the
inhabitants of Jerusalem.
15 And
many among
them
shall stumble
and
fall, and be
broken,
and be
snared, and
be taken.
16 Bind
up the
testimony, seal
the law
among my
disciples.
17 And I
will
wait upon
the
Lord, that
hideth
his face
from the
house of
Jacob,
and I
will look
for him.
Behold, I
and the
children whom
the
Lord hath
given
me are
for
signs and
wonders in
Israel
from
the Lord
of
Hosts,
which dwelleth in Mount Zion.
19 And
when
they
shall
say
unto you:
Seek
unto
them
that
have
familiar
spirits, and
unto
wizards
that
peep
and
mutter—should
not a
people
seek
unto
their
God for
the living to hear from the dead?
20 To
the
law
and to
the
testimony;
and
if
they
speak
not
according to
this
word, it
is
because
there is no light in them.
And
they
shall
pass
through
it
hardly
bestead
and
hungry;
it
shall
come
to
pass
that
when
they
shall
be
hungry,
they
shall
fret
themselves,
and
curse
their king and their God, and look upward.
And
they
shall
look
unto
the
earth
and
behold
trouble,
and
darkness,
dimness
of
anguish,
and shall be driven to darkness.