Chapter 5 The Nephites separate themselves
from the Lamanites, keep the law of Moses,
and build a temple—Because of their
unbelief, the Lamanites are cut off from the
presence of the Lord, are cursed, and become a
scourge unto the Nephites. About 588–559 B.C.
1 Behold, it came to pass that I,
Nephi, did cry much unto the Lord my
God, because of the anger of my brethren.
2 But behold, their anger did
increase against me, insomuch that
they did seek to take away my life.
3 Yea, they did murmur against
me, saying: Our younger brother
thinks to rule over us; and we
have had much trial because of
him; wherefore, now let us
slay him, that we may not be
afflicted more because of his words.
For behold, we will not have
him to be our ruler; for it
belongs unto us, who are the elder
brethren, to rule over this people.
4 Now I do not write upon
these plates all the words which
they murmured against me. But
it sufficeth me to say, that
they did seek to take away my life.
5 And it came to pass
that the Lord did warn me,
that I, Nephi, should
depart from them and flee
into the wilderness, and all
those who would go with me.
6 Wherefore, it came to
pass that I, Nephi, did
take my family, and also
Zoram and his family,
and Sam, mine elder
brother and his family, and
Jacob and Joseph, my
younger brethren, and also
my sisters, and all those
who would go with me.
And all those who would
go with me were those who
believed in the
warnings and the revelations of
God; wherefore, they
did hearken unto my words.
7 And we did take our
tents and whatsoever
things were possible for
us, and did journey in
the wilderness for the
space of many days. And
after we had journeyed
for the space of many
days we did pitch our tents.
8 And my people
would that we should
call the name of the
place Nephi;
wherefore, we did call it Nephi.
9 And all those
who were with me did
take upon them to
call themselves
the people of Nephi.
10 And we did
observe to keep the
judgments, and
the statutes, and
the commandments
of the Lord in all
things,
according to the law of Moses.
11 And the Lord
was with us; and
we did prosper
exceedingly; for
we did sow
seed, and we did
reap again in
abundance. And we
began to raise
flocks, and herds,
and animals of every kind.
12 And I,
Nephi, had also
brought the records
which were
engraven upon the
plates of
brass; and also the
ball, or
compass, which was
prepared for my
father by the
hand of the Lord,
according to
that which is written.
13 And it came
to pass that
we began to
prosper
exceedingly, and to
multiply in the land.
14 And I,
Nephi, did take
the sword of
Laban, and
after the
manner of it did
make many
swords, lest by
any means the
people who
were now called
Lamanites
should come
upon us and
destroy us; for I
knew their
hatred towards
me and my
children and
those who were called my people.
15 And I did
teach my
people to
build buildings,
and to work
in all
manner of wood,
and of iron,
and of
copper, and of
brass, and of
steel, and
of gold, and
of silver,
and of
precious ores,
which were in great abundance.
16 And I,
Nephi, did
build a
temple; and I
did
construct it after
the manner
of the
temple of
Solomon save it
were not
built of so
many
precious things;
for they
were not to be
found upon
the land,
wherefore,
it could
not be built
like unto
Solomon’s
temple. But
the manner
of the
construction was
like unto
the temple
of Solomon;
and the
workmanship thereof was exceedingly fine.
17 And it
came to
pass that I,
Nephi,
did cause my
people to
be
industrious, and
to labor
with their hands.
18 And it
came to
pass that
they
would that I
should
be their
king. But
I, Nephi,
was
desirous that
they
should have
no king;
nevertheless, I
did for
them
according to
that which was in my power.
19 And
behold,
the words
of the
Lord had
been
fulfilled
unto my
brethren, which
he spake
concerning
them, that I
should
be their
ruler
and their
teacher.
Wherefore, I
had been
their
ruler and
teacher,
according
to the
commandments of
the
Lord, until
the time
they sought to take away my life.
Wherefore,
the
word of
the Lord
was
fulfilled
which
he spake
unto
me,
saying
that:
Inasmuch as
they
will not
hearken
unto
thy
words they
shall
be cut
off from
the
presence
of the
Lord.
And
behold,
they were cut off from his presence.
21 And
he had
caused
the
cursing to
come
upon
them, yea,
even a
sore
cursing,
because of
their
iniquity.
For
behold,
they had
hardened their
hearts
against him,
that
they had
become
like
unto a
flint;
wherefore, as
they were
white,
and
exceedingly fair
delightsome,
that they
might
not be
enticing
unto
my
people the
Lord God
did
cause a
skin of
blackness to
come
upon them.
22 And
thus
saith
the
Lord
God: I
will
cause
that they
shall
be
loathsome unto
thy
people,
save
they
shall
repent
of their iniquities.
And
cursed
shall
be
the
seed of
him
that
mixeth
with
their
seed;
for
they
shall be
cursed
even
with
the
same
cursing.
And
the
Lord spake it, and it was done.
And
because
of
their
cursing
which
was
upon
them
they did
become an
idle
people,
full
of
mischief
and
subtlety,
did
seek in
the
wilderness
for
beasts of
prey.
And
the
Lord
God
said
unto
me:
They
shall
be
a
scourge
unto
thy
seed,
to
stir
them up
in
remembrance
of
me;
and
inasmuch
as
they
will
not
remember
me,
and
hearken
unto
my
words,
they shall scourge them even unto destruction.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
I,
Nephi,
did
consecrate
Jacob
and
Joseph,
that
they
should
be
priests
and
teachers over the land of my people.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
we
lived
after
the manner of happiness.
And
thirty
years
had
passed
away
from
the
time
we
left
Jerusalem.
And
I,
Nephi,
had
kept
the
records
upon
my
plates,
which
I
had
made,
of
my
people
thus
far.
30 And it came to pass that the Lord God said unto me: Make other plates; and thou shalt engraven many things upon them which are good in my sight, for the profit of thy
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
Lord
God
said
unto
me:
Make
other
plates;
and
thou
shalt
engraven many things upon them which are good in my sight, for the profit of thy people.
31 Wherefore, I, Nephi, to be obedient to the commandments of the Lord, went and made these plates upon which I have engraven these
Wherefore,
I,
Nephi,
to
be
obedient
to
the
commandments
of
the
Lord,
went
and
made
these
plates
upon
which
I
have
engraven
these
things.
32 And I engraved that which is pleasing unto God. And if my people are pleased with the things of God they will be pleased with mine engravings which are upon these
And
I
engraved
that
which
is
pleasing
unto
God.
And
if
my
people
are
pleased
with
the
things
of
God
they
will
be
pleased
with
mine
engravings
which
are
upon
these
plates.
33 And if my people desire to know the more particular part of the history of my people they must search mine other
And
if
my
people
desire
to
know
the
more
particular
part
of
the
history
of
my
people
they
must
search
mine
other
plates.
34 And it sufficeth me to say that forty years had passed away, and we had already had wars and contentions with our brethren.
And
it
sufficeth
me
to
say
that
forty
years
had
passed
away,
and
we
had
already
wars
and
contentions
with
our
brethren.