Chapter 21 The stem of Jesse (Christ) will judge
in righteousness—The knowledge of God will cover
the earth in the Millennium—The Lord will raise an
ensign and gather Israel—Compare
Isaiah 11. About
559–545 B.C.
1 And there shall come forth a rod out of the stem
of Jesse, and a branch shall grow out of his
roots
2 And the Spirit of the Lord shall rest upon him,
the spirit of wisdom and understanding, the spirit
of counsel and might, the spirit of knowledge and
of the fear of the Lord
3 And shall make him of quick understanding in the
fear of the Lord; and he shall not judge after
the sight of his eyes, neither reprove after the
hearing of his ears
4 But with righteousness shall he judge the poor,
and reprove with equity for the meek of the earth;
and he shall smite the earth with the rod of his
mouth, and with the breath of his lips shall he
slay the wicked
5 And righteousness shall be the girdle of his
loins, and faithfulness the girdle of his reins
6 The wolf also shall dwell with the lamb, and the
leopard shall lie down with the kid, and the calf
and the young lion and fatling together; and a
little child shall lead them
7 And the cow and the bear shall feed; their young
ones shall lie down together; and the lion shall
eat straw like the ox
8 And the sucking child shall play on the hole of
the asp, and the weaned child shall put his hand
on the cockatrice’s den
9 They shall not hurt nor destroy in all my holy
mountain, for the earth shall be full of the
knowledge of the Lord, as the waters cover the sea
10 And in that day there shall be a root of Jesse,
which shall stand for an ensign of the people; to
it shall the Gentiles seek; and his rest shall be
glorious
11 And it shall come to pass in that day that the
Lord shall set his hand again the second time to
recover the remnant of his people which shall be
left, from Assyria, and from Egypt, and from
Pathros, and from Cush, and from Elam, and from Shinar,
and from Hamath, and from the islands of the sea
12 And he shall set up an ensign for the nations,
and shall assemble the outcasts of Israel, and
gather together the dispersed of Judah from the four
corners of the earth
13 The envy of Ephraim also shall depart, and the
adversaries of Judah shall be cut off; Ephraim
shall not envy Judah, and Judah shall not vex
Ephraim
14 But they shall fly upon the shoulders of the
Philistines towards the west; they shall spoil them
of the east together; they shall lay their hand
upon Edom and Moab; and the children of Ammon shall
obey them
15 And the Lord shall utterly destroy the tongue
of the Egyptian sea; and with his mighty wind he
shall shake his hand over the river, and shall smite
it in the seven streams, and make men go over dry
shod
16 And there shall be a highway for the remnant of
his people which shall be left, from Assyria,
like as it was to Israel in the day that he came up
out of the land of Egypt.