Chapter 12 Isaiah sees the latter-day
temple, gathering of Israel, and
millennial judgment and peace—The proud and
wicked will be brought low at the Second
Coming—Compare
Isaiah 2. About 559–545 B.C.
1 The word that Isaiah, the son of
Amoz, saw concerning Judah and Jerusalem:
2 And it shall come to pass in the
last days, when the mountain of
the Lord’s house shall be
established in the top of the mountains,
and shall be exalted above the
hills, and all nations shall flow unto it.
3 And many people shall go and
say, Come ye, and let us go up to
the mountain of the Lord, to the
house of the God of Jacob; and he
will teach us of his ways, and we
will walk in his paths; for out
of Zion shall go forth the law,
and the word of the Lord from Jerusalem.
4 And he shall judge among the
nations, and shall rebuke
many people: and they shall beat
their swords into plow-shares,
and their spears into
pruning-hooks—nation shall not lift
up sword against nation,
neither shall they learn war any more.
5 O house of Jacob, come ye
and let us walk in the
light of the Lord; yea, come,
for ye have all gone
astray, every one to his wicked ways.
6 Therefore, O Lord,
thou hast forsaken thy
people, the house of Jacob,
because they be
replenished from the east, and
hearken unto soothsayers
like the Philistines,
and they please themselves
in the children of strangers.
7 Their land also is
full of silver and
gold, neither is there
any end of their
treasures; their land is
also full of horses,
neither is there any
end of their chariots.
8 Their land is
also full of idols;
they worship the work
of their own
hands, that which their
own fingers have made.
9 And the mean
man boweth not
down, and the great
man humbleth
himself not,
therefore, forgive him not.
10 O ye wicked
ones, enter
into the rock, and
hide thee in
the dust, for
the fear of the
Lord and the
glory of his
majesty shall smite thee.
11 And it
shall come to pass
that the
lofty looks of man
shall be
humbled, and the
haughtiness of
men shall be
bowed down, and
the Lord
alone shall be
exalted in that day.
12 For the
day of the Lord
of Hosts
soon cometh upon
all nations,
yea, upon
every one; yea,
upon the
proud and lofty,
and upon
every one who is
lifted up,
and he shall
be brought low.
13 Yea, and
the day of
the Lord
shall come upon
all the
cedars of
Lebanon, for they
are high and
lifted up;
and upon all
the oaks of Bashan;
14 And upon
all the
high
mountains, and upon
all the
hills, and
upon all the
nations
which are
lifted up, and
upon every people;
15 And
upon every
high
tower, and
upon every
fenced wall;
16 And
upon all
the
ships of the
sea,
and upon
all the
ships of
Tarshish, and
upon all
pleasant pictures.
17 And
the
loftiness
of man
shall
be bowed
down,
and the
haughtiness
of men
shall be
made
low; and
the
Lord
alone shall
be exalted in that day.
18 And
the
idols he
shall
utterly
abolish.
19 And
they
shall
go
into the
holes
of the
rocks, and
into
the
caves of
earth,
for the
fear
of the
Lord
shall
come
upon
them and
the
glory
of his
majesty
shall
smite
them, when
he
ariseth to shake terribly the earth.
20 In
that
day
a man
shall
cast his
idols of
silver,
and his
idols of
gold,
which he
hath
made
for
himself to
worship,
to the moles and to the bats;
21 To
go
into
the
clefts
of
the
rocks,
and
into
the
tops of
ragged
rocks,
for the
fear
of
the
Lord
shall
come
upon
them
and
the
majesty
of
his
glory
shall
smite
them,
when
he
ariseth to
shake
terribly
the
earth.
Cease
ye
from
man,
whose
breath
is in
his
nostrils;
for
wherein
is he
to be accounted of?