Chapter 27 Darkness and apostasy will cover the
earth in the last days—The Book of Mormon will
come forth—Three witnesses will testify of the
book—The learned man will say he cannot read the
sealed book—The Lord will do a marvelous work and
a wonder—Compare
Isaiah 29. About 559–545 B.C.
1 But, behold, in the last days, or in the
days of the Gentiles—yea, behold all the nations
of the Gentiles and also the Jews, both those
who shall come upon this land and those who
shall be upon other lands, yea, even upon all
the lands of the earth, behold, they will be
drunken with iniquity and all manner of abominations—
2 And when that day shall come they
shall be visited of the Lord of Hosts, with
thunder and with earthquake, and with a
great noise, and with storm, and with
tempest, and with the flame of devouring fire.
3 And all the nations that fight
against Zion, and that distress her, shall
be as a dream of a night vision; yea,
it shall be unto them, even as unto a
hungry man which dreameth, and behold
he eateth but he awaketh and his soul
is empty; or like unto a thirsty man
which dreameth, and behold he drinketh
but he awaketh and behold he is faint,
and his soul hath appetite; yea, even
so shall the multitude of all the
nations be that fight against Mount Zion.
4 For behold, all ye that doeth
iniquity, stay yourselves and wonder, for
ye shall cry out, and cry; yea, ye
shall be drunken but not with wine, ye
shall stagger but not with strong drink.
5 For behold, the Lord hath poured
out upon you the spirit of deep
sleep. For behold, ye have closed your
eyes, and ye have rejected the
prophets; and your rulers, and the seers
hath he covered because of your iniquity.
6 And it shall come to pass
that the Lord God shall bring
forth unto you the words of a
book, and they shall be the
words of them which have slumbered.
7 And behold the book shall
be sealed; and in the book
shall be a revelation from
God, from the beginning of the
world to the ending thereof.
8 Wherefore, because of
the things which are sealed
up, the things which are
sealed shall not be
delivered in the day of the
wickedness and abominations of
the people. Wherefore the
book shall be kept from them.
9 But the book shall be
delivered unto a man,
and he shall deliver the
words of the book, which
are the words of those
who have slumbered in the
dust, and he shall
deliver these words unto another;
10 But the words which
are sealed he shall not
deliver, neither shall
he deliver the book.
For the book shall be
sealed by the power of
God, and the revelation
which was sealed shall
be kept in the book
until the own due time of
the Lord, that they may
come forth; for behold,
they reveal all things
from the foundation of
the world unto the end thereof.
11 And the day cometh
that the words of the
book which were sealed
shall be read upon
the house tops; and they
shall be read by the
power of Christ; and
all things shall be
revealed unto the
children of men which ever
have been among the
children of men, and which
ever will be even
unto the end of the earth.
12 Wherefore, at that
day when the book
shall be delivered unto
the man of whom I
have spoken, the book
shall be hid from the
eyes of the world,
that the eyes of none
shall behold it save
it be that three
witnesses shall behold it,
by the power of God,
besides him to whom
the book shall be
delivered; and they
shall testify to the
truth of the book and the things therein.
13 And there is none
other which shall
view it, save it be a
few according to
the will of God, to
bear testimony of his
word unto the
children of men; for the
Lord God hath said
that the words of the
faithful should
speak as if it were from the dead.
14 Wherefore, the
Lord God will
proceed to bring forth
the words of the
book; and in the mouth
of as many
witnesses as seemeth him
good will he
establish his word; and wo
be unto him that
rejecteth the word of God!
15 But behold, it
shall come to pass
that the Lord God
shall say unto
him to whom he shall
deliver the book:
Take these words
which are not
sealed and deliver
them to another, that
he may show them
unto the learned,
saying: Read this,
I pray thee. And
the learned shall
say: Bring hither
the book, and I will read them.
16 And now,
because of the
glory of the world
and to get
gain will they say
this, and not
for the glory of God.
17 And the
man shall say:
I cannot
bring the book,
for it is sealed.
18 Then
shall the
learned say: I
cannot read it.
19 Wherefore
it shall
come to pass,
that the
Lord God will
deliver again
the book
and the words
thereof to
him that is
not learned;
and the man
that is not
learned
shall say: I am
not learned.
20 Then
shall the Lord
God say
unto him: The
learned
shall not
read them, for
they have
rejected
them, and I
am able to
do mine own
work;
wherefore thou
shalt read
the words
which I shall give unto thee.
21 Touch
not the
things which
are
sealed, for I
will bring
them forth
in mine
own due
time; for I
will show
unto the
children of
men that I
am able to
do mine own work.
Wherefore, when
thou hast
read the
words which
I have
commanded
thee, and
obtained the
witnesses
which I
have
promised unto
thee, then
shalt thou
seal up the
book
again, and
hide it up
unto me,
that I may
preserve the
words
which thou
hast not
read, until I
shall see
fit in
mine own
wisdom to
reveal all
things unto
the
children of men.
23 For
behold, I
am God;
and I am a
God of
miracles;
and I will
show
unto the
world that I
am the
same
yesterday,
today, and
forever;
and I work
not
among the
children of
men save
it be
according to their faith.
24 And
again it
shall
come to
pass that
the Lord
shall
say unto
him that
shall
read the
words
that shall
be delivered him:
Forasmuch
as this
people
draw
near unto
me
with their
mouth,
and
with
their lips
do
honor me,
but have
removed their
hearts
far
from me,
and
their fear
towards me is
taught by the precepts of men—
Therefore, I
will
proceed
to do a
marvelous
work
among
this
people,
yea, a
marvelous
work and
a
wonder,
for the
wisdom of
their
wise
and
learned
shall
perish,
and
the
understanding of their prudent shall be hid.
And wo
unto
them
that
seek
deep
to
hide
their
counsel
from the
Lord! And
their
works
are in
the
dark;
and
they
say:
Who
seeth
us,
and who
knoweth
us?
And
they
also
say:
Surely,
your
turning of
things
upside
down
shall
be
esteemed as
the
potter’s
clay.
But
behold, I
will
show
unto
them,
saith
the
Lord
of
Hosts,
that
I
know all
their
works.
For
shall
the
work
say of
him
that
made
it, he
me
not? Or shall the thing framed say of him that framed it, he had no understanding?
But
behold,
saith
the
Lord of
Hosts:
I
will
show
unto
the
children of
men
that it
is
yet
a
very
little
while
and
Lebanon
shall be
turned
into
a
fruitful
field;
and
the
fruitful field shall be esteemed as a forest.
And
in
that
day
shall
the
deaf
hear
the
words
of
the
book,
and
the
eyes
of
the
blind
shall
see
out of obscurity and out of darkness.
And
the
meek
also
shall
increase,
and
their
joy
shall
be
in
the
Lord,
and
the
poor
among men shall rejoice in the Holy One of Israel.
For
assuredly
as
the
Lord
liveth
they
shall
see
that
the
terrible
one
is
brought
to
naught,
and
the
scorner
is
consumed,
and
all
that
watch
for
iniquity
are
cut
off;
And
they
that
make
a
man
an
offender
for
a
word,
and
lay
a
snare
for
him
that
reproveth
in
the
gate,
and
turn
aside
the
just
for
a
thing
of
naught.
Therefore,
thus
saith
the
Lord,
who
redeemed
Abraham,
concerning
the
house
of
Jacob:
Jacob
shall
not
now
be
ashamed,
neither
shall
his
face
now
wax
pale.
But
when
he
seeth
his
children,
the
work
of
my
hands,
in
the
midst
of
him,
they
shall
sanctify
my
name,
and
sanctify
the
Holy
One
of
Jacob,
and
shall
fear
the
God
of
Israel.
They
also
that
erred
in
spirit
shall
come
to
understanding,
and
they
that
murmured
shall
learn
doctrine.