Chapter 4 Lehi counsels and blesses his
posterity—He dies and is buried—Nephi
glories in the goodness of God—Nephi puts his
trust in the Lord forever. About 588–570 B.C.
1 And now, I, Nephi, speak
concerning the prophecies of which my
father hath spoken, concerning
Joseph, who was carried into Egypt.
2 For behold, he truly
prophesied concerning all his
seed. And the prophecies which
he wrote, there are not many
greater. And he prophesied
concerning us, and our
future generations; and they are
written upon the plates of brass.
3 Wherefore, after my
father had made an end of
speaking concerning the
prophecies of Joseph, he
called the children of
Laman, his sons, and his
daughters, and said unto them:
Behold, my sons, and my
daughters, who are the
sons and the daughters of
my firstborn, I would that
ye should give ear unto my words.
4 For the Lord God hath
said that: Inasmuch as
ye shall keep my
commandments ye shall prosper in
the land; and inasmuch
as ye will not keep my
commandments ye shall be
cut off from my presence.
5 But behold, my sons
and my daughters, I
cannot go down to my
grave save I should leave
a blessing upon you;
for behold, I know
that if ye are brought up
in the way ye should
go ye will not depart from it.
6 Wherefore, if ye
are cursed, behold,
I leave my
blessing upon you, that
the cursing may be
taken from you and be
answered upon the
heads of your parents.
7 Wherefore,
because of my
blessing the Lord God
will not suffer
that ye shall
perish; wherefore, he
will be merciful
unto you and unto
your seed forever.
8 And it came
to pass that
after my father
had made an end
of speaking to
the sons and
daughters of
Laman, he caused the
sons and
daughters of Lemuel
to be brought before him.
9 And he spake
unto them,
saying: Behold,
my sons and my
daughters,
who are the sons
and the
daughters of my
second son;
behold I leave unto
you the same
blessing which
I left unto
the sons and
daughters of
Laman; wherefore,
thou shalt
not utterly be
destroyed; but
in the end thy
seed shall be blessed.
10 And it
came to pass
that when my
father had made
an end of
speaking unto
them, behold,
he spake unto
the sons of
Ishmael, yea,
and even all
his household.
11 And after
he had made
an end of
speaking unto
them, he
spake unto
Sam, saying:
Blessed art
thou, and thy
seed; for
thou shalt
inherit the
land like unto
thy brother
Nephi. And
thy seed
shall be
numbered with his
seed; and
thou shalt be
even like
unto thy
brother, and thy
seed like
unto his seed;
and thou
shalt be blessed in all thy days.
12 And it
came to pass
after my
father, Lehi,
had spoken
unto all his
household,
according to
the feelings
of his heart
and the
Spirit of the
Lord which was
in him, he
waxed old.
And it came
to pass that
he died, and
was buried.
13 And it
came to pass
that not
many days
after his
death, Laman
and Lemuel
and the sons
of Ishmael
were angry
with me
because of
the
admonitions of the Lord.
14 For I,
Nephi, was
constrained to
speak unto
them,
according to his
word; for
I had
spoken many
things unto
them, and
also my
father,
before his
death; many
of which
sayings are
written
upon mine
other
plates; for a
more history
part are
written upon mine other plates.
15 And
upon these
I write
the things
of my
soul, and
many of
the
scriptures which
are
engraven upon
the
plates of
brass. For
my soul
delighteth
in the
scriptures,
and my
heart
pondereth
them, and
writeth
them for the
learning
and the profit of my children.
Behold, my
soul
delighteth in
the
things of
the Lord;
and my
heart
pondereth
continually upon
the
things
which I have
seen and heard.
Nevertheless,
notwithstanding
the great
goodness of
the
Lord, in
showing
me his
great
and
marvelous
works, my
heart
exclaimeth: O
wretched man
that I
am! Yea,
my
heart
sorroweth
because
of my
flesh;
my soul
grieveth because of mine iniquities.
18 I
am
encompassed
about,
because
of the
temptations
and
the sins
which
do so
easily beset me.
And
when I
desire
to
rejoice, my
heart
groaneth
because
of my
sins;
nevertheless,
I
know in
whom I have trusted.
20 My
God
hath
been
my
support; he
hath
led
me
through
mine
afflictions in
the
wilderness;
and
he
hath
preserved me
upon
the
waters of
great
deep.
He
hath
filled me
with
his
love,
even
unto
the
consuming of my flesh.
He
hath
confounded
mine
enemies,
unto
the
causing
of
them
to
quake
before
me.
Behold,
he
hath
heard
my
cry
by
day,
and
he
hath
given me
knowledge
by
visions in
the
night-time.
And
by
day
have
I
waxed
bold
in
mighty
prayer
before
him;
yea,
my
voice
have I
sent
up
on
high;
and
angels came down and ministered unto me.
And
upon
the
wings
of
his
Spirit
hath
my
body
been
carried
away
upon
exceedingly
high
mountains.
And
mine
eyes
have
beheld
great
things,
yea,
even too great for man; therefore I was bidden that I should not write them.
26 O then, if I have seen so great things, if the Lord in his condescension unto the children of men hath visited men in so much mercy, why should my heart weep and my soul linger in the valley of sorrow, and my flesh waste away, and my strength slacken, because of mine
O
then,
if
I
have
seen
so
great
things,
if
the
Lord
in
his
condescension
unto
the
children
of
men
hath
visited
men
in
so
much
mercy,
why
should my heart weep and my soul linger in the valley of sorrow, and my flesh waste away, and my strength slacken, because of mine afflictions?
27 And why should I yield to sin, because of my flesh? Yea, why should I give way to temptations, that the evil one have place in my heart to destroy my peace and afflict my soul? Why am I angry because of mine
And
why
should
I
yield
to
sin,
because
of
my
flesh?
Yea,
why
should
I
give
way
to
temptations,
that
the
evil
one
have
place
in
my
heart
to
destroy
my
peace
and
afflict
my
soul?
Why
am
I
angry
because
of
mine
enemy?
28 Awake, my soul! No longer droop in sin. Rejoice, O my heart, and give place no more for the enemy of my
Awake,
my
soul!
No
longer
droop
in
sin.
Rejoice,
O
my
heart,
and
give
place
no
more
for
the
enemy
of
my
soul.
29 Do not anger again because of mine enemies. Do not slacken my strength because of mine
Do
not
anger
again
because
of
mine
enemies.
Do
not
slacken
my
strength
because
of
mine
afflictions.
30 Rejoice, O my heart, and cry unto the Lord, and say: O Lord, I will praise thee forever; yea, my soul will rejoice in thee, my God, and the rock of my
Rejoice,
O
my
heart,
and
cry
unto
the
Lord,
and
say:
O
Lord,
I
will
praise
thee
forever;
yea,
my
soul
will
rejoice
in
thee,
my
God,
and
the
rock
of
my
salvation.
31 O Lord, wilt thou redeem my soul? Wilt thou deliver me out of the hands of mine enemies? Wilt thou make me that I may shake at the appearance of
O
Lord,
wilt
thou
redeem
my
soul?
Wilt
thou
deliver
me
out
of
the
hands
of
mine
enemies?
Wilt
thou
make
me
that
I
may
shake
at
the
appearance
of
sin?
32 May the gates of hell be shut continually before me, because that my heart is broken and my spirit is contrite! O Lord, wilt thou not shut the gates of thy righteousness before me, that I may walk in the path of the low valley, that I may be strict in the plain
May
the
gates
of
hell
be
shut
continually
before
me,
because
that
my
heart
is
broken
and
my
spirit
is
contrite!
O
Lord,
wilt
thou
not
shut
the
gates
of
thy
righteousness
before
me,
that
I
may
walk
in
the
path
of
the
low
valley,
that
I
may
be
strict
in
the
plain
road!
33 O Lord, wilt thou encircle me around in the robe of thy righteousness! O Lord, wilt thou make a way for mine escape before mine enemies! Wilt thou make my path straight before me! Wilt thou not place a stumbling block in my way—but that thou wouldst clear my way before me, and hedge not up my way, but the ways of mine
O
Lord,
wilt
thou
encircle
me
around
in
the
robe
of
thy
righteousness!
O
Lord,
wilt
thou
make
a
way
for
mine
escape
before
mine
enemies!
Wilt
thou
make
my
path
straight
before
me!
Wilt
thou
not
place
a
stumbling
block
in
my
way—but
that
thou
wouldst
clear
my
way
before
me,
and
hedge
not
up
my
way,
but
the
ways
of
mine
enemy.
34 O Lord, I have trusted in thee, and I will trust in thee forever. I will not put my trust in the arm of flesh; for I know that cursed is he that putteth his trust in the arm of flesh. Yea, cursed is he that putteth his trust in man or maketh flesh his
O
Lord,
I
have
trusted
in
thee,
and
I
will
trust
in
thee
forever.
I
will
not
put
my
trust
in
the
arm
of
flesh;
for
I
know
that
cursed
is
he
that
putteth
his
trust
in
the
arm
of
flesh.
Yea,
cursed
is
he
that
putteth
his
trust
in
man
or
maketh
flesh
his
arm.
35 Yea, I know that God will give liberally to him that asketh. Yea, my God will give me, if I ask not amiss; therefore I will lift up my voice unto thee; yea, I will cry unto thee, my God, the rock of my righteousness. Behold, my voice shall forever ascend up unto thee, my rock and mine everlasting God. Amen.
Yea,
I
know
that
God
will
give
liberally
to
him
that
asketh.
Yea,
my
God
will
give
amiss;
therefore
I
will
lift
up
my
voice
unto
thee;
yea,
I
will
cry
unto
thee,
my
God,
the
rock
of
my
righteousness.
Behold,
my
voice
shall
forever
ascend
up
unto
thee,
my
rock
and
mine
everlasting
God.
Amen.