Chapter 33 Nephi’s words are true—They testify
of Christ—Those who believe in Christ will
believe Nephi’s words, which will stand as a
witness before the judgment bar. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And now I, Nephi, cannot write all the
things which were taught among my people;
neither am I mighty in writing, like unto
speaking; for when a man speaketh by the power of
the Holy Ghost the power of the Holy Ghost
carrieth it unto the hearts of the children of men.
2 But behold, there are many that harden
their hearts against the Holy Spirit,
that it hath no place in them; wherefore,
they cast many things away which are
written and esteem them as things of naught.
3 But I, Nephi, have written what I
have written, and I esteem it as
of great worth, and especially unto
my people. For I pray continually
for them by day, and mine eyes water
my pillow by night, because of
them; and I cry unto my God in faith,
and I know that he will hear my cry.
4 And I know that the Lord God
will consecrate my prayers for
the gain of my people. And the
words which I have written in
weakness will be made strong unto
them; for it persuadeth them to do
good; it maketh known unto them
of their fathers; and it
speaketh of Jesus, and persuadeth them
to believe in him, and to endure
to the end, which is life eternal.
5 And it speaketh harshly
against sin, according to the
plainness of the truth; wherefore, no
man will be angry at the words
which I have written save he
shall be of the spirit of the devil.
6 I glory in plainness; I
glory in truth; I glory
in my Jesus, for he hath
redeemed my soul from hell.
7 I have charity for my
people, and great
faith in Christ that I
shall meet many souls
spotless at his judgment-seat.
8 I have charity
for the Jew—I say
Jew, because I mean
them from whence I came.
9 I also have
charity for the
Gentiles. But behold,
for none of these
can I hope except
they shall be
reconciled unto Christ,
and enter into the
narrow gate, and
walk in the strait
path which leads
to life, and
continue in the path
until the end of the
day of probation.
10 And now, my
beloved brethren,
and also Jew, and
all ye ends of
the earth, hearken
unto these words
and believe in
Christ; and if ye
believe not in
these words believe
in Christ. And if
ye shall believe
in Christ ye
will believe in
these words, for they
are the words of
Christ, and he
hath given them
unto me; and they
teach all men that
they should do good.
11 And if they
are not the words
of Christ,
judge ye—for Christ
will show unto
you, with power
and great glory,
that they are
his words, at the
last day; and
you and I shall
stand face to face
before his bar;
and ye shall
know that I have
been commanded of
him to write
these things,
notwithstanding my weakness.
12 And I pray
the Father in
the name of
Christ that many
of us, if not
all, may be
saved in his
kingdom at that
great and last day.
13 And now,
my beloved
brethren, all
those who are
of the house
of Israel, and
all ye ends
of the earth,
I speak unto
you as the
voice of one
crying from
the dust:
Farewell until
that great day shall come.
14 And you
that will not
partake of
the goodness
of God, and
respect the
words of
the Jews, and
also my
words, and the
words which
shall proceed
forth out
of the mouth
of the Lamb
of God,
behold, I bid
you an
everlasting
farewell, for these
words shall
condemn you at the last day.
15 For what
I seal on
earth,
shall be
brought against
you at the
judgment
bar; for thus
hath the
Lord
commanded me, and I
must obey. Amen.