Isaiah 51 and 52:1–2. About 559–545 B.C.
1 Hearken unto me, ye that follow after
righteousness. Look unto the rock from whence ye are hewn,
and to the hole of the pit from whence ye are
digged
2 Look unto Abraham, your father, and unto Sarah,
she that bare you; for I called him alone, and
blessed him
3 For the Lord shall comfort Zion, he will comfort
all her waste places; and he will make her
wilderness like Eden, and her desert like the garden of
the Lord. Joy and gladness shall be found therein,
thanksgiving and the voice of melody
4 Hearken unto me, my people; and give ear unto
me, O my nation; for a law shall proceed from me,
and I will make my judgment to rest for a light for
the people
5 My righteousness is near; my salvation is gone
forth, and mine arm shall judge the people. The
isles shall wait upon me, and on mine arm shall they
trust
6 Lift up your eyes to the heavens, and look upon
the earth beneath; for the heavens shall vanish
away like smoke, and the earth shall wax old like a
garment; and they that dwell therein shall die in
like manner. But my salvation shall be forever,
and my righteousness shall not be abolished
7 Hearken unto me, ye that know righteousness, the
people in whose heart I have written my law, fear
ye not the reproach of men, neither be ye afraid
of their revilings
8 For the moth shall eat them up like a garment,
and the worm shall eat them like wool. But my
righteousness shall be forever, and my salvation from
generation to generation
9 Awake, awake! Put on strength, O arm of the
Lord; awake as in the ancient days. Art thou not he
that hath cut Rahab, and wounded the dragon
10 Art thou not he who hath dried the sea, the
waters of the great deep; that hath made the depths
of the sea a way for the ransomed to pass over
11 Therefore, the redeemed of the Lord shall
return, and come with singing unto Zion; and
everlasting joy and holiness shall be upon their heads; and
they shall obtain gladness and joy; sorrow and
mourning shall flee away
12 I am he; yea, I am he that comforteth you.
Behold, who art thou, that thou shouldst be afraid of
man, who shall die, and of the son of man, who
shall be made like unto grass
13 And forgettest the Lord thy maker, that hath
stretched forth the heavens, and laid the
foundations of the earth, and hast feared continually every
day, because of the fury of the oppressor, as if
he were ready to destroy? And where is the fury of
the oppressor
14 The captive exile hasteneth, that he may be
loosed, and that he should not die in the pit, nor
that his bread should fail
15 But I am the Lord thy God, whose waves roared;
the Lord of Hosts is my name
16 And I have put my words in thy mouth, and have
covered thee in the shadow of mine hand, that I
may plant the heavens and lay the foundations of the
earth, and say unto Zion: Behold, thou art my
people
17 Awake, awake, stand up, O Jerusalem, which hast
drunk at the hand of the Lord the cup of his
fury—thou hast drunken the dregs of the cup of
trembling wrung out
18 And none to guide her among all the sons she
hath brought forth; neither that taketh her by the
hand, of all the sons she hath brought up
19 These two sons are come unto thee, who shall be
sorry for thee—thy desolation and destruction,
and the famine and the sword—and by whom shall I
comfort thee
20 Thy sons have fainted, save these two; they lie
at the head of all the streets; as a wild bull in
a net, they are full of the fury of the Lord, the
rebuke of thy God
21 Therefore hear now this, thou afflicted, and
drunken, and not with wine
22 Thus saith thy Lord, the Lord and thy God
pleadeth the cause of his people; behold, I have taken
out of thine hand the cup of trembling, the dregs
of the cup of my fury; thou shalt no more drink it
again
23 But I will put it into the hand of them that
afflict thee; who have said to thy soul: Bow down,
that we may go over—and thou hast laid thy body as
the ground and as the street to them that went
over
24 Awake, awake, put on thy strength, O Zion; put
on thy beautiful garments, O Jerusalem, the holy
city; for henceforth there shall no more come into
thee the uncircumcised and the unclean