Chapter 22 In the millennial day all men will
praise the Lord—He will dwell among them—Compare
Isaiah 12. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And in that day thou shalt say: O Lord, I will
praise thee; though thou wast angry with me thine
anger is turned away, and thou comfortedst me
2 Behold, God is my salvation; I will trust, and
not be afraid; for the Lord Jehovah is my strength
and my song; he also has become my salvation
3 Therefore, with joy shall ye draw water out of
the wells of salvation
4 And in that day shall ye say: Praise the Lord,
call upon his name, declare his doings among the
people, make mention that his name is exalted
5 Sing unto the Lord; for he hath done excellent
things; this is known in all the earth
6 Cry out and shout, thou inhabitant of Zion; for
great is the Holy One of Israel in the midst of
thee.