Chapter 26 Christ will minister to the
Nephites—Nephi foresees the destruction of
his people—They will speak from the dust—The
Gentiles will build up false churches and
secret combinations—The Lord forbids men
to practice priestcrafts. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And after Christ shall have risen
from the dead he shall show himself unto
you, my children, and my beloved
brethren; and the words which he shall speak
unto you shall be the law which ye shall do.
2 For behold, I say unto you that I
have beheld that many generations
shall pass away, and there shall be great
wars and contentions among my people.
3 And after the Messiah shall come
there shall be signs given unto
my people of his birth, and also of
his death and resurrection; and
great and terrible shall that day
be unto the wicked, for they shall
perish; and they perish because
they cast out the prophets, and the
saints, and stone them, and slay
them; wherefore the cry of the
blood of the saints shall ascend up to
God from the ground against them.
4 Wherefore, all those who are
proud, and that do wickedly,
the day that cometh shall burn
them up, saith the Lord of
Hosts, for they shall be as stubble.
5 And they that kill the
prophets, and the saints, the
depths of the earth shall
swallow them up, saith the
Lord of Hosts; and
mountains shall cover them, and
whirlwinds shall carry them
away, and buildings shall
fall upon them and crush them
to pieces and grind them to powder.
6 And they shall be
visited with thunderings, and
lightnings, and
earthquakes, and all manner of
destructions, for the fire
of the anger of the Lord
shall be kindled against
them, and they shall be as
stubble, and the day
that cometh shall consume
them, saith the Lord of Hosts.
7 O the pain, and the
anguish of my soul for the
loss of the slain of my
people! For I, Nephi,
have seen it, and it well
nigh consumeth me
before the presence of the
Lord; but I must cry unto
my God: Thy ways are just.
8 But behold, the
righteous that hearken
unto the words of the
prophets, and destroy
them not, but look
forward unto Christ with
steadfastness for the
signs which are given,
notwithstanding all
persecution—behold, they
are they which shall not perish.
9 But the Son of
Righteousness shall
appear unto them; and he
shall heal them, and
they shall have peace
with him, until three
generations shall
have passed away, and
many of the fourth
generation shall have
passed away in righteousness.
10 And when these
things have passed
away a speedy
destruction cometh unto my
people; for,
notwithstanding the pains of
my soul, I have seen
it; wherefore, I
know that it shall
come to pass; and they
sell themselves for
naught; for, for the
reward of their
pride and their
foolishness they shall reap
destruction; for
because they yield
unto the devil and
choose works of darkness
rather than light,
therefore they must go down to hell.
11 For the Spirit
of the Lord will
not always strive
with man. And when
the Spirit ceaseth
to strive with
man then cometh
speedy destruction,
and this grieveth my soul.
12 And as I
spake concerning the
convincing of
the Jews, that
Jesus is the very
Christ, it must
needs be that
the Gentiles be
convinced also
that Jesus is the
Christ, the Eternal God;
13 And that he
manifesteth
himself unto all
those who
believe in him, by
the power of the
Holy Ghost;
yea, unto every
nation, kindred,
tongue, and
people, working
mighty miracles,
signs, and
wonders, among the
children of men
according to their faith.
14 But behold,
I prophesy
unto you
concerning the last
days;
concerning the days
when the Lord God
shall bring
these things
forth unto the
children of men.
15 After my
seed and the
seed of my
brethren shall
have dwindled
in unbelief,
and shall
have been
smitten by the
Gentiles; yea,
after the Lord
God shall
have camped
against them
round about, and
shall have
laid siege
against them with
a mount, and
raised forts
against
them; and after
they shall
have been
brought down low in
the dust,
even that they
are not, yet
the words of
the righteous
shall be
written, and the
prayers of
the faithful
shall be
heard, and all
those who have
dwindled in unbelief shall not be forgotten.
16 For those
who shall
be destroyed
shall speak
unto them
out of the
ground, and
their speech
shall be low
out of the
dust, and
their voice
shall be as one
that hath a
familiar
spirit; for the
Lord God
will give unto
him power,
that he may
whisper
concerning them,
even as it
were out of
the ground;
and their
speech shall whisper out of the dust.
17 For thus
saith the
Lord God:
They shall
write the
things which
shall be
done among
them, and
they shall be
written and
sealed up
in a book,
and those
who have
dwindled in
unbelief
shall not have
them, for
they seek to
destroy the things of God.
Wherefore, as those
who have
been
destroyed have
been destroyed
speedily;
and the
multitude of
their
terrible ones
shall be as
chaff that
passeth
away—yea, thus
saith the
Lord God: It
shall be at
an
instant, suddenly—
19 And it
shall come
to pass,
that those
who have
dwindled
in unbelief
shall be
smitten by
the hand
of the Gentiles.
20 And the
Gentiles
are lifted
up in the
pride of
their
eyes, and have
stumbled,
because
of the
greatness of
their
stumbling
block, that
they have
built up many
churches;
nevertheless, they
put down
the power
and
miracles of God,
and preach
up unto
themselves
their own
wisdom and
learning,
that they
may get
gain and
grind upon
the face of
the poor.
21 And
there are
many
churches built
up which
cause
envyings,
and
strifes, and malice.
22 And
there are
also
secret
combinations,
even as in
times of
old,
according to
the
combinations
of the
devil, for
he is the
founder
of all
these
things; yea,
the founder
of
murder, and
works of
darkness;
yea, and
he leadeth
them by
the neck
with a
flaxen
cord, until
he bindeth
them
with his
strong cords
forever.
23 For
behold,
my
beloved
brethren, I
say unto
you that
the Lord
God
worketh not
in darkness.
24 He
doeth
not
anything
save it be
for
the
benefit of
world; for
he
loveth the
world,
even
that he
layeth
down his
own
life that
he may
draw
all men
unto
him.
Wherefore,
he
commandeth
none
that they
shall not partake of his salvation.
Behold,
doth he
cry
unto
any,
saying:
Depart
from
me?
Behold, I
say
unto
you,
Nay; but
he
saith:
Come
unto me
all ye
ends
of the
earth,
buy
milk
and
honey,
without money and without price.
Behold,
hath
he
commanded
any
that
they
should
depart out
of
the
synagogues,
or
out of
the
houses
of
worship?
Behold, I say unto you, Nay.
Hath he
commanded
any
that
they
should not
partake
of his
salvation?
Behold I
say
unto
you,
Nay;
but
he
hath
given it
free
for
all
men;
and he
hath
commanded
his
people
that
they
should
persuade
all men
to
repentance.
Behold,
hath
the
Lord
commanded
any
that
they
should
not
partake
of
his
goodness?
Behold
I
say
unto
you,
Nay;
but
all
men
are
privileged
the
one
like
unto the other, and none are forbidden.
He
commandeth
that
there
shall be
no
priestcrafts;
for,
behold,
priestcrafts
are
that
men
preach
and
set
themselves
up
for a
light
unto
the
world,
that
they
may
get
gain
and
praise
of
the
world;
but
they
seek
not
the
welfare
of
Zion.
Behold,
the
Lord
hath
forbidden
this
thing;
wherefore,
the
Lord
God
hath
given
a
commandment
that
all
men
should
have
charity,
which
charity
is
love.
And
except
they
should
have
charity
they
were
nothing.
Wherefore,
if
they should have charity they would not suffer the laborer in Zion to perish.
But
the
laborer
in
Zion
shall
labor
for
Zion;
if
they
labor for money they shall perish.
32 And again, the Lord God hath commanded that men should not murder; that they should not lie; that they should not steal; that they should not take the name of the Lord their God in vain; that they should not envy; that they should not have malice; that they should not contend one with another; that they should not commit whoredoms; and that they should do none of these things; for whoso doeth them shall
And
again,
the
Lord
God
hath
commanded
that
men
should
not
murder;
that
they
should
not
lie;
that
they
should
not
steal;
that
they
should
not
take
the
name
of
the
Lord
their
God
in
vain;
that
they
should
not envy; that they should not have malice; that they should not contend one with another; that they should not commit whoredoms; and that they should do none of these things; for whoso doeth them shall perish.
33 For none of these iniquities come of the Lord; for he doeth that which is good among the children of men; and he doeth nothing save it be plain unto the children of men; and he inviteth them all to come unto him and partake of his goodness; and he denieth none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, male and female; and he remembereth the heathen; and all are alike unto God, both Jew and Gentile.
For
none
of
these
iniquities
come
of
the
Lord;
for
he
doeth
that
which
is
good
among
the
children
of
men;
and
he
doeth
nothing
save
it
be
plain
unto
the
children
of
men;
and
he
inviteth
them
all
to
come
unto
him
and
partake
of
his
goodness;
and
he
denieth
none
that
come
unto
him,
black
and
white,
bond
and
free,
male
and
female;
he
remembereth
the
heathen;
and
all
are
alike
unto
God,
both
Jew
and
Gentile.