Chapter 23 The destruction of Babylon is a type of
the destruction at the Second Coming—It will be a
day of wrath and vengeance—Babylon (the world)
will fall forever—Compare
Isaiah 13. About
559–545 B.C.
1 The burden of Babylon, which Isaiah the son of
Amoz did see
2 Lift ye up a banner upon the high mountain,
exalt the voice unto them, shake the hand, that they
may go into the gates of the nobles
3 I have commanded my sanctified ones, I have also
called my mighty ones, for mine anger is not upon
them that rejoice in my highness
4 The noise of the multitude in the mountains like
as of a great people, a tumultuous noise of the
kingdoms of nations gathered together, the Lord of
Hosts mustereth the hosts of the battle
5 They come from a far country, from the end of
heaven, yea, the Lord, and the weapons of his
indignation, to destroy the whole land
6 Howl ye, for the day of the Lord is at hand; it
shall come as a destruction from the Almighty
7 Therefore shall all hands be faint, every man’s
heart shall melt
8 And they shall be afraid; pangs and sorrows
shall take hold of them; they shall be amazed one at
another; their faces shall be as flames
9 Behold, the day of the Lord cometh, cruel both
with wrath and fierce anger, to lay the land
desolate; and he shall destroy the sinners thereof out
of it
10 For the stars of heaven and the constellations
thereof shall not give their light; the sun shall
be darkened in his going forth, and the moon shall
not cause her light to shine
11 And I will punish the world for evil, and the
wicked for their iniquity; I will cause the
arrogancy of the proud to cease, and will lay down the
haughtiness of the terrible
12 I will make a man more precious than fine gold;
even a man than the golden wedge of Ophir
13 Therefore, I will shake the heavens, and the
earth shall remove out of her place, in the wrath of
the Lord of Hosts, and in the day of his fierce
anger
14 And it shall be as the chased roe, and as a
sheep that no man taketh up; and they shall every man
turn to his own people, and flee every one into
his own land
15 Every one that is proud shall be thrust
through; yea, and every one that is joined to the wicked
shall fall by the sword
16 Their children also shall be dashed to pieces
before their eyes; their houses shall be spoiled
and their wives ravished
17 Behold, I will stir up the Medes against them,
which shall not regard silver and gold, nor shall
they delight in it
18 Their bows shall also dash the young men to
pieces; and they shall have no pity on the fruit of
the womb; their eyes shall not spare children
19 And Babylon, the glory of kingdoms, the beauty
of the Chaldees’ excellency, shall be as when God
overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah
20 It shall never be inhabited, neither shall it
be dwelt in from generation to generation: neither
shall the Arabian pitch tent there; neither shall
the shepherds make their fold there
21 But wild beasts of the desert shall lie there;
and their houses shall be full of doleful
creatures; and owls shall dwell there, and satyrs shall
dance there
22 And the wild beasts of the islands shall cry in
their desolate houses, and dragons in their
pleasant palaces; and her time is near to come, and her
day shall not be prolonged. For I will destroy
her speedily; yea, for I will be merciful unto my
people, but the wicked shall perish.