Chapter 28 Many false churches will be built
up in the last days—They will teach false,
vain, and foolish doctrines—Apostasy will
abound because of false teachers—The devil
will rage in the hearts of men—He will teach
all manner of false doctrines. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And now, behold, my brethren, I have
spoken unto you, according as the
Spirit hath constrained me; wherefore, I
know that they must surely come to pass.
2 And the things which shall be
written out of the book shall be of
great worth unto the children of men,
and especially unto our seed,
which is a remnant of the house of Israel.
3 For it shall come to pass in
that day that the churches which
are built up, and not unto the
Lord, when the one shall say unto
the other: Behold, I, I am the
Lord’s; and the others shall
say: I, I am the Lord’s; and thus
shall every one say that hath
built up churches, and not unto the Lord—
4 And they shall contend one
with another; and their priests
shall contend one with
another, and they shall teach with
their learning, and deny the
Holy Ghost, which giveth utterance.
5 And they deny the power
of God, the Holy One of
Israel; and they say unto the
people: Hearken unto us, and
hear ye our precept; for
behold there is no God
today, for the Lord and the
Redeemer hath done his work,
and he hath given his power unto men;
6 Behold, hearken ye unto
my precept; if they shall
say there is a miracle
wrought by the hand of the
Lord, believe it not; for
this day he is not a God of
miracles; he hath done his work.
7 Yea, and there shall
be many which shall say:
Eat, drink, and be
merry, for tomorrow we die;
and it shall be well with us.
8 And there shall also
be many which shall
say: Eat, drink, and be
merry; nevertheless,
fear God—he will
justify in committing a
little sin; yea, lie a
little, take the
advantage of one because of
his words, dig a pit
for thy neighbor; there
is no harm in this;
and do all these things,
for tomorrow we die;
and if it so be that
we are guilty, God will
beat us with a few
stripes, and at last we
shall be saved in the kingdom of God.
9 Yea, and there
shall be many which shall
teach after this
manner, false and vain
and foolish doctrines,
and shall be puffed
up in their hearts,
and shall seek deep to
hide their counsels
from the Lord; and
their works shall be in the dark.
10 And the blood
of the saints
shall cry from the
ground against them.
11 Yea, they
have all gone
out of the way;
they have
become corrupted.
12 Because of
pride, and
because of
false teachers,
and false
doctrine, their
churches have
become
corrupted, and
their churches
are lifted up;
because of
pride they are puffed up.
13 They rob
the poor
because of
their fine
sanctuaries; they
rob the
poor because of
their fine
clothing;
and they
persecute the
meek and the
poor in heart,
because in
their pride
they are puffed up.
14 They
wear stiff
necks and high
heads;
yea, and
because of
pride, and
wickedness, and
abominations, and
whoredoms, they
have all
gone astray
save it be
a few, who
are the
humble
followers of
Christ;
nevertheless, they
are led,
that in many
instances
they do err
because
they are taught by the precepts of men.
15 O the
wise, and
the
learned, and the
rich, that
are
puffed up in
the pride of
their
hearts, and
all those
who preach
false
doctrines, and
all those
who
commit
whoredoms, and
pervert the
right way
of the
Lord, wo, wo,
wo be unto
them,
saith the
Lord God
Almighty, for
they shall be thrust down to hell!
16 Wo
unto them
that turn
aside the
just for
a thing
of naught
and
revile against
that
which is
good, and
say that it
is of no
worth!
For the
day shall
come that
the Lord
God will
speedily
visit the
inhabitants of
the earth;
and in
that day
that they
are fully
ripe in iniquity they shall perish.
17 But
behold,
if the
inhabitants of the
earth
shall
repent of
their
wickedness
and
abominations
they
shall not
be
destroyed,
saith the Lord of Hosts.
18 But
behold,
that
great
and
abominable
church,
the
whore of
all the
earth,
must
tumble to
the
earth,
and great
must
be the fall thereof.
19 For
the
kingdom
of
the
devil must
shake, and
they
which
belong
to it
must
needs
be
stirred up
unto
repentance,
or the
devil
will
grasp
them
with
his
everlasting
chains,
and they
be stirred up to anger, and perish;
20 For
behold, at
that
day
shall he
rage
in the
hearts
of
the
children
of men,
and
stir
them up
to
anger
against
that
which is
good.
And
others
will
he
pacify,
and
lull
them
away
into
carnal
security,
that
they
will
say:
All
is
well in
Zion;
yea,
Zion
prospereth,
all is
well—and
thus
the
devil
cheateth
their
souls, and
leadeth them away carefully down to hell.
And
behold,
others he
flattereth
away,
and
telleth
them
there
is
no
hell;
and
he
saith
unto
them:
I
am no
devil,
for
there is
none—and
thus
he
whispereth
in
their
ears,
until he
grasps
them
with
his awful chains, from whence there is no deliverance.
Yea,
they
are
grasped
with
death,
and
hell;
death,
and
hell,
the
devil,
and
all
that
have
been
seized
therewith
must
stand
before
the
throne
of
God,
and
be
judged
according
to
their
works,
from
whence
they
must
go
into
the
place prepared for them, even a lake of fire and brimstone, which is endless torment.
Therefore,
wo
be
unto
him
that
is at ease in Zion!
25 Wo be unto him that crieth: All is
Wo
be
unto
him
that crieth: All is well!
26 Yea, wo be unto him that hearkeneth unto the precepts of men, and denieth the power of God, and the gift of the Holy
Yea,
wo
be
unto
him
that
hearkeneth
unto
the
precepts
of
men,
and
denieth
the
power
of
God,
and
the
gift
of
the
Holy
Ghost!
27 Yea, wo be unto him that saith: We have received, and we need no
Yea,
wo
be
unto
him
that
saith:
We
have
received,
and
we
need
no
more!
28 And in fine, wo unto all those who tremble, and are angry because of the truth of God! For behold, he that is built upon the rock receiveth it with gladness; and he that is built upon a sandy foundation trembleth lest he shall
And
in
fine,
wo
unto
all
those
who
tremble,
and
are
angry
because
of
the
truth
of
God!
For
behold,
he
that
is
built
upon
the
rock
receiveth
it
with
gladness;
and
he
that
is
built
upon
a
sandy
foundation
trembleth
lest
he
shall
fall.
29 Wo be unto him that shall say: We have received the word of God, and we need no more of the word of God, for we have
Wo
be
unto
him
that
shall
say:
We
have
received
the
word
of
God,
and
we
need
no
more
of
the
word
of
God,
for
we
have
enough!
30 For behold, thus saith the Lord God: I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little; and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, and lend an ear unto my counsel, for they shall learn wisdom; for unto him that receiveth I will give more; and from them that shall say, We have enough, from them shall be taken away even that which they
For
behold,
thus
saith
the
Lord
God:
I
will
give
unto
the
children
of
men
line
upon
line,
precept
upon
precept,
here
a
little
and
there
a
little;
and
blessed
are
those
who
hearken
unto
my
precepts,
and
lend
an
ear
unto
my
counsel,
for
they
shall
learn
wisdom;
for
unto
him
that
receiveth
I
will
give
more;
and
from
them
that
shall
say,
We
have
enough,
from
them
shall
be
taken
away
even
that
which
they
have.
31 Cursed is he that putteth his trust in man, or maketh flesh his arm, or shall hearken unto the precepts of men, save their precepts shall be given by the power of the Holy
Cursed
is
he
that
putteth
his
trust
in
man,
or
maketh
flesh
his
arm,
or
shall
hearken
unto
the
precepts
of
men,
save
their
precepts
shall
be
given
by
the
power
of
the
Holy
Ghost.
32 Wo be unto the Gentiles, saith the Lord God of Hosts! For notwithstanding I shall lengthen out mine arm unto them from day to day, they will deny me; nevertheless, I will be merciful unto them, saith the Lord God, if they will repent and come unto me; for mine arm is lengthened out all the day long, saith the Lord God of Hosts.
Wo
be
unto
the
Gentiles,
saith
the
Lord
God
of
Hosts!
For
notwithstanding
I
shall
lengthen
out
mine
arm
unto
them
from
day
to
day,
they
will
deny
me;
nevertheless,
I
will
be
merciful
unto
them,
saith
the
Lord
God,
if
they
will
repent
and
come
unto
me;
for
mine
arm
is
lengthened
out
all
the
day
long,
saith
the
Lord
God
of
Hosts.