Chapter 16 Isaiah sees the Lord—Isaiah’s
sins are forgiven—He is called to
prophesy—He prophesies of the rejection by the
Jews of Christ’s teachings—A remnant will
return—Compare
Isaiah 6. About 559–545 B.C.
1 In the year that king Uzziah
died, I saw also the Lord sitting
upon a throne, high and lifted up,
and his train filled the temple.
2 Above it stood the
seraphim; each one had six wings;
with twain he covered his face,
and with twain he covered his
feet, and with twain he did fly.
3 And one cried unto
another, and said: Holy,
holy, holy, is the Lord
of Hosts; the whole
earth is full of his glory.
4 And the posts of
the door moved at the
voice of him that
cried, and the house
was filled with smoke.
5 Then said I: Wo
is unto me! for I
am undone; because
I am a man of
unclean lips; and I
dwell in the midst
of a people of
unclean lips; for
mine eyes have seen
the King, the Lord of Hosts.
6 Then flew one of
the seraphim unto
me, having a live
coal in his hand,
which he had
taken with the tongs
from off the altar;
7 And he laid it
upon my mouth, and
said: Lo, this has
touched thy lips;
and thine
iniquity is taken away,
and thy sin purged.
8 Also I heard
the voice of the
Lord, saying: Whom
shall I send, and
who will go for
us? Then I said:
Here am I; send me.
9 And he said:
Go and tell
this people—Hear
ye indeed, but
they understood
not; and see ye
indeed, but
they perceived not.
10 Make the
heart of this
people fat, and
make their
ears heavy, and
shut their
eyes—lest they see
with their
eyes, and hear
ears, and
understand with their
heart, and be
converted and be healed.
11 Then said
I: Lord, how
long? And he
said: Until
the cities be
wasted
without inhabitant,
and the
houses without
man, and the
land be utterly desolate;
12 And the
Lord have
removed men
far away,
for there
shall be a
great
forsaking in the
midst of the land.
13 But yet
there
shall be a
tenth, and
they shall
return,
and shall be
eaten, as
a teil
tree, and as
an oak
whose
substance is in
them when
they cast
their
leaves; so the
holy seed
shall be
the substance thereof.