Chapter 20 The destruction of Assyria is a type of
the destruction of the wicked at the Second
Coming—Few people will be left after the Lord comes
again—The remnant of Jacob will return in that
day—Compare
Isaiah 10. About 559–545 B.C.
1 Wo unto them that decree unrighteous decrees,
and that write grievousness which they have
prescribed
2 To turn away the needy from judgment, and to
take away the right from the poor of my people, that
widows may be their prey, and that they may rob
the fatherless
3 And what will ye do in the day of visitation,
and in the desolation which shall come from far? to
whom will ye flee for help? and where will ye
leave your glory
4 Without me they shall bow down under the
prisoners, and they shall fall under the slain. For all
this his anger is not turned away, but his hand is
stretched out still
5 O Assyrian, the rod of mine anger, and the staff
in their hand is their indignation
6 I will send him against a hypocritical nation,
and against the people of my wrath will I give him
a charge to take the spoil, and to take the prey,
and to tread them down like the mire of the
streets
7 Howbeit he meaneth not so, neither doth his
heart think so; but in his heart it is to destroy and
cut off nations not a few
8 For he saith: Are not my princes altogether
kings
9 Is not Calno as Carchemish? Is not Hamath as
Arpad? Is not Samaria as Damascus
10 As my hand hath founded the kingdoms of the
idols, and whose graven images did excel them of
Jerusalem and of Samaria
11 Shall I not, as I have done unto Samaria and
her idols, so do to Jerusalem and to her idols
12 Wherefore it shall come to pass that when the
Lord hath performed his whole work upon Mount Zion
and upon Jerusalem, I will punish the fruit of the
stout heart of the king of Assyria, and the glory
of his high looks
13 For he saith: By the strength of my hand and by
my wisdom I have done these things; for I am
prudent; and I have moved the borders of the people,
and have robbed their treasures, and I have put
down the inhabitants like a valiant man
14 And my hand hath found as a nest the riches of
the people; and as one gathereth eggs that are
left have I gathered all the earth; and there was
none that moved the wing, or opened the mouth, or
peeped
15 Shall the ax boast itself against him that
heweth therewith? Shall the saw magnify itself against
him that shaketh it? As if the rod should shake
itself against them that lift it up, or as if the
staff should lift up itself as if it were no wood
16 Therefore shall the Lord, the Lord of Hosts,
send among his fat ones, leanness; and under his
glory he shall kindle a burning like the burning of a
fire
17 And the light of Israel shall be for a fire,
and his Holy One for a flame, and shall burn and
shall devour his thorns and his briers in one day
18 And shall consume the glory of his forest, and
of his fruitful field, both soul and body; and
they shall be as when a standard-bearer fainteth
19 And the rest of the trees of his forest shall
be few, that a child may write them
20 And it shall come to pass in that day, that the
remnant of Israel, and such as are escaped of the
house of Jacob, shall no more again stay upon him
that smote them, but shall stay upon the Lord,
the Holy One of Israel, in truth
21 The remnant shall return, yea, even the remnant
of Jacob, unto the mighty God
22 For though thy people Israel be as the sand of
the sea, yet a remnant of them shall return; the
consumption decreed shall overflow with
righteousness
23 For the Lord God of Hosts shall make a
consumption, even determined in all the land
24 Therefore, thus saith the Lord God of Hosts: O
my people that dwellest in Zion, be not afraid of
the Assyrian; he shall smite thee with a rod, and
shall lift up his staff against thee, after the
manner of Egypt
25 For yet a very little while, and the
indignation shall cease, and mine anger in their
destruction
26 And the Lord of Hosts shall stir up a scourge
for him according to the slaughter of Midian at the
rock of Oreb; and as his rod was upon the sea so
shall he lift it up after the manner of Egypt
27 And it shall come to pass in that day that his
burden shall be taken away from off thy shoulder,
and his yoke from off thy neck, and the yoke shall
be destroyed because of the anointing
28 He is come to Aiath, he is passed to Migron; at
Michmash he hath laid up his carriages
29 They are gone over the passage; they have taken
up their lodging at Geba; Ramath is afraid;
Gibeah of Saul is fled
30 Lift up the voice, O daughter of Gallim; cause
it to be heard unto Laish, O poor Anathoth
31 Madmenah is removed; the inhabitants of Gebim
gather themselves to flee
32 As yet shall he remain at Nob that day; he
shall shake his hand against the mount of the daughter
of Zion, the hill of Jerusalem
33 Behold, the Lord, the Lord of Hosts shall lop
the bough with terror; and the high ones of stature
shall be hewn down; and the haughty shall be
humbled
34 And he shall cut down the thickets of the
forests with iron, and Lebanon shall fall by a mighty
one.