Chapter 3 Joseph in Egypt saw the Nephites in
vision—He prophesied of Joseph Smith, the latter-day
seer; of Moses, who would deliver Israel; and of
the coming forth of the Book of Mormon. About
588–570 B.C.
1 And now I speak unto you, Joseph, my last-born.
Thou wast born in the wilderness of mine
afflictions; yea, in the days of my greatest sorrow did thy
mother bear thee
2 And may the Lord consecrate also unto thee this
land, which is a most precious land, for thine
inheritance and the inheritance of thy seed with thy
brethren, for thy security forever, if it so be
that ye shall keep the commandments of the Holy One
of Israel
3 And now, Joseph, my last-born, whom I have
brought out of the wilderness of mine afflictions, may
the Lord bless thee forever, for thy seed shall
not utterly be destroyed
4 For behold, thou art the fruit of my loins; and
I am a descendant of Joseph who was carried
captive into Egypt. And great were the covenants of the
Lord which he made unto Joseph
5 Wherefore, Joseph truly saw our day. And he
obtained a promise of the Lord, that out of the fruit
of his loins the Lord God would raise up a
righteous branch unto the house of Israel; not the
Messiah, but a branch which was to be broken off,
nevertheless, to be remembered in the covenants of the
Lord that the Messiah should be made manifest unto
them in the latter days, in the spirit of power,
unto the bringing of them out of darkness unto
light—yea, out of hidden darkness and out of captivity
unto freedom
6 For Joseph truly testified, saying: A seer shall
the Lord my God raise up, who shall be a choice
seer unto the fruit of my loins
7 Yea, Joseph truly said: Thus saith the Lord unto
me: A choice seer will I raise up out of the
fruit of thy loins; and he shall be esteemed highly
among the fruit of thy loins. And unto him will I
give commandment that he shall do a work for the
fruit of thy loins, his brethren, which shall be of
great worth unto them, even to the bringing of them
to the knowledge of the covenants which I have
made with thy fathers
8 And I will give unto him a commandment that he
shall do none other work, save the work which I
shall command him. And I will make him great in mine
eyes; for he shall do my work
11 But a seer will I raise up out of the fruit of
thy loins; and unto him will I give power to bring
forth my word unto the seed of thy loins—and not
to the bringing forth my word only, saith the
Lord, but to the convincing them of my word, which
shall have already gone forth among them
12 Wherefore, the fruit of thy loins shall write;
and the fruit of the loins of Judah shall write;
and that which shall be written by the fruit of thy
loins, and also that which shall be written by
the fruit of the loins of Judah, shall grow
together, unto the confounding of false doctrines and
laying down of contentions, and establishing peace
among the fruit of thy loins, and bringing them to
the knowledge of their fathers in the latter days,
and also to the knowledge of my covenants, saith
the Lord
13 And out of weakness he shall be made strong, in
that day when my work shall commence among all my
people, unto the restoring thee, O house of
Israel, saith the Lord
14 And thus prophesied Joseph, saying: Behold,
that seer will the Lord bless; and they that seek to
destroy him shall be confounded; for this promise,
which I have obtained of the Lord, of the fruit
of my loins, shall be fulfilled. Behold, I am sure
of the fulfilling of this promise
15 And his name shall be called after me; and it
shall be after the name of his father. And he shall
be like unto me; for the thing, which the Lord
shall bring forth by his hand, by the power of the
Lord shall bring my people unto salvation
16 Yea, thus prophesied Joseph: I am sure of this
thing, even as I am sure of the promise of Moses;
for the Lord hath said unto me, I will preserve
thy seed forever
17 And the Lord hath said: I will raise up a
Moses; and I will give power unto him in a rod; and I
will give judgment unto him in writing. Yet I will
not loose his tongue, that he shall speak much,
for I will not make him mighty in speaking. But I
will write unto him my law, by the finger of mine
own hand; and I will make a spokesman for him
20 And they shall cry from the dust; yea, even
repentance unto their brethren, even after many
generations have gone by them. And it shall come to
pass that their cry shall go, even according to the
simpleness of their words
21 Because of their faith their words shall
proceed forth out of my mouth unto their brethren who
are the fruit of thy loins; and the weakness of
their words will I make strong in their faith, unto
the remembering of my covenant which I made unto thy
fathers
22 And now, behold, my son Joseph, after this
manner did my father of old prophesy
23 Wherefore, because of this covenant thou art
blessed; for thy seed shall not be destroyed, for
they shall hearken unto the words of the book
24 And there shall rise up one mighty among them,
who shall do much good, both in word and in deed,
being an instrument in the hands of God, with
exceeding faith, to work mighty wonders, and do that
thing which is great in the sight of God, unto the
bringing to pass much restoration unto the house
of Israel, and unto the seed of thy brethren
25 And now, blessed art thou, Joseph. Behold, thou
art little; wherefore hearken unto the words of
thy brother, Nephi, and it shall be done unto thee
even according to the words which I have spoken.
Remember the words of thy dying father. Amen.