Chapter 32 Angels speak by the power of the Holy
Ghost—Men must pray and gain knowledge for
themselves from the Holy Ghost. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And now, behold, my beloved brethren, I suppose
that ye ponder somewhat in your hearts concerning
that which ye should do after ye have entered in
by the way. But, behold, why do ye ponder these
things in your hearts
2 Do ye not remember that I said unto you that
after ye had received the Holy Ghost ye could speak
with the tongue of angels? And now, how could ye
speak with the tongue of angels save it were by the
Holy Ghost
3 Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost;
wherefore, they speak the words of Christ. Wherefore,
I said unto you, feast upon the words of Christ;
for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all
things what ye should do
6 Behold, this is the doctrine of Christ, and
there will be no more doctrine given until after he
shall manifest himself unto you in the flesh. And
when he shall manifest himself unto you in the
flesh, the things which he shall say unto you shall ye
observe to do
7 And now I, Nephi, cannot say more; the Spirit
stoppeth mine utterance, and I am left to mourn
because of the unbelief, and the wickedness, and the
ignorance, and the stiffneckedness of men; for they
will not search knowledge, nor understand great
knowledge, when it is given unto them in plainness,
even as plain as word can be
8 And now, my beloved brethren, I perceive that ye
ponder still in your hearts; and it grieveth me
that I must speak concerning this thing. For if ye
would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man
to pray, ye would know that ye must pray; for the
evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray, but
teacheth him that he must not pray
9 But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray
always, and not faint; that ye must not perform any
thing unto the Lord save in the first place ye
shall pray unto the Father in the name of Christ, that
he will consecrate thy performance unto thee,
that thy performance may be for the welfare of thy
soul.