Chapter 29 Many Gentiles will reject the
Book of Mormon—They will say, We need no
more Bible—The Lord speaks to many
nations—He will judge the world out of the
books which will be written. About 559–545 B.C.
1 But behold, there shall be many—at
that day when I shall proceed to do a
marvelous work among them, that I may
remember my covenants which I have made
unto the children of men, that I may set
my hand again the second time to recover
my people, which are of the house of Israel;
2 And also, that I may remember the
promises which I have made unto thee,
Nephi, and also unto thy father, that I
would remember your seed; and that the
words of your seed should proceed
forth out of my mouth unto your seed; and
my words shall hiss forth unto the
ends of the earth, for a standard unto
my people, which are of the house of Israel;
3 And because my words shall hiss
forth—many of the Gentiles shall say:
A Bible! A Bible! We have got a
Bible, and there cannot be any more Bible.
4 But thus saith the Lord God: O
fools, they shall have a Bible; and
it shall proceed forth from the
Jews, mine ancient covenant people. And
what thank they the Jews for the
Bible which they receive from them?
Yea, what do the Gentiles mean? Do
they remember the travails, and the
labors, and the pains of the Jews,
and their diligence unto me, in
bringing forth salvation unto the Gentiles?
5 O ye Gentiles, have ye
remembered the Jews, mine ancient covenant
people? Nay; but ye have cursed
them, and have hated them, and have
not sought to recover them. But
behold, I will return all these
things upon your own heads; for I the
Lord have not forgotten my people.
6 Thou fool, that shall say: A
Bible, we have got a Bible, and we
need no more Bible. Have ye obtained
a Bible save it were by the Jews?
7 Know ye not that there are more
nations than one? Know ye not
that I, the Lord your God, have
created all men, and that I remember
those who are upon the isles of
the sea; and that I rule in the
heavens above and in the earth
beneath; and I bring forth my word
unto the children of men, yea,
even upon all the nations of the earth?
8 Wherefore murmur ye, because
that ye shall receive more of
my word? Know ye not that the
testimony of two nations is a
witness unto you that I am
God, that I remember one nation
like unto another? Wherefore,
I speak the same words unto
one nation like unto another.
And when the two nations shall
run together the testimony of
the two nations shall run together also.
9 And I do this that I may
prove unto many that I am the
same yesterday, today, and
forever; and that I speak
forth my words according to
mine own pleasure. And because
that I have spoken one word
ye need not suppose that I
cannot speak another; for my
work is not yet finished;
neither shall it be until the
end of man, neither from
that time henceforth and forever.
10 Wherefore, because that
ye have a Bible ye need
not suppose that it
contains all my words; neither
need ye suppose that I have
not caused more to be written.
11 For I command all
men, both in the east and
in the west, and in the
north, and in the south,
and in the islands of
the sea, that they shall
write the words which I
speak unto them; for out
of the books which shall
be written I will judge
the world, every man
according to their works,
according to that which is written.
12 For behold, I shall
speak unto the Jews and
they shall write it;
and I shall also speak
unto the Nephites and
they shall write it; and
I shall also speak unto
the other tribes of
the house of Israel,
which I have led away, and
they shall write it;
and I shall also speak
unto all nations of the
earth and they shall write it.
13 And it shall come
to pass that the Jews
shall have the words of
the Nephites, and the
Nephites shall have
the words of the Jews;
and the Nephites and
the Jews shall have the
words of the lost
tribes of Israel; and the
lost tribes of Israel
shall have the words
of the Nephites and the Jews.
14 And it shall come
to pass that my
people, which are of the
house of Israel, shall
be gathered home
unto the lands of their
possessions; and my
word also shall be
gathered in one. And I
will show unto them
that fight against my
word and against my
people, who are of the
house of Israel, that
I am God, and that I
covenanted with
Abraham that I would
remember his seed forever.