Chapter 11 Jacob saw his Redeemer—The
law of Moses typifies Christ and
proves He will come. About 559–545 B.C.
1 And now, Jacob spake many more
things to my people at that time;
nevertheless only these things have I
caused to be written, for the
things which I have written sufficeth me.
2 And now I, Nephi, write more of
the words of Isaiah, for my soul
delighteth in his words. For I will
liken his words unto my people,
and I will send them forth unto all
my children, for he verily saw my
Redeemer, even as I have seen him.
3 And my brother, Jacob, also
has seen him as I have seen him;
wherefore, I will send their
words forth unto my children to
prove unto them that my words
are true. Wherefore, by the
words of three, God hath said, I
will establish my word.
Nevertheless, God sendeth more
witnesses, and he proveth all his words.
4 Behold, my soul delighteth
in proving unto my people
the truth of the coming of
Christ; for, for this end hath
the law of Moses been
given; and all things which have
been given of God from the
beginning of the world, unto
man, are the typifying of him.
5 And also my soul
delighteth in the covenants of
the Lord which he hath
made to our fathers; yea,
my soul delighteth in his
grace, and in his
justice, and power, and mercy in
the great and eternal
plan of deliverance from death.
6 And my soul delighteth
in proving unto my people
that save Christ should
come all men must perish.
7 For if there be no
Christ there be no God;
and if there be no
God we are not, for
there could have been no
creation. But there is
a God, and he is
Christ, and he cometh in
the fulness of his own time.
8 And now I write
some of the words of
Isaiah, that whoso of my
people shall see
these words may lift up
their hearts and
rejoice for all men. Now
these are the words,
and ye may liken them
unto you and unto all men.