Chapter 2 Redemption comes through the Holy
Messiah—Freedom of choice (agency) is
essential to existence and progression—Adam
fell that men might be—Men are free to choose
liberty and eternal life. About 588–570 B.C.
1 And now, Jacob, I speak unto you:
Thou art my firstborn in the days of
my tribulation in the wilderness. And
behold, in thy childhood thou hast
suffered afflictions and much sorrow,
because of the rudeness of thy brethren.
2 Nevertheless, Jacob, my firstborn
in the wilderness, thou knowest the
greatness of God; and he shall
consecrate thine afflictions for thy gain.
3 Wherefore, thy soul shall be
blessed, and thou shalt dwell safely
with thy brother, Nephi; and thy days
shall be spent in the service of
thy God. Wherefore, I know that thou
art redeemed, because of the
righteousness of thy Redeemer; for thou
hast beheld that in the fulness of
time he cometh to bring salvation unto men.
4 And thou hast beheld in thy
youth his glory; wherefore, thou
art blessed even as they unto
whom he shall minister in the
flesh; for the Spirit is the same,
yesterday, today, and forever. And
the way is prepared from the
fall of man, and salvation is free.
5 And men are instructed
sufficiently that they know good from
evil. And the law is given
unto men. And by the law no flesh
is justified; or, by the law
men are cut off. Yea, by the
temporal law they were cut off; and
also, by the spiritual law
they perish from that which is
good, and become miserable forever.
6 Wherefore, redemption
cometh in and through
the Holy Messiah; for he
is full of grace and truth.
7 Behold, he offereth
himself a sacrifice
for sin, to answer the
ends of the law, unto
all those who have a
broken heart and a
contrite spirit; and unto
none else can the ends
of the law be answered.
8 Wherefore, how great
the importance to
make these things known
unto the inhabitants of
the earth, that they
may know that there is
no flesh that can
dwell in the presence of
God, save it be
through the merits, and
mercy, and grace of the
Holy Messiah, who layeth
down his life
according to the flesh, and
taketh it again by the
power of the Spirit,
that he may bring to
pass the resurrection of
the dead, being the
first that should rise.
9 Wherefore, he is
the firstfruits
unto God, inasmuch as
he shall make
intercession for all the
children of men;
and they that
believe in him shall be saved.
10 And because of
the intercession
for all, all men
come unto God;
wherefore, they stand
in the presence of
him, to be judged
of him according
to the truth and
holiness which is in
him. Wherefore,
the ends of the law
which the Holy
One hath given, unto
the inflicting of
the punishment
which is affixed,
which punishment
that is affixed is in
opposition to
that of the happiness
which is affixed,
to answer the ends of the atonement—
11 For it must
needs be, that
there is an
opposition in all things.
If not so, my
firstborn in the
wilderness,
righteousness could not
be brought to
pass, neither
wickedness, neither
holiness nor misery,
neither good nor
bad. Wherefore,
all things must
needs be a compound
in one;
wherefore, if it should
be one body it
must needs remain as
dead, having no
life neither
death, nor corruption
nor
incorruption, happiness nor
misery, neither sense nor insensibility.
12 Wherefore, it
must needs have
been created
for a thing of
naught; wherefore
there would have
been no purpose
in the end of
its creation.
Wherefore, this
thing must needs
destroy the wisdom
of God and his
eternal purposes,
and also the
power, and the
mercy, and the justice of God.
13 And if ye
shall say there
is no law, ye
shall also say
there is no sin.
If ye shall say
there is no
sin, ye shall
also say there is
no
righteousness. And if there
be no
righteousness there be
no happiness.
And if there be
no
righteousness nor happiness
there be no
punishment nor
misery. And if
these things are
not there is no
God. And if
there is no God
we are not,
neither the earth;
for there could
have been no
creation of
things, neither to
act nor to be
acted upon;
wherefore, all things must have vanished away.
14 And now, my
sons, I speak
unto you
these things for
your profit and
learning; for
there is a
God, and he hath
created all
things, both
the heavens and
the earth, and
all things
that in them
are, both things
to act and
things to be acted upon.
15 And to
bring about his
eternal
purposes in the
end of man,
after he had
created our
first parents,
and the beasts
of the field
and the fowls
of the air,
and in fine,
all things
which are
created, it must
needs be that
there was an
opposition;
even the
forbidden fruit in
opposition
to the tree of
life; the
one being sweet and the other bitter.
Wherefore, the Lord
God gave unto
man that he
should act
for himself.
Wherefore,
man could
not act for
himself save
it should be
that he was
enticed by
the one or the other.
17 And I,
Lehi,
according to the
things
which I have
read, must
needs suppose
that an
angel of God,
according
to that
which is
written, had
fallen from
heaven;
wherefore, he
became a
devil, having
sought that
which was evil before God.
18 And
because he
had fallen
from
heaven, and had
become
miserable
forever, he
sought also
the
misery of all
mankind.
Wherefore,
he said
unto Eve,
yea, even
that old
serpent, who
is the
devil, who is
the father
of all
lies,
wherefore he
said: Partake
of the
forbidden
fruit, and
ye shall
not die, but
be as God, knowing good and evil.
19 And
after Adam
and Eve
had
partaken of the
forbidden fruit
they were
driven
out of the
garden of
Eden, to
till the earth.
20 And
they have
brought
forth
children;
yea,
even the
family of
all the earth.
21 And
the
days of
children of
men
were
prolonged,
according to
the will
of God,
that
they
might
repent
while in
the
flesh;
wherefore,
their
state
became a
state of
probation,
and their
time
was
lengthened,
according to
the
commandments
which the
Lord God
gave
unto the
children of
men. For
he
gave
commandment
that
all men
must
repent;
for he
showed
unto all
men
that they
were lost, because of the transgression of their parents.
22 And
now,
behold, if
Adam
had not
transgressed
he
would
not have
fallen, but
he
would
have
remained
in the
garden of
Eden.
And all
things
which were
created
must have
remained in
the
same
state in
which
they
were
after
they
were
created;
and
they must have remained forever, and had no end.
And
they
would
have
had no
children;
wherefore
they
would
have
remained
in a
state
of
innocence,
having no
joy,
for
they
knew
no
misery;
doing
no good, for they knew no sin.
But
behold,
all
things
have
been
done
in
the
wisdom
of
him who
knoweth
all
things.
Adam
fell
that
men
might
be; and
men
are,
that
they
might
have
joy.
And
the
Messiah
cometh in
the
fulness
of
time,
that
he
may
redeem
the
children of
men
from
the
fall.
And
because
that
they
are
redeemed
from
the
fall
they
have
become
free
forever,
knowing
good
from
evil;
to
act
for
themselves
and
not to
be
acted
upon,
save
it
be
by
the
punishment
of
the
law
at the great and last day, according to the commandments which God hath given.
Wherefore,
men
are
free
according
to
the
flesh;
and
all
things
are
given
them
which
are
expedient
unto
man.
And
they
are
free
to
choose
liberty
and
eternal
life,
through
the
great
Mediator
of
all
men,
or
to
choose
captivity
and
death,
according
to
the
captivity
and power of the devil; for he seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself.
And
now,
my
sons,
I
would
that
ye
should
look
to
the
great
Mediator,
and
hearken
unto
his
great
commandments;
and
be
faithful
unto
his
words, and choose eternal life, according to the will of his Holy Spirit;
29 And not choose eternal death, according to the will of the flesh and the evil which is therein, which giveth the spirit of the devil power to captivate, to bring you down to hell, that he may reign over you in his own
And
not
choose
eternal
death,
according
to
the
will
of
the
flesh
and
the
evil
which
is
therein,
which
giveth
the spirit of the devil power to captivate, to bring you down to hell, that he may reign over you in his own kingdom.
30 I have spoken these few words unto you all, my sons, in the last days of my probation; and I have chosen the good part, according to the words of the prophet. And I have none other object save it be the everlasting welfare of your souls. Amen.
I
have
spoken
these
few
words
unto
you
all,
my
sons,
in
the
last
days
of
my
probation;
and
I
have
chosen
the
good
part,
according
to
the
words
of
the
prophet.
And
I
have
none
other
object
save
it
be
the
everlasting
welfare
of
your
souls.
Amen.