The Words of MormonChapter 1 Mormon abridges
the large plates of Nephi—He puts the small
plates with the other plates—King Benjamin
establishes peace in the land. About A.D. 385.
1 And now I, Mormon, being about to
deliver up the record which I have been
making into the hands of my son
Moroni, behold I have witnessed almost all
the destruction of my people, the Nephites.
2 And it is many hundred years
after the coming of Christ that I
deliver these records into the hands of
my son; and it supposeth me that he
will witness the entire
destruction of my people. But may God grant
that he may survive them, that he
may write somewhat concerning them,
and somewhat concerning Christ, that
perhaps some day it may profit them.
3 And now, I speak somewhat
concerning that which I have
written; for after I had made an
abridgment from the plates of Nephi,
down to the reign of this king
Benjamin, of whom Amaleki spake, I
searched among the records
which had been delivered into my
hands, and I found these plates,
which contained this small account
of the prophets, from Jacob
down to the reign of this king
Benjamin, and also many of the words of Nephi.
4 And the things which are upon
these plates pleasing me,
because of the prophecies of the
coming of Christ; and my fathers
knowing that many of them have
been fulfilled; yea, and I also
know that as many things as
have been prophesied concerning
us down to this day have been
fulfilled, and as many as go
beyond this day must surely come to pass—
5 Wherefore, I chose these
things, to finish my record
upon them, which remainder of
my record I shall take from
the plates of Nephi; and I
cannot write the hundredth
part of the things of my people.
6 But behold, I shall take
these plates, which
contain these prophesyings and
revelations, and put them
with the remainder of my
record, for they are choice
unto me; and I know they
will be choice unto my brethren.
7 And I do this for a
wise purpose; for thus it
whispereth me, according
to the workings of the
Spirit of the Lord which
is in me. And now, I do
not know all things;
but the Lord knoweth all
things which are to come;
wherefore, he worketh
in me to do according to his will.
8 And my prayer to God
is concerning my
brethren, that they may once
again come to the
knowledge of God, yea, the
redemption of Christ;
that they may once again
be a delightsome people.
9 And now I, Mormon,
proceed to finish out
my record, which I take
from the plates of
Nephi; and I make it
according to the
knowledge and the
understanding which God has given me.
10 Wherefore, it
came to pass that after
Amaleki had
delivered up these plates
into the hands of
king Benjamin, he took
them and put them
with the other plates,
which contained
records which had been
handed down by the
kings, from
generation to generation
until the days of king Benjamin.
11 And they were
handed down from king
Benjamin, from
generation to
generation until they have
fallen into my
hands. And I, Mormon,
pray to God that
they may be preserved
from this time
henceforth. And I know
that they will be
preserved; for there
are great things
written upon them,
out of which my
people and their
brethren shall be judged
at the great and
last day, according
to the word of God which is written.
12 And now,
concerning this king
Benjamin—he had
somewhat of contentions
among his own people.
13 And it came to
pass also that
the armies of the
Lamanites came
down out of the
land of Nephi, to
battle against his
people. But
behold, king Benjamin
gathered together
his armies, and
he did stand
against them; and he
did fight with
the strength of his
own arm, with
the sword of Laban.
14 And in the
strength of the
Lord they did
contend against
their enemies, until
they had slain
many thousands
of the Lamanites.
And it came to
pass that they
did contend
against the Lamanites
until they had
driven them out
of all the lands
of their inheritance.
15 And it came
to pass that
after there had
been false
Christs, and their
mouths had been
shut, and they
punished
according to their crimes;
16 And after
there had been
false
prophets, and false
preachers and
teachers among
the people, and
all these
having been
punished according
to their
crimes; and after
there having
been much
contention and many
dissensions
away unto the
Lamanites,
behold, it came to
pass that king
Benjamin,
with the
assistance of the holy
prophets who were among his people—
17 For
behold, king
Benjamin was a holy
man, and he
did reign
over his people
in
righteousness; and
there were many
holy men in
the land, and
they did speak
the word of
God with
power and with
authority; and
they did use
much
sharpness because of
the
stiffneckedness of the people—
Wherefore, with the
help of
these, king
Benjamin, by
laboring with
all the might
of his body
and the
faculty of his
whole soul,
and also the
prophets,
did once more
establish
peace in the land.