Chapter 10 There is silence in the land
for many hours—The voice of Christ promises
to gather His people as a hen gathers her
chickens—The more righteous part of the
people have been preserved. About A.D. 34–35.
1 And now behold, it came to pass that
all the people of the land did hear
these sayings, and did witness of it. And
after these sayings there was silence
in the land for the space of many hours;
2 For so great was the astonishment
of the people that they did cease
lamenting and howling for the loss of
their kindred which had been slain;
therefore there was silence in all
the land for the space of many hours.
3 And it came to pass that there
came a voice again unto the
people, and all the people did
hear, and did witness of it, saying:
4 O ye people of these great
cities which have fallen, who are
descendants of Jacob, yea, who
are of the house of Israel,
how oft have I gathered you as a
hen gathereth her chickens
under her wings, and have nourished you.
5 And again, how oft would I
have gathered you as a hen
gathereth her chickens under her
wings, yea, O ye people of the
house of Israel, who have
fallen; yea, O ye people of the
house of Israel, ye that dwell
at Jerusalem, as ye that have
fallen; yea, how oft would I
have gathered you as a hen
gathereth her chickens, and ye would not.
6 O ye house of Israel
whom I have spared, how oft
will I gather you as a hen
gathereth her chickens
under her wings, if ye will
repent and return unto me
with full purpose of heart.
7 But if not, O house of
Israel, the places of
your dwellings shall
become desolate until the
time of the fulfilling of
the covenant to your fathers.
8 And now it came to
pass that after the
people had heard these
words, behold, they began to
weep and howl again
because of the loss of
their kindred and friends.
9 And it came to pass
that thus did the
three days pass away. And
it was in the morning,
and the darkness
dispersed from off the
face of the land, and the
earth did cease to
tremble, and the rocks
did cease to rend, and
the dreadful groanings
did cease, and all
the tumultuous noises did pass away.
10 And the earth did
cleave together
again, that it stood; and
the mourning, and the
weeping, and the
wailing of the people
who were spared alive
did cease; and their
mourning was turned
into joy, and their
lamentations into the
praise and thanksgiving
unto the Lord Jesus
Christ, their Redeemer.
11 And thus far were
the scriptures
fulfilled which had been
spoken by the prophets.
12 And it was the
more righteous part of
the people who were
saved, and it was
they who received the
prophets and stoned
them not; and it
was they who had not
shed the blood of the
saints, who were spared—
13 And they were
spared and were not
sunk and buried up
in the earth; and
they were not drowned
in the depths of
the sea; and they
were not burned by
fire, neither were
they fallen upon and
crushed to death;
and they were not
carried away in the
whirlwind; neither
were they
overpowered by the vapor of
smoke and of darkness.
14 And now, whoso
readeth, let him
understand; he that
hath the
scriptures, let him search
them, and see and
behold if all
these deaths and
destructions by fire,
and by smoke, and
by tempests, and
by whirlwinds, and
by the opening of
the earth to
receive them, and all
these things are
not unto the
fulfilling of the
prophecies of many of the holy prophets.
15 Behold, I say
unto you, Yea,
many have
testified of these
things at the
coming of Christ, and
were slain
because they
testified of these things.
16 Yea, the
prophet Zenos did
testify of
these things, and
also Zenock
spake concerning
these things,
because they
testified
particularly concerning
us, who are the
remnant of their seed.
17 Behold, our
father Jacob
also testified
concerning a
remnant of the
seed of
Joseph. And behold,
are not we a
remnant of the
seed of
Joseph? And these
things which
testify of us,
are they not
written upon the
plates of
brass which our
father Lehi
brought out of Jerusalem?
18 And it
came to pass
that in the
ending of the
thirty and
fourth year,
behold, I will
show unto you
that the people
of Nephi who
were spared,
and also
those who had
been called
Lamanites, who
had been
spared, did have
great favors
shown unto
them, and great
blessings
poured out upon
their heads,
insomuch that
soon after
the ascension
of Christ
into heaven he
did truly manifest himself unto them—
19 Showing
his body unto
them, and
ministering
unto them;
and an account
of his
ministry shall
be given
hereafter.
Therefore for
this time I
make an end of my sayings.