Chapter 22 In the last days, Zion and her stakes
will be established, and Israel will be gathered in
mercy and tenderness—They will triumph—Compare
Isaiah 54. About A.D. 34.
1 And then shall that which is written come to
pass: Sing, O barren, thou that didst not bear; break
forth into singing, and cry aloud, thou that
didst not travail with child; for more are the
children of the desolate than the children of the married
wife, saith the Lord
2 Enlarge the place of thy tent, and let them
stretch forth the curtains of thy habitations; spare
not, lengthen thy cords and strengthen thy stakes
3 For thou shalt break forth on the right hand and
on the left, and thy seed shall inherit the
Gentiles and make the desolate cities to be inhabited
4 Fear not, for thou shalt not be ashamed; neither
be thou confounded, for thou shalt not be put to
shame; for thou shalt forget the shame of thy
youth, and shalt not remember the reproach of thy
widowhood any more
5 For thy maker, thy husband, the Lord of Hosts is
his name; and thy Redeemer, the Holy One of
Israel—the God of the whole earth shall he be called
6 For the Lord hath called thee as a woman
forsaken and grieved in spirit, and a wife of youth, when
thou wast refused, saith thy God
7 For a small moment have I forsaken thee, but
with great mercies will I gather thee
8 In a little wrath I hid my face from thee for a
moment, but with everlasting kindness will I have
mercy on thee, saith the Lord thy Redeemer
9 For this, the waters of Noah unto me, for as I
have sworn that the waters of Noah should no more
go over the earth, so have I sworn that I would not
be wroth with thee
10 For the mountains shall depart and the hills be
removed, but my kindness shall not depart from
thee, neither shall the covenant of my peace be
removed, saith the Lord that hath mercy on thee
11 O thou afflicted, tossed with tempest, and not
comforted! Behold, I will lay thy stones with fair
colors, and lay thy foundations with sapphires
12 And I will make thy windows of agates, and thy
gates of carbuncles, and all thy borders of
pleasant stones
13 And all thy children shall be taught of the
Lord; and great shall be the peace of thy children
14 In righteousness shalt thou be established;
thou shalt be far from oppression for thou shalt not
fear, and from terror for it shall not come near
thee
15 Behold, they shall surely gather together
against thee, not by me; whosoever shall gather
together against thee shall fall for thy sake
16 Behold, I have created the smith that bloweth
the coals in the fire, and that bringeth forth an
instrument for his work; and I have created the
waster to destroy
17 No weapon that is formed against thee shall
prosper; and every tongue that shall revile against
thee in judgment thou shalt condemn. This is the
heritage of the servants of the Lord, and their
righteousness is of me, saith the Lord.