Chapter 24 The Lord’s messenger will
prepare the way for the Second Coming—Christ will
sit in judgment—Israel is commanded to pay
tithes and offerings—A book of remembrance
is kept—Compare
Malachi 3. About A.D. 34.
1 And it came to pass that he commanded
them that they should write the words which
the Father had given unto Malachi, which
he should tell unto them. And it came to
pass that after they were written he
expounded them. And these are the words which he
did tell unto them, saying: Thus said the
Father unto Malachi—Behold, I will send my
messenger, and he shall prepare the way
before me, and the Lord whom ye seek shall
suddenly come to his temple, even the
messenger of the covenant, whom ye delight in;
behold, he shall come, saith the Lord of Hosts.
2 But who may abide the day of his
coming, and who shall stand when
he appeareth? For he is like a
refiner’s fire, and like fuller’s soap.
3 And he shall sit as a refiner
and purifier of silver; and he
shall purify the sons of Levi,
and purge them as gold and silver,
that they may offer unto the
Lord an offering in righteousness.
4 Then shall the offering of
Judah and Jerusalem be pleasant
unto the Lord, as in the days
of old, and as in former years.
5 And I will come near to
you to judgment; and I will be
a swift witness against the
sorcerers, and against the
adulterers, and against
false swearers, and against
those that oppress the hireling
in his wages, the widow and
the fatherless, and that
turn aside the stranger, and
fear not me, saith the Lord of Hosts.
6 For I am the Lord, I
change not; therefore ye sons
of Jacob are not consumed.
7 Even from the days of
your fathers ye are gone
away from mine ordinances,
and have not kept them.
Return unto me and I will
return unto you, saith
the Lord of Hosts. But ye
say: Wherein shall we return?
8 Will a man rob God?
Yet ye have robbed me.
But ye say: Wherein
have we robbed thee? In
tithes and offerings.
9 Ye are cursed
with a curse, for ye
have robbed me, even
this whole nation.
10 Bring ye all
the tithes into the
storehouse, that
there may be meat
in my house; and
prove me now
herewith, saith the Lord
of Hosts, if I
will not open you the
windows of
heaven, and pour you out
a blessing that
there shall not be
room enough to receive it.
11 And I will
rebuke the devourer
for your sakes,
and he shall not
destroy the fruits
of your ground;
neither shall
your vine cast her
fruit before the
time in the
fields, saith the Lord of Hosts.
12 And all
nations shall
call you blessed,
for ye shall
be a
delightsome land, saith
the Lord of Hosts.
13 Your
words have been
stout
against me, saith
the Lord.
Yet ye say:
What have we
spoken against thee?
14 Ye have
said: It is
vain to
serve God,
and what doth
it profit
that we
have kept his
ordinances
and that we
have
walked
mournfully before
the Lord of Hosts?
15 And now
we call
the proud
happy; yea,
they that
work
wickedness are
set up;
yea, they
that tempt
God are
even delivered.
16 Then
they that
feared
the Lord
spake often
one to
another,
and the
Lord
hearkened and
heard; and
a book
of
remembrance was
written
before him
for them
that
feared the
Lord, and
that thought upon his name.
17 And
they
shall be
mine, saith
the
Lord of
Hosts, in
that day
when I
make up
my
jewels; and I
will
spare them
as a man
spareth
his own
son that serveth him.
18 Then
shall
ye
return and
discern
between the
righteous and
the
wicked,
between
him that
serveth
God
and him
that serveth him not.