Chapter 25 At the Second Coming, the proud
and wicked will be burned as
stubble—Elijah will return before that great and
dreadful day—Compare
Malachi 4. About A.D. 34.
1 For behold, the day cometh that shall
burn as an oven; and all the proud, yea,
and all that do wickedly, shall be
stubble; and the day that cometh shall burn
them up, saith the Lord of Hosts, that
it shall leave them neither root nor branch.
2 But unto you that fear my name,
shall the Son of Righteousness arise with
healing in his wings; and ye shall go
forth and grow up as calves in the stall.
3 And ye shall tread down the wicked;
for they shall be ashes under the
soles of your feet in the day that I
shall do this, saith the Lord of Hosts.
4 Remember ye the law of Moses,
my servant, which I commanded
unto him in Horeb for all Israel,
with the statutes and judgments.
5 Behold, I will send you
Elijah the prophet before
the coming of the great
and dreadful day of the Lord;
6 And he shall turn the
heart of the fathers to the
children, and the heart of
the children to their
fathers, lest I come and
smite the earth with a curse.