Chapter 19 The twelve disciples minister unto the
people and pray for the Holy Ghost—The disciples
are baptized and receive the Holy Ghost and the
ministering of angels—Jesus prays using words that
cannot be written—He attests to the exceedingly
great faith of these Nephites. About A.D. 34.
1 And now it came to pass that when Jesus had
ascended into heaven, the multitude did disperse, and
every man did take his wife and his children and
did return to his own home
2 And it was noised abroad among the people
immediately, before it was yet dark, that the multitude
had seen Jesus, and that he had ministered unto
them, and that he would also show himself on the
morrow unto the multitude
3 Yea, and even all the night it was noised abroad
concerning Jesus; and insomuch did they send
forth unto the people that there were many, yea, an
exceedingly great number, did labor exceedingly all
that night, that they might be on the morrow in
the place where Jesus should show himself unto the
multitude
4 And it came to pass that on the morrow, when the
multitude was gathered together, behold, Nephi
and his brother whom he had raised from the dead,
whose name was Timothy, and also his son, whose name
was Jonas, and also Mathoni, and Mathonihah, his
brother, and Kumen, and Kumenonhi, and Jeremiah,
and Shemnon, and Jonas, and Zedekiah, and
Isaiah—now these were the names of the disciples whom Jesus
had chosen—and it came to pass that they went
forth and stood in the midst of the multitude
5 And behold, the multitude was so great that they
did cause that they should be separated into
twelve bodies
6 And the twelve did teach the multitude; and
behold, they did cause that the multitude should kneel
down upon the face of the earth, and should pray
unto the Father in the name of Jesus
7 And the disciples did pray unto the Father also
in the name of Jesus. And it came to pass that
they arose and ministered unto the people
8 And when they had ministered those same words
which Jesus had spoken—nothing varying from the
words which Jesus had spoken—behold, they knelt again
and prayed to the Father in the name of Jesus
9 And they did pray for that which they most
desired; and they desired that the Holy Ghost should be
given unto them
10 And when they had thus prayed they went down
unto the water’s edge, and the multitude followed
them
11 And it came to pass that Nephi went down into
the water and was baptized
12 And he came up out of the water and began to
baptize. And he baptized all those whom Jesus had
chosen
13 And it came to pass when they were all baptized
and had come up out of the water, the Holy Ghost
did fall upon them, and they were filled with the
Holy Ghost and with fire
14 And behold, they were encircled about as if it
were by fire; and it came down from heaven, and
the multitude did witness it, and did bear record;
and angels did come down out of heaven and did
minister unto them
15 And it came to pass that while the angels were
ministering unto the disciples, behold, Jesus came
and stood in the midst and ministered unto them
16 And it came to pass that he spake unto the
multitude, and commanded them that they should kneel
down again upon the earth, and also that his
disciples should kneel down upon the earth
17 And it came to pass that when they had all
knelt down upon the earth, he commanded his disciples
that they should pray
18 And behold, they began to pray; and they did
pray unto Jesus, calling him their Lord and their
God
19 And it came to pass that Jesus departed out of
the midst of them, and went a little way off from
them and bowed himself to the earth, and he said
20 Father, I thank thee that thou hast given the
Holy Ghost unto these whom I have chosen; and it is
because of their belief in me that I have chosen
them out of the world
21 Father, I pray thee that thou wilt give the
Holy Ghost unto all them that shall believe in their
words
22 Father, thou hast given them the Holy Ghost
because they believe in me; and thou seest that they
believe in me because thou hearest them, and they
pray unto me; and they pray unto me because I am
with them
23 And now Father, I pray unto thee for them, and
also for all those who shall believe on their
words, that they may believe in me, that I may be in
them as thou, Father, art in me, that we may be
one
24 And it came to pass that when Jesus had thus
prayed unto the Father, he came unto his disciples,
and behold, they did still continue, without
ceasing, to pray unto him; and they did not multiply
many words, for it was given unto them what they
should pray, and they were filled with desire
25 And it came to pass that Jesus blessed them as
they did pray unto him; and his countenance did
smile upon them, and the light of his countenance
did shine upon them, and behold they were as white
as the countenance and also the garments of Jesus;
and behold the whiteness thereof did exceed all
the whiteness, yea, even there could be nothing upon
earth so white as the whiteness thereof
26 And Jesus said unto them: Pray on; nevertheless
they did not cease to pray
27 And he turned from them again, and went a
little way off and bowed himself to the earth; and he
prayed again unto the Father, saying
28 Father, I thank thee that thou hast purified
those whom I have chosen, because of their faith,
and I pray for them, and also for them who shall
believe on their words, that they may be purified in
me, through faith on their words, even as they are
purified in me
29 Father, I pray not for the world, but for those
whom thou hast given me out of the world, because
of their faith, that they may be purified in me,
that I may be in them as thou, Father, art in me,
that we may be one, that I may be glorified in
them
30 And when Jesus had spoken these words he came
again unto his disciples; and behold they did pray
steadfastly, without ceasing, unto him; and he did
smile upon them again; and behold they were
white, even as Jesus
31 And it came to pass that he went again a little
way off and prayed unto the Father
32 And tongue cannot speak the words which he
prayed, neither can be written by man the words which
he prayed
33 And the multitude did hear and do bear record;
and their hearts were open and they did understand
in their hearts the words which he prayed
34 Nevertheless, so great and marvelous were the
words which he prayed that they cannot be written,
neither can they be uttered by man
35 And it came to pass that when Jesus had made an
end of praying he came again to the disciples,
and said unto them: So great faith have I never seen
among all the Jews; wherefore I could not show
unto them so great miracles, because of their
unbelief
36 Verily I say unto you, there are none of them
that have seen so great things as ye have seen;
neither have they heard so great things as ye have
heard.