Third NephiThe Book of Nephi the Son of Nephi,
Who Was the Son of HelamanAnd Helaman was the son
of Helaman, who was the son of Alma, who was
the son of Alma, being a descendant of Nephi who
was the son of Lehi, who came out of Jerusalem in
the first year of the reign of Zedekiah, the
king of Judah.Chapter 1 Nephi, the son of Helaman,
departs out of the land, and his son Nephi
keeps the records—Though signs and wonders abound,
the wicked plan to slay the righteous—The night
of Christ’s birth arrives—The sign is given, and
a new star arises—Lyings and deceivings
increase, and the Gadianton robbers slaughter many. About A.D. 1–4.
1 Now it came to pass that the ninety and
first year had passed away and it was six
hundred years from the time that Lehi left
Jerusalem; and it was in the year that Lachoneus was
the chief judge and the governor over the land.
2 And Nephi, the son of Helaman, had
departed out of the land of Zarahemla, giving
charge unto his son Nephi, who was his
eldest son, concerning the plates of brass,
and all the records which had been kept, and
all those things which had been kept
sacred from the departure of Lehi out of Jerusalem.
3 Then he departed out of the land, and
whither he went, no man knoweth; and
his son Nephi did keep the records in
his stead, yea, the record of this people.
4 And it came to pass that in the
commencement of the ninety and second
year, behold, the prophecies of the
prophets began to be fulfilled more fully;
for there began to be greater signs and
greater miracles wrought among the people.
5 But there were some who began
to say that the time was past for
the words to be fulfilled, which
were spoken by Samuel, the Lamanite.
6 And they began to rejoice over
their brethren, saying: Behold
the time is past, and the words
of Samuel are not fulfilled;
therefore, your joy and your faith
concerning this thing hath been vain.
7 And it came to pass that
they did make a great uproar
throughout the land; and the
people who believed began to be
very sorrowful, lest by any
means those things which had
been spoken might not come to pass.
8 But behold, they did
watch steadfastly for that day
and that night and that day
which should be as one day
as if there were no night,
that they might know that
their faith had not been vain.
9 Now it came to pass
that there was a day set
apart by the unbelievers,
that all those who
believed in those traditions
should be put to death
except the sign should
come to pass, which had
been given by Samuel the prophet.
10 Now it came to
pass that when Nephi,
the son of Nephi, saw
this wickedness of his
people, his heart
was exceedingly sorrowful.
11 And it came to
pass that he went
out and bowed himself
down upon the
earth, and cried
mightily to his God in
behalf of his people,
yea, those who
were about to be
destroyed because of
their faith in the
tradition of their fathers.
12 And it came to
pass that he cried
mightily unto the
Lord all that
day; and behold, the
voice of the Lord
came unto him, saying:
13 Lift up your
head and be of
good cheer; for
behold, the time is
at hand, and on
this night shall
the sign be given,
and on the morrow
come I into the
world, to show
unto the world that
I will fulfil
all that which I
have caused to be
spoken by the
mouth of my holy prophets.
14 Behold, I
come unto my own,
to fulfil all
things which I have
made known unto
the children of
men from the
foundation of the
world, and to do
the will, both
of the Father
and of the Son—of
the Father
because of me, and of
the Son because
of my flesh.
And behold, the
time is at hand,
and this night
shall the sign be given.
15 And it came
to pass that
the words which
came unto Nephi
were fulfilled,
according as
they had been
spoken; for
behold, at the going
down of the
sun there was no
darkness; and
the people began
to be
astonished because
there was no
darkness when the night came.
16 And there
were many, who
had not
believed the words
of the
prophets, who fell to
the earth and
became as if
they were dead,
for they knew
that the
great plan of
destruction which
they had laid
for those who
believed in
the words of the
prophets had
been
frustrated; for the
sign which had
been given was already at hand.
17 And they
began to know
that the Son
of God must
shortly
appear; yea, in
fine, all the
people upon the
face of the
whole earth
from the west
to the east,
both in the
land north and
in the land
south, were
so exceedingly
astonished
that they fell to the earth.
18 For they
knew that
the prophets
had testified
of these
things for
many years, and
that the
sign which had
been given
was already
at hand; and
they began
to fear
because of their
iniquity
and their unbelief.
19 And it
came to pass
that there
was no
darkness in
all that
night, but it
was as light
as though
it was
mid-day. And it
came to
pass that the
sun did
rise in the
morning
again,
according to its
proper order;
and they
knew that it
was the
day that the
Lord should
be born,
because of
the sign which had been given.
20 And it
had come
to pass,
yea, all
things, every
whit,
according to
the words
of the prophets.
21 And it
came to
pass also
that a
new star
did
appear,
according to the word.
22 And
it came
to pass
that from
this
time forth
there
began to
be
lyings sent
forth
among the
people,
by Satan,
to
harden their
hearts,
to the
intent
that they
might
not
believe in
those
signs and
wonders
which they
had
seen; but
notwithstanding
these
lyings and
deceivings the
more part
of the
people
did believe, and were converted unto the Lord.
23 And
it came
to
pass that
Nephi
went
forth
among the
people,
and
also many
others,
baptizing
unto
repentance,
in the
which
there
was a
great
remission
of sins.
And
thus the
people
began
again to have peace in the land.
24 And
there
were
no
contentions,
save it
were a
few
that
began to
preach,
endeavoring to
prove
by the
scriptures
that
it was
no
more
expedient
to
observe
the law
of
Moses.
Now in
this
thing
they
did err,
having not understood the scriptures.
But it
came
to
pass
that
they
soon
became
converted,
and
were
convinced
of
the
error
which
they
were
in,
for it
was
made
known
unto
them
that
the
law
was not
yet
fulfilled,
and
that
it
must be
fulfilled
in
every
whit;
yea,
the
word
came
unto
them
that
it
must be
fulfilled;
yea,
that one
jot
or
tittle
should not
pass
away
till
it
should
all
be
fulfilled;
therefore
in
this
same
year were they brought to a knowledge of their error and did confess their faults.
And
thus
the
ninety
and
second
year
did
pass
away,
bringing
glad
tidings
unto
the
people
because
of
the
signs
which
did
come
to
pass,
according
to
the
words
of the prophecy of all the holy prophets.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
the
ninety
and
third
year
did
also
pass
away
in
peace,
save
it
were
for
the
Gadianton
robbers,
who
dwelt
upon
the
mountains,
who
did
infest
the
land;
for
so
strong
were
their
holds
and
their
secret
places
that
the
people
could
not
overpower them; therefore they did commit many murders, and did do much slaughter among the people.
And
it
came
to
pass
that
in
the
ninety
and
fourth
year
they
began
to
increase
in
a
great
degree,
because
there
were
many
dissenters
of
the
Nephites
who
did
flee
unto them, which did cause much sorrow unto those Nephites who did remain in the land.
And
there
was
also
a
cause
of
much
sorrow
among
the
Lamanites;
for
behold,
they
had
many
children
who
did
grow
up
and
began
to
wax
strong
in
years,
that
they
became
for
themselves,
and
were
led
away
by
some
who
were
Zoramites,
by
their
lyings
and
their
flattering
words,
to
join
those
Gadianton
robbers.
And
thus
were
the
Lamanites
afflicted
also,
and
began
to
decrease
as
to
their
faith
and
righteousness,
because
of
the
wickedness
of
the
rising
generation.