Chapter 9 In the darkness, the voice of Christ
proclaims the destruction of many people and cities
for their wickedness—He also proclaims His
divinity, announces that the law of Moses is fulfilled,
and invites men to come unto Him and be saved. About
A.D. 34.
1 And it came to pass that there was a voice heard
among all the inhabitants of the earth, upon all
the face of this land, crying
2 Wo, wo, wo unto this people; wo unto the
inhabitants of the whole earth except they shall repent;
for the devil laugheth, and his angels rejoice,
because of the slain of the fair sons and daughters
of my people; and it is because of their iniquity
and abominations that they are fallen
3 Behold, that great city Zarahemla have I burned
with fire, and the inhabitants thereof
4 And behold, that great city Moroni have I caused
to be sunk in the depths of the sea, and the
inhabitants thereof to be drowned
5 And behold, that great city Moronihah have I
covered with earth, and the inhabitants thereof, to
hide their iniquities and their abominations from
before my face, that the blood of the prophets and
the saints shall not come any more unto me against
them
6 And behold, the city of Gilgal have I caused to
be sunk, and the inhabitants thereof to be buried
up in the depths of the earth
7 Yea, and the city of Onihah and the inhabitants
thereof, and the city of Mocum and the inhabitants
thereof, and the city of Jerusalem and the
inhabitants thereof; and waters have I caused to come up
in the stead thereof, to hide their wickedness
and abominations from before my face, that the blood
of the prophets and the saints shall not come up
any more unto me against them
8 And behold, the city of Gadiandi, and the city
of Gadiomnah, and the city of Jacob, and the city
of Gimgimno, all these have I caused to be sunk,
and made hills and valleys in the places thereof;
and the inhabitants thereof have I buried up in the
depths of the earth, to hide their wickedness and
abominations from before my face, that the blood
of the prophets and the saints should not come up
any more unto me against them
9 And behold, that great city Jacobugath, which
was inhabited by the people of king Jacob, have I
caused to be burned with fire because of their sins
and their wickedness, which was above all the
wickedness of the whole earth, because of their secret
murders and combinations; for it was they that
did destroy the peace of my people and the
government of the land; therefore I did cause them to be
burned, to destroy them from before my face, that
the blood of the prophets and the saints should not
come up unto me any more against them
10 And behold, the city of Laman, and the city of
Josh, and the city of Gad, and the city of
Kishkumen, have I caused to be burned with fire, and the
inhabitants thereof, because of their wickedness
in casting out the prophets, and stoning those whom
I did send to declare unto them concerning their
wickedness and their abominations
11 And because they did cast them all out, that
there were none righteous among them, I did send
down fire and destroy them, that their wickedness and
abominations might be hid from before my face,
that the blood of the prophets and the saints whom I
sent among them might not cry unto me from the
ground against them
12 And many great destructions have I caused to
come upon this land, and upon this people, because
of their wickedness and their abominations
13 O all ye that are spared because ye were more
righteous than they, will ye not now return unto
me, and repent of your sins, and be converted, that
I may heal you
14 Yea, verily I say unto you, if ye will come
unto me ye shall have eternal life. Behold, mine arm
of mercy is extended towards you, and whosoever
will come, him will I receive; and blessed are those
who come unto me
15 Behold, I am Jesus Christ the Son of God. I
created the heavens and the earth, and all things
that in them are. I was with the Father from the
beginning. I am in the Father, and the Father in me;
and in me hath the Father glorified his name
16 I came unto my own, and my own received me not.
And the scriptures concerning my coming are
fulfilled
17 And as many as have received me, to them have I
given to become the sons of God; and even so will
I to as many as shall believe on my name, for
behold, by me redemption cometh, and in me is the law
of Moses fulfilled
18 I am the light and the life of the world. I am
Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end
19 And ye shall offer up unto me no more the
shedding of blood; yea, your sacrifices and your burnt
offerings shall be done away, for I will accept
none of your sacrifices and your burnt offerings
20 And ye shall offer for a sacrifice unto me a
broken heart and a contrite spirit. And whoso cometh
unto me with a broken heart and a contrite
spirit, him will I baptize with fire and with the Holy
Ghost, even as the Lamanites, because of their
faith in me at the time of their conversion, were
baptized with fire and with the Holy Ghost, and they
knew it not
21 Behold, I have come unto the world to bring
redemption unto the world, to save the world from
sin
22 Therefore, whoso repenteth and cometh unto me
as a little child, him will I receive, for of such
is the kingdom of God. Behold, for such I have
laid down my life, and have taken it up again;
therefore repent, and come unto me ye ends of the earth,
and be saved.