Chapter 29 The coming forth of the Book of Mormon
is a sign that the Lord has commenced to gather
Israel and fulfill His covenants—Those who reject
His latter-day revelations and gifts will be cursed.
About A.D. 34–35.
1 And now behold, I say unto you that when the
Lord shall see fit, in his wisdom, that these sayings
shall come unto the Gentiles according to his
word, then ye may know that the covenant which the
Father hath made with the children of Israel,
concerning their restoration to the lands of their
inheritance, is already beginning to be fulfilled
2 And ye may know that the words of the Lord,
which have been spoken by the holy prophets, shall all
be fulfilled; and ye need not say that the Lord
delays his coming unto the children of Israel
3 And ye need not imagine in your hearts that the
words which have been spoken are vain, for behold,
the Lord will remember his covenant which he hath
made unto his people of the house of Israel
4 And when ye shall see these sayings coming forth
among you, then ye need not any longer spurn at
the doings of the Lord, for the sword of his
justice is in his right hand; and behold, at that day,
if ye shall spurn at his doings he will cause that
it shall soon overtake you
5 Wo unto him that spurneth at the doings of the
Lord; yea, wo unto him that shall deny the Christ
and his works
6 Yea, wo unto him that shall deny the revelations
of the Lord, and that shall say the Lord no
longer worketh by revelation, or by prophecy, or by
gifts, or by tongues, or by healings, or by the power
of the Holy Ghost
7 Yea, and wo unto him that shall say at that day,
to get gain, that there can be no miracle wrought
by Jesus Christ; for he that doeth this shall
become like unto the son of perdition, for whom there
was no mercy, according to the word of Christ
8 Yea, and ye need not any longer hiss, nor spurn,
nor make game of the Jews, nor any of the remnant
of the house of Israel; for behold, the Lord
remembereth his covenant unto them, and he will do
unto them according to that which he hath sworn
9 Therefore ye need not suppose that ye can turn
the right hand of the Lord unto the left, that he
may not execute judgment unto the fulfilling of the
covenant which he hath made unto the house of
Israel.