Chapter 30 The latter-day Gentiles are commanded
to repent, come unto Christ, and be numbered with
the house of Israel. About A.D. 34–35.
1 Hearken, O ye Gentiles, and hear the words of
Jesus Christ, the Son of the living God, which he
hath commanded me that I should speak concerning
you, for, behold he commandeth me that I should
write, saying
2 Turn, all ye Gentiles, from your wicked ways;
and repent of your evil doings, of your lyings and
deceivings, and of your whoredoms, and of your
secret abominations, and your idolatries, and of your
murders, and your priestcrafts, and your envyings,
and your strifes, and from all your wickedness
and abominations, and come unto me, and be baptized
in my name, that ye may receive a remission of
your sins, and be filled with the Holy Ghost, that ye
may be numbered with my people who are of the
house of Israel.