Chapter 6 The Nephites prosper—Pride, wealth, and
class distinctions arise—The Church is rent with
dissensions—Satan leads the people in open
rebellion—Many prophets cry repentance and are slain—Their
murderers conspire to take over the government.
About A.D. 26–30.
1 And now it came to pass that the people of the
Nephites did all return to their own lands in the
twenty and sixth year, every man, with his family,
his flocks and his herds, his horses and his
cattle, and all things whatsoever did belong unto them
2 And it came to pass that they had not eaten up
all their provisions; therefore they did take with
them all that they had not devoured, of all their
grain of every kind, and their gold, and their
silver, and all their precious things, and they did
return to their own lands and their possessions,
both on the north and on the south, both on the land
northward and on the land southward
3 And they granted unto those robbers who had
entered into a covenant to keep the peace of the land,
who were desirous to remain Lamanites, lands,
according to their numbers, that they might have,
with their labors, wherewith to subsist upon; and
thus they did establish peace in all the land
4 And they began again to prosper and to wax
great; and the twenty and sixth and seventh years
passed away, and there was great order in the land; and
they had formed their laws according to equity
and justice
5 And now there was nothing in all the land to
hinder the people from prospering continually, except
they should fall into transgression
6 And now it was Gidgiddoni, and the judge,
Lachoneus, and those who had been appointed leaders, who
had established this great peace in the land
7 And it came to pass that there were many cities
built anew, and there were many old cities
repaired
8 And there were many highways cast up, and many
roads made, which led from city to city, and from
land to land, and from place to place
9 And thus passed away the twenty and eighth year,
and the people had continual peace
10 But it came to pass in the twenty and ninth
year there began to be some disputings among the
people; and some were lifted up unto pride and
boastings because of their exceedingly great riches, yea,
even unto great persecutions
11 For there were many merchants in the land, and
also many lawyers, and many officers
12 And the people began to be distinguished by
ranks, according to their riches and their chances
for learning; yea, some were ignorant because of
their poverty, and others did receive great learning
because of their riches
13 Some were lifted up in pride, and others were
exceedingly humble; some did return railing for
railing, while others would receive railing and
persecution and all manner of afflictions, and would
not turn and revile again, but were humble and
penitent before God
14 And thus there became a great inequality in all
the land, insomuch that the church began to be
broken up; yea, insomuch that in the thirtieth year
the church was broken up in all the land save it
were among a few of the Lamanites who were
converted unto the true faith; and they would not depart
from it, for they were firm, and steadfast, and
immovable, willing with all diligence to keep the
commandments of the Lord
15 Now the cause of this iniquity of the people
was this—Satan had great power, unto the stirring up
of the people to do all manner of iniquity, and
to the puffing them up with pride, tempting them to
seek for power, and authority, and riches, and
the vain things of the world
16 And thus Satan did lead away the hearts of the
people to do all manner of iniquity; therefore
they had enjoyed peace but a few years
17 And thus, in the commencement of the thirtieth
year—the people having been delivered up for the
space of a long time to be carried about by the
temptations of the devil whithersoever he desired to
carry them, and to do whatsoever iniquity he
desired they should—and thus in the commencement of
this, the thirtieth year, they were in a state of
awful wickedness
18 Now they did not sin ignorantly, for they knew
the will of God concerning them, for it had been
taught unto them; therefore they did wilfully rebel
against God
19 And now it was in the days of Lachoneus, the
son of Lachoneus, for Lachoneus did fill the seat of
his father and did govern the people that year
20 And there began to be men inspired from heaven
and sent forth, standing among the people in all
the land, preaching and testifying boldly of the
sins and iniquities of the people, and testifying
unto them concerning the redemption which the Lord
would make for his people, or in other words, the
resurrection of Christ; and they did testify boldly
of his death and sufferings
21 Now there were many of the people who were
exceedingly angry because of those who testified of
these things; and those who were angry were chiefly
the chief judges, and they who had been high
priests and lawyers; yea, all those who were lawyers
were angry with those who testified of these things
22 Now there was no lawyer nor judge nor high
priest that could have power to condemn any one to
death save their condemnation was signed by the
governor of the land
23 Now there were many of those who testified of
the things pertaining to Christ who testified
boldly, who were taken and put to death secretly by the
judges, that the knowledge of their death came
not unto the governor of the land until after their
death
24 Now behold, this was contrary to the laws of
the land, that any man should be put to death except
they had power from the governor of the land
25 Therefore a complaint came up unto the land of
Zarahemla, to the governor of the land, against
these judges who had condemned the prophets of the
Lord unto death, not according to the law
26 Now it came to pass that they were taken and
brought up before the judge, to be judged of the
crime which they had done, according to the law which
had been given by the people
27 Now it came to pass that those judges had many
friends and kindreds; and the remainder, yea, even
almost all the lawyers and the high priests, did
gather themselves together, and unite with the
kindreds of those judges who were to be tried
according to the law
28 And they did enter into a covenant one with
another, yea, even into that covenant which was given
by them of old, which covenant was given and
administered by the devil, to combine against all
righteousness
29 Therefore they did combine against the people
of the Lord, and enter into a covenant to destroy
them, and to deliver those who were guilty of
murder from the grasp of justice, which was about to be
administered according to the law
30 And they did set at defiance the law and the
rights of their country; and they did covenant one
with another to destroy the governor, and to
establish a king over the land, that the land should no
more be at liberty but should be subject unto
kings.