Chapter 5 The Nephites repent and forsake
their sins—Mormon writes the history of
his people and declares the everlasting
word to them—Israel will be gathered in
from her long dispersion. About A.D. 22–26.
1 And now behold, there was not a
living soul among all the people of the
Nephites who did doubt in the least
the words of all the holy prophets who
had spoken; for they knew that it
must needs be that they must be fulfilled.
2 And they knew that it must be
expedient that Christ had come,
because of the many signs which had been
given, according to the words of
the prophets; and because of the
things which had come to pass already
they knew that it must needs be that
all things should come to pass
according to that which had been spoken.
3 Therefore they did forsake
all their sins, and their
abominations, and their
whoredoms, and did serve God with
all diligence day and night.
4 And now it came to pass
that when they had taken
all the robbers prisoners,
insomuch that none did
escape who were not slain,
they did cast their
prisoners into prison, and did
cause the word of God to be
preached unto them; and as
many as would repent of
their sins and enter into a
covenant that they would
murder no more were set at liberty.
5 But as many as there
were who did not enter
into a covenant, and
who did still continue to
have those secret
murders in their hearts,
yea, as many as were
found breathing out
threatenings against their
brethren were condemned
and punished according to the law.
6 And thus they did
put an end to all
those wicked, and
secret, and abominable
combinations, in the
which there was so
much wickedness, and
so many murders committed.
7 And thus had the
twenty and second
year passed away,
and the twenty and
third year also, and
the twenty and
fourth, and the twenty
and fifth; and thus
had twenty and
five years passed away.
8 And there had
many things
transpired which, in the
eyes of some, would
be great and
marvelous;
nevertheless, they cannot all
be written in
this book; yea, this
book cannot
contain even a hundredth
part of what was
done among so many
people in the
space of twenty and five years;
9 But behold
there are records
which do contain
all the
proceedings of this
people; and a
shorter but true
account was given by Nephi.
10 Therefore I
have made my
record of these
things according
to the record
of Nephi, which
was engraven
on the plates
which were called
the plates of Nephi.
11 And behold,
I do make the
record on
plates which I
have made with
mine own hands.
12 And
behold, I am called
Mormon,
being called
after the land of
Mormon, the
land in which
Alma did
establish the
church among
the people,
yea, the first
church which
was
established among them
after their transgression.
13 Behold, I
am a
disciple of Jesus
Christ, the
Son of God.
I have been
called of
him to declare
his word
among his
people, that
they might have
everlasting life.
14 And it
hath become
expedient
that I,
according to
the will of
God, that
the prayers
of those who
have gone
hence, who
were the
holy ones,
should be
fulfilled
according to
their faith,
should make
a record
of these
things which have been done—
15 Yea, a
small
record of that
which
hath taken
place from
the time
that Lehi
left
Jerusalem, even
down until
the present time.
Therefore I do
make my
record
from the
accounts
which have
been given
by those
who were
before
me, until
the
commencement of my day;
17 And
then I do
make a
record
of the
things
which I
have seen
with mine
own eyes.
18 And
I know
the
record
which I
make to
be a
just and a
true
record;
nevertheless
there
are many
things
which,
according to
our
language,
we are not able to write.
19 And
now I
make
an end
of my
saying,
which is
of
myself,
and
proceed
to give
my
account
of the
things
which have been before me.
20 I
am
Mormon,
and
a
pure
descendant of
Lehi. I
have
reason
to
bless
my
God and
Savior
Jesus
Christ,
that
he
brought
our
fathers
out of
the
land
of
Jerusalem,
(and no
one
knew
it
save it
were
himself
and
those
whom
he
brought
out
of
that
land)
and
that he
hath
given
me
and my
people so much knowledge unto the salvation of our souls.
Surely he
hath
blessed
the
house
of
Jacob,
and
hath
been
merciful
unto the seed of Joseph.
And
insomuch
as
the
children
of
Lehi
have
kept
his
commandments
he
hath
blessed
them
and
prospered them according to his word.
Yea,
and
surely
shall
he
again
bring
a
remnant
of
the
seed
of
Joseph
to
the
knowledge
of
the
Lord
their
God.
And
as
surely
the
Lord
liveth,
will
he
gather
in
from
the
four
quarters
of
the
earth
all
the
remnant
of
the
seed
of
Jacob, who are scattered abroad upon all the face of the earth.
25 And as he hath covenanted with all the house of Jacob, even so shall the covenant wherewith he hath covenanted with the house of Jacob be fulfilled in his own due time, unto the restoring all the house of Jacob unto the knowledge of the covenant that he hath covenanted with
And
as
he
hath
covenanted
with
all
the
house
of
Jacob,
even
so
shall
the
covenant
wherewith
he
hath
covenanted
with
the
house
of
Jacob
be
fulfilled in his own due time, unto the restoring all the house of Jacob unto the knowledge of the covenant that he hath covenanted with them.
26 And then shall they know their Redeemer, who is Jesus Christ, the Son of God; and then shall they be gathered in from the four quarters of the earth unto their own lands, from whence they have been dispersed; yea, as the Lord liveth so shall it be. Amen.
And
then
shall
they
know
their
Redeemer,
who
is
Jesus
Christ,
the
Son
of
God;
and
then
shall
they
be
gathered
in
from
the
four
quarters
of
the
earth
unto
their
own
lands,
from
whence
they
have
been
dispersed;
yea,
as
the
Lord
liveth
so
shall
it
be.
Amen.