Chapter 4 The Nephite armies defeat the
Gadianton robbers—Giddianhi is slain, and his
successor, Zemnarihah, is hanged—The Nephites praise
the Lord for their victories. About A.D. 19–22.
1 And it came to pass that in the latter
end of the eighteenth year those armies of
robbers had prepared for battle, and began
to come down and to sally forth from the
hills, and out of the mountains, and the
wilderness, and their strongholds, and
their secret places, and began to take
possession of the lands, both which were in the
land south and which were in the land
north, and began to take possession of all the
lands which had been deserted by the
Nephites, and the cities which had been left desolate.
2 But behold, there were no wild
beasts nor game in those lands
which had been deserted by the
Nephites, and there was no game for the
robbers save it were in the wilderness.
3 And the robbers could not exist
save it were in the wilderness,
for the want of food; for the
Nephites had left their lands
desolate, and had gathered their flocks
and their herds and all their
substance, and they were in one body.
4 Therefore, there was no chance
for the robbers to plunder and
to obtain food, save it were to
come up in open battle against
the Nephites; and the Nephites
being in one body, and having so
great a number, and having
reserved for themselves provisions,
and horses and cattle, and flocks
of every kind, that they might
subsist for the space of seven
years, in the which time they did
hope to destroy the robbers from
off the face of the land; and
thus the eighteenth year did pass away.
5 And it came to pass that
in the nineteenth year
Giddianhi found that it was
expedient that he should go up to
battle against the Nephites,
for there was no way that
they could subsist save it
were to plunder and rob and murder.
6 And they durst not spread
themselves upon the face
of the land insomuch that
they could raise grain, lest
the Nephites should come
upon them and slay them;
therefore Giddianhi gave
commandment unto his armies that
in this year they should go
up to battle against the Nephites.
7 And it came to pass
that they did come up to
battle; and it was in the
sixth month; and behold,
great and terrible was the
day that they did come up
to battle; and they were
girded about after the
manner of robbers; and
they had a lamb-skin about
their loins, and they were
dyed in blood, and their
heads were shorn, and
they had head-plates upon
them; and great and
terrible was the appearance of
the armies of Giddianhi,
because of their armor,
and because of their being dyed in blood.
8 And it came to pass
that the armies of the
Nephites, when they saw
the appearance of the
army of Giddianhi, had
all fallen to the earth,
and did lift their
cries to the Lord their
God, that he would spare
them and deliver them
out of the hands of their enemies.
9 And it came to pass
that when the armies
of Giddianhi saw this
they began to shout
with a loud voice,
because of their joy, for
they had supposed that
the Nephites had fallen
with fear because of
the terror of their armies.
10 But in this thing
they were
disappointed, for the Nephites
did not fear them; but
they did fear their
God and did
supplicate him for protection;
therefore, when the
armies of Giddianhi
did rush upon them
they were prepared to
meet them; yea, in the
strength of the Lord
they did receive them.
11 And the battle
commenced in this the
sixth month; and
great and terrible was
the battle thereof,
yea, great and
terrible was the
slaughter thereof, insomuch
that there never was
known so great a
slaughter among all
the people of Lehi
since he left Jerusalem.
12 And
notwithstanding the
threatenings and the oaths
which Giddianhi
had made, behold,
the Nephites did
beat them, insomuch
that they did fall
back from before them.
13 And it came to
pass that
Gidgiddoni commanded
that his armies
should pursue them
as far as the
borders of the
wilderness, and that
they should not
spare any that
should fall into their
hands by the
way; and thus they
did pursue them
and did slay them,
to the borders of
the wilderness,
even until they
had fulfilled the
commandment of Gidgiddoni.
14 And it came to
pass that
Giddianhi, who had
stood and fought with
boldness, was
pursued as he fled;
and being weary
because of his
much fighting he
was overtaken and
slain. And thus
was the end of
Giddianhi the robber.
15 And it came
to pass that the
armies of the
Nephites did
return again to their
place of
security. And it came
to pass that
this nineteenth
year did pass away,
and the robbers
did not come
again to battle;
neither did they
come again in
the twentieth year.
16 And in the
twenty and first
year they did
not come up to
battle, but
they came up on
all sides to lay
siege round
about the people
of Nephi; for
they did suppose
that if they
should cut off
the people of
Nephi from their
lands, and
should hem them in
on every side,
and if they
should cut them off
from all their
outward
privileges, that they
could cause
them to yield
themselves up according to their wishes.
17 Now they
had appointed
unto themselves
another
leader, whose name
was Zemnarihah;
therefore it
was Zemnarihah
that did
cause that this
siege should take place.
18 But
behold, this was an
advantage to
the
Nephites; for it was
impossible
for the robbers
to lay siege
sufficiently
long to have
any effect
upon the
Nephites, because
of their much
provision
which they had
laid up in store,
19 And
because of the
scantiness of
provisions
among the
robbers; for
behold, they
had nothing
save it were
meat for
their
subsistence, which
meat they did
obtain in the wilderness;
20 And it
came to pass
that the
wild game
became scarce
in the
wilderness
insomuch that
the robbers
were about
to perish
with hunger.
21 And the
Nephites
were
continually
marching out
by day and
by night,
and
falling upon
their
armies, and
cutting them
off by
thousands and
by tens of thousands.
22 And
thus it
became the
desire of
the
people of
Zemnarihah to
withdraw
from
their
design, because
of the
great
destruction
which came
upon
them by night and by day.
23 And
it came
to pass
that
Zemnarihah
did give
command
unto his
people
that
they should
withdraw
themselves
from the
siege, and
march
into the
furthermost
parts of the land northward.
24 And
now,
Gidgiddoni being
aware
of
their
design, and
knowing
of
their
weakness
because
of the
want of
food,
and the
great
slaughter which
had
been made
among
them,
therefore he
did send
out his
armies
in the
night-time,
and did
cut off
the
way of
their
retreat,
and did
place his armies in the way of their retreat.
25 And
this
did
they do
in the
night-time,
and
got on
their
march
beyond
the
robbers, so
that on
the
morrow,
when
the
robbers
began
their
march,
they
were
met by
the
armies
of the
Nephites
both in their front and in their rear.
And the
robbers
who
were on
the
south
were
also
cut
off
in
their
places
of
retreat. And
all
these
things
were
done by command of Gidgiddoni.
And
there
were
many
thousands
who
did
yield
themselves up
prisoners
unto
the
Nephites,
and
the
remainder of them were slain.
And
their
leader,
Zemnarihah,
was
taken
and
hanged
upon a
tree,
yea,
even
upon
the
top
thereof
until
he
was
dead.
And
when
they
had
hanged
him
until
he
was
dead
they
did
fell
the tree to the earth, and did cry with a loud voice, saying:
May
the
Lord
preserve
his
people
in
righteousness
and
in
holiness
of
heart,
that
they
may
cause
to
be
felled
to
the
earth
all
who
shall
seek
to
slay
them
because
of
power
and
secret
combinations,
even
as
this
man
hath
been
felled
to
the
earth.
And
they
did
rejoice
and
cry
again
with
one
voice,
saying:
May
the
God
of
Abraham,
and
the
God
of
Isaac,
and
the
God
of
Jacob,
protect
this
people
in
righteousness, so long as they shall call on the name of their God for protection.
31 And it came to pass that they did break forth, all as one, in singing, and praising their God for the great thing which he had done for them, in preserving them from falling into the hands of their
And
it
came
to
pass
that
they
did
break
forth,
all
as
one,
in
singing,
and
praising
their
God
for
the
great thing which he had done for them, in preserving them from falling into the hands of their enemies.
32 Yea, they did cry: Hosanna to the Most High God. And they did cry: Blessed be the name of the Lord God Almighty, the Most High
Yea,
they
did
cry:
Hosanna
to
the
Most
High
God.
And
they
did
cry:
Blessed
be
the
name
of
the
Lord
God
Almighty,
the
Most
High
God.
33 And their hearts were swollen with joy, unto the gushing out of many tears, because of the great goodness of God in delivering them out of the hands of their enemies; and they knew it was because of their repentance and their humility that they had been delivered from an everlasting destruction.
And
their
hearts
were
swollen
with
joy,
unto
the
gushing
out
of
many
tears,
because
of
the
great
goodness
of
God
in
delivering
them
out
of
the
hands
of
their
enemies;
and
they
knew
it
was
because
of
their
repentance
and
their
humility
that
they
had
been
delivered
from
an
everlasting
destruction.