Chapter 3 Giddianhi, the Gadianton leader,
demands that Lachoneus and the Nephites
surrender themselves and their lands—Lachoneus
appoints Gidgiddoni as chief captain of the
armies—The Nephites assemble in Zarahemla and
Bountiful to defend themselves. About A.D. 16–18.
1 And now it came to pass that in the
sixteenth year from the coming of Christ,
Lachoneus, the governor of the land,
received an epistle from the leader and the
governor of this band of robbers; and these
were the words which were written, saying:
2 Lachoneus, most noble and chief
governor of the land, behold, I write this
epistle unto you, and do give unto you
exceedingly great praise because of your
firmness, and also the firmness of
your people, in maintaining that which ye
suppose to be your right and liberty;
yea, ye do stand well, as if ye were
supported by the hand of a god, in the
defence of your liberty, and your
property, and your country, or that which ye do call so.
3 And it seemeth a pity unto me, most
noble Lachoneus, that ye should be so
foolish and vain as to suppose that ye
can stand against so many brave men
who are at my command, who do now at
this time stand in their arms, and do
await with great anxiety for the word—Go
down upon the Nephites and destroy them.
4 And I, knowing of their
unconquerable spirit, having proved them in
the field of battle, and knowing of
their everlasting hatred towards you
because of the many wrongs which ye
have done unto them, therefore if
they should come down against you they
would visit you with utter destruction.
5 Therefore I have written this
epistle, sealing it with mine own
hand, feeling for your welfare,
because of your firmness in that which
ye believe to be right, and your
noble spirit in the field of battle.
6 Therefore I write unto you,
desiring that ye would yield up
unto this my people, your cities,
your lands, and your
possessions, rather than that they should
visit you with the sword and that
destruction should come upon you.
7 Or in other words, yield
yourselves up unto us, and
unite with us and become
acquainted with our secret works, and
become our brethren that ye
may be like unto us—not our
slaves, but our brethren and
partners of all our substance.
8 And behold, I swear unto
you, if ye will do this,
with an oath, ye shall not be
destroyed; but if ye will
not do this, I swear unto
you with an oath, that on
the morrow month I will
command that my armies shall
come down against you, and
they shall not stay their hand
and shall spare not, but
shall slay you, and shall
let fall the sword upon you
even until ye shall become extinct.
9 And behold, I am
Giddianhi; and I am the governor of
this the secret society of
Gadianton; which society
and the works thereof I know
to be good; and they are
of ancient date and they
have been handed down unto us.
10 And I write this
epistle unto you, Lachoneus,
and I hope that ye will
deliver up your lands and
your possessions, without
the shedding of blood,
that this my people may
recover their rights and
government, who have
dissented away from you because
of your wickedness in
retaining from them their
rights of government, and
except ye do this, I will
avenge their wrongs. I am Giddianhi.
11 And now it came to
pass when Lachoneus
received this epistle he
was exceedingly
astonished, because of the
boldness of Giddianhi
demanding the possession of
the land of the
Nephites, and also of
threatening the people and
avenging the wrongs of those
that had received no
wrong, save it were they
had wronged themselves
by dissenting away
unto those wicked and abominable robbers.
12 Now behold, this
Lachoneus, the governor,
was a just man, and
could not be frightened
by the demands and
the threatenings of a
robber; therefore he did
not hearken to the
epistle of Giddianhi,
the governor of the
robbers, but he did cause
that his people should
cry unto the Lord for
strength against the
time that the robbers
should come down against them.
13 Yea, he sent a
proclamation among all
the people, that they
should gather
together their women, and
their children, their
flocks and their
herds, and all their
substance, save it were
their land, unto one place.
14 And he caused
that fortifications
should be built round
about them, and the
strength thereof
should be exceedingly
great. And he caused
that armies, both of
the Nephites and of
the Lamanites, or of
all them who were
numbered among the
Nephites, should be
placed as guards round
about to watch
them, and to guard them
from the robbers day and night.
15 Yea, he said
unto them: As the
Lord liveth, except
ye repent of all
your iniquities,
and cry unto the
Lord, ye will in
nowise be delivered
out of the hands of
those Gadianton robbers.
16 And so great
and marvelous were
the words and
prophecies of
Lachoneus that they
did cause fear to
come upon all the
people; and they
did exert
themselves in their
might to do according
to the words of Lachoneus.
17 And it came
to pass that
Lachoneus did
appoint chief captains
over all the
armies of the
Nephites, to command
them at the
time that the
robbers should come
down out of the
wilderness against them.
18 Now the
chiefest among all
the chief
captains and the
great commander of
all the armies
of the
Nephites was
appointed, and his name
was Gidgiddoni.
19 Now it was
the custom
among all the
Nephites to
appoint for their
chief captains,
(save it were
in their
times of
wickedness) some one
that had the
spirit of
revelation and also
prophecy;
therefore, this
Gidgiddoni was a
great prophet
among them, as
also was the chief judge.
20 Now the
people said
unto Gidgiddoni:
Pray unto
the Lord, and
let us go up
upon the
mountains and into
the
wilderness, that we
may fall upon
the robbers
and destroy
them in their own lands.
21 But
Gidgiddoni saith
unto them: The
Lord forbid;
for if we
should go up
against them the
Lord would
deliver us
into their
hands; therefore
we will
prepare ourselves
in the center
of our lands,
and we will
gather all
our armies
together, and we
will not go
against them,
but we will
wait till they
shall come
against us;
therefore as
the Lord
liveth, if we do
this he will
deliver them
into our hands.
22 And it
came to pass
in the
seventeenth year,
latter end of the
year, the
proclamation
of Lachoneus
had gone
forth
throughout all the
face of the
land, and
they had taken
their
horses, and their
chariots,
and their
cattle, and all
their
flocks, and their
herds, and
their grain,
and all
their substance,
and did
march forth by
thousands
and by tens of
thousands,
until they
had all gone
forth to the
place which
had been
appointed that
they should
gather
themselves
together, to defend themselves against their enemies.
23 And the
land which
was
appointed was the
land of
Zarahemla, and
the land
which was
between the
land
Zarahemla and the
Bountiful, yea,
to the line
which was
between the
land
Bountiful and the land Desolation.
24 And
there were a
great many
thousand
people who
were
called
Nephites, who did
gather
themselves
together in
this
land. Now
Lachoneus did
cause that
they
should gather
themselves
together
in the
land
southward, because
of the
great curse
which was upon the land northward.
25 And
they did
fortify
themselves
against
their
enemies; and
they did
dwell in
one land,
and in
one body,
and they
did fear
the words
which had
been
spoken by
Lachoneus,
insomuch
that they
did
repent of all
their
sins; and
they did
put up
their
prayers unto
the Lord
their God,
that he
would
deliver them
in the
time that
their
enemies should come down against them to battle.
26 And
they were
exceedingly
sorrowful
because
of their
enemies.
And
Gidgiddoni
did
cause that
they
should make
weapons
of war
of every
kind,
and they
should be
strong
with
armor, and
shields,
and with
bucklers,
after
the manner of his instruction.