Chapter 2 Wickedness and abominations
increase among the people—The Nephites and
Lamanites unite to defend themselves against the
Gadianton robbers—Converted Lamanites become
white and are called Nephites. About A.D. 5–16.
1 And it came to pass that thus passed
away the ninety and fifth year also, and
the people began to forget those signs
and wonders which they had heard, and
began to be less and less astonished at a
sign or a wonder from heaven, insomuch
that they began to be hard in their
hearts, and blind in their minds, and began to
disbelieve all which they had heard and seen—
2 Imagining up some vain thing in their
hearts, that it was wrought by men and
by the power of the devil, to lead
away and deceive the hearts of the people;
and thus did Satan get possession of
the hearts of the people again, insomuch
that he did blind their eyes and lead
them away to believe that the doctrine
of Christ was a foolish and a vain thing.
3 And it came to pass that the people
began to wax strong in wickedness and
abominations; and they did not believe
that there should be any more signs or
wonders given; and Satan did go about,
leading away the hearts of the people,
tempting them and causing them that they
should do great wickedness in the land.
4 And thus did pass away the
ninety and sixth year; and also the
ninety and seventh year; and
also the ninety and eighth year;
and also the ninety and ninth year;
5 And also an hundred years
had passed away since the
days of Mosiah, who was king
over the people of the Nephites.
6 And six hundred and
nine years had passed away
since Lehi left Jerusalem.
7 And nine years had
passed away from the time
when the sign was given,
which was spoken of by
the prophets, that Christ
should come into the world.
8 Now the Nephites
began to reckon their
time from this period
when the sign was given,
or from the coming of
Christ; therefore,
nine years had passed away.
9 And Nephi, who was
the father of
Nephi, who had the charge
of the records, did
not return to the
land of Zarahemla,
and could nowhere be
found in all the land.
10 And it came to
pass that the
people did still
remain in wickedness,
notwithstanding the
much preaching
and prophesying
which was sent among
them; and thus
passed away the tenth
year also; and the
eleventh year
also passed away in iniquity.
11 And it came to
pass in the
thirteenth year there
began to be wars
and contentions
throughout all
the land; for the
Gadianton robbers
had become so
numerous, and did
slay so many of the
people, and did
lay waste so many
cities, and did
spread so much
death and carnage
throughout the
land, that it became
expedient that
all the people,
both the Nephites
and the Lamanites,
should take up arms against them.
12 Therefore,
all the Lamanites
who had become
converted unto
the Lord did unite
with their
brethren, the
Nephites, and were
compelled, for the
safety of their
lives and their
women and their
children, to
take up arms
against those
Gadianton robbers, yea,
and also to
maintain their
rights, and the
privileges of their
church and of
their worship, and
their freedom and their liberty.
13 And it came
to pass that
before this
thirteenth year
had passed
away the Nephites
were
threatened with utter
destruction
because of this
war, which had
become exceedingly sore.
14 And it
came to pass
that those
Lamanites who had
united with
the Nephites
were numbered
among the Nephites;
15 And their
curse was
taken from them,
and their
skin became
white like unto
the Nephites;
16 And their
young men
and their
daughters
became
exceedingly fair, and
they were
numbered among
the
Nephites, and were
called
Nephites. And
thus ended the
thirteenth year.
17 And it
came to pass
in the
commencement
of the
fourteenth year,
the war
between the
robbers and
the people
of Nephi
did continue
and did
become
exceedingly sore;
nevertheless, the
people of Nephi
did gain
some
advantage of the
robbers,
insomuch that
they did
drive them
back out of
their lands
into the
mountains and into their secret places.
18 And
thus ended
the
fourteenth year.
And in the
fifteenth
year they
did come
forth
against the
people of
Nephi; and
because of
the
wickedness of the
people of
Nephi,
and their
many
contentions and
dissensions, the
Gadianton
robbers did
gain many advantages over them.
19 And
thus ended
the
fifteenth
year, and
thus were
the people
in a
state of many
afflictions; and
the sword
of
destruction
did hang
over them,
insomuch
that they
were
about to be
smitten
down by
it, and
this because of their iniquity.