Chapter 16 Jesus will visit others of the
lost sheep of Israel—In the latter days the
gospel will go to the Gentiles and then to the
house of Israel—The Lord’s people will see eye
to eye when He brings again Zion. About A.D. 34.
1 And verily, verily, I say unto you
that I have other sheep, which are not of
this land, neither of the land of
Jerusalem, neither in any parts of that land
round about whither I have been to minister.
2 For they of whom I speak are
they who have not as yet heard
my voice; neither have I at any
time manifested myself unto them.
3 But I have received a
commandment of the Father that I
shall go unto them, and that
they shall hear my voice, and
shall be numbered among my
sheep, that there may be one
fold and one shepherd;
therefore I go to show myself unto them.
4 And I command you that ye
shall write these sayings
after I am gone, that if it
so be that my people at
Jerusalem, they who have seen
me and been with me in my
ministry, do not ask the
Father in my name, that they
may receive a knowledge of
you by the Holy Ghost, and
also of the other tribes
whom they know not of, that
these sayings which ye shall
write shall be kept and
shall be manifested unto the
Gentiles, that through the
fulness of the Gentiles,
the remnant of their seed,
who shall be scattered forth
upon the face of the earth
because of their unbelief,
may be brought in, or may
be brought to a knowledge of me, their Redeemer.
5 And then will I gather
them in from the four
quarters of the earth; and
then will I fulfil the
covenant which the Father
hath made unto all the
people of the house of Israel.
6 And blessed are the
Gentiles, because of
their belief in me, in and
of the Holy Ghost,
which witnesses unto them
of me and of the Father.
7 Behold, because of
their belief in me,
saith the Father, and
because of the
unbelief of you, O house of
Israel, in the
latter day shall the truth
come unto the
Gentiles, that the fulness
of these things shall
be made known unto them.
8 But wo, saith the
Father, unto the
unbelieving of the
Gentiles—for
notwithstanding they have
come forth upon the
face of this land,
and have scattered
my people who are
of the house of
Israel; and my people
who are of the
house of Israel have
been cast out from
among them, and have
been trodden under feet by them;
9 And because of
the mercies of the
Father unto the
Gentiles, and also
the judgments of
the Father upon my
people who are of
the house of
Israel, verily, verily,
I say unto you,
that after all this,
and I have caused
my people who are
of the house of
Israel to be
smitten, and to be
afflicted, and to be
slain, and to be
cast out from among
them, and to become
hated by them,
and to become a hiss
and a byword among them—
10 And thus
commandeth the Father
that I should say
unto you: At
that day when the
Gentiles shall sin
against my
gospel, and shall
reject the fulness of
my gospel, and
shall be lifted up
in the pride of
their hearts above
all nations, and
above all the
people of the whole
earth, and shall
be filled with
all manner of
lyings, and of
deceits, and of
mischiefs, and all
manner of hypocrisy,
and murders, and
priestcrafts, and
whoredoms, and of
secret
abominations; and if they
shall do all
those things, and
shall reject the
fulness of my
gospel, behold, saith
the Father, I will
bring the fulness of my gospel from among them.
11 And then will
I remember my
covenant which I
have made unto
my people, O
house of Israel, and
I will bring my
gospel unto them.
12 And I will
show unto thee, O
house of Israel,
that the
Gentiles shall not
have power over
you; but I will
remember my
covenant unto you, O
house of Israel,
and ye shall come
unto the
knowledge of the
fulness of my gospel.
13 But if the
Gentiles will
repent and return
unto me, saith
the Father,
behold they shall
be numbered
among my people,
O house of Israel.
14 And I will
not suffer my
people, who
are of the house
of Israel, to
go through
among them, and
tread them
down, saith the Father.
15 But if
they will not
turn unto me,
and hearken
unto my voice,
I will suffer
them, yea, I
will suffer
my people, O
house of
Israel, that they
shall go
through among
them, and shall
tread them
down, and they
shall be as
salt that
hath lost its
savor, which is
thenceforth
good for
nothing but to be
cast out,
and to be
trodden under foot
of my people, O house of Israel.
16 Verily,
verily, I say
unto you,
thus hath the
Father
commanded
me—that I should
give unto
this people
this land for
their inheritance.
17 And
then the
words of the
prophet
Isaiah shall
be
fulfilled, which say:
18 Thy
watchmen
shall lift
up the
voice; with
the
voice
together shall
they sing,
for they
shall
see eye to
eye when
the Lord
shall bring again Zion.
19 Break
forth
into joy,
sing
together,
ye waste
places
of
Jerusalem;
for the
Lord hath
comforted his
people, he
hath
redeemed Jerusalem.
20 The
Lord
hath made
bare
his holy
arm in
the
eyes of
all the
nations; and
ends of
the
earth
shall see
the salvation of God.