Chapter 27 Jesus commands them to call the Church
in His name—His mission and atoning sacrifice
constitute His gospel—Men are commanded to repent and
be baptized that they may be sanctified by the
Holy Ghost—They are to be even as Jesus is. About
A.D. 34–35.
1 And it came to pass that as the disciples of
Jesus were journeying and were preaching the things
which they had both heard and seen, and were
baptizing in the name of Jesus, it came to pass that the
disciples were gathered together and were united
in mighty prayer and fasting
2 And Jesus again showed himself unto them, for
they were praying unto the Father in his name; and
Jesus came and stood in the midst of them, and said
unto them: What will ye that I shall give unto
you
3 And they said unto him: Lord, we will that thou
wouldst tell us the name whereby we shall call
this church; for there are disputations among the
people concerning this matter
4 And the Lord said unto them: Verily, verily, I
say unto you, why is it that the people should
murmur and dispute because of this thing
5 Have they not read the scriptures, which say ye
must take upon you the name of Christ, which is my
name? For by this name shall ye be called at the
last day
6 And whoso taketh upon him my name, and endureth
to the end, the same shall be saved at the last
day
7 Therefore, whatsoever ye shall do, ye shall do
it in my name; therefore ye shall call the church
in my name; and ye shall call upon the Father in my
name that he will bless the church for my sake
8 And how be it my church save it be called in my
name? For if a church be called in Moses’ name
then it be Moses’ church; or if it be called in the
name of a man then it be the church of a man; but
if it be called in my name then it is my church, if
it so be that they are built upon my gospel
9 Verily I say unto you, that ye are built upon my
gospel; therefore ye shall call whatsoever things
ye do call, in my name; therefore if ye call upon
the Father, for the church, if it be in my name
the Father will hear you
10 And if it so be that the church is built upon
my gospel then will the Father show forth his own
works in it
11 But if it be not built upon my gospel, and is
built upon the works of men, or upon the works of
the devil, verily I say unto you they have joy in
their works for a season, and by and by the end
cometh, and they are hewn down and cast into the
fire, from whence there is no return
12 For their works do follow them, for it is
because of their works that they are hewn down;
therefore remember the things that I have told you
13 Behold I have given unto you my gospel, and
this is the gospel which I have given unto you—that I
came into the world to do the will of my Father,
because my Father sent me
14 And my Father sent me that I might be lifted up
upon the cross; and after that I had been lifted
up upon the cross, that I might draw all men unto
me, that as I have been lifted up by men even so
should men be lifted up by the Father, to stand
before me, to be judged of their works, whether they
be good or whether they be evil
15 And for this cause have I been lifted up;
therefore, according to the power of the Father I will
draw all men unto me, that they may be judged
according to their works
16 And it shall come to pass, that whoso repenteth
and is baptized in my name shall be filled; and
if he endureth to the end, behold, him will I hold
guiltless before my Father at that day when I
shall stand to judge the world
17 And he that endureth not unto the end, the same
is he that is also hewn down and cast into the
fire, from whence they can no more return, because
of the justice of the Father
18 And this is the word which he hath given unto
the children of men. And for this cause he
fulfilleth the words which he hath given, and he lieth
not, but fulfilleth all his words
19 And no unclean thing can enter into his
kingdom; therefore nothing entereth into his rest save it
be those who have washed their garments in my
blood, because of their faith, and the repentance of
all their sins, and their faithfulness unto the
end
20 Now this is the commandment: Repent, all ye
ends of the earth, and come unto me and be baptized
in my name, that ye may be sanctified by the
reception of the Holy Ghost, that ye may stand spotless
before me at the last day
21 Verily, verily, I say unto you, this is my
gospel; and ye know the things that ye must do in my
church; for the works which ye have seen me do that
shall ye also do; for that which ye have seen me
do even that shall ye do
22 Therefore, if ye do these things blessed are
ye, for ye shall be lifted up at the last day
23 Write the things which ye have seen and heard,
save it be those which are forbidden
24 Write the works of this people, which shall be,
even as hath been written, of that which hath
been
25 For behold, out of the books which have been
written, and which shall be written, shall this
people be judged, for by them shall their works be
known unto men
26 And behold, all things are written by the
Father; therefore out of the books which shall be
written shall the world be judged
27 And know ye that ye shall be judges of this
people, according to the judgment which I shall give
unto you, which shall be just. Therefore, what
manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you,
even as I am
28 And now I go unto the Father. And verily I say
unto you, whatsoever things ye shall ask the
Father in my name shall be given unto you
29 Therefore, ask, and ye shall receive; knock,
and it shall be opened unto you; for he that asketh,
receiveth; and unto him that knocketh, it shall
be opened
30 And now, behold, my joy is great, even unto
fulness, because of you, and also this generation;
yea, and even the Father rejoiceth, and also all the
holy angels, because of you and this generation;
for none of them are lost
31 Behold, I would that ye should understand; for
I mean them who are now alive of this generation;
and none of them are lost; and in them I have
fulness of joy
32 But behold, it sorroweth me because of the
fourth generation from this generation, for they are
led away captive by him even as was the son of
perdition; for they will sell me for silver and for
gold, and for that which moth doth corrupt and which
thieves can break through and steal. And in that
day will I visit them, even in turning their works
upon their own heads
33 And it came to pass that when Jesus had ended
these sayings he said unto his disciples: Enter ye
in at the strait gate; for strait is the gate, and
narrow is the way that leads to life, and few
there be that find it; but wide is the gate, and
broad the way which leads to death, and many there be
that travel therein, until the night cometh,
wherein no man can work.