Chapter 23 Jesus approves the words of Isaiah—He
commands the people to search the prophets—The
words of Samuel the Lamanite concerning the
Resurrection are added to their records. About A.D. 34.
1 And now, behold, I say unto you, that ye
ought to search these things. Yea, a
commandment I give unto you that ye search these things
diligently; for great are the words of Isaiah.
2 For surely he spake as touching all
things concerning my people which are of the
house of Israel; therefore it must needs
be that he must speak also to the Gentiles.
3 And all things that he spake
have been and shall be, even
according to the words which he spake.
4 Therefore give heed to my
words; write the things
which I have told you; and
according to the time and the
will of the Father they
shall go forth unto the Gentiles.
5 And whosoever will
hearken unto my words and
repenteth and is
baptized, the same shall be
saved. Search the
prophets, for many there be
that testify of these things.
6 And now it came to
pass that when Jesus
had said these words
he said unto them
again, after he had
expounded all the
scriptures unto them which
they had received, he
said unto them:
Behold, other scriptures I
would that ye should
write, that ye have not.
7 And it came to
pass that he said
unto Nephi:
Bring forth the
record which ye have kept.
8 And when
Nephi had brought
forth the
records, and laid
them before him,
he cast his eyes
upon them and said:
9 Verily I say
unto you, I
commanded my
servant Samuel, the
Lamanite, that
he should
testify unto this
people, that at
the day that the
Father should
glorify his
name in me that
there were many
saints who
should arise from
the dead, and
should appear unto
many, and
should minister
unto them. And he
said unto them:
Was it not so?
10 And his
disciples
answered him and
said: Yea, Lord,
Samuel did
prophesy according
to thy words,
and they were
all fulfilled.
11 And Jesus
said unto
them: How be it
that ye have
not written
this thing,
that many
saints did arise
and appear
unto many and
did minister unto them?
12 And it
came to pass
that Nephi
remembered
that this
thing had
not been written.
13 And it
came to
pass that
Jesus
commanded that
it should
be written;
therefore
it was
written
according as
he commanded.
14 And
now it came
to pass
that when
Jesus
had
expounded all
the
scriptures in
one, which
they had
written,
he
commanded them
that they
should
teach the
things
which he
had expounded unto them.