Chapter 14 Jesus commands: Judge not; ask
of God; beware of false prophets—He
promises salvation to those who do the will of
the Father—Compare
Matthew 7. About A.D. 34.
1 And now it came to pass that when
Jesus had spoken these words he
turned again to the multitude, and
did open his mouth unto them again,
saying: Verily, verily, I say unto
you, Judge not, that ye be not judged.
2 For with what judgment ye
judge, ye shall be judged; and
with what measure ye mete, it
shall be measured to you again.
3 And why beholdest thou the
mote that is in thy brother’s
eye, but considerest not the
beam that is in thine own eye?
4 Or how wilt thou say to thy
brother: Let me pull the
mote out of thine eye—and
behold, a beam is in thine own eye?
5 Thou hypocrite, first
cast the beam out of thine
own eye; and then shalt
thou see clearly to cast the
mote out of thy brother’s eye.
6 Give not that which is
holy unto the dogs, neither
cast ye your pearls
before swine, lest they trample
them under their feet,
and turn again and rend you.
7 Ask, and it shall be
given unto you; seek, and
ye shall find; knock, and
it shall be opened unto you.
8 For every one that
asketh, receiveth; and he
that seeketh, findeth;
and to him that
knocketh, it shall be opened.
9 Or what man is
there of you, who, if
his son ask bread,
will give him a stone?
10 Or if he ask a
fish, will he
give him a serpent?
11 If ye then,
being evil, know
how to give good
gifts unto your
children, how
much more shall
your Father who
is in heaven give
good things to
them that ask him?
12 Therefore,
all things
whatsoever ye
would that men
should do to
you, do ye even
so to them, for
this is the
law and the prophets.
13 Enter ye
in at the
strait gate; for
wide is the
gate, and
broad is the way,
which
leadeth to
destruction, and many
there be who
go in thereat;
14 Because
strait is the
gate, and
narrow is the
way, which
leadeth unto
life, and
few there be
that find it.
15 Beware
of false
prophets, who
come to you
in sheep’s
clothing,
but
inwardly they are
ravening wolves.
16 Ye
shall know
them by their
fruits.
Do men
gather grapes
of thorns,
or figs
of thistles?
17 Even
so every
good tree
bringeth
forth
good fruit;
but a
corrupt tree
bringeth
forth evil fruit.
18 A
good tree
cannot
bring
forth evil
fruit,
neither a
corrupt
tree
bring forth
good fruit.
Every tree
that
bringeth
not
forth good
fruit
is hewn
down,
and
cast into the fire.
Wherefore,
by
their
fruits ye
shall
know them.
21 Not
every
one
that
saith
unto me,
Lord,
shall
enter
into
the
kingdom
of
heaven;
but he
that
doeth
the
will of
my Father who is in heaven.
Many
will
say to
me in
that
day:
Lord,
have we
not
prophesied
in
thy
name,
and in
thy
name
have
cast
out
devils, and
in
thy
name done many wonderful works?
And
then
will
I
profess
unto
them: I
never
knew
you;
depart
from
me,
ye that work iniquity.
Therefore,
whoso
heareth
these
sayings of
mine
and
doeth
them, I
will
liken
him
unto
a
wise
man,
who
built
his
house
upon
a
rock—
And
the
rain
descended,
and
the
floods
came,
and
the
winds
blew,
and
beat
upon
that
house;
and
it
fell
not, for it was founded upon a rock.
And
every
one
that
heareth
these
sayings
of
mine
and
doeth
them
not
shall
be
likened
unto
a
foolish man, who built his house upon the sand—
27 And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell, and great was the fall of it.
And
the
rain
descended,
and
the
floods
came,
and
the
winds
blew,
and beat upon that house; and it fell, and great was the fall of it.