Chapter 26 Jesus expounds all things from
the beginning to the end—Babes and children
utter marvelous things that cannot be
written—Those in the Church of Christ have all
things in common among them. About A.D. 34.
1 And now it came to pass that when Jesus
had told these things he expounded them
unto the multitude; and he did expound
all things unto them, both great and small.
2 And he saith: These scriptures,
which ye had not with you, the Father
commanded that I should give unto you;
for it was wisdom in him that they
should be given unto future generations.
3 And he did expound all things,
even from the beginning until the time
that he should come in his
glory—yea, even all things which should come
upon the face of the earth, even
until the elements should melt with
fervent heat, and the earth should be
wrapt together as a scroll, and the
heavens and the earth should pass away;
4 And even unto the great and
last day, when all people, and all
kindreds, and all nations and
tongues shall stand before God, to be
judged of their works, whether
they be good or whether they be evil—
5 If they be good, to the
resurrection of everlasting life;
and if they be evil, to the
resurrection of damnation; being
on a parallel, the one on the
one hand and the other on the
other hand, according to the
mercy, and the justice, and
the holiness which is in Christ,
who was before the world began.
6 And now there cannot be
written in this book
even a hundredth part of the
things which Jesus did
truly teach unto the people;
7 But behold the plates
of Nephi do contain the
more part of the things
which he taught the people.
8 And these things have
I written, which are a
lesser part of the
things which he taught the
people; and I have
written them to the intent
that they may be
brought again unto this
people, from the Gentiles,
according to the words
which Jesus hath spoken.
9 And when they shall
have received this,
which is expedient that
they should have
first, to try their faith,
and if it shall so be
that they shall
believe these things then
shall the greater things
be made manifest unto them.
10 And if it so be
that they will not
believe these
things, then shall the
greater things be
withheld from them,
unto their condemnation.
11 Behold, I was
about to write
them, all which
were engraven upon
the plates of
Nephi, but the Lord
forbade it,
saying: I will try the
faith of my people.
12 Therefore I,
Mormon, do write
the things
which have been
commanded me of the
Lord. And now I,
Mormon, make an
end of my
sayings, and proceed
to write the
things which have
been commanded me.
13 Therefore, I
would that ye
should behold
that the Lord
truly did teach
the people, for
the space of
three days; and
after that he
did show himself
unto them oft,
and did break
bread oft, and
bless it, and
give it unto them.
14 And it came
to pass that
he did teach
and minister
unto the
children of the
multitude of whom
hath been
spoken, and he did
loose their
tongues, and
they did speak
unto their
fathers great and
marvelous
things, even
greater than he had
revealed unto
the people;
and he loosed
their tongues that they could utter.
15 And it
came to pass
that after he
had ascended
into heaven—the
second time
that he
showed himself
unto them, and
had gone unto
the Father,
after having
healed all
their sick, and
their lame,
and opened the
eyes of
their blind and
unstopped the
ears of the
deaf, and even
had done all
manner of
cures among
them, and raised
a man from
the dead, and
had shown
forth his power
unto them,
and had ascended unto the Father—
16 Behold,
it came to
pass on the
morrow that
the multitude
gathered
themselves
together, and
they both saw
and heard
these
children; yea, even
babes did
open their
mouths and
utter marvelous
things; and
the things
which they
did utter were
forbidden
that there
should not any man write them.
17 And it
came to pass
that the
disciples whom
Jesus had
chosen began
from that time
forth to
baptize and to
teach as
many as did
come unto
them; and as
many as were
baptized in
the name of
Jesus were
filled with the
Holy Ghost.
18 And many
of them
saw and heard
unspeakable things,
which are
not lawful to
be written.
19 And
they taught,
and did
minister one
to
another; and
they had all
things
common among
them,
every man
dealing
justly, one with another.
20 And it
came to
pass that
they did
do all
things
even as
Jesus had
commanded them.
21 And
they who
were
baptized in
the
name of
Jesus were
called
the
church of Christ.