Chapter 13 Jesus teaches the Nephites the Lord’s
Prayer—They are to lay up treasures in heaven—The
twelve disciples in their ministry are commanded to
take no thought for temporal things—Compare
Matthew 6. About A.D. 34.
1 Verily, verily, I say that I would that ye
should do alms unto the poor; but take heed that ye do
not your alms before men to be seen of them;
otherwise ye have no reward of your Father who is in
heaven
2 Therefore, when ye shall do your alms do not
sound a trumpet before you, as will hypocrites do in
the synagogues and in the streets, that they may
have glory of men. Verily I say unto you, they have
their reward
3 But when thou doest alms let not thy left hand
know what thy right hand doeth
4 That thine alms may be in secret; and thy Father
who seeth in secret, himself shall reward thee
openly
5 And when thou prayest thou shalt not do as the
hypocrites, for they love to pray, standing in the
synagogues and in the corners of the streets, that
they may be seen of men. Verily I say unto you,
they have their reward
6 But thou, when thou prayest, enter into thy
closet, and when thou hast shut thy door, pray to thy
Father who is in secret; and thy Father, who seeth
in secret, shall reward thee openly
7 But when ye pray, use not vain repetitions, as
the heathen, for they think that they shall be
heard for their much speaking
8 Be not ye therefore like unto them, for your
Father knoweth what things ye have need of before ye
ask him
9 After this manner therefore pray ye: Our Father
who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name
10 Thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven
11 And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our
debtors
12 And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us
from evil
13 For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and
the glory, forever. Amen
14 For, if ye forgive men their trespasses your
heavenly Father will also forgive you
15 But if ye forgive not men their trespasses
neither will your Father forgive your trespasses
16 Moreover, when ye fast be not as the
hypocrites, of a sad countenance, for they disfigure their
faces that they may appear unto men to fast. Verily
I say unto you, they have their reward
17 But thou, when thou fastest, anoint thy head,
and wash thy face
18 That thou appear not unto men to fast, but unto
thy Father, who is in secret; and thy Father, who
seeth in secret, shall reward thee openly
19 Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth,
where moth and rust doth corrupt, and thieves
break through and steal
20 But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven,
where neither moth nor rust doth corrupt, and
where thieves do not break through nor steal
21 For where your treasure is, there will your
heart be also
22 The light of the body is the eye; if,
therefore, thine eye be single, thy whole body shall be
full of light
23 But if thine eye be evil, thy whole body shall
be full of darkness. If, therefore, the light that
is in thee be darkness, how great is that
darkness
24 No man can serve two masters; for either he
will hate the one and love the other, or else he will
hold to the one and despise the other. Ye cannot
serve God and Mammon
25 And now it came to pass that when Jesus had
spoken these words he looked upon the twelve whom he
had chosen, and said unto them: Remember the words
which I have spoken. For behold, ye are they whom
I have chosen to minister unto this people.
Therefore I say unto you, take no thought for your
life, what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink; nor
yet for your body, what ye shall put on. Is not the
life more than meat, and the body than raiment
26 Behold the fowls of the air, for they sow not,
neither do they reap nor gather into barns; yet
your heavenly Father feedeth them. Are ye not much
better than they
27 Which of you by taking thought can add one
cubit unto his stature
28 And why take ye thought for raiment? Consider
the lilies of the field how they grow; they toil
not, neither do they spin
29 And yet I say unto you, that even Solomon, in
all his glory, was not arrayed like one of these
30 Wherefore, if God so clothe the grass of the
field, which today is, and tomorrow is cast into the
oven, even so will he clothe you, if ye are not
of little faith
31 Therefore take no thought, saying, What shall
we eat? or, What shall we drink? or, Wherewithal
shall we be clothed
32 For your heavenly Father knoweth that ye have
need of all these things
33 But seek ye first the kingdom of God and his
righteousness, and all these things shall be added
unto you
34 Take therefore no thought for the morrow, for
the morrow shall take thought for the things of
itself. Sufficient is the day unto the evil thereof.