Chapter 15 Jesus announces that the law of Moses
is fulfilled in Him—The Nephites are the other
sheep of whom He spoke in Jerusalem—Because of
iniquity, the Lord’s people in Jerusalem do not know
of the scattered sheep of Israel. About A.D. 34.
1 And now it came to pass that when Jesus had
ended these sayings he cast his eyes round
about on the multitude, and said unto them:
Behold, ye have heard the things which I taught
before I ascended to my Father; therefore,
whoso remembereth these sayings of mine and
doeth them, him will I raise up at the last day.
2 And it came to pass that when Jesus
had said these words he perceived that
there were some among them who marveled,
and wondered what he would concerning
the law of Moses; for they understood
not the saying that old things had
passed away, and that all things had become new.
3 And he said unto them: Marvel
not that I said unto you that
old things had passed away, and
that all things had become new.
4 Behold, I say unto you
that the law is fulfilled
that was given unto Moses.
5 Behold, I am he that
gave the law, and I am
he who covenanted with
my people Israel;
therefore, the law in me is
fulfilled, for I have
come to fulfil the law;
therefore it hath an end.
6 Behold, I do not
destroy the prophets, for
as many as have not
been fulfilled in me,
verily I say unto you,
shall all be fulfilled.
7 And because I said
unto you that old
things have passed
away, I do not destroy
that which hath
been spoken concerning
things which are to come.
8 For behold, the
covenant which I
have made with my
people is not all
fulfilled; but the law
which was given unto
Moses hath an end in me.
9 Behold, I am
the law, and the
light. Look unto
me, and endure to
the end, and ye
shall live; for
unto him that
endureth to the end
will I give eternal life.
10 Behold, I
have given unto you
the
commandments; therefore
keep my
commandments. And this is
the law and the
prophets, for
they truly testified of me.
11 And now it
came to pass that
when Jesus had
spoken these
words, he said unto
those twelve
whom he had chosen:
12 Ye are my
disciples; and
ye are a light
unto this
people, who are a
remnant of
the house of Joseph.
13 And
behold, this is the
land of your
inheritance;
and the
Father hath given
it unto you.
14 And not
at any time
hath the
Father given me
commandment
that I
should tell it
unto your
brethren at Jerusalem.
15 Neither
at any time
hath the
Father given
me
commandment that I
should
tell unto them
concerning
the other
tribes of
the house of
Israel,
whom the
Father hath led
away out of the land.
16 This
much did
the Father
command
me, that
I should
tell unto them:
17 That
other
sheep I
have which
are not
of this
fold;
them also
I must
bring,
and they
shall
hear my
voice; and
there
shall be
one
fold, and one shepherd.
18 And
now,
because of
stiffneckedness
and
unbelief they
understood not
my word;
therefore I was
commanded to
say no
more of the
Father
concerning this
thing
unto them.
19 But,
verily,
I say
unto you
that the
Father
hath
commanded
me, and I
tell it
unto
you, that
ye were
separated
from
among them
because
of
their
iniquity;
therefore it
is
because of
their
iniquity
that they
know not
of you.
20 And
verily,
I say
unto
you again
that
the
other
tribes hath
the
Father
separated
from
them; and
it is
because
of
their
iniquity
that they know not of them.
21 And
verily
I say
unto
you, that
ye are
they of
whom I
said:
Other
sheep I
have
which are
not of
this
fold;
them also
I must
bring,
and
they
shall hear
my
voice; and
there
shall be
one
fold, and
shepherd.
22 And
they
understood me
not, for
they
supposed
it had
been
the
Gentiles;
for they
understood not
that
the
Gentiles
should be
converted
through
their
preaching.
23 And
they
understood
me not
that I
said
they
shall
hear my
voice; and
they
understood me
not
that
the
Gentiles
should
not at
any
time
hear my
voice—that I
should not
manifest
myself
unto
them save it were by the Holy Ghost.
But
behold,
ye
have
both
heard
my
voice,
and
seen
me; and
ye
are my
sheep,
and ye
are
numbered
among
those
whom
the Father hath given me.