Chapter 8 Tempests, earthquakes, fires,
whirlwinds, and physical upheavals attest the
crucifixion of Christ—Many people are
destroyed—Darkness covers the land for three days—Those
who remain bemoan their fate. About A.D. 33–34.
1 And now it came to pass that
according to our record, and we know our record
to be true, for behold, it was a just
man who did keep the record—for he
truly did many miracles in the name of
Jesus; and there was not any man who could
do a miracle in the name of Jesus save
he were cleansed every whit from his iniquity—
2 And now it came to pass, if there
was no mistake made by this man in
the reckoning of our time, the
thirty and third year had passed away;
3 And the people began to look
with great earnestness for the
sign which had been given by the
prophet Samuel, the Lamanite,
yea, for the time that there should
be darkness for the space of
three days over the face of the land.
4 And there began to be great
doubtings and disputations
among the people, notwithstanding
so many signs had been given.
5 And it came to pass in
the thirty and fourth year,
in the first month, on
the fourth day of the month,
there arose a great
storm, such an one as never had
been known in all the land.
6 And there was also a
great and terrible
tempest; and there was
terrible thunder, insomuch
that it did shake the
whole earth as if it was
about to divide asunder.
7 And there were
exceedingly sharp lightnings,
such as never had been
known in all the land.
8 And the city of
Zarahemla did take fire.
9 And the city of
Moroni did sink into
the depths of the
sea, and the
inhabitants thereof were drowned.
10 And the earth was
carried up upon the
city of Moronihah,
that in the place of
the city there
became a great mountain.
11 And there was a
great and
terrible destruction in
the land southward.
12 But behold,
there was a more
great and terrible
destruction in
the land northward;
for behold, the
whole face of the
land was
changed, because of the
tempest and the
whirlwinds, and
the thunderings and
the lightnings,
and the
exceedingly great quaking
of the whole earth;
13 And the
highways were
broken up, and the
level roads were
spoiled, and
many smooth
places became rough.
14 And many
great and
notable cities were
sunk, and many
were burned,
and many were
shaken till
the buildings
thereof had
fallen to the
earth, and the
inhabitants
thereof were slain,
and the
places were left desolate.
15 And there
were some
cities which
remained; but
the damage
thereof was
exceedingly great,
and there
were many in
them who were slain.
16 And there
were some
who were
carried away in
the
whirlwind; and
whither they went
no man
knoweth, save
they know that
they were
carried away.
17 And thus
the face
of the whole
earth
became
deformed, because
of the
tempests, and
the
thunderings, and the
lightnings, and the
quaking of the earth.
18 And
behold, the
rocks were
rent in
twain; they
were
broken up upon
the face
of the
whole earth,
insomuch
that they
were found
in broken
fragments,
and in
seams and in
cracks,
upon all the face of the land.
19 And it
came to
pass that
when the
thunderings, and
the
lightnings,
and the
storm, and
the
tempest, and
quakings of the
earth did
cease—for behold,
they did
last for
about
the space
of three
hours; and
it was
said by
some that
the time
was
greater;
nevertheless,
all these
great and
terrible
things
were done
in about
the space
of three
hours—and then
behold,
there was darkness upon the face of the land.
20 And
it came
to pass
that
there was
thick
darkness
upon all
the face
of the
land,
insomuch
that the
inhabitants
thereof who
had not
fallen
could feel
the vapor of darkness;
21 And
there
could be
no
light,
because of
the
darkness,
neither
candles,
torches;
neither
could
there
be fire
kindled
with
their
fine and
exceedingly
dry wood,
so
that there
could not be any light at all;
22 And
there
was
not any
light
seen,
neither
fire, nor
glimmer,
neither
the
sun, nor
moon,
nor the
stars, for
so
great
were the
mists
of
darkness
which
were upon the face of the land.
And it
came
to
pass
that it
did
last
for
the
space
of
three
days
that
there
was no
light
seen;
and
there
was
great
mourning and
howling
and
weeping
among all
the
people
continually;
yea,
great
were
the
groanings
of
the
people,
because of
the
darkness and the great destruction which had come upon them.
And
in
one
place
they
were
heard
to
cry,
saying:
O
that
we
had
repented
before
this
great
and
terrible
day,
and
then
would
our
brethren
have
been
spared,
and
they
would
not
have been burned in that great city Zarahemla.
And
in
another
place
they
were
heard
to
cry
and
mourn,
saying:
O
that
we
had
repented
before
this
great
and
terrible
day,
and
had
not
killed
and
stoned
the
prophets,
and
cast
them
out;
then
would
our
mothers
and
our
fair
daughters,
and
our
children
have
been
spared,
and
not
have
been
buried up in that great city Moronihah. And thus were the howlings of the people great and terrible.