Chapter 21 Israel will be gathered when the
Book of Mormon comes forth—The Gentiles will
be established as a free people in
America—They will be saved if they believe and obey;
otherwise, they will be cut off and
destroyed—Israel will build the New Jerusalem, and
the lost tribes will return. About A.D. 34.
1 And verily I say unto you, I give unto
you a sign, that ye may know the time when
these things shall be about to take
place—that I shall gather in, from their long
dispersion, my people, O house of Israel,
and shall establish again among them my Zion;
2 And behold, this is the thing which
I will give unto you for a sign—for
verily I say unto you that when these
things which I declare unto you, and
which I shall declare unto you hereafter
of myself, and by the power of the
Holy Ghost which shall be given unto you
of the Father, shall be made known
unto the Gentiles that they may know
concerning this people who are a remnant
of the house of Jacob, and concerning
this my people who shall be scattered by them;
3 Verily, verily, I say unto you, when
these things shall be made known unto
them of the Father, and shall come
forth of the Father, from them unto you;
4 For it is wisdom in the Father
that they should be established in
this land, and be set up as a free
people by the power of the Father,
that these things might come forth
from them unto a remnant of your
seed, that the covenant of the Father
may be fulfilled which he hath
covenanted with his people, O house of Israel;
5 Therefore, when these works
and the works which shall be
wrought among you hereafter shall
come forth from the Gentiles,
unto your seed which shall
dwindle in unbelief because of iniquity;
6 For thus it behooveth the
Father that it should come
forth from the Gentiles, that
he may show forth his power
unto the Gentiles, for this
cause that the Gentiles, if
they will not harden their
hearts, that they may repent
and come unto me and be
baptized in my name and know of
the true points of my
doctrine, that they may be
numbered among my people, O house of Israel;
7 And when these things
come to pass that thy seed
shall begin to know these
things—it shall be a sign
unto them, that they may
know that the work of the
Father hath already
commenced unto the fulfilling of
the covenant which he hath
made unto the people who
are of the house of Israel.
8 And when that day
shall come, it shall come to
pass that kings shall
shut their mouths; for
that which had not been
told them shall they see;
and that which they had
not heard shall they consider.
9 For in that day, for
my sake shall the
Father work a work, which
shall be a great and
a marvelous work among
them; and there shall
be among them those
who will not believe
it, although a man shall
declare it unto them.
10 But behold, the
life of my servant shall
be in my hand;
therefore they shall not hurt
him, although he
shall be marred because of
them. Yet I will heal
him, for I will show
unto them that my
wisdom is greater than the
cunning of the devil.
11 Therefore it
shall come to pass that
whosoever will not
believe in my words,
who am Jesus Christ,
which the Father
shall cause him to
bring forth unto the
Gentiles, and shall
give unto him power
that he shall bring
them forth unto the
Gentiles, (it shall be
done even as Moses
said) they shall be
cut off from among
my people who are of the covenant.
12 And my people
who are a remnant of
Jacob shall be
among the Gentiles,
yea, in the midst of
them as a lion among
the beasts of the
forest, as a young
lion among the
flocks of sheep, who,
if he go through
both treadeth down and
teareth in pieces,
and none can deliver.
13 Their hand
shall be lifted up
upon their
adversaries, and all
their enemies
shall be cut off.
14 Yea, wo be
unto the
Gentiles except they
repent; for it
shall come to
pass in that day,
saith the
Father, that I will
cut off thy
horses out of the
midst of thee,
and I will
destroy thy chariots;
15 And I will
cut off the
cities of thy
land, and
throw down all
thy strongholds;
16 And I will
cut off
witchcrafts out
of thy land,
and thou shalt
have no more
soothsayers;
17 Thy
graven images I
will also cut
off, and
thy standing
images out of
the midst
of thee, and
thou shalt
no more
worship the works
of thy hands;
18 And I
will pluck up
thy groves
out of the
midst of
thee; so
will I destroy
thy cities.
19 And it
shall come
to pass
that all
lyings, and
deceivings, and
envyings, and
strifes,
and
priestcrafts, and
whoredoms, shall be done away.
20 For it
shall
come to
pass, saith
the
Father, that
at that
day
whosoever will
not repent
and come
unto my
Beloved
Son, them
will I
cut off
from among
my people,
O house of Israel;
21 And I
will
execute
vengeance
and fury
upon
them, even
as upon
the
heathen,
such as
they have not heard.
22 But
if they
will
repent
and
hearken
unto my
words,
and
harden not
their
hearts, I
will
establish my
church
among
them, and
they
shall
come in
unto the
covenant and
be
numbered
among this
the
remnant
of
Jacob, unto
whom I
have
given this land for their inheritance;
23 And
they
shall
assist
my
people,
the
remnant
of
Jacob,
and also
as
many of
the
house of
Israel as
shall
come,
that
they may
build
a
city,
which
shall be called the New Jerusalem.
And
then
shall
they
assist
my
people
that
they
may
be
gathered
in,
who
are
scattered
upon
all the
face
of
the
land,
in unto the New Jerusalem.
And
then
shall
the
power
of
heaven
come
down
among
them;
and
I
also
will be in the midst.
And
then
shall
the
work
of
the
Father
commence
at
that
day,
even
when
this
gospel
shall
be
preached
among
the
remnant
of
this
people.
Verily
I
say
unto
you,
at
that
day
shall
the
work
of
the
Father
commence
among
all
the
dispersed
of
my
people,
yea,
even the tribes which have been lost, which the Father hath led away out of Jerusalem.
Yea,
the
work
shall
commence
among
all
the
dispersed
of
my
people,
with
the
Father
to
prepare
the
way
whereby
they
may
come
unto
me,
that
they
may
call
on
the
Father
in
my
name.
Yea,
and
then
shall
the
work
commence,
with
the
Father
among
all
nations
in
preparing
the
way
whereby
his
people may be gathered home to the land of their inheritance.
And
they
shall
go
out
from
all
nations;
and
they
shall
not
go
out
in
haste,
nor
go
by
flight,
for
I
will
go
before
them,
saith
the
Father,
and
I
will
be
their
rearward.