Chapter 20 Jesus provides bread and wine
miraculously and again administers the sacrament unto the
people—The remnant of Jacob will come to the
knowledge of the Lord their God and will inherit the
Americas—Jesus is the prophet like unto Moses, and
the Nephites are children of the prophets—Others of
the Lord’s people will be gathered to Jerusalem.
About A.D. 34.
1 And it came to pass that he commanded the
multitude that they should cease to pray, and also his
disciples. And he commanded them that they should
not cease to pray in their hearts
2 And he commanded them that they should arise and
stand up upon their feet. And they arose up and
stood upon their feet
3 And it came to pass that he brake bread again
and blessed it, and gave to the disciples to eat
4 And when they had eaten he commanded them that
they should break bread, and give unto the
multitude
5 And when they had given unto the multitude he
also gave them wine to drink, and commanded them
that they should give unto the multitude
6 Now, there had been no bread, neither wine,
brought by the disciples, neither by the multitude
7 But he truly gave unto them bread to eat, and
also wine to drink
8 And he said unto them: He that eateth this bread
eateth of my body to his soul; and he that
drinketh of this wine drinketh of my blood to his soul;
and his soul shall never hunger nor thirst, but
shall be filled
9 Now, when the multitude had all eaten and drunk,
behold, they were filled with the Spirit; and
they did cry out with one voice, and gave glory to
Jesus, whom they both saw and heard
10 And it came to pass that when they had all
given glory unto Jesus, he said unto them: Behold now
I finish the commandment which the Father hath
commanded me concerning this people, who are a
remnant of the house of Israel
11 Ye remember that I spake unto you, and said
that when the words of Isaiah should be
fulfilled—behold they are written, ye have them before you,
therefore search them
12 And verily, verily, I say unto you, that when
they shall be fulfilled then is the fulfilling of
the covenant which the Father hath made unto his
people, O house of Israel
13 And then shall the remnants, which shall be
scattered abroad upon the face of the earth, be
gathered in from the east and from the west, and from
the south and from the north; and they shall be
brought to the knowledge of the Lord their God, who
hath redeemed them
14 And the Father hath commanded me that I should
give unto you this land, for your inheritance
15 And I say unto you, that if the Gentiles do not
repent after the blessing which they shall
receive, after they have scattered my people
16 Then shall ye, who are a remnant of the house
of Jacob, go forth among them; and ye shall be in
the midst of them who shall be many; and ye shall
be among them as a lion among the beasts of the
forest, and as a young lion among the flocks of
sheep, who, if he goeth through both treadeth down and
teareth in pieces, and none can deliver
17 Thy hand shall be lifted up upon thine
adversaries, and all thine enemies shall be cut off
18 And I will gather my people together as a man
gathereth his sheaves into the floor
19 For I will make my people with whom the Father
hath covenanted, yea, I will make thy horn iron,
and I will make thy hoofs brass. And thou shalt
beat in pieces many people; and I will consecrate
their gain unto the Lord, and their substance unto
the Lord of the whole earth. And behold, I am he who
doeth it
20 And it shall come to pass, saith the Father,
that the sword of my justice shall hang over them at
that day; and except they repent it shall fall
upon them, saith the Father, yea, even upon all the
nations of the Gentiles
21 And it shall come to pass that I will establish
my people, O house of Israel
22 And behold, this people will I establish in
this land, unto the fulfilling of the covenant which
I made with your father Jacob; and it shall be a
New Jerusalem. And the powers of heaven shall be in
the midst of this people; yea, even I will be in
the midst of you
23 Behold, I am he of whom Moses spake, saying: A
prophet shall the Lord your God raise up unto you
of your brethren, like unto me; him shall ye hear
in all things whatsoever he shall say unto you.
And it shall come to pass that every soul who will
not hear that prophet shall be cut off from among
the people
24 Verily I say unto you, yea, and all the
prophets from Samuel and those that follow after, as many
as have spoken, have testified of me
25 And behold, ye are the children of the
prophets; and ye are of the house of Israel; and ye are of
the covenant which the Father made with your
fathers, saying unto Abraham: And in thy seed shall
all the kindreds of the earth be blessed
26 The Father having raised me up unto you first,
and sent me to bless you in turning away every one
of you from his iniquities; and this because ye
are the children of the covenant
27 And after that ye were blessed then fulfilleth
the Father the covenant which he made with
Abraham, saying: In thy seed shall all the kindreds of
the earth be blessed—unto the pouring out of the
Holy Ghost through me upon the Gentiles, which
blessing upon the Gentiles shall make them mighty above
all, unto the scattering of my people, O house of
Israel
28 And they shall be a scourge unto the people of
this land. Nevertheless, when they shall have
received the fulness of my gospel, then if they shall
harden their hearts against me I will return their
iniquities upon their own heads, saith the
Father
29 And I will remember the covenant which I have
made with my people; and I have covenanted with
them that I would gather them together in mine own
due time, that I would give unto them again the land
of their fathers for their inheritance, which is
the land of Jerusalem, which is the promised land
unto them forever, saith the Father
30 And it shall come to pass that the time cometh,
when the fulness of my gospel shall be preached
unto them
31 And they shall believe in me, that I am Jesus
Christ, the Son of God, and shall pray unto the
Father in my name
32 Then shall their watchmen lift up their voice,
and with the voice together shall they sing; for
they shall see eye to eye
33 Then will the Father gather them together
again, and give unto them Jerusalem for the land of
their inheritance
34 Then shall they break forth into joy—Sing
together, ye waste places of Jerusalem; for the Father
hath comforted his people, he hath redeemed
Jerusalem
35 The Father hath made bare his holy arm in the
eyes of all the nations; and all the ends of the
earth shall see the salvation of the Father; and the
Father and I are one
36 And then shall be brought to pass that which is
written: Awake, awake again, and put on thy
strength, O Zion; put on thy beautiful garments, O
Jerusalem, the holy city, for henceforth there shall
no more come into thee the uncircumcised and the
unclean
37 Shake thyself from the dust; arise, sit down, O
Jerusalem; loose thyself from the bands of thy
neck, O captive daughter of Zion
38 For thus saith the Lord: Ye have sold
yourselves for naught, and ye shall be redeemed without
money
39 Verily, verily, I say unto you, that my people
shall know my name; yea, in that day they shall
know that I am he that doth speak
40 And then shall they say: How beautiful upon the
mountains are the feet of him that bringeth good
tidings unto them, that publisheth peace; that
bringeth good tidings unto them of good, that
publisheth salvation; that saith unto Zion: Thy God
reigneth
41 And then shall a cry go forth: Depart ye,
depart ye, go ye out from thence, touch not that which
is unclean; go ye out of the midst of her; be ye
clean that bear the vessels of the Lord
42 For ye shall not go out with haste nor go by
flight; for the Lord will go before you, and the God
of Israel shall be your rearward
43 Behold, my servant shall deal prudently; he
shall be exalted and extolled and be very high
44 As many were astonished at thee—his visage was
so marred, more than any man, and his form more
than the sons of men
45 So shall he sprinkle many nations; the kings
shall shut their mouths at him, for that which had
not been told them shall they see; and that which
they had not heard shall they consider
46 Verily, verily, I say unto you, all these
things shall surely come, even as the Father hath
commanded me. Then shall this covenant which the Father
hath covenanted with his people be fulfilled; and
then shall Jerusalem be inhabited again with my
people, and it shall be the land of their
inheritance.