Chapter 7 The chief judge is murdered, the
government is destroyed, and the people divide into
tribes—Jacob, an anti-Christ, becomes king of a secret
combination—Nephi preaches repentance and faith in
Christ—Angels minister to him daily, and he
raises his brother from the dead—Many repent and are
baptized. About A.D. 30–33.
1 Now behold, I will show unto you that they did
not establish a king over the land; but in this
same year, yea, the thirtieth year, they did destroy
upon the judgment-seat, yea, did murder the chief
judge of the land
2 And the people were divided one against another;
and they did separate one from another into
tribes, every man according to his family and his
kindred and friends; and thus they did destroy the
government of the land
3 And every tribe did appoint a chief or a leader
over them; and thus they became tribes and leaders
of tribes
4 Now behold, there was no man among them save he
had much family and many kindreds and friends;
therefore their tribes became exceedingly great
5 Now all this was done, and there were no wars as
yet among them; and all this iniquity had come
upon the people because they did yield themselves
unto the power of Satan
6 And the regulations of the government were
destroyed, because of the secret combination of the
friends and kindreds of those who murdered the
prophets
7 And they did cause a great contention in the
land, insomuch that the more righteous part of the
people had nearly all become wicked; yea, there were
but few righteous men among them
8 And thus six years had not passed away since the
more part of the people had turned from their
righteousness, like the dog to his vomit, or like the
sow to her wallowing in the mire
9 Now this secret combination, which had brought
so great iniquity upon the people, did gather
themselves together, and did place at their head a man
whom they did call Jacob
10 And they did call him their king; therefore he
became a king over this wicked band; and he was
one of the chiefest who had given his voice against
the prophets who testified of Jesus
11 And it came to pass that they were not so
strong in number as the tribes of the people, who were
united together save it were their leaders did
establish their laws, every one according to his
tribe; nevertheless they were enemies; notwithstanding
they were not a righteous people, yet they were
united in the hatred of those who had entered into
a covenant to destroy the government
12 Therefore, Jacob seeing that their enemies were
more numerous than they, he being the king of the
band, therefore he commanded his people that they
should take their flight into the northernmost
part of the land, and there build up unto themselves
a kingdom, until they were joined by dissenters,
(for he flattered them that there would be many
dissenters) and they become sufficiently strong to
contend with the tribes of the people; and they did
so
13 And so speedy was their march that it could not
be impeded until they had gone forth out of the
reach of the people. And thus ended the thirtieth
year; and thus were the affairs of the people of
Nephi
14 And it came to pass in the thirty and first
year that they were divided into tribes, every man
according to his family, kindred and friends;
nevertheless they had come to an agreement that they
would not go to war one with another; but they were
not united as to their laws, and their manner of
government, for they were established according to
the minds of those who were their chiefs and their
leaders. But they did establish very strict laws
that one tribe should not trespass against another,
insomuch that in some degree they had peace in
the land; nevertheless, their hearts were turned
from the Lord their God, and they did stone the
prophets and did cast them out from among them
15 And it came to pass that Nephi—having been
visited by angels and also the voice of the Lord,
therefore having seen angels, and being eye-witness,
and having had power given unto him that he might
know concerning the ministry of Christ, and also
being eye-witness to their quick return from
righteousness unto their wickedness and abominations
16 Therefore, being grieved for the hardness of
their hearts and the blindness of their minds—went
forth among them in that same year, and began to
testify, boldly, repentance and remission of sins
through faith on the Lord Jesus Christ
17 And he did minister many things unto them; and
all of them cannot be written, and a part of them
would not suffice, therefore they are not written
in this book. And Nephi did minister with power
and with great authority
18 And it came to pass that they were angry with
him, even because he had greater power than they,
for it were not possible that they could disbelieve
his words, for so great was his faith on the Lord
Jesus Christ that angels did minister unto him
daily
19 And in the name of Jesus did he cast out devils
and unclean spirits; and even his brother did he
raise from the dead, after he had been stoned and
suffered death by the people
20 And the people saw it, and did witness of it,
and were angry with him because of his power; and
he did also do many more miracles, in the sight of
the people, in the name of Jesus
21 And it came to pass that the thirty and first
year did pass away, and there were but few who were
converted unto the Lord; but as many as were
converted did truly signify unto the people that they
had been visited by the power and Spirit of God,
which was in Jesus Christ, in whom they believed
22 And as many as had devils cast out from them,
and were healed of their sicknesses and their
infirmities, did truly manifest unto the people that
they had been wrought upon by the Spirit of God, and
had been healed; and they did show forth signs
also and did do some miracles among the people
23 Thus passed away the thirty and second year
also. And Nephi did cry unto the people in the
commencement of the thirty and third year; and he did
preach unto them repentance and remission of sins
24 Now I would have you to remember also, that
there were none who were brought unto repentance who
were not baptized with water
25 Therefore, there were ordained of Nephi, men
unto this ministry, that all such as should come
unto them should be baptized with water, and this as
a witness and a testimony before God, and unto the
people, that they had repented and received a
remission of their sins
26 And there were many in the commencement of this
year that were baptized unto repentance; and thus
the more part of the year did pass away.