Chapter 18 Jesus institutes the sacrament among
the Nephites—They are commanded to pray always
in His name—Those who eat His flesh and drink His
blood unworthily are damned—The disciples are
given power to confer the Holy Ghost. About A.D. 34.
1 And it came to pass that Jesus
commanded his disciples that they should
bring forth some bread and wine unto him.
2 And while they were gone for
bread and wine, he commanded
the multitude that they should
sit themselves down upon the earth.
3 And when the disciples had
come with bread and wine,
he took of the bread and
brake and blessed it; and he
gave unto the disciples and
commanded that they should eat.
4 And when they had
eaten and were filled, he
commanded that they should
give unto the multitude.
5 And when the
multitude had eaten and were
filled, he said unto
the disciples: Behold
there shall one be
ordained among you, and to
him will I give power
that he shall break
bread and bless it and
give it unto the
people of my church, unto
all those who shall
believe and be baptized in my name.
6 And this shall ye
always observe to do,
even as I have done,
even as I have broken
bread and blessed it
and given it unto you.
7 And this shall ye
do in remembrance of
my body, which I
have shown unto you.
And it shall be a
testimony unto the
Father that ye do always
remember me. And if
ye do always
remember me ye shall have
my Spirit to be with you.
8 And it came to
pass that when he said
these words, he
commanded his disciples
that they should
take of the wine of the
cup and drink of
it, and that they
should also give unto
the multitude that
they might drink of it.
9 And it came to
pass that they did
so, and did drink of
it and were filled;
and they gave unto
the multitude, and
they did drink,
and they were filled.
10 And when the
disciples had done
this, Jesus said
unto them:
Blessed are ye for
this thing which ye
have done, for
this is fulfilling
my commandments,
and this doth
witness unto the
Father that ye are
willing to do that
which I have commanded you.
11 And this
shall ye always do
to those who
repent and are
baptized in my name;
and ye shall do
it in
remembrance of my blood,
which I have shed
for you, that
ye may witness
unto the Father
that ye do always
remember me. And
if ye do always
remember me ye
shall have my
Spirit to be with you.
12 And I give
unto you a
commandment that ye
shall do these
things. And if
ye shall always
do these
things blessed are
ye, for ye are
built upon my rock.
13 But whoso
among you shall
do more or
less than these
are not built
upon my rock,
but are built
upon a sandy
foundation; and
when the rain
descends, and
the floods
come, and the
winds blow, and
beat upon
them, they shall
fall, and the
gates of hell
are ready open to receive them.
14 Therefore
blessed are
ye if ye shall
keep my
commandments,
which the Father
hath
commanded me that I
should give unto you.
15 Verily,
verily, I say
unto you,
ye must watch
and pray
always, lest
ye be tempted
by the
devil, and ye be
led away
captive by him.
16 And as I
have
prayed among you
even so
shall ye pray
in my
church, among
my people
who do repent
and are
baptized in
my name.
Behold I am
the light; I
have set an
example for you.
17 And it
came to
pass that
when Jesus
had spoken
these
words unto his
disciples, he
turned again
unto the
multitude and
said unto them:
Behold, verily,
verily,
I say
unto you, ye
must
watch and
pray always
lest ye
enter
into
temptation; for
Satan
desireth to
have you,
that he
may sift you as wheat.
Therefore ye
must
always pray
unto
the Father
in my name;
20 And
whatsoever ye
shall
ask the
Father
in my
name,
which is
right,
believing that
ye
shall
receive,
behold it
shall
be given unto you.
Pray in
your
families
unto
the
Father,
always
in my
name,
that
your
wives
and
your
children may be blessed.
And
behold,
ye
shall
meet
together
oft;
and ye
shall
not
forbid any
man
from
coming
unto you
when
ye
shall
meet
together,
but
suffer
them
that
they
may
come unto you and forbid them not;
But ye
shall
pray
for
them,
and
shall
not
cast
them
out;
and
if it
so be
that
they
come
unto
you
oft
ye
shall
pray
for
them
unto the
Father,
in my
name.
Therefore,
hold
up
your
light
that it
may
shine
unto
the
world.
Behold I
am
the
light
which
ye
shall
hold
up—that
which
ye
have
seen
me
do.
Behold ye
see
that I
have
prayed unto the Father, and ye all have witnessed.
And
ye
see
that I
have
commanded
that
none of
you
should
go
away,
but
rather
have
commanded
that
ye
should
come
unto
me,
that
ye
might
feel
and
see;
even
so
shall ye
do
unto
the
world;
and
whosoever
breaketh
this
commandment
suffereth
himself to
be
led
into
temptation.
And
now
it
came
to
pass
that
when
Jesus
had
spoken
these
words,
he
turned
his
eyes
again
upon
the
disciples
whom he had chosen, and said unto them:
Behold
verily,
I
say
unto
you,
I
give
unto
you
another
commandment,
and
then
I
must
go
unto
my
Father
that I may fulfil other commandments which he hath given me.
And
now
behold,
this
is
the
commandment
which
I
give
unto
you,
that
ye
shall
not
suffer
any
one
knowingly
to
partake
of
my
flesh
and
blood
unworthily,
when
ye
shall
minister
it;
29 For whoso eateth and drinketh my flesh and blood unworthily eateth and drinketh damnation to his soul; therefore if ye know that a man is unworthy to eat and drink of my flesh and blood ye shall forbid
For
whoso
eateth
and
drinketh
my
flesh
and
blood
unworthily
eateth
and
drinketh
damnation
to
his
soul; therefore if ye know that a man is unworthy to eat and drink of my flesh and blood ye shall forbid him.
30 Nevertheless, ye shall not cast him out from among you, but ye shall minister unto him and shall pray for him unto the Father, in my name; and if it so be that he repenteth and is baptized in my name, then shall ye receive him, and shall minister unto him of my flesh and
Nevertheless,
ye
shall
not
cast
him
out
from
among
you,
but
ye
shall
minister
unto
him
and
shall
pray
for
him
unto
the
Father,
in
my
name;
that
he
repenteth
and
is
baptized
in
my
name,
then
shall
ye
receive
him,
and
shall
minister
unto
him
of
my
flesh
and
blood.
31 But if he repent not he shall not be numbered among my people, that he may not destroy my people, for behold I know my sheep, and they are
But
if
he
repent
not
he
shall
not
be
numbered
among
my
people,
that
he
may
not
destroy
my
people,
for
behold
I
know
my
sheep,
and
they
are
numbered.
32 Nevertheless, ye shall not cast him out of your synagogues, or your places of worship, for unto such shall ye continue to minister; for ye know not but what they will return and repent, and come unto me with full purpose of heart, and I shall heal them; and ye shall be the means of bringing salvation unto
Nevertheless,
ye
shall
not
cast
him
out
of
your
synagogues,
or
your
places
of
worship,
for
unto
such
shall
ye
continue
to
minister;
for
ye
know
not
but
what
they
will
return
and
repent,
come
unto
me
with
full
purpose
of
heart,
and
I
shall
heal
them;
and
ye
shall
be
the
means
of
bringing
salvation
unto
them.
33 Therefore, keep these sayings which I have commanded you that ye come not under condemnation; for wo unto him whom the Father
Therefore,
keep
these
sayings
which
I
have
commanded
you
that
ye
come
not
under
condemnation;
for
wo
unto
him
whom
the
Father
condemneth.
34 And I give you these commandments because of the disputations which have been among you. And blessed are ye if ye have no disputations among
And
I
give
you
these
commandments
because
of
the
disputations
which
have
been
among
you.
And
blessed
are
ye
if
have
no
disputations
among
you.
35 And now I go unto the Father, because it is expedient that I should go unto the Father for your
And
now
I
go
unto
the
Father,
because
it
is
expedient
that
I
should
go
unto
the
Father
for
your
sakes.
36 And it came to pass that when Jesus had made an end of these sayings, he touched with his hand the disciples whom he had chosen, one by one, even until he had touched them all, and spake unto them as he touched
And
it
came
to
pass
that
when
Jesus
had
made
an
end
of
these
sayings,
he
touched
with
his
hand
the
disciples
whom
he
had
chosen,
one
by
one,
even
until
he
had
touched
them
all,
and
spake
unto
them
as
he
touched
them.
37 And the multitude heard not the words which he spake, therefore they did not bear record; but the disciples bare record that he gave them power to give the Holy Ghost. And I will show unto you hereafter that this record is
And
the
multitude
heard
not
the
words
which
he
spake,
therefore
they
did
not
bear
record;
but
the
disciples
bare
record
that
he
gave
them
power
to
give
the
Holy
Ghost.
And
I
will
show
unto
you
hereafter
that
this
record
is
true.
38 And it came to pass that when Jesus had touched them all, there came a cloud and overshadowed the multitude that they could not see
And
it
came
to
pass
that
when
Jesus
had
touched
them
all,
there
came
a
cloud
and
overshadowed
the
multitude
that
they
could
not
see
Jesus.
39 And while they were overshadowed he departed from them, and ascended into heaven. And the disciples saw and did bear record that he ascended again into heaven.
And
while
they
were
overshadowed
he
departed
from
them,
and
ascended
into
heaven.
And
the
disciples
saw
and
did
bear
record
that
he
ascended
again
into
heaven.