Chapter 17 Jesus directs the people to ponder
His words and pray for understanding—He heals
their sick—He prays for the people, using
language that cannot be written—Angels minister to and
fire encircles their little ones. About A.D. 34.
1 Behold, now it came to pass that when
Jesus had spoken these words he looked
round about again on the multitude, and he
said unto them: Behold, my time is at hand.
2 I perceive that ye are weak,
that ye cannot understand all my
words which I am commanded of the
Father to speak unto you at this time.
3 Therefore, go ye unto your
homes, and ponder upon the
things which I have said, and
ask of the Father, in my name,
that ye may understand, and
prepare your minds for the
morrow, and I come unto you again.
4 But now I go unto the
Father, and also to show myself
unto the lost tribes of
Israel, for they are not lost
unto the Father, for he
knoweth whither he hath taken them.
5 And it came to pass
that when Jesus had thus
spoken, he cast his eyes
round about again on the
multitude, and beheld they
were in tears, and did
look steadfastly upon him as
if they would ask him to
tarry a little longer with them.
6 And he said unto
them: Behold, my
bowels are filled with
compassion towards you.
7 Have ye any that
are sick among you?
Bring them hither.
Have ye any that
are lame, or blind,
or halt, or maimed,
or leprous, or
that are withered, or
that are deaf, or
that are afflicted
in any manner? Bring
them hither and I
will heal them, for
I have compassion
upon you; my bowels
are filled with mercy.
8 For I perceive
that ye desire
that I should show
unto you what I
have done unto
your brethren at
Jerusalem, for I see
that your faith
is sufficient
that I should heal you.
9 And it came to
pass that when
he had thus
spoken, all the
multitude, with one
accord, did go
forth with their
sick and their
afflicted, and
their lame, and
with their blind,
and with their
dumb, and with
all them that were
afflicted in
any manner; and he
did heal them
every one as they
were brought forth unto him.
10 And they did
all, both they
who had been
healed and they
who were whole,
bow down at
his feet, and did
worship him;
and as many as
could come for
the multitude
did kiss his
feet, insomuch that
they did bathe
his feet with their tears.
11 And it came
to pass that
he commanded
that their
little children
should be brought.
12 So they
brought their
little
children and set
them down upon
the ground
round about him,
and Jesus
stood in the
midst; and the
multitude
gave way till
they had all
been brought unto him.
13 And it
came to pass
that when
they had all
been brought,
and Jesus
stood in the
midst, he
commanded the
multitude
that they
should kneel down
upon the ground.
14 And it
came to pass
that when
they had
knelt upon
the ground,
Jesus
groaned within
himself, and
said:
Father, I am
troubled
because of the
wickedness
of the
people of the house of Israel.
15 And
when he had
said these
words, he
himself
also knelt
upon the
earth; and
behold he
prayed unto
the
Father, and the
things
which he
prayed cannot
be
written, and the
multitude
did bear
record who heard him.
16 And
after this
manner do
they
bear record:
The eye
hath
never seen,
neither
hath the
ear heard,
before,
so great
and
marvelous
things as we
saw and
heard Jesus
speak unto the Father;
17 And
no tongue
can
speak,
neither can
there be
written
by any
man,
neither can
the
hearts of
men
conceive so
great and
marvelous
things as we
both saw
and
heard Jesus
speak;
and no
one can
conceive
of the
joy which
filled
our
souls at the
time we
heard him pray for us unto the Father.
18 And
it came
to
pass that
when
Jesus had
made
an end
of
praying unto
the
Father,
he
arose; but
so great
was
the joy
of the
multitude that they were overcome.
19 And
it
came to
pass
that
Jesus
spake
unto
them, and
bade
them arise.
20 And
they
arose
from
the
earth,
and he
said
unto
them:
Blessed
are ye
because of
your
faith.
And now
behold, my
joy is
full.
And
when he
had
said
these
words, he
wept,
and
the
multitude
bare
record
of
it,
and he
took
their
little
children,
one by
one,
and
blessed
them,
and prayed unto the Father for them.
And
when
he
had
done
this
he
wept again;
And
he
spake
unto
the
multitude,
and
said
unto
them:
Behold
your
little
ones.
And
as
they
looked
to
behold
they
cast
their
eyes
towards
heaven,
and
they
saw
the
heavens
open,
and
they
saw
angels
descending
out
of
heaven
as
it
were
in
the
midst
of
fire;
and
they
came
down
and
encircled
those
little
ones
about, and they were encircled about with fire; and the angels did minister unto them.
And
the
multitude
did
see
and
hear
bear
record;
and
they
know
that
their
record
is
true
for
they
all
of
them
did
see
and
hear,
every
man
for
himself;
and
they
were
in
number
about two thousand and five hundred souls; and they did consist of men, women, and children.