Chapter 28 Nine of the twelve disciples desire and
are promised an inheritance in Christ’s kingdom
when they die—The Three Nephites desire and are
given power over death so as to remain on the earth
until Jesus comes again—They are translated and see
things not lawful to utter, and they are now
ministering among men. About A.D. 34–35.
1 And it came to pass when Jesus had said these
words, he spake unto his disciples, one by one,
saying unto them: What is it that ye desire of me,
after that I am gone to the Father
2 And they all spake, save it were three, saying:
We desire that after we have lived unto the age of
man, that our ministry, wherein thou hast called
us, may have an end, that we may speedily come
unto thee in thy kingdom
3 And he said unto them: Blessed are ye because ye
desired this thing of me; therefore, after that
ye are seventy and two years old ye shall come unto
me in my kingdom; and with me ye shall find rest
4 And when he had spoken unto them, he turned
himself unto the three, and said unto them: What will
ye that I should do unto you, when I am gone unto
the Father
5 And they sorrowed in their hearts, for they
durst not speak unto him the thing which they desired
6 And he said unto them: Behold, I know your
thoughts, and ye have desired the thing which John, my
beloved, who was with me in my ministry, before
that I was lifted up by the Jews, desired of me
7 Therefore, more blessed are ye, for ye shall
never taste of death; but ye shall live to behold all
the doings of the Father unto the children of
men, even until all things shall be fulfilled
according to the will of the Father, when I shall come in
my glory with the powers of heaven
8 And ye shall never endure the pains of death;
but when I shall come in my glory ye shall be
changed in the twinkling of an eye from mortality to
immortality; and then shall ye be blessed in the
kingdom of my Father
9 And again, ye shall not have pain while ye shall
dwell in the flesh, neither sorrow save it be for
the sins of the world; and all this will I do
because of the thing which ye have desired of me, for
ye have desired that ye might bring the souls of
men unto me, while the world shall stand
10 And for this cause ye shall have fulness of
joy; and ye shall sit down in the kingdom of my
Father; yea, your joy shall be full, even as the Father
hath given me fulness of joy; and ye shall be
even as I am, and I am even as the Father; and the
Father and I are one
11 And the Holy Ghost beareth record of the Father
and me; and the Father giveth the Holy Ghost unto
the children of men, because of me
12 And it came to pass that when Jesus had spoken
these words, he touched every one of them with his
finger save it were the three who were to tarry,
and then he departed
13 And behold, the heavens were opened, and they
were caught up into heaven, and saw and heard
unspeakable things
14 And it was forbidden them that they should
utter; neither was it given unto them power that they
could utter the things which they saw and heard
15 And whether they were in the body or out of the
body, they could not tell; for it did seem unto
them like a transfiguration of them, that they were
changed from this body of flesh into an immortal
state, that they could behold the things of God
16 But it came to pass that they did again
minister upon the face of the earth; nevertheless they
did not minister of the things which they had heard
and seen, because of the commandment which was
given them in heaven
17 And now, whether they were mortal or immortal,
from the day of their transfiguration, I know not
18 But this much I know, according to the record
which hath been given—they did go forth upon the
face of the land, and did minister unto all the
people, uniting as many to the church as would believe
in their preaching; baptizing them, and as many
as were baptized did receive the Holy Ghost
19 And they were cast into prison by them who did
not belong to the church. And the prisons could
not hold them, for they were rent in twain
20 And they were cast down into the earth; but
they did smite the earth with the word of God,
insomuch that by his power they were delivered out of
the depths of the earth; and therefore they could
not dig pits sufficient to hold them
21 And thrice they were cast into a furnace and
received no harm
22 And twice were they cast into a den of wild
beasts; and behold they did play with the beasts as a
child with a suckling lamb, and received no harm
23 And it came to pass that thus they did go forth
among all the people of Nephi, and did preach the
gospel of Christ unto all people upon the face of
the land; and they were converted unto the Lord,
and were united unto the church of Christ, and
thus the people of that generation were blessed,
according to the word of Jesus
24 And now I, Mormon, make an end of speaking
concerning these things for a time
25 Behold, I was about to write the names of those
who were never to taste of death, but the Lord
forbade; therefore I write them not, for they are
hid from the world
26 But behold, I have seen them, and they have
ministered unto me
27 And behold they will be among the Gentiles, and
the Gentiles shall know them not
28 They will also be among the Jews, and the Jews
shall know them not
29 And it shall come to pass, when the Lord seeth
fit in his wisdom that they shall minister unto
all the scattered tribes of Israel, and unto all
nations, kindreds, tongues and people, and shall
bring out of them unto Jesus many souls, that their
desire may be fulfilled, and also because of the
convincing power of God which is in them
30 And they are as the angels of God, and if they
shall pray unto the Father in the name of Jesus
they can show themselves unto whatsoever man it
seemeth them good
31 Therefore, great and marvelous works shall be
wrought by them, before the great and coming day
when all people must surely stand before the
judgment-seat of Christ
32 Yea even among the Gentiles shall there be a
great and marvelous work wrought by them, before
that judgment day
33 And if ye had all the scriptures which give an
account of all the marvelous works of Christ, ye
would, according to the words of Christ, know that
these things must surely come
34 And wo be unto him that will not hearken unto
the words of Jesus, and also to them whom he hath
chosen and sent among them; for whoso receiveth not
the words of Jesus and the words of those whom he
hath sent receiveth not him; and therefore he
will not receive them at the last day
35 And it would be better for them if they had not
been born. For do ye suppose that ye can get rid
of the justice of an offended God, who hath been
trampled under feet of men, that thereby salvation
might come
36 And now behold, as I spake concerning those
whom the Lord hath chosen, yea, even three who were
caught up into the heavens, that I knew not whether
they were cleansed from mortality to immortality
37 But behold, since I wrote, I have inquired of
the Lord, and he hath made it manifest unto me that
there must needs be a change wrought upon their
bodies, or else it needs be that they must taste of
death
38 Therefore, that they might not taste of death
there was a change wrought upon their bodies, that
they might not suffer pain nor sorrow save it were
for the sins of the world
39 Now this change was not equal to that which
shall take place at the last day; but there was a
change wrought upon them, insomuch that Satan could
have no power over them, that he could not tempt
them; and they were sanctified in the flesh, that
they were holy, and that the powers of the earth
could not hold them
40 And in this state they were to remain until the
judgment day of Christ; and at that day they were
to receive a greater change, and to be received
into the kingdom of the Father to go no more out,
but to dwell with God eternally in the heavens.