Red Sea—They leave their property—Lehi offers a sacrifice to the
Lord and teaches his sons to keep the commandments—Laman and
Lemuel murmur against their father—Nephi is obedient and prays in
faith; the Lord speaks to him, and he is chosen
to rule over his brethren. About 600 B.C.
1 For behold, it came to pass that the Lord
spake unto my father, yea, even in a dream, and
said unto him: Blessed art thou Lehi, because of the
things which thou hast done; and because thou hast been
faithful and declared unto this people the things which I
commanded thee, behold, they seek to take away thy life.
2 And it came to pass that the Lord commanded
my father, even in a dream, that he should take
his family and depart into the wilderness.
3 And it came to pass that he was obedient
unto the word of the Lord, wherefore he did as
the Lord commanded him.
4 And it came to pass that he departed into
the wilderness. And he left his house, and the land
of his inheritance, and his gold, and his silver, and
his precious things, and took nothing with him, save it
were his family, and provisions, and tents, and departed into
the wilderness.
5 And he came down by the borders near the
shore of the Red Sea; and he traveled in the
wilderness in the borders which are nearer the Red Sea;
and he did travel in the wilderness with his family,
which consisted of my mother, Sariah, and my elder brothers,
who were Laman, Lemuel, and Sam.
6 And it came to pass that when he had
traveled three days in the wilderness, he pitched his tent
in a valley by the side of a river of
water.
7 And it came to pass that he built an
altar of stones, and made an offering unto the Lord,
and gave thanks unto the Lord our God.
8 And it came to pass that he called the
name of the river, Laman, and it emptied into the
Red Sea; and the valley was in the borders near
the mouth thereof.
9 And when my father saw that the waters of
the river emptied into the fountain of the Red Sea,
he spake unto Laman, saying: O that thou mightest be
like unto this river, continually running into the fountain of
all righteousness!
10 And he also spake unto Lemuel: O that thou
mightest be like unto this valley, firm and steadfast, and
immovable in keeping the commandments of the Lord!
11 Now this he spake because of the stiffneckedness of
Laman and Lemuel; for behold they did murmur in many
things against their father, because he was a visionary man,
and had led them out of the land of Jerusalem,
to leave the land of their inheritance, and their gold,
and their silver, and their precious things, to perish in
the wilderness. And this they said he had done because
of the foolish imaginations of his heart.
12 And thus Laman and Lemuel, being the eldest, did
murmur against their father. And they did murmur because they
knew not the dealings of that God who had created
them.
13 Neither did they believe that Jerusalem, that great city,
could be destroyed according to the words of the prophets.
And they were like unto the Jews who were at
Jerusalem, who sought to take away the life of my
father.
14 And it came to pass that my father did
speak unto them in the valley of Lemuel, with power,
being filled with the Spirit, until their frames did shake
before him. And he did confound them, that they durst
not utter against him; wherefore, they did as he commanded
them.
15 And my father dwelt in a tent.
16 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, being
exceedingly young, nevertheless being large in stature, and also having
great desires to know of the mysteries of God, wherefore,
I did cry unto the Lord; and behold he did
visit me, and did soften my heart that I did
believe all the words which had been spoken by my
father; wherefore, I did not rebel against him like unto
my brothers.
17 And I spake unto Sam, making known unto him
the things which the Lord had manifested unto me by
his Holy Spirit. And it came to pass that he
believed in my words.
18 But, behold, Laman and Lemuel would not hearken unto
my words; and being grieved because of the hardness of
their hearts I cried unto the Lord for them.
19 And it came to pass that the Lord spake
unto me, saying: Blessed art thou, Nephi, because of thy
faith, for thou hast sought me diligently, with lowliness of
heart.
20 And inasmuch as ye shall keep my commandments, ye
shall prosper, and shall be led to a land of
promise; yea, even a land which I have prepared for
you; yea, a land which is choice above all other
lands.
21 And inasmuch as thy brethren shall rebel against thee,
they shall be cut off from the presence of the
Lord.
22 And inasmuch as thou shalt keep my commandments, thou
shalt be made a ruler and a teacher over thy
brethren.
23 For behold, in that day that they shall rebel
against me, I will curse them even with a sore
curse, and they shall have no power over thy seed
except they shall rebel against me also.
24 And if it so be that they rebel against
me, they shall be a scourge unto thy seed, to
stir them up in the ways of remembrance.